<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<questions>  
  <question>
    <id>74b1c7a681e1456e8a1dd47cf8eac788</id>
    <practiceSet>e46cd0282a75410a87f70800fb101ffd</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>Nature is full of millions of plants. Thousands of them have been identified and studied by scientists in detail. Millions of them yet remain to be identified and studied. Lingri is one such plant of the main type “ferns” which has been identified but not studied in sufficient detail. Lingri grows in shady pockets in nullahs in the hills at an altitude varying from 1000 to 3000 meters. It is deep green- colored plant like a compound leaf of plants of the leguminaceae family. The main plant grows to a size of nearly 30 to 50 cm while the central stalk grows from nearly 60 to 80 cm. The stalk is covered with grayish hair. The tip coils around itself like a snake coils itself in self-defense. Lingri starts showing itself in its natural habitat from early spring. It keeps growing till autumn. The villagers collect its tender stalk and use it as a vegetable. While these can be so used as culinary substitute throughout its growing season, its preparation tastes better during the period April to June. In areas where lingri is found in abundance, people even make pickles and use it throughout the year.</description>
      <title></title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>f4ecbc6e9db84f86934f5b5f9bb14aba</id>
    <practiceSet>e46cd0282a75410a87f70800fb101ffd</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>I have spoken of liberty as good, but it is not an absolute good. We all recognize the need to restrain murderers, and it is even more important to restrain murderous states. Liberty must be limited by law, and its most valuable forms can only exist within the framework of law. What the world most needs are effective laws to control international relations. The first and most difficult step in the creation of such laws is the establishment of adequate sanctions and this is only possible through the creation of a single armed force, which is in control of the whole world. But such an armed force, like a municipal police force is not an end in itself. It is the means to growth of a social system governed by law, where force is not the prerogative of private individuals or nations, but is exercised only by a neutral authority in accordance with rules laid down in advance. There is hope that law, rather than private force, may come to govern the relations of nations with the present century.</description>
      <title></title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
    <question>
    <id>0d9c171693794048b5d6a99fadd4deba</id>
    <practiceSet>e46cd0282a75410a87f70800fb101ffd</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will have 20 minutes to plan, write and revise an essay about the topic below. Your response will be judged on how well you develop a position, organize your ideas, present supporting details and control the elements of standard written English. You should write 200-300 words.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:20:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>Prosperity brings friends and adversity tries them. How true is this statement? Explain.</description>
      <title></title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question> 
 <question>
    <id>a02b0437357f4c9fa9763bff7f7eb8ea</id>
    <practiceSet>3db6c7215baa422783ab459e3d30f17c</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>Elephants are found in India and in Africa. The African elephant differs in some points from the Indian, being larger, with longer tusks and bigger ear. In fact, the two are considered to be different species. In both countries, they live in herds in the jungles, and are naturally shy animals that keep away from men. Elephants, with their great size and strength, are fine advertisement for vegetarianism, for they live entirely on leaves of trees, grass, roots and bulbs. In Africa, elephants are hunted mainly for their tusks, which are made of ivory and are very valuable.  Their skins are so thick that an ordinary bullet will not pierce them; and so large gun, called elephant guns are used to kill the animals. In old days elephants were used in battles in India. Where all Indian Kings had their regiments of trained fighting elephants and they still have their place in state procession, when they are painted with bright colours and covered with silk and velvet clothes.</description>
      <title></title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>408e9dc454cd49b9aea2d7591246e183</id>
    <practiceSet>3db6c7215baa422783ab459e3d30f17c</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>71% of the Earth’s surface is covered by oceans. These oceans contain roughly 97% of the Earth’s water supply. The oceans of Earth are unique in our Solar system. No other planet in our Solar System has liquid water. The oceans of Earth serve many functions, especially affecting the weather and temperature. They moderate the Earth's temperature by absorbing incoming solar radiation which is stored as heat energy. The always-moving ocean currents distribute this heat energy around the globe. This heats the land and air during winter and cools it during summer. The Earth's oceans are all connected to one another.  There were five recognized oceans: the Pacific, Atlantic, Antarctic, Indian, and Arctic. There are also many seas like the South China Sea, the Caribbean Sea, and the Mediterranean Sea.</description>
      <title>EARTH'S OCEANS</title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
   <question>
    <id>408e9dc454cd49b9aea2d7591246e183</id>
    <practiceSet>3db6c7215baa422783ab459e3d30f17c</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>71% of the Earth’s surface is covered by oceans. These oceans contain roughly 97% of the Earth’s water supply. The oceans of Earth are unique in our Solar system. No other planet in our Solar System has liquid water. The oceans of Earth serve many functions, especially affecting the weather and temperature. They moderate the Earth's temperature by absorbing incoming solar radiation which is stored as heat energy. The always-moving ocean currents distribute this heat energy around the globe. This heats the land and air during winter and cools it during summer. The Earth's oceans are all connected to one another.  There were five recognized oceans: the Pacific, Atlantic, Antarctic, Indian, and Arctic. There are also many seas like the South China Sea, the Caribbean Sea, and the Mediterranean Sea.</description>
      <title>EARTH'S OCEANS</title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question> 
  <question>
    <id>61153aedda8f428a9c24888849d9eb95</id>
    <practiceSet>3db6c7215baa422783ab459e3d30f17c</practiceSet>
    <type>WRITE_ESSAY</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will have 20 minutes to plan, write and revise an essay about the topic below. Your response will be judged on how well you develop a position, organize your ideas, present supporting details and control the elements of standard written English. You should write 200-300 words.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:20:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>Television has two roles: to inform and to entertain. Explain which of these roles you see as more important. To what extent do you think that TV today performs each of these roles in an effective way? Support your point of view with details from your own experiences, observations or reading.</description>
      <title></title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
<question>
    <id>7aa137f487274da98706c6b4fe281ceb</id>
    <practiceSet>5f0ddb8a83f04b5f9684f293f1be47aa</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>Organ donation is considered one of the kindest and noblest act of mankind. The gift of life that one can give is donating an organ . When a person dies, there is no use of the organs for that person. So, why not take an opportunity to kindle a light in somebody’s life? The process of organ donation includes taking of healthy organs and tissues from one person for transplantation into another. The organs that can be donated are internal organs like heart, liver, kidney, lungs, intestines and pancreas. Apart from these, skin, cornea and bone marrow can also be donated. Some organs can be donated while the donor is alive. However, most organ and tissue donations occur after the donor has died. There is no restriction on the age and background of organ donors. Minors(below the age of 18) need permission from parent or guardian to become a donor whereas people above the age of 18 can sign a donor card and donate.</description>
      <title></title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>c3a40b6098f04c0ba19d999e08bbfa6c</id>
    <practiceSet>5f0ddb8a83f04b5f9684f293f1be47aa</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>Kinds Of Flesh Eating Plants {newline} There are flesh eating plants out of all strange plants in the world. These carnivorous plants can be found in areas where the soil has very little nutrients. These are called carnivorous as they trap insects and arthropods, produce digestive juices, dissolve the prey and derive most of their nutrients from this process. There are five basic trapping mechanisms found in these plants namely pitfall traps, fly paper traps, snap traps, bladder traps and lobster pot traps. Let’s see the differences between different genera and understand couple of plants using each mechanism.{newline} Sarracenia: Sarracenia is a carnivorous plant with a pitfall trap whose leaves have evolved into a funnel with a hood like structure growing over the opening to prevent rain water from diluting the digestive juices. Insects get attracted by color, smell and a nectar-like secretion on the lip of the pitcher. Slippery footings cause insects to fall inside the plant where they die and are digested by proteases and other enzymes.{newline} Genlisea: Genlisea, also known as corkscrew plant, and are small herbs with yellow flowers that make use of lobster pot traps. Lobster pot traps are traps that are easy to enter but impossible to exit. These plants have two distinct types of leaves – photosynthetic leaves above ground, and specialized underground leaves to attract, trap and digest small organisms. These underground leaves form hollow tubes under the ground that have a forward propelling corkscrew shape, and with the aid of constant water flow, small microbes can make their way into these tubes, but cannot find a way out again. When they reach the correct part of the tubes, they get digested and absorbed.</description>
      <title></title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>2b8d6bf7116d4cecabbe285827166ca1</id>
    <practiceSet>5f0ddb8a83f04b5f9684f293f1be47aa</practiceSet>
    <type>WRITE_ESSAY</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will have 20 minutes to plan, write and revise an essay about the topic below. Your response will be judged on how well you develop a position, organize your ideas, present supporting details and control the elements of standard written English. You should write 200-300 words.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:20:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>The mass media including T.V, radio and newspaper has become an integral part of our lives. It not only has influenced our society but also has shaped our opinion and character. Give your opinion on this ?</description>
      <title></title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question> 
<question>
    <id>4582747abfd14e24a4edf72b8a2887ca</id>
    <practiceSet>a7fec3f9448d4e6cb8a59784bbb2a1df</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>Kinds of Flesh Eating Plants{newline}There are flesh eating plants out of all strange plants in the world. These carnivorous plants can be found in areas where the soil has very little nutrients. These are called carnivorous as they trap insects and arthropods, produce digestive juices, dissolve the prey and derive most of their nutrients from this process. There are five basic trapping mechanisms found in these plants namely pitfall traps, fly paper traps, snap traps, bladder traps and lobster pot traps. Let’s see the differences between different genera and understand couple of plants using each mechanism.Sarracenia: Sarracenia is a carnivorous plant with a pitfall trap whose leaves have evolved into a funnel with a hood like structure growing over the opening to prevent rain water from diluting the digestive juices. Insects get attracted by color, smell and a nectar-like secretion on the lip of the pitcher. Slippery footings cause insects to fall inside the plant where they die and are digested by proteases and other enzymes.{newline} Genlisea: Genlisea, also known as corkscrew plant, and are small herbs with yellow flowers that make use of lobster pot traps. Lobster pot traps are traps that are easy to enter but impossible to exit. These plants have two distinct types of leaves – photosynthetic leaves above ground, and specialized underground leaves to attract, trap and digest small organisms. These underground leaves form hollow tubes under the ground that have a forward propelling corkscrew shape, and with the aid of constant water flow, small microbes can make their way into these tubes, but cannot find a way out again. When they reach the correct part of the tubes, they get digested and absorbed.</description>
      <title></title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>120905b22a2a48379f624e1bfa68963d</id>
    <practiceSet>a7fec3f9448d4e6cb8a59784bbb2a1df</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>Spirituality -Spirituality may refer to almost any kind of meaningful activity which leads to personal growth, or blissful experience. Traditionally, spirituality refers to connecting with the inner soul, but there is however, no single agreed upon definition of the same.{newline} The entire crusade of spiritualism first began to arise in the 5th century. During this phase however, it was more religious. By the 11th century, the meaning of this word began to change and it started to denote the mental aspect of life. Today spirituality often embraces the idea of an ultimate immaterial reality.{newline} There are presently about five kinds of spiritualism namely Mystical, Authoritarian, Intellectual, Service and Social spirituality.{newline} In the fast moving world today, the practice of spirituality often comes as a relief to many.  One of the central themes of this is that it is believed to be helpful for creating a positive energy. The two important techniques to create this positive energy are by practicing meditation and relaxation.{newline} Today individuals are not only using these methods, but are also steadily promoting this art with about 15 million people worldwide adhering to the same.</description>
      <title></title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
    <question>
    <id>fb3c23c57351407ea4ed996dd00d940d</id>
    <practiceSet>a7fec3f9448d4e6cb8a59784bbb2a1df</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will have 20 minutes to plan, write and revise an essay about the topic below. Your response will be judged on how well you develop a position, organize your ideas, present supporting details and control the elements of standard written English. You should write 200-300 words.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:20:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>Social Media websites have changed the way of mass communication and has some negative and positive effects on individual's lives as well as on the society. To what extent do you agree or disagree.</description>
      <title></title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>7d5e0dc7d0b445e3a13a272f934b38c6</id>
    <practiceSet>a7fec3f9448d4e6cb8a59784bbb2a1df</practiceSet>
    <type>WRITE_ESSAY</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will have 20 minutes to plan, write and revise an essay about the topic below. Your response will be judged on how well you develop a position, organize your ideas, present supporting details and control the elements of standard written English. You should write 200-300 words.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:20:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>The environment we live in is no more a safe place to live. It is in danger due to various problem. What are the underlying causes? Who is responsible to combat this? What measures should be taken according to you?</description>
      <title></title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>   
  </questions>
