<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<questions>
  <question>
    <id>fd6d3f9e15a14ed7bbd696aeaba2f5da</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1fd7c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_WRITE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a short lecture. Write a summary for fellow student who was not present at the lecture. You should write 50-70 words. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points presented in the lecture.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>9781447961871_1_13.tpm</media>
      <delay>0</delay>
      <answer>correct answer is this text here</answer>
      <maxWordCount>70</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
   <question>
    <id>5f4877a2331e42aea6c1ae7790da9cf9</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1fd7c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_WRITE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a short lecture. Write a summary for fellow student who was not present at the lecture. You should write 50-70 words. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points presented in the lecture.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>The-Sick-Lion.tpm</media>
      <delay>0</delay>
      <answer>correct answer is this text here</answer>
      <maxWordCount>70</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>  
   <question>
    <id>b8093c04689249dcbb72f59e05b1f65e</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1fd7c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_WRITE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a short lecture. Write a summary for fellow student who was not present at the lecture. You should write 50-70 words. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points presented in the lecture.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>12669885.tpm</media>
      <delay>0</delay>
      <answer>correct answer is this text here</answer>
      <maxWordCount>70</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>   
 <question>
    <id>3fe32019a7ad45afacb950e914aeb570</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1fd7c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_SELECT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting  all the correct responses. You will need to select more than one response.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>According to the speaker, which of the following statements are true?</title>
      <media>9781447961871_1_35.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>Consumers' don't understand their own purchase decisions well.</o0>
        <o1>Marketers engage experts to understand consumers' minds.</o1>
        <o2>95 percent of consumers use emotion in their purchase decisions.</o2>
        <o3>Many big companies research consumer purchase decisions.</o3>
        <o4>Marketers have a good instinct for consumers' thoughts.</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>0|3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>  
   <question>
    <id>2a392a741c2946aeb57361eca5271de1</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1fd7c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_SELECT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting  all the correct responses. You will need to select more than one response.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>Sir Francis Drake added wealth to the treasury and diminished Spain's _________.</title>
      <media>T6MCMA1-audio25.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>unlimited power</o0>
        <o1>unrestricted growth</o1>
        <o2>territory</o2>
        <o3>treaties</o3>
        <o4>Answer not available in article</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>0|1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
     <question>
    <id>26ad925d964f457caffd0b898dd37fcc</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1fd7c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_SELECT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting  all the correct responses. You will need to select more than one response.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>Going by the lecture, which of the following statements is true about enzymes?</title>
      <media>T15MCMA1audio22.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>They catabolise internally in the digestive system and metabolize externally.</o0>
        <o1>They are a result of Metabolic reactions which first originate from the digestive system.</o1>
        <o2>They are needed for cells to survive internally and digest food externally.</o2>
        <o3>They are produced within cells and set off reactions internally and externally.</o3>
        <o4>They are the natural catalyst. </o4>
      </options>
      <answer>3|4</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
 <question>
    <id>05a94df8a2ad45d790e993cce32f0d59</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1fd7c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_FILL_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Type the missing words in each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Philippe Croizon, a man who lost all four limbs in an {blank} accident, successfully completed his International Straits Swimming {blank} this week. In his final stretch to connect five continents, the Frenchman crossed the frigid waters of the Bering Strait linking Asia and the{blank}. The 44-year-old man used flippers to cross between Alaska’s Little Diomede Island to Russia’s Big Diomede Island, which he said was more challenging than {blank} the English Channel in 2010. Previously this year he crossed three other straits, linking Australia to Asia, Asia to Africa, and Europe to Asia. Croizon hopes to inspire disabled people worldwide, and will be working at the Paralympics as a radio and television {blank}.</description>
      <title>Limbless Swimmer Links Five Continents</title>
      <media>EnglishClub.com-news-limbless-swimmer - new.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <answer>electrocution|Challenge|||Americas|||crossing|||commentator</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
 <question>
    <id>042ff5e19b574c2c9e6d9311b7d73792</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1fd7c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_FILL_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Type the missing words in each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>It was only in 1849 that the police began to keep a count, and they recorded a total of almost 250,000 persons as {blank} evicted between 1849 and 1854 of the more than 100,000 Irish that sailed to Canada in 1847, an {blank} one out of five died from disease and malnutrition, including over 5,000 at Grosse Isle, Quebec, an island in the Saint Lawrence River used to quarantine ships near Quebec City. Overcrowded, poorly maintained and badly {blank} vessels, known as coffin ships, sailed from small, unregulated harbors in the West of Ireland in contravention of British {blank} requirements and mortality rates were high.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>T10B1-audio27.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <answer>officially|estimated|||provisioned|||safety</answer>
    </template>
  </question>  
   <question>
    <id>22ed2b7d999e4b9f89c3f4bcec6d1502</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1fd7c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_HIGHLIGHT_CORRECT_SUMMARY</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Click on paragraph that best relates to the recording.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>T3HCS2-audio30.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>If a certain person is predisposed with a natural talent for a certain thing, it means he/she is destined to succeed over everyone else. He/she does not require to put in hard work to succeed.</o0>
        <o1>You should follow your natural talents to be successful in life. If you don’t do this you will end up working hard without any success.</o1>
        <o2>Effort and Hard work are the determining factor when it comes to success. Even if a person has a natural talent, it does not mean that the person will attain greatness unless he/she puts in the effort.</o2>
        <o3>Naturally talented people are overrated. They do not tend to succeed in life. Stephen King a world renowned author also agrees to this statement.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
   <question>
    <id>66b0f41e823e483094a224ef0907d732</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1fd7c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_HIGHLIGHT_CORRECT_SUMMARY</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Click on paragraph that best relates to the recording.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>T8HCS1-audio26.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>There are various ways of hypnotising people. In the commonest, the patients are told that hypnosis will help them, is safe, and is not a sign of weakness of character. They are then asked to concentrate on a bright object, and the hypnotist suggests they are going to sleep. Hypnosis is sometimes used for public entertainment, but this is undesirable. People cannot be hypnotised into doing things they think are wrong.</o0>
        <o1>There are various ways of hypnotising people. In the commonest, the patients are told that hypnosis will help them, is safe, and is not a sign of weakness of character. They are then asked to concentrate on a bright object, and the hypnotist suggests they are going to sleep. The patients goes into a trance, and can be made to remember things they have forgotten, or to do various surprising things. Hypnosis is sometimes used for public entertainment, but this is undesirable. People cannot be hypnotised into doing things they think are wrong.</o1>
        <o2>There are various ways of hypnotising people. In the commonest, the patients are told that hypnosis will help them, is safe, and is not a sign of weakness of character. They are then asked to concentrate on a bright object, and the hypnotist suggests they are going to sleep. The patients goes into a trance, and can be made to remember things they have forgotten, or to do various surprising things. Hypnosis is sometimes used for public entertainment, but this is undesirable.</o2>
      </options>
      <answer>1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>  
  <question>
    <id>6dc430e6df26431e93f0e7a837212915</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1fd7c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_CHOICE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple -choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>The researchers supported by the National Institute of Child Health ___.</title>
      <media>T3MCSA1-audio31.tpm</media>
      <delay>5</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>took care of women who're suffering from alcohol</o0>
        <o1>have spent a lot of money on fertility</o1>
        <o2>have been victims of infertility</o2>
        <o3>said alcohol may affect women's fertility</o3>
		<o4>have also worked for Harvard University</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>bf2fb72004b54ff68ce5e7cad8be7c9d</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1fd7c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_CHOICE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple -choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>It's obvious that Aristotle ___.</title>
      <media>T8MCSA1audio28.tpm</media>
      <delay>5</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>thinks that it is the brain which contains the intelligence</o0>
        <o1>died in his sixties</o1>
        <o2>observed only birds and fish</o2>
        <o3>is both a great philosopher and a biologist</o3>
		<o4>described both the habits and the structure of animals better than anyone else</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>  
  <question>
    <id>55bd475bd3954f038a884ed89f3a5fab</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1fd7c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_SELECT_MISSING_WORD</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording on Early deep-sea research. At the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>9781447961871_1_44.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>robot submersibles</o0>
        <o1>whales</o1>
        <o2>the surface</o2>
       </options>
      <answer>2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>250417b3224d4c9086712873cf52b4cc</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1fd7c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_SELECT_MISSING_WORD</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording on Sea life at extreme depths. At the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>29781447961871_1_44.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>high temperatures</o0>
        <o1>extreme darkness</o1>
        <o2>disturbance by shipping</o2>
         </options>
      <answer>1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>504bd7da627849d38e0cede902309d6d</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1fd7c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_HIGHLIGHT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Below is a transcription of the recording. Some words in the transcription differ from what the speaker(s) said. Please click on words that are different.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Italian University To Become English, The Politecnico di Milano, a leading university in Italy, has declared that it is becoming an English-speaking school. The university’s top officials defended the decision, saying that switching to English for degree and adapt courses is the only way to compete as an international institution. The university’s rector said this change will make the university more attractive to overseas students from places like China and India. Despite some unwillingness, many current students and professors agree that this change will also make graduates more employable. The country’s higher education minister hopes other universities in Italy will do the same. It is fetching a trend for degree courses at major universities in China and South Korea to be taught in English.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>EnglishClubcom-news-italian-university-new.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <answer>declared|adapt|unwillingness|fetching</answer>
      <maxWordCount></maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>  
  <question>
    <id>95141aac98d5417ea2879d6695c8de94</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1fd7c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_HIGHLIGHT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Below is a transcription of the recording. Some words in the transcription differ from what the speaker(s) said. Please click on words that are different.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>So last time, we talked about the more convenient energy sources and the way they relate human activity to the environment. I included hydroelectricity  in that. It's renewable but it's been around for a while. It's a pretty big contributor already to that we're ... to how we're generating energy. So we've already discussed hydropower but tonight I'll go on and talk about these other renewables. And in each case I've put for electricity or fuel because, in principle, you can produce electricity from each of these sources but if you don't want to consume it right away, you could convert it to some kind of a fuel.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>9781447961871_1_49.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <answer>convenient|hydroelectricity|pretty|tonight|produce|consume</answer>
      <maxWordCount></maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>   
 <question>
    <id>618c876331fb46938e1c05de9ebb089c</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1fd7c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>12678964.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <answer>Don't forget to close the door when you leave.</answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
 <question>
    <id>d5726d83d3ed40ffbff87682e62d3f78</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1fd7c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>12678983.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <answer>Would you mind delivering this package for me?</answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
 <question>
    <id>5ae0783c99cb40bdbaf18c11f798ee82</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1fd7c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>312678995.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <answer>Let these dry before you try moving them anywhere.</answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
<question>
    <id>d2479df1ea934958bc521c76fe90e863</id>
    <practiceSet>89e5ed3d303847b48535195f410d564a</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_WRITE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a short lecture. Write a summary for fellow student who was not present at the lecture. You should write 50-70 words. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points presented in the lecture.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>1. -Huntsman-Fisherman.tpm</media>
      <delay>0</delay>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>70</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
   <question>
    <id>ea9dda1343634a6a9602974d9924bc3e</id>
    <practiceSet>89e5ed3d303847b48535195f410d564a</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_WRITE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a short lecture. Write a summary for fellow student who was not present at the lecture. You should write 50-70 words. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points presented in the lecture.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>2. T9 RL 1 - audio12.tpm</media>
      <delay>0</delay>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>70</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>    
 <question>
    <id>8f886e27d923486ebc1d1d6aabddd0f7</id>
    <practiceSet>89e5ed3d303847b48535195f410d564a</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_SELECT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting  all the correct responses. You will need to select more than one response.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>The main purpose of this passage is to</title>
      <media>1. T1 MCMA 1 - audio27.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>determine which food chain is the most efficient</o0>
        <o1>describe the food network among plants and animals</o1>
        <o2>explain the process of photosynthesis in green plants </o2>
        <o3>appeal to conservationists to protect endangered plant species</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>1|2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>  
   <question>
    <id>72fd2cc31985431a86e100db9318ab42</id>
    <practiceSet>89e5ed3d303847b48535195f410d564a</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_SELECT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting  all the correct responses. You will need to select more than one response.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>Which of the following statements best about the lecture?</title>
      <media>2. T14 MCMA 1 - audio25.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>Developing strength and the ways various methods which you can use to grow yourself.</o0>
        <o1>Developing your neuromuscular, physiological and energetic strengths and then motivating others.</o1>
        <o2>Getting yourself organised and understand what you are going to do with your life. </o2>
        <o3>Use the four pillars to become a confident human being, mainly by eating healthy and treating others with respect.</o3>
        <o4>Various types of strength.</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>1|4</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
 <question>
    <id>cd5cbaa6abde44999ed171c918f3373c</id>
    <practiceSet>89e5ed3d303847b48535195f410d564a</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_FILL_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Type the missing words in each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Arctic Ice Hits Record Low, Arctic sea ice fell to a record low this September, down 18% from the previous record set in 2007. Scientists believe the sea ice in the {blank} could be gone in the summer months as early as 2015. Previous reports had {blank} that the melting could occur by 2050. Experts warn that the higher {blank} in the Arctic will cause the release of greenhouse gases that are currently frozen in the permafrost from the last ice age. This will increase the rate of global warming, causing {blank} climate change. Environmentalist groups predict that the impact will be extreme in the northern {blank} . Sea ice plays an important role in cooling the Earth.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>2. EnglishClub.com-news-arctic-ice - new.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <answer>Arctic|suggested|||temperatures|||drastic|||hemisphere</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
 <question>
    <id>dd4a43cb733c4ef9a9cd10a10f61a2cd</id>
    <practiceSet>89e5ed3d303847b48535195f410d564a</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_FILL_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Type the missing words in each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Organic Foods Have Same Nutritional Value,A new study out of Stanford {blank} suggests that organic foods have no additional nutritional value than non-organic foods. The study suggests that other factors, such as the {blank} of the produce when it is picked, determine the nutritional quality. The study did find that organic food contained significantly less {blank} residue than non-organic food. Despite the massive research that went into the study, critics say that the research is flawed and based on short-term {blank} . Consumers have a variety of reasons for choosing organic foods, including concerns about animal welfare and the environment. Certified-organic food is produced with {blank} and animal-friendly production methods, and does not contain genetically modified ingredients.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>1. EnglishClub.com-news-organic-food - new.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <answer>University|ripeness|||pesticide|||evidence|||environmentally</answer>
    </template>
  </question>  
  <question>
    <id>6ee0c1862cc34efb8263b59d7cc260a7</id>
    <practiceSet>89e5ed3d303847b48535195f410d564a</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_HIGHLIGHT_CORRECT_SUMMARY</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Click on paragraph that best relates to the recording.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>1. T7 HCS 1 - audio29.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>Present-day education is mostly concerned with developing the intellect and training people to participate in a technological society. The result is a sick, unhappy, violent civilisation. This will best be achieved through a minimum of teaching and a maximum of play and self-expression. There should not be too much emphasis on teaching traditional school subjects; children are not very interested in them, and will in any case learn very quickly and easily anything they really need.</o0>
        <o1>Present-day education is mostly concerned with developing the intellect and training people to participate in a technological society. The result is a sick, unhappy, violent civilisation. The purpose of education should be to help people find happiness, pursue their interests, and develop emotionally. This will best be achieved through a minimum of teaching and a maximum of play and self-expression. There should not be too much emphasis on teaching traditional school subjects; children are not very interested in them, and will in any case learn very quickly and easily anything they really need.</o1>
        <o2>The result is a sick, unhappy, violent civilisation. The purpose of education should be to help people find happiness, pursue their interests, and develop emotionally. This will best be achieved through a minimum of teaching and a maximum of play and self-expression. There should not be too much emphasis on teaching traditional school subjects; children are not very interested in them, and will in any case learn very quickly and easily anything they really need.</o2>
      </options>
      <answer>1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
   <question>
    <id>0e5a015f960e41b297bcd5655cd2699b</id>
    <practiceSet>89e5ed3d303847b48535195f410d564a</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_HIGHLIGHT_CORRECT_SUMMARY</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Click on paragraph that best relates to the recording.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>2. T9 HCS 2 - audio28.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>Mutation causes cancer and it is the uninterrupted growth which is different from normal cell growth. Sometimes mutation in cells can be detected and autocorrected by human body. But it cheats and causes cancer.</o0>
        <o1>Mutation causes cancer and it is the uneven growth which is different from normal cell growth. Sometimes mutation in cells can be detected and autocorrected by human body.</o1>
        <o2>Mutation causes cancer and it is the uninterrupted growth which is different from normal cell growth. Sometimes mutation in cells can be detected and autocorrected by human body. But it cheats and causes cancer undergoing unwanted growth.</o2>
      </options>
      <answer>2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>  
  <question>
    <id>ee0964a6eceb4b3eafc447e0c6660e63</id>
    <practiceSet>89e5ed3d303847b48535195f410d564a</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_CHOICE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple -choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>It's stated in the passage that ________.</title>
      <media>1. T6 MCSA 1 - audio30.tpm</media>
      <delay>5</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>there is more than one way to take notes</o0>
        <o1>is among the pioneers of the Romantic movement</o1>
        <o2>is rebellious against the French Revaluation</o2>
        <o3>is the advocate of marriage</o3>
		<o4>Emile is one of his daughters who was brought up in an atmosphere of truth</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>1579902016fc4968a0118935fa88d438</id>
    <practiceSet>89e5ed3d303847b48535195f410d564a</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_CHOICE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple -choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>Although 3/4 of the electricity is generated from fossil fuels, ____.</title>
      <media>2. T10 MCSA 1 - audio31.tpm</media>
      <delay>5</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>we should consider the potential dangers of nuclear power</o0>
        <o1>everything has got an expense; and nuclear power's is its radioactivity</o1>
        <o2>it may contribute to global warming, the greenhouse effect</o2>
        <o3>half of the air pollution is caused by the plants using them</o3>
		<o4>coal also contains a surprising amount of radioactive material</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>  
  <question>
    <id>ce63c5c280854e52938a59233ed7b6bc</id>
    <practiceSet>89e5ed3d303847b48535195f410d564a</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_SELECT_MISSING_WORD</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording on tourism. At the end of recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>1. T7 SMW 1 - audio32.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>ideals</o0>
        <o1>conservation ideals</o1>
        <o2>conservation</o2>
          </options>
      <answer>1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>40616cefa31d4457b9de7e1d046ef536</id>
    <practiceSet>89e5ed3d303847b48535195f410d564a</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_SELECT_MISSING_WORD</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording on Nature of genius. At the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>2. T8 SMW 1 - audio29.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>always very scientific, basis</o0>
        <o1>always</o1>
        <o2>basis</o2>
        <o3>very scientific, basis</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>a47104a5ab59496db22a8e0fe409ec2f</id>
    <practiceSet>89e5ed3d303847b48535195f410d564a</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_HIGHLIGHT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Below is a transcription of the recording. Some words in the transcription differ from what the speaker(s) said. Please click on words that are different.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Manhunt for Canadian Killer Ends In Berlin, A Canadian man accused of killing and dismembering a school student in Montreal has been arrested in Berlin after a weeklong international manhunt. Investigators began looking for a man leaving by the name of “Luka Magnotta” after a human foot and hand were mailed to some Canadian political parties. The victim was a 33-year-old Chinese national who had been presence Concordia University. Canadian police found the victim’s torso in a suitcase outside Magnotta’s residence in Montreal. Additional body parts were mailed to two Vancouver schools. The two men were reportedly dating, and the killing was placed online. Magnotta was picked up by police in an Internet café in Berlin when an employee there recognized Magnotta after seeing the story in the news. Magnotta, a man gripped with promoting himself on the Internet, had previously posted information online about how to disappear.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>1. News-Canadian-Psycho - new.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <answer>school|leaving|presence|residence|placed|picked|gripped</answer>
      <maxWordCount></maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>  
  <question>
    <id>08cf5be7a6824dafb3987f2df0e36e7e</id>
    <practiceSet>89e5ed3d303847b48535195f410d564a</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_HIGHLIGHT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Below is a transcription of the recording. Some words in the transcription differ from what the speaker(s) said. Please click on words that are different.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>NYC Tower Surpasses Empire State Building, On Monday, April 30th, the new One World Trade Center tower became the tallest building in New York City when a feature was added to the 100th floor. Currently under construction, the replacement tower is now 1,271 feet, just a bit higher than the Empire State Building. This landmark in construction history took place the day before the one-year anniversary of Osama bin Laden’s death. When the building is complete in 2014, the One World Trade Center tower will be America’s tallest skyscraper. This record is currently held by Chicago’s Willis Tower, which situates at 1,450 feet. The new One World Trade Center, which stands close to the memorial twin pools, will be a little bit taller than the original tower that was destroyed in a terrorist radical attack on September 11th, 2001. Dubai’s Bhurj Khalifa will remain the tallest building in the world.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>2. News-One-World-Tower - new.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <answer>NYC|feature|landmark|situates|radical</answer>
      <maxWordCount></maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>   
<question>
    <id>25512b9c37d242dbb256f47dbed6c864</id>
    <practiceSet>89e5ed3d303847b48535195f410d564a</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>1. T9 D1 - audio34.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <answer>They advertised that they had house for sale.</answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>d1f703e8442e47bc8a298edab03b7de4</id>
    <practiceSet>89e5ed3d303847b48535195f410d564a</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>2. T12 D1 - audio35.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <answer>I couldn't get out of my garage because there was car in the way.</answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
 <question>
    <id>c5b335db7bde4d8ab53987b1871af67c</id>
    <practiceSet>89e5ed3d303847b48535195f410d564a</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>3. T13 D1 - audio35.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <answer>My grandfather gave me a birthday present.</answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
 <question>
    <id>c072234da8314b978c636bceff9f047f</id>
    <practiceSet>89e5ed3d303847b48535195f410d564a</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>4. T10 D1 - audio36.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <answer>Your collar has a stain on it.</answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
<question>
    <id>585c3c32f06c44f3b96ec9b7d576d0f1</id>
    <practiceSet>a540452272644faab9254ea73290cb9d</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_WRITE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a short lecture. Write a summary for fellow student who was not present at the lecture. You should write 50-70 words. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points presented in the lecture.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>1. T14 S1 - audio23.tpm</media>
      <delay>0</delay>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>70</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
   <question>
    <id>4d4d4380ccdc4fa1969fdb354a7b877d</id>
    <practiceSet>a540452272644faab9254ea73290cb9d</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_WRITE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a short lecture. Write a summary for fellow student who was not present at the lecture. You should write 50-70 words. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points presented in the lecture.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>2. T3 S1 - audio24.tpm</media>
      <delay>0</delay>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>70</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>    
 <question>
    <id>6074cd03f78346ee910ce5e23e6d128e</id>
    <practiceSet>a540452272644faab9254ea73290cb9d</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_SELECT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting  all the correct responses. You will need to select more than one response.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>What were some of the key implications about the people in Sydney you can draw from this talk?</title>
      <media>T12MCMA1audio25.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>They are generally relaxed and would encourage stressful people to be calm.</o0>
        <o1>They like to drive around for leisure.</o1>
        <o2>They are courteous and expect you to be the same.</o2>
        <o3>They are optimistic with a can do attitude.</o3>
        <o4>They will go out of their way to help you.</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>0|2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>  
   <question>
    <id>ef36011a5e714c57a8d3ac351709c0e8</id>
    <practiceSet>a540452272644faab9254ea73290cb9d</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_SELECT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting  all the correct responses. You will need to select more than one response.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>Some of the key concepts related to the talk are </title>
      <media>T13MCMA1audio25.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>A mistake people often make is to try to get the whole thing done right away</o0>
        <o1>Breaking things down in small pieces makes it more complex.</o1>
        <o2>People in general don’t have the patience while executing.</o2>
        <o3>If you have an idea you should make the final finished product first.</o3>
        <o4>When you have an idea it is important to get something up as soon as possible and then get feedback.</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>0|4</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
 <question>
    <id>5c74c93bb3554d7a8944d45dac559063</id>
    <practiceSet>a540452272644faab9254ea73290cb9d</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_FILL_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Type the missing words in each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Any sound scientific theory, whether of time or of any other {blank}, should in my opinion be based on the most workable philosophy of science: the positivist {blank} put forward by Karl Popper and others. According to this way of thinking, a scientific theory is a mathematical model that describes and {blank} the observations we make. A good theory will describe a large range of phenomena on the basis of a few simple postulates and will make definite predictions that can be {blank}. If one takes the positivist position, as I do, one cannot say what time actually is. All one can do is describe what has been found to be a very good {blank} model for time and say what {blank} it makes.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>T13 B1audio26.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <answer>concept|approach|||codifies|||tested|||mathematical|||predictions</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
 <question>
    <id>4876f724efd04ed296bc9e5c61c452d9</id>
    <practiceSet>a540452272644faab9254ea73290cb9d</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_FILL_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Type the missing words in each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Blue laws—known also as Sunday laws—are laws {blank} to restrict or ban some or all Sunday activities for religious reasons, particularly to promote the {blank} of a day of {blank} or rest. Blue laws may also restrict shopping or ban sale of certain Qs on specific days, most often on Sundays in the western world. Some Islamic nations may ban on Fridays. Blue laws are {blank} in parts of the United States and Canada as well as some European countries, particularly in Austria, Germany, Switzerland, and Norway {blank} most stores closed on Sundays.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>T14B2audio27.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <answer>designed|observance|||worship|||enforced|||keeping</answer>
    </template>
  </question>  
 <question>
    <id>b060b56ad7404634ae877899371930ab</id>
    <practiceSet>a540452272644faab9254ea73290cb9d</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_FILL_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Type the missing words in each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>In some contexts, theology has been held to belong in institutions of higher {blank} primarily as a form of professional training for Christian {blank}. This was the basis on which Friedrich Schleiermacher, a liberal {blank}, argued for the inclusion of theology in the new University of Berlin in 1810.For instance, in Germany, theological faculties at state universities are typically tied to {blank} denominations, Protestant or Roman Catholic, and those faculties will offer denominationally bound degrees, and have denominationally bound public posts amongst their faculty; as well as contributing ‘to the development and growth of Christian knowledge’ {blank} ‘provide the academic training for the future clergy and teachers of religious instruction at German {blank}.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>T11B2audio28.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <answer>education|ministry|||theologian|||particular|||they|||schools</answer>
    </template>
  </question> 
   <question>
    <id>98234c0128324948913fe6822a1ec04a</id>
    <practiceSet>a540452272644faab9254ea73290cb9d</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_HIGHLIGHT_CORRECT_SUMMARY</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Click on paragraph that best relates to the recording.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>1. T4 HCS 2 - audio30.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>The speaker is voicing her fears in the hope it will be heard. She is scared of breathing, fishing in the rivers, starving children and going out in the sun.</o0>
        <o1>The speaker is demonstrating how more importance is given to the elections and stock market. No one cares about the starving children and how she is no longer able to go fishing with her dad in Vancouver.</o1>
        <o2>The speaker has heard about plants and animals going extinct. The fish have got cancers due to the ozone layer and chemicals and these factors are causing children around the world to starve.</o2>
        <o3>The speaker is fighting for her future and is representing starving children, dying animals and all</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
   <question>
    <id>228e73d43029406a9e49942eda769944</id>
    <practiceSet>a540452272644faab9254ea73290cb9d</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_HIGHLIGHT_CORRECT_SUMMARY</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Click on paragraph that best relates to the recording.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>2. T10 HCS 2 - audio30.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>Symmetry is everywhere in nature. And we usually associate it with beauty: a imperfectly shaped leaf or a butterfly with intricate patterns mirrored on each wing. But it turns out that asymmetry is pretty not important, too — and more common than you might think.</o0>
        <o1>Symmetry is everywhere in nature. And we usually associate it with beauty: a perfectly shaped leaf or a butterfly with intricate patterns mirrored on each wing. </o1>
        <o2>Symmetry is everywhere in nature. And we usually associate it with beauty: a perfectly shaped leaf or a butterfly with intricate patterns mirrored on each wing. But it turns out that asymmetry is pretty important, too — and more common than you might think.</o2>
       </options>
      <answer>2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>51586eef8ce14c96b77c28ca69e7e170</id>
    <practiceSet>a540452272644faab9254ea73290cb9d</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_CHOICE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple -choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>According to the passage, Rousseau___.</title>
      <media>T9MCSA1audio29.tpm</media>
      <delay>5</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>is the unique person who is a member of the Romantic movement</o0>
        <o1>is among the pioneers of the Romantic movement</o1>
        <o2>is rebellious against the French Revaluation</o2>
        <o3>is the advocate of marriage</o3>
		<o4>Emile is one of his daughters who was brought up in an atmosphere of truth</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>eccb9ced6cca42f1bb4cf2767ad6d592</id>
    <practiceSet>a540452272644faab9254ea73290cb9d</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_CHOICE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple -choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>We can infer from the passage that___.</title>
      <media>T12MCSA1audio30.tpm</media>
      <delay>5</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>it's not definite when and where Homer was born</o0>
        <o1>Homer only deals with poetry</o1>
        <o2>recent research shows the impossibility of finding Homer's birth date</o2>
        <o3>some suggest that he was born in 800 BC</o3>
		<o4>Homer's birth place is known but his date of birth is still unknown</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>cf3066dab71943e3874901a7986069dc</id>
    <practiceSet>a540452272644faab9254ea73290cb9d</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_SELECT_MISSING_WORD</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording on Soccer. At the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>T11SMW2audio33.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>of the competition.</o0>
        <o1>competition</o1>
        <o2>of the trend</o2>
        <o3>severe competition</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
   <question>
    <id>3b04622bb3d24f968a3bb9db8a46df80</id>
    <practiceSet>a540452272644faab9254ea73290cb9d</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_SELECT_MISSING_WORD</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording on Minority languages. At the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>T10SMW1audio32.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>very limited success</o0>
        <o1>limited</o1>
        <o2>success</o2>
        <o3>vary</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>   
   <question>
    <id>8c23d6194bbf4f13a6bc9e1440099385</id>
    <practiceSet>a540452272644faab9254ea73290cb9d</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_HIGHLIGHT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Below is a transcription of the recording. Some words in the transcription differ from what the speaker(s) said. Please click on words that are different.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>The battles of Marathon and Tours are examples of how war has often determined the development of Western civilization. The basis of Western civilization was probably decided at the Battle of Marathon about 2,500 years ago. In the battle, a small number of Greek soldiers led by a famous Greek general defeated 100,000 invading Persians under the Persian king. Because the Greeks won, Greek ideas about many subjects matter and became the foundation of Western society. Whereas Marathon laid the basis of Western civilization, its start remained the same as a result of the Battle of Tours in A.D. 732. Before this battle, Muslim armies had taken control of a large number of countries, but they were stopped by a group of soldiers led by Charles Martel in France. If the Muslims had won at Tours, Islam might have become the major religion of West society.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>T10HIW1audio34.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <answer>the|matter|start|west</answer>
      <maxWordCount></maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>  
  <question>
    <id>6d2ed38b833a459191413c44a7735431</id>
    <practiceSet>a540452272644faab9254ea73290cb9d</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_HIGHLIGHT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Below is a transcription of the recording. Some words in the transcription differ from what the speaker(s) said. Please click on words that are different.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Once, she want a beautiful dress to wear to a sweetheart dance. She asked her sister for some money to buy the dress. She was disappointed because her sister didn’t have money to give her. She sat in silence for a little while and that started yelling out loud. She said here friends go anything they want but she didn’t. Then she felt sorry for herself and asked why she was born into a poor family. Not having money has caused this girl to think negative about herself and her family. It has caused a lot of stress in her life.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>2. T10 HIW 2 - audio35.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <answer>want|that|here|go|negative</answer>
      <maxWordCount></maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>   
 <question>
    <id>87123520d9a64055b90aca11c11be093</id>
    <practiceSet>a540452272644faab9254ea73290cb9d</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>T11D2audio37.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <answer>What would you do if you saw a man from another planet?</answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
 <question>
    <id>604bb0c5bff246ecb7049a6a0e08342f</id>
    <practiceSet>a540452272644faab9254ea73290cb9d</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>T15D1audio32.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <answer>I know you've been waiting a long time, but could you wait just a little bit longer.</answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
 <question>
    <id>2c33c0cce2174f2cb8c0e78c40fdfdb8</id>
    <practiceSet>a540452272644faab9254ea73290cb9d</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>T5D2audio35.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <answer>They failed to take into account the special needs of old people.</answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  
  <!--New tests 25022017-->
  <question>
    <id>4a94a1e6b65c4448a0908c1acb4480c0</id>
    <practiceSet>39d265f15f41481891312961d73f01bf</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_WRITE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a short lecture. Write a summary for fellow student who was not present at the lecture. You should write 50-70 words. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points presented in the lecture.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Summarize spoken Text - Q1.tpm</media>
      <delay>0</delay>
      <answer>correct answer is this text here</answer>
      <maxWordCount>70</maxWordCount>
      <transcript>Two years ago, some people dared friends to pour a bucket filled with ice water over their heads. If the friends refused, they were required to donate money to help finance research into a brain disease. Most of them took the cold water and donated money, too. Many people recorded themselves getting covered with freezing water. They posted the videos on social media websites, such as YouTube. Then they dared others to pass the challenge. As the campaign grew in popularity, sports stars, politicians and media celebrities got involved. Lots of other people did, too. Eventually, the campaign raised over $100 million for an organization called the ALS Association. ALS is short for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Doctors first recognized the brain disease in the 1800s. ALS became known across the United States in 1939 when baseball star Lou Gehrig retired from the New York Yankees because of the condition. ALS affects nerve cells in the brain and the spinal cord. Eventually, patients cannot control their muscles. They become paralyzed. Most patients will die within five years after they develop the disease. Earlier this week, the ALS Association announced that money raised by the Ice Bucket Challenge financed a discovery. Researchers working on a project called MinE announced they identified a gene that is partly responsible for the disease. The gene is called NEK1. The study involved researchers from 11 countries. They looked at the NEK1 gene and found that it was present in ALS patients whose parents also suffered from the disease.</transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>d7f8eabf520542818313c789e4f794b9</id>
    <practiceSet>39d265f15f41481891312961d73f01bf</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_WRITE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a short lecture. Write a summary for fellow student who was not present at the lecture. You should write 50-70 words. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points presented in the lecture.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Summarize spoken Text - Q2.tpm</media>
      <delay>0</delay>
      <answer>correct answer is this text here</answer>
      <maxWordCount>70</maxWordCount>
      <transcript>Scientists say a huge percentage of bird species are in danger because their habitats, or homelands, are disappearing. Traditional migration paths take birds through countries that are not protecting locations to stop, rest and feed. The scientists studied the migration, or flight, paths, of almost 1,500 species. They decided that 91 percent of them passed through dangerous areas. The major danger for migratory birds is development. Building and paving has covered over nature where birds stop and feed as they move from one part of the world to another. For example, a bird called the bar-tailed godwit migrates from its breeding grounds in the Arctic. It flies all the way to the southern hemisphere in Australia and New Zealand. Along the way, the small birds stop at Yellow Sea mudflats in China, North Korea and South Korea. One of the scientists who worked on the study says “many of these critical sites have been lost to land reclamation owing to urban, industrial and agricultural expansion.” The problem, according to investigators, is that many of these small birds die along their migration because they don’t have a safe place to eat and rest. There is no place to restore their energy for the next leg of their journey.</transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>38e3edaf87c542cfba5630df14f46c4c</id>
    <practiceSet>39d265f15f41481891312961d73f01bf</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_WRITE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a short lecture. Write a summary for fellow student who was not present at the lecture. You should write 50-70 words. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points presented in the lecture.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Summarize Spoken Text - Q3.tpm</media>
      <delay>0</delay>
      <answer>correct answer is this text here</answer>
      <maxWordCount>70</maxWordCount>
      <transcript>Bob Dylan (born Robert Allen Zimmerman, May 24, 1941, in Duluth, Minnesota) is an American singer-songwriter, author, poet, and painter, who has been a major figure in popular music for five decades. Much of Dylan's most celebrated work dates from the 1960s, when he became an informal chronicler and a reluctant figurehead of American unrest. A number of his songs, such as "Blowin' in the Wind" and "The Times They Are a-Changing'", became anthems of the civil rights movements. His most recent studio album, Modern Times, released on August 29, 2006, entered the U.S. album chart at number one, and that same year was named Album of the Year by Rolling Stone magazine. Dylan's early lyrics incorporated political, social, philosophical, and literary influences, defying existing pop music conventions and appealing widely to the counterculture. While expanding and personalizing musical styles, he has explored many traditions of American song, from folk, blues and country to gospel, rock and roll and rockabilly to English, Scottish and Irish folk music, and even jazz and swing. Dylan performs with the guitar, piano and harmonica. Backed by a changing line-up of musicians, he has toured steadily since the late 1980s on what has been dubbed the "Never Ending Tour". Although his accomplishments as performer and recording artist have been central to his career, his songwriting is generally regarded as his greatest contribution.</transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>8d8512edf8c34e54b44986be4b73c029</id>
    <practiceSet>39d265f15f41481891312961d73f01bf</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_SELECT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting  all the correct responses. You will need to select more than one response.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>According to the speaker, which of the following statements are not true?</title>
      <media>Multiple choice, choose multiple answers - Q4.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>The study shows that most of the people do not give up the resolution.</o0>
        <o1>The people make the same resolution every year.</o1>
        <o2>45 percent of the people are stick to their resolution.</o2>
        <o3>In the first week the majority of the people are able to keep their annual promises.</o3>
        <o4>The person doesn’t require a strong will power to keep continuing with the set resolution of the year.</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>0|4</answer>
      <transcript>The start of every New Year is when we all make plans to change our life for the better over the forthcoming twelve months. Psychiatry professor Jayashri Kulkarni says: "January 1 is a 'magical' date and a vow made on this day is much more powerful than one made on August 26, for example." So, we all make a list of things to quit, start or change. Unfortunately, most of these promises are, more often than not, broken by January 31st. They are usually the identical resolutions that were not fulfilled from the previous year, and the years prior to that. The website usa.gov says people, "tend to make the same resolutions year after year, even though they have a hard time sticking to them". Research shows 45 per cent of us make a New Year’s resolution. The most common vows include losing weight, volunteering to help others, quitting smoking, saving money, and getting fit. Others include eating healthier food, drinking less alcohol, and going on a trip. However, research also shows that most of us are not so good at sticking to these. A study from the University of Scranton reveals that 71 per cent of us stick to our annual promises for the first two weeks; six months later, less than 50 percent are still on track to keep their resolutions. Most people who give up on their resolutions do so because of a lack of willpower and the use of the 'escape clause' that they will 'try again next year'.</transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>b65caa6d279c462ba996c25ec12d66b8</id>
    <practiceSet>39d265f15f41481891312961d73f01bf</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_SELECT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting  all the correct responses. You will need to select more than one response.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>What effect does unemployment has on youngsters?</title>
      <media>Multiple choice, choose multiple answers - Q5.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>They enjoy watching TV at home.</o0>
        <o1>They become isolated as they are stressed.</o1>
        <o2>They lose their confidence.</o2>
        <o3>They like to spend their free time with their friends.</o3>
        <o4>They lead a normal life by interacting with the people. </o4>
      </options>
      <answer>1|2</answer>
      <transcript>A new survey from Britain shows that a third of young, unemployed people regularly "fall apart" emotionally. They are so stressed or unhappy that they cannot control their emotions, so they have problems living a "normal" life. The survey is from a youth charity called the Prince's Trust. Its researchers asked questions to 2,200 people who did not have a job. Almost half of them said they often felt anxious about everyday situations, and that they tried not to meet new people. One in eight of those surveyed said they were too stressed to leave the house. The charity said: "Thousands of young people feel like prisoners in their own homes. Without the right support, these young people become socially isolated." Many of these young people struggle with day-to-day life, which means it becomes more and more difficult to find a job. Britain's Employment Minister Esther McVey said: "Our young people are some of the best and most talented in the world." She said it was important to try and match these people with the right jobs. Researcher David Fass added: "Young people are our future and it is important that we invest in them and provide them with the tools they need to reach their full potential." Jack, 25, explained how hard it was for him to be unemployed. He said: "I would wake up and wouldn't want to leave the house. I stopped speaking to my friends and I had absolutely no confidence speaking to people."</transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>d76342fa42414486ac2dbb3aa7656c41</id>
    <practiceSet>39d265f15f41481891312961d73f01bf</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_SELECT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting  all the correct responses. You will need to select more than one response.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>Why were Final year students angry after they took the exam?</title>
      <media>Multiple choice, choose multiple answers - Q6.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>They were not able to answer the exam questions as they were not prepared.</o0>
        <o1>The exam questions were out of  the course.</o1>
        <o2>The level of the questions was not the same taught in the class.</o2>
        <o3>The environment in the examination hall was very disturbing.</o3>
        <o4>The students were not prepared with difficult math as they were not taught.</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>1|2|4</answer>
      <transcript>Final-year students at a university in England are angry after they took an economics exam. Students from the University of Sheffield have signed a petition to say the exam questions were 'impossible' to answer. Nearly all of the 100 students who took the exam complained and signed the online petition. They want the university to look into this. The students say the exam contained questions on topics that were not in their course. They also say the questions included a lot of difficult maths that they had not been taught. One student said a lecturer told them they would only need 'simple' maths. They are now worried that they will get low test scores, and that this will affect what kind of degree they get. The head of the economics department, professor Andy Dickerson, told the BBC that the exam was fair. He said not all the questions needed maths. He said the level of maths in the exams was the same as the level taught to students on the course. Professor Dickerson also said all the exam questions were on topics the students had studied. He said: "All questions were based on topics taught in the course and for which further reading was provided." He added that one question in the exam used a term that students may not have seen before. He said this was no problem because the question explained the meaning of the term. The university said it would look carefully at the results.</transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>c4dff988e8d542d6bf2eb5641cbdf487</id>
    <practiceSet>39d265f15f41481891312961d73f01bf</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_FILL_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Type the missing words in each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>The people of Scotland have decided to continue their 300-year {blank} with England. So the UK survives.  Pro-independence {blank} say they're disappointed, but insist the high  {blank} shows there's an  {blank} for change. Few would disagree, and accept the result doesn't mean Britain goes back to business  {blank}. In the hours and days ahead, the Prime Minister David Cameron and the other party leaders will now have to  {blank} on their promise in the last days of the campaign to give Scotland more powers. And no-one believes that can be done without a wider {blank} of how the rest of the UK is governed.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Fill in the blanks - Q7.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <answer>union |campaigners |||turnout |||appetite |||as usual|||deliver |||shake-up</answer>
    </template>
    <transcript> The people of Scotland have decided to continue their 300-year union with England. So the UK survives. Pro-independence campaigners say they're disappointed, but insist the high turnout shows there's an appetite for change. Few would disagree, and accept the result doesn't mean Britain goes back to business as usual. In the hours and days ahead, the Prime Minister David Cameron and the other party leaders will now have to deliver on their promise in the last days of the campaign to give Scotland more powers. And no-one believes that can be done without a wider shake-up of how the rest of the UK is governed.</transcript>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>4790d4379b10469ca81af1b8588c1857</id>
    <practiceSet>39d265f15f41481891312961d73f01bf</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_FILL_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Type the missing words in each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>According to ecologists, having a personality means showing a {blank} pattern of behavior over time. Researchers from the University of {blank} studied colonies of rock ants across the western US, both by {blank} them in the wild and by taking whole {blank} back to the lab. They found that certain risky behaviors, like {blank} widely for food and responding {blank} to a threat, went together, and colonies further north tended to take more of these risks. The study suggests those more {blank} personalities could be an adaptation to the limited window of activity left by the long, {blank} northern winter.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Fill in the blanks - Q8.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <answer>consistent |Arizona |||following |||colonies |||foraging |||aggressively |||adventurous |||snowy </answer>
      <transcript>According to ecologists, having a personality means showing a consistent pattern of behaviour over time. Researchers from the University of Arizona studied colonies of rock ants across the western US, both by following them in the wild and by taking whole colonies back to the lab. They found that certain risky behaviours, like foraging widely for food and responding aggressively to a threat, went together, and colonies further north tended to take more of these risks. The study suggests those more adventurous personalities could be an adaptation to the limited window of activity left by the long, snowy northern winter.</transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>67c47f5c1f1547abbf4ec77f7dd6a932</id>
    <practiceSet>39d265f15f41481891312961d73f01bf</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_HIGHLIGHT_CORRECT_SUMMARY</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Click on paragraph that best relates to the recording.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Highlight Correct Summary - Q9.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>Canada is the world’s second largest country occupying most of the northern North America which has been inhabited by aboriginal people, formed as a federal, semi-autonomous polity, it is bilingual and multicultural country, technologically advance and maintains diversified economy which is reliant upon natural resources and trade.</o0>
        <o1>Canada occupies most of the northern North America, the lands have been inhabited for millennia by aboriginal peoples, it was formed as a federal, semi autonomous polity, having a long and simple relationship with United States.</o1>
        <o2>Canada is a bilingual and multicultural country formed as a federal, semi autonomous polity, which is not technologically that advance. It maintains diversified economy that is dependent on natural resources and has a trade with United States; it doesn’t maintain any long relationship with United States because of complexity.</o2>
        <o3>Canada is a bilingual and multicultural country which has been inhabited by aboriginal people million years ago, it is legally dependent on British parliament,  A federation now comprising ten provinces and three territories, Canada is a parliamentary democracy and a constitutional monarchy with Queen Elizabeth II as its head of state.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>0</answer>
      <transcript>Canada is a country occupying most of northern North America, extending from the Atlantic Ocean in the east to the Pacific Ocean in the west and northward into the Arctic Ocean. It is the world's second largest country by total area, and shares land borders with the United States to the south and northwest. The lands have been inhabited for millennia by aboriginal peoples. Beginning in the late 15th century, British and French expeditions explored and later settled the Atlantic coast. France ceded nearly all of its colonies in North America in 1763 after the Seven Years War. In 1867, with the union of three British North American colonies through Confederation, Canada was formed as a federal, semi-autonomous polity. This began an accretion of additional provinces and territories and a process of increasing autonomy from the United Kingdom, highlighted by the Statute of Westminster in 1931 and culminating in the Canada Act in 1982 which severed the vestiges of legal dependence on the British parliament. A federation now comprising ten provinces and three territories, Canada is a parliamentary democracy and a constitutional monarchy with Queen Elizabeth II as its head of state. It is a bilingual and multicultural country, with both English and French as official languages at the federal level. Technologically advanced and industrialized, Canada maintains a diversified economy that is heavily reliant upon its abundant natural resources and upon trade—particularly with the United States, with which Canada has had a long and complex relationship.</transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>bbe31116cc89452a9e7fd22def8460cb</id>
    <practiceSet>39d265f15f41481891312961d73f01bf</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_HIGHLIGHT_CORRECT_SUMMARY</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Click on paragraph that best relates to the recording.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Highlight Correct Summary - Q10.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>Recycling is not accessible to the people so they dump most of their electronic products which leach toxins into environment. Even the companies like Best Buy and Staple charge more to recycle the products which are not within people’s approach. This has created lack of accessibility and increase in E-waste.</o0>
        <o1>Companies like Staple and Best Buy are the pioneers in recycling program and have announced publicly that they only allow responsible recyclers who are certified to touch those electronics, and that’s very important point.</o1>
        <o2>E-waste in the dump can leach toxins into the environment, companies like Staples and Best Buy subsidize electronics recycling and take e-waste for free. According to Shegerin, it’s a great approach as that has made people aware and this has created a new recycling paradigm making it accessible to the public and allowing certified and responsible recyclers to touch those electronics.</o2>
        <o3>E-waste in the dump can leach toxins into the environment, companies like Staples and Best Buy subsidize electronics recycling and take e-waste for huge charges. According to Shegerin, it’s a negative approach as that has made people pay more  and this has created a new recycling paradigm making it accessible to the public and allowing certified and responsible recyclers to touch those electronics</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>2</answer>
      <transcript>CURWOOD: Many of us have clunky old TVs, or obsolete computer clutter. And despite good intentions, chances are when we finally get rid of it, we won’t recycle it, according a survey by Best Buy. And e-waste in the dump can leach toxins into the environment. So some companies including Staples and Best Buy subsidize electronics recycling and take e-waste for free. To find out more, we called up John Shegerian, CEO and Co-Founder of Electronic Recyclers International. He spoke with Living on Earth’s Helen Palmer. PALMER: Tell me, first of all, there’s this recent survey from Best Buy which noted that only a third of people, just over a third, actually manage to recycle any of their electronics, though about two-thirds really want to. What gets in the way of actually recycling this old electronic junk? SHEGERIAN: Well, what gets in the way of most people recycling is apathy, or lack of accessibility or knowledge. But once people know how to recycle, where to recycle, most people want to do the right thing. And recycling rates therefore are rising. Best Buy has seen their volumes go up year after year with their great recycling program, which they pioneered in about 2007. And so, to me, it's very encouraging that retailers like them have created a new recycling paradigm making it accessible for the public at large and they've led on that and others have followed. PALMER: Yes, I believe Staples as well takes recycling...I don't know who else does. SHEGERIAN: Well, you're right. Staples and Best Buy are the platinum standard because not only do they take old electronics back, but they also have announced publicly that they only allow responsible recyclers who are certified to touch those electronics, and that's a very, very important point. </transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>98e5c037ed844e96bb51dcd7c03b82a3</id>
    <practiceSet>39d265f15f41481891312961d73f01bf</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_CHOICE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple -choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>Which of the following statement is true?</title>
      <media>Listening - Multiple choice, choose single answer - Q11.tpm</media>
      <delay>5</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>eyelashes increase evaporation of the eye by 70 percent.</o0>
        <o1>eyelashes help protect the eyes from drying out.</o1>
        <o2>eyelashes fail in reducing the deposits of small airborne particles.</o2>
        <o3>eyelashes are mystery as to what their function is.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>1</answer>
      <transcript>Scientists have come up with answers to the age-old question of why eyelashes are the length they are. Researchers at the Georgia Institute of Technology conducted a variety of tests on the lashes of 22 different mammals. One was to create a special wind tunnel and an artificial eye to provide mathematical models of how the wind blew over lashes. The conclusion of head researcher David Hu is that the function of eyelashes is to help protect the eyes from drying out and that the optimal eyelash length for this to happen is one-third as long as the eye is wide. Professor Hu found that across a wide variety of mammals, the ratio of eyelash length and eye width was consistently one-third. Dr Hu started his investigation after the birth of his newborn daughter. He wondered why his baby kept on batting her eyelids. He told the International Business Times that: "Eyelashes that rim the eyes in mammals have been a mystery for a long time as to what their function was. There were a lot of hypotheses, from dust catchers to triggering the blink reflex….What we did was the first aerodynamic study of eyelashes. We showed using three independent means that eyelashes reduce evaporation of the eye by 70 per cent, and they reduce [the deposits] of small airborne particles." A colleague said Hu had a talent for, "looking at what everybody has looked at, and seeing what nobody has seen."</transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>cd04cc182abc4389b19a6235c6b1dbc0</id>
    <practiceSet>39d265f15f41481891312961d73f01bf</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_CHOICE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple -choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>The speaker’s major concern is:</title>
      <media>Listening - Multiple choice, choose single answer - Q12.tpm</media>
      <delay>5</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>overcooked meat rather than from where it comes</o0>
        <o1>huge amount of antibiotics consumed by people.</o1>
        <o2>consumption of antibiotics in farm animals creating big risk to everyone.</o2>
        <o3>how antibiotics in food are making superbugs weaker.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>2</answer>
      <transcript>A new report warns that people could be in danger from superbugs if they eat rare and undercooked meat. The report is called the Review on Antimicrobial Resistance. Researchers looked into how antibiotics in food are making bugs stronger. The report said the use of antibiotics in agriculture is making bugs stronger and more resistant to our medicines. The researchers said the huge amount of antibiotics in farming could be dangerous to people's health around the world. They suggested that farmers reduce the amount of antibiotics they give to their animals. The leader of the research, Jim O'Neill, said this was important if we wanted to make sure that our life-saving medicines still work effectively. The researchers are calling for strict targets to reduce the number of antibiotics given to farm animals. Mr O'Neill said this was necessary because of the huge amount of antibiotics farmers give their animals. He said: "I find it [unbelievable] that in many countries, most of the consumption of antibiotics is in animals, rather than humans. This creates a big risk for everyone." He added that the public could get ill from superbugs if they ate meat that was rare or undercooked. He said: "My advice to consumers is that they have to make sure they cook meat properly. If you are going to choose to cook it as rare as possible you have to be aware of where it's coming from."</transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>68676d41904548cb952324e8cb48fee2</id>
    <practiceSet>39d265f15f41481891312961d73f01bf</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_SELECT_MISSING_WORD</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording on Diseases. At the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>You will hear a recording on Diseases. At the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Select missing word - Q13.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>sweating</o0>
        <o1>malnutrition</o1>
        <o2>sneezing</o2>
        <o3>allergy</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>0</answer>
      <transcript>Many diseases that doctors thought had almost disappeared are now making a comeback. Britain's National Health Service (NHS) has reported a serious rise in the number of people with diseases such as tuberculosis (TB), cholera, measles and whooping cough. An NHS spokesperson said that TB is now more common in England than it is in less developed countries such Rwanda, Iraq, and Guatemala. Tuberculosis is also increasing across the globe. In 2013, it killed 1.5 million people worldwide, and that number is rising. Tuberculosis largely affects very poor people. It is an infectious disease that affects the lungs. Its symptoms include bad coughs, fever, weight loss and sweating.</transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>12a20d95cfc348d691210deb706f41dc</id>
    <practiceSet>39d265f15f41481891312961d73f01bf</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_SELECT_MISSING_WORD</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording on Public Health. At the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>You will hear a recording on Public Health. At the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Select missing word - Q14.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>rates of sugar</o0>
        <o1>level of sugar</o1>
        <o2>rates of obesity</o2>
        <o3>price</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>2</answer>
    </template>
    <transcript>Governments in the United States and United Kingdom are waging a war on sugar in the interests of public health. Both countries claim that the overconsumption of sugar by much of the population is detrimental to people's well-being. On Thursday, the U.S. government issued new dietary guidelines that strongly recommend people receive less than 10 per cent of their daily calorie intake from added sugar. On the same day, British Prime Minister David Cameron said he has not ruled out the idea of a tax on sugar to encourage consumers to buy food with reduced levels of the sweet stuff. Politicians in the U.K. are debating how a reduction in the intake of sugar could help alleviate Britain's rising rates of obesity.</transcript>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>edca9dcd11b441eba3c79b2705cee9de</id>
    <practiceSet>39d265f15f41481891312961d73f01bf</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_HIGHLIGHT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Below is a transcription of the recording. Some words in the transcription differ from what the speaker(s) said. Please click on words that are different.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description> Researchers say that many of the diseases that are making a backtrack are both preventable and treatable. One big problem in England is that TB is affecting young people who have malnutrition – they do not have enough to eat. The number of elderly who have to go without food has tripled in the past three years. This is putting these old people in greater harm of getting TB. A UK doctor said she did not understand why society wasn't doing more to rescue TB. She said: "Malnutrition is preventable. It is totally acceptable that…there are at least one million older people malnourished or at risk of malnourishment." She said there needed to be a huge focus on better nutrition and proper medicine.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Highlight Incorrect Words- Q15.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <answer>backtrack|young|tripled|harm|rescue|acceptable|huge</answer>
      <maxWordCount></maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>c0cac32913b74db4b38a3069de11b94c</id>
    <practiceSet>39d265f15f41481891312961d73f01bf</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_HIGHLIGHT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Below is a transcription of the recording. Some words in the transcription differ from what the speaker(s) said. Please click on words that are different.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>The tax was applied on January 1, 2014 and purchases of the taxed beverages went down by 12 per cent by December of that year. Sales of mineral water increased by forty per cent over the same period. An alternative to taxing sugared drinks is to reduce the level of sugar in them. Researchers at Queen Mary University in London say that increasing the sugar content in sugar-sweetened drinks by 40 per cent over five years could prevent one million cases of diabetes in the U.K. Researchers say people might not even notice the growth.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Highlight Incorrect Words- Q16.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <answer>applied|forty|increasing|diabetes|growth</answer>
      <maxWordCount></maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>11bdc7698b7846269063e751fd838abf</id>
    <practiceSet>39d265f15f41481891312961d73f01bf</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Write from dictation- Q17.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <answer>Annual premature European deaths caused by air pollution are estimated at 430,000.</answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>0a9b324698a5480fb1495002d50398b1</id>
    <practiceSet>39d265f15f41481891312961d73f01bf</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Write from dictation- Q18.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <answer>I would like to recommend you to hire a personal tutor if you want to qualify in the entrance exam.</answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>ce10f6bb41fd487191740308aa0e4dff</id>
    <practiceSet>39d265f15f41481891312961d73f01bf</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Write from dictation- Q19.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <answer>Before starting the project, kindly go through the given instructions.</answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>a705888ad39745c1a9b1b671db91058f</id>
    <practiceSet>dffc4ce9224b4f05b2d81e9a523be1d7</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_WRITE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a short lecture. Write a summary for fellow student who was not present at the lecture. You should write 50-70 words. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points presented in the lecture.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>2Listening - Summarize Spoken Text - Q1.tpm</media>
      <delay>0</delay>
      <answer>correct answer is this text here</answer>
      <maxWordCount>70</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>4eff02984478415f8a9802922ce2fcda</id>
    <practiceSet>dffc4ce9224b4f05b2d81e9a523be1d7</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_WRITE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a short lecture. Write a summary for fellow student who was not present at the lecture. You should write 50-70 words. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points presented in the lecture.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>2Listening - Summarize Spoken Text - Q2.tpm</media>
      <delay>0</delay>
      <answer>correct answer is this text here</answer>
      <maxWordCount>70</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
    <!-- Changes done as per new request from Sharan -->
  <!-- <question> -->
    <!-- <id>6c498389e3c04848b61aa38657bb73e7</id> -->
    <!-- <practiceSet>dffc4ce9224b4f05b2d81e9a523be1d7</practiceSet> -->
    <!-- <type>LISTEN_AND_WRITE</type> -->
    <!-- <itemType>LISTENING</itemType> -->
    <!-- <instruction>You will hear a short lecture. Write a summary for fellow student who was not present at the lecture. You should write 50-70 words. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points presented in the lecture.</instruction> -->
    <!-- <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime> -->
    <!-- <template> -->
      <!-- <description></description> -->
      <!-- <title></title> -->
      <!-- <media>2Listening - Summarize Spoken Text - Q3.tpm</media> -->
      <!-- <delay>0</delay> -->
      <!-- <answer>correct answer is this text here</answer> -->
      <!-- <maxWordCount>70</maxWordCount> -->
    <!-- </template> -->
  <!-- </question> -->
  <question>
    <id>542f0f54f1d044e094a7aed4273f665c</id>
    <practiceSet>dffc4ce9224b4f05b2d81e9a523be1d7</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_SELECT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting  all the correct responses. You will need to select more than one response.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>According to the speaker, which of the following statements are not true?</title>
      <media>2Listening - Multiple choice, choose multiple answers - Q4.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>lack of sleep is just the part of modern life.</o0>
        <o1>43% of women do not sleep well and compared to men this figure is more.</o1>
        <o2>lack of sleep doesn’t affect the life style.</o2>
        <o3>lack of sleep can bring serious underlying medical conditions.</o3>
        <o4>Sleep apnoea can lead to heart attack.</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>1|3|4</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>184f52dfbf964111a4a41df416da5877</id>
    <practiceSet>dffc4ce9224b4f05b2d81e9a523be1d7</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_SELECT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting  all the correct responses. You will need to select more than one response.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>Over-the-counter  medicine  can cause more harm as it may include:-</title>
      <media>2Listening - Multiple choice, choose multiple answers - Q5.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>cognitive impairment.</o0>
        <o1>higher glucose metabolism.</o1>
        <o2>increase in brain size.</o2>
        <o3>dementia</o3>
        <o4>asthma</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>0|3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>fdeeb03a29134f7eaa3d763c4db27935</id>
    <practiceSet>dffc4ce9224b4f05b2d81e9a523be1d7</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_FILL_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Type the missing words in each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>It was in the 1980s that many of us became {blank} that small individual actions could harm the planet itself.  Hairsprays were cited as one of the causes of the hole in the {blank} ozone layer. People were told to wear sunscreen to avoid skin cancer as the layer {blank} and more UV light got through. By 1987 world governments had agreed to ban most of the ozone-eating chemicals. The World {blank} Organisation say at last the ozone layer is showing signs of thickening, although it will be a while before they know if the hole is actually {blank}.  The same organisation {blank} earlier this week that climate change was heading in the opposite direction with {blank} in the atmosphere at a record level.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>2Listening - Fill in the blanks – Q6.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <answer>aware |Antarctic|||thinned|||Meteorological|||healing|||warned|||greenhouse gases</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>3584bb16a9394feca0652477b402f72a</id>
    <practiceSet>dffc4ce9224b4f05b2d81e9a523be1d7</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_FILL_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Type the missing words in each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>For many people commuting is a {blank} evil. Most see going by car or van as the 'least worst' option. This study by the researchers at the University of East Anglia challenges that {blank}.  It suggests walking, cycling or travelling by public transport can {blank}. Crucially, it suggests those who switch from the car to an active commute feel better across a range of {blank} measures, including concentration, decision making and the ability to {blank} to problems.  The researchers say policies {blank} people to leave their cars at home could have a dramatic impact on public {blank}.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>2Listening - Fill in the blanks – Q7.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <answer>necessary|assumption|||lift the mood|||psychological|||face up|||encouraging|||wellbeing</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>374442274b7746c4ba800f2a63b5233d</id>
    <practiceSet>dffc4ce9224b4f05b2d81e9a523be1d7</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_FILL_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Type the missing words in each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Dinosaurs ruled the Earth for about {blank} years. Then they disappeared. Scientists have {blank} for years about what killed off the dinosaurs. Was it the huge volcanic eruption 66 million years ago in what is now India? That {blank} changed the Earth’s climate in a major way. Then, just 150,000 years later, a {blank} from space struck the coast of Mexico. This also caused changes to the climate. Both {blank} events happened during what is called the Cretaceous Period in Earth’s history. Scientists have long {blank} which event caused the dinosaurs to disappear? One reason the debate continued was the failure of the scientists to find a {blank} window from which to look into the past.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>2Listening - Fill in the blanks – Q8.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <answer>160 million |argued|||explosion|||meteorite|||catastrophic|||debated|||perfect</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>d3e2de8c75c846ce98f5a2eafa55902f</id>
    <practiceSet>dffc4ce9224b4f05b2d81e9a523be1d7</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_HIGHLIGHT_CORRECT_SUMMARY</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Click on paragraph that best relates to the recording.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>2Listening - Highlight Correct Summary - Q9.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>By 2050, more plastics will weigh in ocean which will be more than fish, the plastic is not bio-degradable,  only 14% of plastic can be recycled which is effecting the sea life as fish are dying from choking after eating plastics as it has intestinal blockage and starvation.</o0>
        <o1>Plastic has disturbed the sea life, atleast 8 millions of plastic is thrown in oceans around the world. It cannot be recycled nor can its usage be reduced as the plastic is not bio-degradable, fish has intestinal blockage and starvation leading to death.</o1>
        <o2>By  2025, more plastics will weigh in ocean which will be more than fish, atleast 8 millions of plastic is thrown in ocean around the world, 53% plastic is recycled but still it is the threat to sea life as fish has intestinal blockage and starvation leading to death.</o2>
        <o3>By 2025, more plastics will weigh in ocean which will be more than fish, atleast 8 millions of plastic is thrown, the plastic is not bio-degradable. This is the threat to sea life as fish has intestinal blockage and starvation leading to death.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>2e235b86ed8a411a9f2ebf7980198ae6</id>
    <practiceSet>dffc4ce9224b4f05b2d81e9a523be1d7</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_HIGHLIGHT_CORRECT_SUMMARY</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Click on paragraph that best relates to the recording.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>2Listening - Highlight Correct Summary - Q10.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>People  are investing in Wall street investment firms because they are getting good return comparative to stock exchange and secondly the firm gives them the clear picture where their investments are going. The main reason of investing in Wall street firm is that politicians have not funded pension funds and secondly, they do not pay what is owed by the workers.</o0>
        <o1>People are investing more of their pension funds in Wall street investments because the charges are less and risk is low comparative to stock exchange and investing with government. The main reason of investing in Wall street is that politicians have not funded pension funds and secondly, they do not pay what is owed by the workers. </o1>
        <o2>People are investing more of their pension funds in high fee, High-risk Wall street investments, because there is a debate among the politicians to raise the taxes and  not to fund  pension funds and secondly, they do not pay what is owed by the workers. The returns in Wall street firms have been more than stock exchange and inspite of no campaign contribution people invest in Wall street.</o2>
        <o3>People are investing more of their pension funds in high fee, High-risk Wall street investments, because politicians have not funded pension funds and secondly, they do not pay what is owed by the workers. The returns in Wall street firms have been lower than stock exchange but still people invest because of campaign contribution and even people hardly know where their investment is going.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>a68412ab403a46b78e5ec939dc3c65e7</id>
    <practiceSet>dffc4ce9224b4f05b2d81e9a523be1d7</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_CHOICE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple -choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>As per the lecture, why is sugar considered to be harmful?</title>
      <media>2Listening - Multiple choice, choose single answer - Q11.tpm</media>
      <delay>5</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>Its consumption may increase the glucose level in blood.</o0>
        <o1>It may cause increase in taxes by 12% end of this year.</o1>
        <o2>More intake of sugar could aggravate rising rates of obesity.</o2>
        <o3>It may increase one million cases of obesity in the UK over five years.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>c5cc5a6cc0e340e5b8f91edc7e1a4bf6</id>
    <practiceSet>dffc4ce9224b4f05b2d81e9a523be1d7</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_CHOICE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple -choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>As per the lecture, which of the given statement is FALSE?</title>
      <media>2Listening - Multiple choice, choose single answer - Q12.tpm</media>
      <delay>5</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>stealing a food to avert hunger is not a crime.</o0>
        <o1>A homeless Ukrainian man was fined and jailed by Supreme court for stealing food.</o1>
        <o2>The case will highlight the extent of poverty in Italy.</o2>
        <o3>Food stolen out of desperation is not considered to be a crime.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>df64db0df9094b0295df1be256829292</id>
    <practiceSet>dffc4ce9224b4f05b2d81e9a523be1d7</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_SELECT_MISSING_WORD</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording on Deep Voices. At the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>You will hear a recording on Deep Voices. At the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>2Listening - Select missing word - Q13.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>dominate others.</o0>
        <o1>scare women</o1>
        <o2>impress their colleagues</o2>
        <o3>attract women</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>5691da2ab61741f99d5e5003518b9870</id>
    <practiceSet>dffc4ce9224b4f05b2d81e9a523be1d7</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_SELECT_MISSING_WORD</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording on Nuclear Plants. At the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>You will hear a recording on Nuclear Plants. At the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>2Listening - Select missing word - Q14.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>serenity</o0>
        <o1>misconception</o1>
        <o2>concerns</o2>
        <o3>negligence</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>7f2102efa58544f18e5a5f80ac64d7cb</id>
    <practiceSet>dffc4ce9224b4f05b2d81e9a523be1d7</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_HIGHLIGHT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Below is a transcription of the recording. Some words in the transcription differ from what the speaker(s) said. Please click on words that are different.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Scientists have invented that one plant, the humble pea, can make decisions regarding how to live best, even though it does not have a brain. Researchers from the UK's Oxford University and Israel's Tel-Hai College grew several pea plants that had their roots separated between two parts. Each pot contained differing amounts of minerals. One pot always had the same amount, while the other pot range between a lot and a little. The plants turned out to be remarkably consistent at converting their roots to the pot with the most nutrients.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>2Listening - Highlight Incorrect Words- Q15.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <answer>invented|live|parts|minerals|range|converting</answer>
      <maxWordCount></maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>59bfbea7d5a3492391d10c17669e1098</id>
    <practiceSet>dffc4ce9224b4f05b2d81e9a523be1d7</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_HIGHLIGHT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Below is a transcription of the recording. Some words in the transcription differ from what the speaker(s) said. Please click on words that are different.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>People experiencing social unease often have a persistent, extreme, and chronic fear of being watched and judged by others and being hampered or humiliated by their own actions. Their fear may be so severe that it significantly impairs their work, school, social life, and other activities. While many people experiencing social anxiety recognize that their fear of being around people may be undesirable or unreasonable, they encounter considerable problem overcoming it.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>2Listening - Highlight Incorrect Words- Q16.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <answer>unease|extreme|hampered|undesirable|problem</answer>
      <maxWordCount></maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>3e8283b1494b43abae3c29faf3d5c87a</id>
    <practiceSet>dffc4ce9224b4f05b2d81e9a523be1d7</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>2Listening - Write from dictation- Q17.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <answer>The relationships among the countries of the United Kingdom have changed over time</answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>0aff3ab8b568486c8c327b67ca8dd1bd</id>
    <practiceSet>dffc4ce9224b4f05b2d81e9a523be1d7</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>2Listening - Write from dictation- Q18.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <answer>KFC was one of the first fast-food chains to expand internationally.</answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>536c20149d8f4dd5a57cbe0cac7b40d8</id>
    <practiceSet>dffc4ce9224b4f05b2d81e9a523be1d7</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>2Listening - Write from dictation- Q19.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <answer>The United States is the world's oldest surviving federation.</answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>1ce6e23816cb49eb8ffdb892a2ef1296</id>
    <practiceSet>e8c3b7b66171443e874f972f432c4103</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_WRITE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a short lecture. Write a summary for fellow student who was not present at the lecture. You should write 50-70 words. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points presented in the lecture.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>3Listening - Summarize Spoken Text - Q1.tpm</media>
      <delay>0</delay>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>70</maxWordCount>
      <transcript></transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>483c06fc3c284fc7b97c924fc5994657</id>
    <practiceSet>e8c3b7b66171443e874f972f432c4103</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_WRITE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a short lecture. Write a summary for fellow student who was not present at the lecture. You should write 50-70 words. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points presented in the lecture.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>3Listening - Summarize Spoken Text - Q2.tpm</media>
      <delay>0</delay>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>70</maxWordCount>
      <transcript></transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>2a36b9ae7370467f9ade8fcc0bbc17dd</id>
    <practiceSet>e8c3b7b66171443e874f972f432c4103</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_SELECT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting  all the correct responses. You will need to select more than one response.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>What is the view of people about making site user friendly:-</title>
      <media>3Listening - Multiple choice, choose multiple answers – Q3.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>They are positive and think that it will help them to perform their activities in better way.</o0>
        <o1>They are frustrated has it has made things more complicated.</o1>
        <o2>The interaction through websites has become more complicated.</o2>
        <o3>It takes less time to download the data.</o3>
        <o4>Phones are easy to access than before.</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>0|4</answer>
      <transcript>The website Breaking News English.com has upgraded its pages to be easier to use on mobile phones and tablets. This improvement means students and teachers who wish to browse the lessons, read the news articles or do the activities on their mobile devices can now do so with ease. The Internet has changed beyond recognition since it started a few decades ago. Being online today is worlds apart from the worldwide web of 20 years ago. Back then, web pages simply consisted of text and took an age to load. People could only view them on bulky desktop computers. Today, we have movies, music, games, GPS and a whole plethora of apps on our mobile phones. The owner of Breaking News English commissioned the website developer markbaindesign.com to make the site mobile friendly. Designer Mark Bain has created many eye-catching sites for some of the world's leading educators. Mr Bain summed up his thoughts on today's online world by saying: "Expectations about what can be done on a phone are rising every day." His work on Breaking News English is already popular. Saeed from Kuwait said: "I'm extremely happy with the new look. It is now much easier to get to grips with the activities." Another student, Rosa from Bolivia, said she could now interact with the news articles and exercises during her daily commute to work.</transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>cf1cf6dccb6d471180f06189cc6626e5</id>
    <practiceSet>e8c3b7b66171443e874f972f432c4103</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_SELECT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting  all the correct responses. You will need to select more than one response.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>Which of the statements are true as per the speaker?</title>
      <media>3Listening - Multiple choice, choose multiple answers – Q4.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>77% people are in favor of a guaranteed basic monthly income.</o0>
        <o1>As per the spokesman, guaranteed basic monthly income will help fight poverty and inequality.</o1>
        <o2>guaranteed basic monthly income will lead to immigration problems.</o2>
        <o3>Monthly income will be sufficient for the survival of the people.</o3>
        <o4>The monthly income will be less than $2500.</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>1|2</answer>
      <transcript>Voters in Switzerland have overwhelmingly rejected a proposal that would have meant introducing a guaranteed basic monthly income for all citizens. The referendum took place on Sunday and resulted in almost 77 per cent of voters opposing the plan. The idea was to provide a minimum salary to those who have been a citizen for at least five years, whether they worked or not. It was suggested the monthly amount could be around $2,500. The group behind the proposal argued that the initiative was necessary to overhaul Switzerland's social welfare system. A spokesperson said it would help fight poverty and inequality. He added that it would provide a top-up for people who earned less than the minimum wage. Supporters of the plan argued that because work was becoming increasingly automated across Switzerland, there were fewer jobs available for workers. Che Wagner from the campaign group Basic Income Switzerland argued that the monthly income would not be money for nothing. He said: "In Switzerland, over 50 per cent of total work that is done is unpaid. It's care work. It's at home. It's in different communities, so that work would be more valued with a basic income." Opponents said it would cause the country many immigration problems. Luzi Stamm from the Swiss People's Party said: "You would have billions of people who would try to move into Switzerland."</transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>f110179a4d25467fa60c662066b95828</id>
    <practiceSet>e8c3b7b66171443e874f972f432c4103</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_FILL_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Type the missing words in each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>The essay kind of just {blank} a regular average Wednesday morning for me, which involved waking up {blank} early, drinking some coffee, regarding the morning and then driving to work. The part of town we live in, we're really {blank} to. It's an older, lower-income part of the city, but we like {blank} that it's just so dynamic and there are so many different people here. Part of the essay captures that because as I drive down a few miles of road to the place where I work, I pass so many different {blank} and so many different lives for me offers a kind of {blank} to the place, or at least, some sort of dynamic that I can {blank} even though there's little natural things to be seen here.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>3Listening - Fill in the blanks – Q5.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <answer>chronicles |decently |||attracted |||especially |||businesses |||wildness |||appreciate </answer>
      <transcript>The essay kind of just chronicles a regular average Wednesday morning for me, which involved waking up decently early, drinking some coffee, regarding the morning and then driving to work. The part of town we live in, we're really attracted to. It's an older, lower-income part of the city, but we like especially that it's just so dynamic and there are so many different people here. Part of the essay captures that because as I drive down a few miles of road to the place where I work, I pass so many different businesses and so many different lives for me offers a kind of wildness to the place, or at least, some sort of dynamic that I can appreciate even though there's little natural things to be seen here. </transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>5e5b8204dafc404e92d1cba373f434a3</id>
    <practiceSet>e8c3b7b66171443e874f972f432c4103</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_FILL_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Type the missing words in each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>The {blank} actress Sophia Loren reportedly once said, “Everything you see I {blank} to spaghetti.” What we see is her great figure – a figure she {blank} to eating pasta. But many people consider pasta bad for maintaining a healthy weight. Modern food experts often suggest avoiding pasta and other {blank}, such as white rice and potatoes. That suggestion is bad news to many people. After all, rice is a {blank} of many Asian countries; potatoes are a staple of some {blank} European diets; and pasta is a staple of the Italian diet and a favorite of people everywhere. These foods are also called {blank}.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>3Listening - Fill in the blanks – Q6.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <answer>Italian|owe|||credits|||carbohydrates|||staple|||Eastern|||comfort foods</answer>
      <transcript>The Italian actress Sophia Loren reportedly once said, “Everything you see I owe to spaghetti.”  What we see is her great figure – a figure she credits to eating pasta. But many people consider pasta bad for maintaining a healthy weight. Modern food experts often suggest avoiding pasta and other carbohydrates, such as white rice and potatoes. That suggestion is bad news to many people. After all, rice is a staple of many Asian countries; potatoes are a staple of some Eastern European diets; and pasta is a staple of the Italian diet and a favorite of people everywhere. These foods are also called comfort foods. </transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>c2c89a7d50ed4fae920886ee4dda895d</id>
    <practiceSet>e8c3b7b66171443e874f972f432c4103</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_FILL_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Type the missing words in each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>The Freedom of Information Act, the means whereby US citizens may {blank} the government for information has been around since 1966 but, according to the Center for Effective Government, federal agencies haven’t quite yet {blank} the art of disclosing. This week, the center released the first ever {blank} measure of how 15 key government agencies process FOIA requests, called the {blank} to Information Scorecard 2014. It assessed the process, the rules and the websites of the 15 most FOIA’d and government agencies and assigned them a {blank} letter grade, like in school, on a scale of A to F.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>3Listening - Fill in the blanks – Q7.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <answer>petition|mastered|||quantifiable|||Access|||standard</answer>
      <transcript>The Freedom of Information Act, the means whereby US citizens may petition the government for information has been around since 1966 but, according to the Center for Effective Government, federal agencies haven’t quite yet mastered the art of disclosing. This week, the center released the first ever quantifiable measure of how 15 key government agencies process FOIA requests, called the Access to Information Scorecard 2014. It assessed the process, the rules and the websites of the 15 most FOIA’d and government agencies and assigned them a standard letter grade, like in school, on a scale of A to F.</transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>7227baf7ee5f4e43a0b13d4205350416</id>
    <practiceSet>e8c3b7b66171443e874f972f432c4103</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_HIGHLIGHT_CORRECT_SUMMARY</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Click on paragraph that best relates to the recording.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>3Listening - Highlight Correct Summary – Q8.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>A small town in Italy has passed legislation requiring people to use only silent fireworks in displays and celebrations. The new measure is to ensure the wellbeing of dogs and other pets. Antonio Maldini said: "You need the booms, cracks and thunder. It's an essential part of the fun." He advised pet owners to keep animals indoors and keep all windows firmly closed.</o0>
        <o1>Fireworks are known to cause problems for war veterans. The explosions bring back painful memories of being in areas of conflict and can trigger post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD). Antonio advised pet owners to keep animals indoors and keep all windows firmly closed.</o1>
        <o2>The sounds and smoke created by fireworks can cause additional health problems in animals. Vets commonly report cases of nausea, tremors and increased anxiety in animals after a fireworks show. However, not everyone agrees with the idea of silent fireworks.</o2>
        <o3>A small town in Italy has passed legislation to use silent fireworks; the sound of fireworks can cause health problems in animals. Awareness of the potential problems created by the sound is growing in Europe, Germany has banned near refugee shelters . But Antonio says that sound of fireworks is essential for fun, he advises pets should be kept indoor.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>3</answer>
      <transcript>A small town in Italy has passed legislation requiring people to use only silent fireworks in displays and celebrations. The new measure is to ensure the wellbeing of dogs and other pets. The town of Collecchio in the province of Parma has decided that the welfare of its pets is more important than the sound of explosions that normally accompanies fireworks. The more sensitive hearing of animals causes them to develop a condition known as 'acoustic stress' that follows sudden and loud noises. The sounds and smoke created by fireworks can cause additional health problems in animals. Vets commonly report cases of nausea, tremors and increased anxiety in animals after a fireworks show. Awareness of the potential problems created by the sound of fireworks is growing in Europe. Over the New Year, Germany banned fireworks near refugee shelters to minimise trauma experienced by refugees who had just fled war zones. Fireworks are also known to cause problems for war veterans. The explosions bring back painful memories of being in areas of conflict and can trigger post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD). However, not everyone agrees with the idea of silent fireworks. Antonio Maldini said: "You need the booms, cracks and thunder. It's an essential part of the fun." He advised pet owners to keep animals indoors and keep all windows firmly closed.</transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>cb9ecb06ee1e420b91a7a8caa0223378</id>
    <practiceSet>e8c3b7b66171443e874f972f432c4103</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_HIGHLIGHT_CORRECT_SUMMARY</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Click on paragraph that best relates to the recording.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>3Listening - Highlight Correct Summary – Q9.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>A Toyota spokeswoman said the company decided to shut down the elevators several weeks ago because of the rising yen. The company is also adjusting the temperature of air conditioners to save money. The spokeswoman said Toyota took similar cost-cutting measures after the financial crisis that happened in September 2008.</o0>
        <o1>A stronger yen means Toyota cars sold overseas are more expensive and profits go down. Toyota's profit for the year ending March 2016 was a record ¥2.31 trillion, which is around $23 billion.</o1>
        <o2>Toyota car company is shutting down two elevators, to save electricity and cut down the cost to strengthen Japanese yen. As per a Toyota spokeswoman “The key objective for the stoppage of elevators specifically is to raise awareness amongst employees and to remind them of the commitment of Toyota has towards increasing competitiveness through staying lean and reducing waste.</o2>
        <o3>Toyota car company is shutting down two elevators, to save electricity and cut down the cost to strengthen Japanese yen. Toyota's profit for the year ending March 2016 was a record ¥2.31 trillion, which is around $23 billion. The spokeswoman said Toyota took similar cost-cutting measures after the financial crisis that happened in September 2008.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>2</answer>
      <transcript>The car company Toyota is shutting down two elevators at its global headquarters to save money. The world's largest automaker said on Thursday it will shut down two of eight elevators at its main Tokyo office. This is to save electricity and to cut down on the costs of operating the building. One reason for this new move is the strengthening Japanese yen. The yen has become much stronger since the UK voted to leave the EU on June the 23rd. One dollar bought nearly 120 yen in January; now it buys just above 100. A stronger yen means Toyota cars sold overseas are more expensive and profits go down. Toyota's profit for the year ending March 2016 was a record ¥2.31 trillion, which is around $23 billion. A Toyota spokeswoman said the company decided to shut down the elevators several weeks ago because of the rising yen. The company is also adjusting the temperature of air conditioners to save money. The spokeswoman said Toyota took similar cost-cutting measures after the financial crisis that happened in September 2008. That also made the yen strengthen against the dollar. The spokeswoman said: "These policies are not new." She added: "The key objective for the stoppage of elevators specifically is to raise awareness amongst employees, and to remind them of the commitment that Toyota has towards the idea of increasing competitiveness through staying lean and reducing waste." </transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>72afcf6c03f24d48b10a844faf46dbd2</id>
    <practiceSet>e8c3b7b66171443e874f972f432c4103</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_CHOICE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple -choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>As per the speaker, which of the statement is true:-</title>
      <media>3Listening - Multiple choice, choose single answers – Q10.tpm</media>
      <delay>5</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>95% of CO2 was converted into limestone.</o0>
        <o1>The experiment will not be adapted by industrial sector.</o1>
        <o2>The experiment would not control the growing CO2 emission.</o2>
        <o3>Carbon emission cannot be controlled permanently.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>0</answer>
      <transcript>Scientists have come up with a smart but simple way to deal with carbon dioxide emissions, by turning them back into stone. Researchers in Iceland pumped 220 tons of CO2 deep underground into volcanic rock. It reacted with minerals in the rock and over a relatively short space of time, transformed into a chalk-like solid substance similar to limestone. The team expressed their surprise at both the success and the speed of the CO2 conversion. Lead scientist Juerg Matter said: "Of our 220 tons of injected CO2, 95 per cent was converted to limestone in less than two years." He added: "It was a huge surprise to all the scientists involved in the project, and we thought, 'Wow! This is really fast'." The scientists hope their experiment will be adapted on a larger, more industrial scale. It could help to alleviate the problem of growing CO2 emissions entering the atmosphere and warming the planet. It could also become a key technique in carbon capture and storage (CCS) solutions. Many other CCS techniques have involved injecting and trapping CO2 underground. However, there was always the problem of the emissions leaking their way back above ground and into the atmosphere. Dr Matter was enthusiastic about his team's experiments. He said: "We need to deal with rising carbon emissions and this is the ultimate permanent storage – turn them back to stone." </transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>0cd5d54a6f8541168c840cb506143f2b</id>
    <practiceSet>e8c3b7b66171443e874f972f432c4103</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_CHOICE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple -choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>According to scientist:-</title>
      <media>3Listening - Multiple choice, choose single answers – Q11.tpm</media>
      <delay>5</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>The contact with Aliens is not possible for human as there is no life except Earth.</o0>
        <o1>Human may take more than 1500 years to make contact with Aliens.</o1>
        <o2>Extraterrestrial does not require to decode the light waves into sounds.</o2>
        <o3>There is no need to be alert as there are rare chances to miss the signal</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>1</answer>
      <transcript>Scientists say it could take at least 1,500 years before humans make contact with species of aliens, or for them to communicate with or find us. Astronomers from Cornell University in the USA combined two existing theories about the possibility of life existing on other planets to form a new equation. One of these theories is the Fermi Paradox described by physicist Enrico Fermi in 1950. This states that while billions of Earth-like planets exist in our galaxy, not one has made contact with Earth yet. The other is the mediocrity principle, which suggests that because there is life on Earth, it will typically exist on Earth-like planets throughout the universe. Study author Evan Solomonides will soon present a research paper on his theory. He said: "We haven't heard from aliens yet, as space is a big place, but that doesn't mean no one is out there." According to Solomonides, extraterrestrials could have received signals from Earth. However, he proposes that ET would not have been able to decipher them. He said they would need to decode the light waves into sounds and analyse 3,000 human languages to understand any messages. He said that signals from Earth have only reached about 8,500 stars and that the Milky Way galaxy alone contains 200 billion stars. He added: "If we stop listening or looking, we may miss the signals, so we should keep looking." </transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>6b3aba4a91a24b11a70c31fe0427824c</id>
    <practiceSet>e8c3b7b66171443e874f972f432c4103</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_SELECT_MISSING_WORD</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording on PLANTS. At the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>You will hear a recording on PLANTS. At the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>3Listening - Select missing word - Q12.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>the most nutrients.</o0>
        <o1>more minerals.</o1>
        <o2>more nutrition.</o2>
        <o3>the most nutritious.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>0</answer>
      <transcript>Plants are a lot smarter than we thought. According to researchers, they are capable of making intelligent decisions regarding risk. Scientists have discovered that one plant, the humble pea, can make decisions regarding how to survive best, even though it does not have a brain. Researchers from the UK's Oxford University and Israel's Tel-Hai College grew several pea plants that had their roots separated between two pots. Each pot contained differing amounts of nutrients. One pot always had the same amount, while the other pot varied between a lot and a little. The plants turned out to be remarkably consistent at diverting their roots to the pot with the most nutrients.</transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>12ac2288019445ad83414dddddc82417</id>
    <practiceSet>e8c3b7b66171443e874f972f432c4103</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_SELECT_MISSING_WORD</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording on Resolution. At the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>You will hear a recording on Resolution. At the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>3Listening - Select missing word - Q13.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>make resolution again</o0>
        <o1>never make any resolution</o1>
        <o2>try again next year</o2>
        <o3>make willpower strong</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>2</answer>
      <transcript>Research shows 45 per cent of us make a New Year’s resolution. The most common vows include losing weight, volunteering to help others, quitting smoking, saving money, and getting fit. Others include eating healthier food, drinking less alcohol, and going on a trip. However, research also shows that most of us are not so good at sticking to these. A study from the University of Scranton reveals that 71 per cent of us stick to our annual promises for the first two weeks; six months later, less than 50 percent are still on track to keep their resolutions. Most people who give up on their resolutions do so because of a lack of willpower and the use of the 'escape clause' that they will </transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>bbb277665d76443193b10d7f144fe643</id>
    <practiceSet>e8c3b7b66171443e874f972f432c4103</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_HIGHLIGHT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Below is a transcription of the recording. Some words in the transcription differ from what the speaker(s) said. Please click on words that are different.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>The ship Mayflower was used as a cargo ship trading (often in wine) between England and other European countries, basically France but also Norway, Germany and Spain. At least between 1609 and 1623 it was headed by Christopher Jones, who was Captain on the trans-atlantic voyage, and based in Rotherhithe. He was cremated in the graveyard of St. Mary's Rotherhithe following his death in March 1620, and it is likely that the ship was broken up for scrap lumber there in the following year. The Mayflower Barn situated just near the small Quaker Village of Jordans in Buckinghamshire, England purposed to be constructed from these timbers.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>3Listening - Highlight Incorrect Words- Q14.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <answer>basically|headed|cremated|1620|near</answer>
      <maxWordCount></maxWordCount>
      <transcript>The ship Mayflower was used as a cargo ship trading (often in wine) between England and other European countries, principally France but also Norway, Germany and Spain. At least between 1609 and 1623 it was mastered by Christopher Jones, who was Captain on the trans-atlantic voyage, and based in Rotherhithe. He was buried in the graveyard of St. Mary's Rotherhithe following his death in March 1623, and it is likely that the ship was broken up for scrap lumber there in the following year. The Mayflower Barn situated just outside the small Quaker Village of Jordans in Buckinghamshire, England purports to be constructed from these timbers.</transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>539f7ce9fa594430920f30b7ea833355</id>
    <practiceSet>e8c3b7b66171443e874f972f432c4103</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_HIGHLIGHT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Below is a transcription of the recording. Some words in the transcription differ from what the speaker(s) said. Please click on words that are different.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>And those jets release just enough carbon monoxide to simulate the atmosphere that crops will almost definitely experience 40 or 60 years from now. They've found crops do grow fast when there's more carbon dioxide. They often produce yields that are 10 percent more. That sounds like a good thing, but Samuel Myers and his subordinates took a closer look, examining not just the quantity of the harvest but also the quality.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>3Listening - Highlight Incorrect Words- Q15.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <answer>monoxide|definitely|fast|yields|more|subordinates</answer>
      <maxWordCount></maxWordCount>
      <transcript>And those jets release just enough carbon dioxide to simulate the atmosphere that crops will almost certainly experience 40 or 60 years from now. They've found crops do grow faster when there's more carbon dioxide. They often produce harvests that are 10 percent bigger. That sounds like a good thing, but Samuel Myers and his colleagues took a closer look, examining not just the quantity of the harvest but also the quality.</transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>749b6bfd3db14762b077980304242732</id>
    <practiceSet>e8c3b7b66171443e874f972f432c4103</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>3Listening - Write from dictation- Q16.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <answer>He has been unlucky, as he is not able to survive in any one of his relationship.</answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>5e890e8444c04b45aaadfa4a93d72654</id>
    <practiceSet>e8c3b7b66171443e874f972f432c4103</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>3Listening - Write from dictation- Q17.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <answer>Some claim that poverty is the product of deindustrialization.</answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>e8da4494a0424aa88563bfa662d7384b</id>
    <practiceSet>e8c3b7b66171443e874f972f432c4103</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>3Listening - Write from dictation- Q18.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <answer>Poverty means lack of basic capacity to participate effectively in society.</answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>1d6593f780c049459aae0c65aeec0d85</id>
    <practiceSet>a2dc026da5a84119be23ddaab151b4fc</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_WRITE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a short lecture. Write a summary for fellow student who was not present at the lecture. You should write 50-70 words. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points presented in the lecture.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>4Listening - Summarize Spoken Text - Q1.tpm</media>
      <delay>0</delay>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>70</maxWordCount>
      <transcript></transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>5a812de6fa95473db9d7c6541b152de2</id>
    <practiceSet>a2dc026da5a84119be23ddaab151b4fc</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_WRITE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a short lecture. Write a summary for fellow student who was not present at the lecture. You should write 50-70 words. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points presented in the lecture.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>4Listening - Summarize Spoken Text - Q2.tpm</media>
      <delay>0</delay>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>70</maxWordCount>
      <transcript></transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>ee77e096fcbd4b8b90a0beeec537b531</id>
    <practiceSet>a2dc026da5a84119be23ddaab151b4fc</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_SELECT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting  all the correct responses. You will need to select more than one response.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>Which of the statements are TRUE as per the lecture?</title>
      <media>4Listening - Multiple choice, choose multiple answers – Q3.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>Pratricia was commissioned to create Graham’s artwork.</o0>
        <o1>Graham is a Robert taken from a character of horror movies.</o1>
        <o2>Graham makes understand the need to improve road system.</o2>
        <o3>Graham has a huge body which prevents it to jump in dangerous situation.</o3>
        <o4>Graham was designed to show the vulnerability of human body.</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>0|2</answer>
      <transcript>A road safety organisation in Australia has created a mock-up of the perfect body needed to survive a car crash. Australia's Transport Accident Commission (TAC) has called its human-looking creation 'Graham'. TAC commissioned a sculpture of Graham and released a video to educate road users about road safety. Although Graham is humanesque, he is somewhat grotesque in parts and resembles a character from a horror movie. The BBC says: "He has a head shaped like a boulder, feet snarled like tree roots and a chest like a wrinkled battering ram." A spokesperson from TAC said Graham was designed to highlight how frail and vulnerable the human body is when involved in a vehicle collision on the roads. TAC commissioned celebrated artist Patricia Piccinini to create the artwork for Graham. She collaborated with a leading trauma surgeon and a road crash investigation expert to get the right look and build for Graham. She gave Graham a thick skull, a wider neck, an inflatable chest that acts like airbags, and hoof-like legs that allow Graham to jump out of dangerous situations. TAC chief executive Joe Calafiore commented on why his organisation commissioned Graham as an educational tool. He said: "Cars have evolved a lot faster than humans and Graham helps us understand why we need to improve every aspect of our roads system to protect ourselves from our own mistakes."</transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>02ed2126fc7d4bd6be75fe5bddab3831</id>
    <practiceSet>a2dc026da5a84119be23ddaab151b4fc</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_SELECT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting  all the correct responses. You will need to select more than one response.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>Why New Zealand has declared a war on pests?</title>
      <media>4Listening - Multiple choice, choose multiple answers – Q4.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>As predators kill approx 25 million of native birds.</o0>
        <o1>Rats, possum and stoats have led to $28 million of loss.</o1>
        <o2>Some of the native birds of New Zealand are becoming extinct.</o2>
        <o3>Pests has effected 5 % of kiwi population till now.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>0|2</answer>
      <transcript>New Zealand has declared war on pests. It wants to make the country predator-free by 2050. Its ambitious target is to remove all non-native species from the country within three decades. Prime Minister John Key says he will introduce strategies to kill introduced species, especially predators that kill New Zealand's native birds. He said: "Rats, possums and stoats kill 25 million of our native birds every year, and prey on other native species such as lizards….We must do more to protect them." His government has given $28 million to a company that will help action his plans. Mr Key said: "This is the most ambitious conservation project attempted anywhere in the world, but we believe if we all work together as a country, we can achieve it." It will take all the efforts of the private and public sectors as well as community groups. New Zealanders do not want more of their country's native birds to become extinct. When European settlers arrived 300 years ago, they brought with them rats and other predators that have killed many different birds. The country's national bird, the kiwi, is now under threat. Only five per cent of kiwi chicks survive to adulthood.</transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>2a659cbdf21444fbac1c719d323b2dfe</id>
    <practiceSet>a2dc026da5a84119be23ddaab151b4fc</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_FILL_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Type the missing words in each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Pastoralism remains a way of life in {blank}. Herders travel from place to place in the dry, {blank} deserts to find food and water for their animals. But some people think this movement of livestock is bad for the environment. They say {blank} should settle on farms and grow their own food, {blank} in times of shortages. Not everyone agrees. Experts recently met in Nairobi to discuss what to do about food shortages caused by {blank}. They say pastoralists make the best use of resources. David Mwangi at the Kenya {blank} Research Institute says grasslands have time to recover.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>4Listening - Fill in the blanks – Q5.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <answer>East Africa |dusty |||pastoralists |||especially |||drought |||Agricultural</answer>
      <transcript>Pastoralism remains a way of life in East Africa. Herders travel from place to place in the dry, dusty deserts to find food and water for their animals. But some people think this movement of livestock is bad for the environment. They say pastoralists should settle on farms and grow their own food, especially in times of shortages. Not everyone agrees. Experts recently met in Nairobi to discuss what to do about food shortages caused by drought. They say pastoralists make the best use of resources. David Mwangi at the Kenya Agricultural Research Institute says grasslands have time to recover. </transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>f36578aa80e1459e8c256c3a34f61072</id>
    <practiceSet>a2dc026da5a84119be23ddaab151b4fc</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_FILL_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Type the missing words in each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Dylan's early lyrics incorporated political, social, {blank}, and literary influences, defying existing pop music conventions and appealing widely to the counterculture. While expanding and {blank} musical styles, he has explored many traditions of American song, from folk, blues and country to {blank}, rock and roll and rockabilly to English, Scottish and Irish folk music, and even jazz and {blank}. Dylan performs with the guitar, piano and harmonica. {blank} by a changing line-up of musicians, he has toured steadily since the late 1980s on what has been dubbed the "Never Ending Tour". Although his {blank} as performer and recording artist have been central to his career, his songwriting is generally regarded as his greatest {blank}.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>4Listening - Fill in the blanks – Q6.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <answer>philosophical|personalizing|||gospel|||swing|||Backed|||accomplishments|||contribution</answer>
      <transcript>Dylan's early lyrics incorporated political, social, philosophical, and literary influences, defying existing pop music conventions and appealing widely to the counterculture. While expanding and personalizing musical styles, he has explored many traditions of American song, from folk, blues and country to gospel, rock and roll and rockabilly to English, Scottish and Irish folk music, and even jazz and swing. Dylan performs with the guitar, piano and harmonica. Backed by a changing line-up of musicians, he has toured steadily since the late 1980s on what has been dubbed the "Never Ending Tour". Although his accomplishments as performer and recording artist have been central to his career, his songwriting is generally regarded as his greatest contribution.</transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>43f6b4c1160d4bbe8e819f291ce3b7bb</id>
    <practiceSet>a2dc026da5a84119be23ddaab151b4fc</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_FILL_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Type the missing words in each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>“Pastoralists would move in search for {blank} and also water. Because what then would happen, if you are in a small area, the moment the water is {blank}, you would have to move to the next area where there is water. It gives the area you have left time to {blank}. And by the time you come back through the loop, this area now has pasture to  {blank}.”</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>4Listening - Fill in the blanks – Q7.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <answer>pasture|exhausted|||regenerate|||graze</answer>
      <transcript>“Pastoralists would move in search for pasture and also water. Because what then would happen, if you are in a small area, the moment the water is exhausted, you would have to move to the next area where there is water. It gives the area you have left time to regenerate. And by the time you come back through the loop, this area now has pasture to graze.”</transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>802e0d12ec4944ad9ffa1263af215ce3</id>
    <practiceSet>a2dc026da5a84119be23ddaab151b4fc</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_HIGHLIGHT_CORRECT_SUMMARY</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Click on paragraph that best relates to the recording.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>4Listening - Highlight Correct Summary – Q8.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>Office workers should exercise for atleast one hour to live longer, being inactive increases risk of getting heart attack, diabetes and cancer, watching TV in access is also not good, Professor Ulf Eklund advised people to take a five-minute break every hour, build physical activity into everyday life.</o0>
        <o1>Watching TV all day is one of the worst things we can do as that also means we get no exercise and are likely to eat unhealthy snacks. , Professor Ulf Eklund advised people to take a five-minute break every hour, build physical activity into everyday life.</o1>
        <o2>Research on over one million adults found that sitting for at least eight hours a day could increase the risk of dying early by up to 60 per cent. However, there is good news for those who sit at a desk all day. An hour's "brisk exercise" each day can cancel out the risk of an early death linked to sitting all day.</o2>
        <o3>Office workers should exercise for atleast one hour to live longer, being inactive increases risk of getting heart attack, diabetes and cancer. Professor Ulf Eklund advised people "Build physical activity into your everyday life to stay healthy."</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>0</answer>
      <transcript>New research shows that office workers and other people who sit down a lot must exercise for one hour a day. If they do this, they will increase their chances of living longer. Doctors have been telling us for a long time that sitting down all day will shorten our life. Researchers now say that sitting in a chair all day is as dangerous to our health as smoking or being overweight. Research on over one million adults found that sitting for at least eight hours a day could increase the risk of dying early by up to 60 per cent. However, there is good news for those who sit at a desk all day. An hour's "brisk exercise" each day can cancel out the risk of an early death linked to sitting all day. The research was published in time for people to read before the Olympics in Rio de Janeiro. Researchers hope this will encourage people to exercise more. They say that being inactive increases the risk of getting heart disease, diabetes and cancer. Watching TV all day is one of the worst things we can do as that also means we get no exercise and are likely to eat unhealthy snacks. One researcher said office workers should find opportunities to get out of their seat more often. Professor Ulf Eklund advised people to: "Take a five-minute break every hour, go to the next office, go upstairs to the coffee machine, go to the printer." He added: "Build physical activity into your everyday life."</transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>7cd9e447ce7249d09bf6b2686c554f14</id>
    <practiceSet>a2dc026da5a84119be23ddaab151b4fc</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_HIGHLIGHT_CORRECT_SUMMARY</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Click on paragraph that best relates to the recording.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>4Listening - Highlight Correct Summary – Q9.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>Millions of people around the world take dietary supplements in the belief that they will boost their health which creates side effects, consumers are well aware about the risks but still  they consume supplements.</o0>
        <o1>Consumers are largely in the dark regarding the ingredients of the supplements and how the body will react to them. Lisa Gill, an editor at CR, said the report showed how dangerous many supplements were.</o1>
        <o2>Millions of people around the world take dietary supplements in the belief that they will boost their health but these supplements lead to serious health risk, consumers use these supplements without being aware about its side effects.</o2>
        <o3>Millions of people around the world take dietary supplements in the belief that they will boost their health. New research casts doubt on the benefits of these pills and tablets.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>2</answer>
      <transcript>Millions of people around the world take dietary supplements in the belief that they will boost their health. New research casts doubt on the benefits of these pills and tablets. A new report from the American organisation Consumer Reports (CR) found serious health risks from supplements that included vitamins, probiotics, and weight loss pills. CR said the biggest problem with supplements is that they are largely unregulated. While medicinal drugs have to be tested for safety and effectiveness, dietary supplements need far less government approval in many countries. This means that consumers are largely in the dark regarding the ingredients of the supplements and how the body will react to them. Lisa Gill, an editor at CR, said the report showed how dangerous many supplements were. She said they could cause liver failure, kidney failure requiring kidney transplants, seizures, and heart problems. </transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>dca2c8d8f4764caa80b874bc4277484e</id>
    <practiceSet>a2dc026da5a84119be23ddaab151b4fc</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_CHOICE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple -choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>What surprising information did a recent experiment reveal about lesser spear-nosed bats?</title>
      <media>4Listening - Multiple choice, choose single answer - Q10.tpm</media>
      <delay>5</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>They filter out echoes from some types of trees.</o0>
        <o1>They can analyze echoes from stationary objects with complex surfaces.</o1>
        <o2>They cannot analyze “jagged” echoes.</o2>
        <o3>They cannot analyze echoes from certain types of small moving objects.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>1</answer>
      <transcript>Now, we’ve tended to underestimate just how sophisticated the abilities of animals that use ultrasound are. In fact, we kind of assumed that they were filtering a lot out—uh, the way a sophisticated radar system can ignore echoes from stationary objects on the ground. Radar does this to remove “ground clutter”—information about, um, hills or buildings that it doesn’t need … but bats—we thought they were filtering out this kind of information because they simply couldn’t analyze it. But it looks as if we were wrong. Recently, there was this experiment with trees and a specific species of bats—a bat called the lesser spear-nosed bat. Now a tree should be a huge acoustical challenge for a bat, right? I mean, it’s got all kinds of surfaces, with different shapes and angles … So, well, the echoes from a tree are going to be a mass of  haotic acoustic reflections, right? Not like the echo from a moth. So, we thought, for a long time, that bats stopped their evaluation at simply “that’s a tree.” Yet, it turns out that-that bats, or at least this particular species, can not only tell that it’s a tree, but can also distinguish between, say, a pine tree and a deciduous tree—like, a maple, or an oak tree … just by their leaves—an-and when I say “leaves,” I mean pine needles, too. </transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>4005026d8c3e4f3ebcf0b5ea8ebbc5f9</id>
    <practiceSet>a2dc026da5a84119be23ddaab151b4fc</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_CHOICE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple -choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>What is the lecture mainly about?</title>
      <media>4Listening - Multiple choice, choose single answer - Q11.tpm</media>
      <delay>5</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>Political events that led to the invention of eyeglasses</o0>
        <o1>A comparison of attitudes toward vision correction in Europe and China</o1>
        <o2>The relationship between the printing press and literacy</o2>
        <o3>An overview of vision correction over time</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>3</answer>
      <transcript>So we’ve been talking about the printing press, how it changed people’s lives, making books more accessible to everyone. More books meant more reading, right? But as you know, not everyone has perfect vision. This increase in literacy, in reading, led to an increase in demand for eyeglasses. And here’s something you probably haven’t thought of: This increased demand impacted societal attitudes towards eyeglasses. But, um, first let me back up a bit and talk about vision correction before the printing press. And what did people with poor vision do—I mean especially those few people who were actually literate—what did they do before glasses were invented? Well, they had different ways of dealing with not seeing well. If you think about it, poor vision wasn’t their only problem. I mean, think about the conditions they lived in: Houses were dark, sometimes there weren’t any windows, candles were the only source of light … So in some places, umm … like ancient Greece, for example, the wealthiest people with poor vision could have someone else read to them. Easy solution if you could afford it. Another solution was something called a reading stone. Around 1000 c.e., European monks would take a piece of clear rock, often quartz, and place it on top of the reading material. The clear rock magnified the letters, making them appear larger. Umm, it’s like what happens when a drop of water falls on something. Whatever’s below the drop of water appears larger, right? Well, the reading stone works in a similar way. </transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>4abd14ce8c414d4abe4506aba9413151</id>
    <practiceSet>a2dc026da5a84119be23ddaab151b4fc</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_SELECT_MISSING_WORD</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording on Reliability. At the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>You will hear a recording on Reliability. At the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>4Listening - Select missing word - Q12.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>only factor</o0>
        <o1>deciding factor</o1>
        <o2>feasible factor</o2>
        <o3>relying factor</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>1</answer>
      <transcript>What’s reliability? Well, a product is reliable if it works the way we expect it to work, if it can go a reasonable amount of time without needing repairs. If a product, a car for example, doesn’t work the way it should and needs repairs too soon, we say it’s unreliable. So product reliability means, basically, the absence of defects or problems that you weren’t expecting. It used to be that when people thought about product quality, they thought mainly about reliability. Today it’s different. People do still care about reliability, don’t get me wrong. It’s just that manufacturing standards are now so high that … take cars for example; today, today’s cars all very reliable. So reliability is important, but it’s not gonna be the deciding factor.</transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>250417b3224d4c9086712873cf52b4cc</id>
    <practiceSet>a2dc026da5a84119be23ddaab151b4fc</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_SELECT_MISSING_WORD</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording on Resolution. At the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>You will hear a recording on Resolution. At the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>4Listening - Select missing word - Q13.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>impacts</o0>
        <o1>effects</o1>
        <o2>medical researches</o2>
        <o3>free camps</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>0</answer>
      <transcript>Pollution from power plants in Pennsylvania and Ohio during 2015 led to the early deaths of more than 4,400 people in America, according to a study by the think tank PSE Healthy Energy and NextGen Climate. Residents closest to the plants near Pittsburgh and Cleveland had the highest premature death rates, but particulates and other pollutants from those power plants increased mortality and morbidity as far away as Maryland, New Jersey and Massachusetts. Poor and disadvantaged communities shouldered most of the burden of this environmental risk, and up to $38 billion in health costs and impacts. </transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>bc03e19a078848118bf95a0837363235</id>
    <practiceSet>a2dc026da5a84119be23ddaab151b4fc</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_HIGHLIGHT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Below is a transcription of the recording. Some words in the transcription differ from what the speaker(s) said. Please click on words that are different.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Myers is not sure what's causing nutrients. One theory is when a plant produces more grain or beans, the amount nutrient get diluted. No matter what the cause, the effects could be really significant, he says, and worst. About two million people around the world already are getting too little iron and zinc in their diets, and it's damaging their growth.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>4Listening - Highlight Incorrect Words- Q14.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <answer>nutrients|amount|worst|million|growth</answer>
      <maxWordCount></maxWordCount>
      <transcript>Myers is not sure what's causing this. One theory is when a plant produces more grain or beans, the trace nutrients get diluted. No matter what the cause, the effects could be really significant, he says, and harmful. About two billion people around the world already are getting too little iron and zinc in their diets, and it's damaging their health.</transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>05a30ab9a93c4c49806db3cfb16afc3f</id>
    <practiceSet>a2dc026da5a84119be23ddaab151b4fc</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_HIGHLIGHT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Below is a transcription of the recording. Some words in the transcription differ from what the speaker(s) said. Please click on words that are different.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Bamboo is widely used as food for polar bears. It is also used for furniture or man-made building products such as flooring and window panes, or blinds. However, bamboo is not used much outside its native grown area. This is mostly because of its round shape. But there are other reasons too. Bamboo, it seems, has an image problem. People think – or have the thinking – that bamboo is a low quality building equipment. "It is viewed in much of the world as well, bamboo is for poor people, and so there's that mentality that we're trying to get over."</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>4Listening - Highlight Incorrect Words- Q15.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <answer>polar|panes|grown|thinking|equipment</answer>
      <maxWordCount></maxWordCount>
      <transcript>Bamboo is widely used as food for panda bears. It is also used for furniture or man-made building products such as flooring and window covers, or blinds. However, bamboo is not used much outside its native growing area. This is mostly because of its round shape. But there are other reasons too. Bamboo, it seems, has an image problem. People think – or have the mentality – that bamboo is a low quality building material. "It is viewed in much of the world as well, bamboo is for poor people, and so there's that mentality that we're trying to get over."</transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>8e96de563d474a7ebabb8094df494fbd</id>
    <practiceSet>a2dc026da5a84119be23ddaab151b4fc</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>4Listening - Write from dictation- Q16.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <answer>I never thought it'd be this easy to hack into your website.</answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>a9a3be77b0c94a249e8029d592bb103b</id>
    <practiceSet>a2dc026da5a84119be23ddaab151b4fc</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>4Listening - Write from dictation- Q17.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <answer>I would appreciate any information you can send to us.</answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>61f6388fb852413ea93c74a543eb1d4c</id>
    <practiceSet>a2dc026da5a84119be23ddaab151b4fc</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>4Listening - Write from dictation- Q18.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <answer>He doesn't have any idea how important this meeting is.</answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>60fea866756d4aad9b4b1bd78dbfdbbc</id>
    <practiceSet>76866578defd49e5be08b21dd869e474</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_WRITE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a short lecture. Write a summary for fellow student who was not present at the lecture. You should write 50-70 words. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points presented in the lecture.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>5Listening - Summarize Spoken Text - Q1.tpm</media>
      <delay>0</delay>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>70</maxWordCount>
      <transcript></transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>3ca49c93ebbb4c3592dd042603d0a1de</id>
    <practiceSet>76866578defd49e5be08b21dd869e474</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_WRITE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a short lecture. Write a summary for fellow student who was not present at the lecture. You should write 50-70 words. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points presented in the lecture.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>5Listening - Summarize Spoken Text - Q2.tpm</media>
      <delay>0</delay>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>70</maxWordCount>
      <transcript>Alf: If we look back to a hundred years ago, we were talking about the Industrial Revolution – countries becoming economic powers, developing their businesses through the use of machines. Now the emphasis has shifted to information, and technology is a tool by which people can gain  that information - be it through computers, on the Internet, or maybe over a mobile phone. And that’s what we’re talking about here: using technology as a tool to get access to information, to find out what’s happening in the world. Gary: And why is this such an important area? Why does it feature in the list of WS Big stories, do you think? Alf: In industrialised countries, we have well-stocked libraries, we have computers in most offices, we have access to the Internet. So a lot of the information we need to do business, to better ourselves through improving our careers is relatively available. In developing countries, that’s much more of a problem. Say you are a farmer in Senegal, and you want to find out what the price is for the mangos or the pineapples that you’re growing. When you come to sell them to the trader, you don’t know what the price of that pineapple is in the capital. You have to take, at face value, what you’re offered for it. But say you had a mobile phone, and that on that mobile phone, you could find out what the price of pineapples was in the capital, that would put you in a much stronger position when it came to selling your goods, and you would get a much better price for your crops. That would make a very big difference to how much money you earned every month.</transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>d6843a595c0243a0ad972a821000357a</id>
    <practiceSet>76866578defd49e5be08b21dd869e474</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_SELECT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting  all the correct responses. You will need to select more than one response.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>Which statements are FALSE as per the lecture:-</title>
      <media>5Listening - Multiple choice, choose multiple answers – Q3.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>OPEC is unlikely to increase the price of oil.</o0>
        <o1>the recession followed with the rise in oil prices in past.</o1>
        <o2>high price of crude is because of insufficient production.</o2>
        <o3>the price of oil is high comparative to last two years.</o3>
        <o4>energy cost has added inflation in oil importing countries.</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>0|2</answer>
      <transcript>Four times already this year OPEC has agreed to boost output. But the price of crude remains stubbornly high - three times the level of less than two years ago. There are signs that energy costs have added to inflation in oil importing countries. Some economists, albeit a minority, are concerned about the historical parallels. In the past when oil prices have risen so sharply, recessions have followed in many oil consuming nations. Nonetheless at this meeting it is not likely that OPEC will increase production again. Its most recent boost came at the beginning of November. The organization prefers to wait and give output changes some time to affect prices. In any event, most analysts think that the high price of crude is not caused by insufficient production. The problem is that stocks of oil products, notably heating oil are low.</transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>2038386f88874d35bc474d81f496de31</id>
    <practiceSet>76866578defd49e5be08b21dd869e474</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_SELECT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting  all the correct responses. You will need to select more than one response.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>Birch tree :-</title>
      <media>5Listening - Multiple choice, choose multiple answers – Q4.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>is grown in dark soil only .</o0>
        <o1>is found in only north eastern part of north america.</o1>
        <o2>Winter Bark is used to make larger containers.</o2>
        <o3>outer layer is thin and is of no use.</o3>
        <o4>is waterproof, used to make utensils.</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>2|4</answer>
      <transcript>Professor  Today we’re going to focus on Iroquois and Huron peoples. Um, they lived in the northeastern Great Lakes region of North America. Now, uh, back then their lives depended on the natural resources of the forest, especially the birch tree. The birch tree can grow in many different types of soils and is prevalent in that area. Now, um, can anyone here describe a birch tree? Male student Umm, they’re tall? And … white? The bark, I mean. Professor Yes, the birch tree has white bark. And this tough protective outer layer of the tree, this, this white bark, is waterproof, and this waterproof quality of the bark, oh, it made it useful for making things like cooking containers, um … a-a variety of utensils. And … i-if you peel birch bark in the winter –– eh, we call it the “winter bark” –– um, another layer, a tougher inner layer of the tree adheres to the bark, producing a stronger material … so the “winter bark” was used for larger utensils and containers. </transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>2038386f88874d35bc474d81f496de32</id>
    <practiceSet>76866578defd49e5be08b21dd869e474</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_FILL_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Type the missing words in each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>The northeastern region is {blank} by rivers and streams, and, uh, the ocean at the coast. The {blank} allowed them to travel over a vast area that-that today would take a few hours to fly over. You see, the Native Americans made canoes of all types, for travel on small streams or on large open ocean waters. For small streams they made narrow, {blank} boats, while, while larger canoes were needed for the ocean. They could travel {blank} the area, only occasionally having to {blank}, to carry the canoe over land a short distance,  to another nearby stream. And since the canoes were so light … this wasn’t a difficult task.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>5Listening - Fill in the blanks – Q5.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <answer>interconnected|canoes|maneuverable|throughout|portage</answer>
      <transcript>Well, like I said, the northeastern region is, uh, interconnected by rivers and streams, and, uh, the ocean at the coast. The canoes allowed them to travel over a vast area that-that today would take a few hours to fly over. You see, the Native Americans made canoes of all types, for travel on small streams or on large open ocean waters. For small streams they made narrow, maneuverable boats, while, while larger canoes were needed for the ocean. They could travel throughout the area, only occasionally having to portage, um to, to, carry the canoe over land a short distance, eh, to another nearby stream. And since the canoes were so light … this wasn’t a difficult task. </transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
    <question>
    <id>04a450f1c7c145238c206ff2100673af</id>
    <practiceSet>76866578defd49e5be08b21dd869e474</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_FILL_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Type the missing words in each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>
        Student:  Hi, Professor {blank}. Do you have a minute?{newline}Professor: Yes, of course, Eric. I think there was {blank} I wanted to talk to you about, too.{newline}Student: Probably my late essay.{newline}Professor: Ah, that must have been it. I thought maybe I’d lost it …{newline}Student: No, I’m sorry. Actually, it was my computer that lost it, the first {blank} of it, and …{newline}Well, anyway, I finally put it in your mailbox yesterday.{newline}Professor:  Oh, and I haven’t checked the mailbox yet today. Well, I’m glad it’s there,  I’ll read it this {blank}.{newline}Student: Well, sorry again. Say, I can send it to you by e-mail too, if you like.{newline}Professor: Great, I’ll be interested to see how it all came out.{newline}Student: Right. Now, uh, I just {blank} some graduate students talking … something about a party for Dean Adams?{newline}Professor:-  Retirement party, yes , all students are invited. Wasn’t there a notice on the {blank} department’s bulletin board?
      </description>       <title></title>
      <media>5Listening - Fill in the blanks – Q6.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <answer>Mason|something|draft|weekend|overheard|anthropology</answer>
      <transcript>Well, like I said, the northeastern region is, uh, interconnected by rivers and streams, and, uh, the ocean at the coast. The canoes allowed them to travel over a vast area that-that today would take a few hours to fly over. You see, the Native Americans made canoes of all types, for travel on small streams or on large open ocean waters. For small streams they made narrow, maneuverable boats, while, while larger canoes were needed for the ocean. They could travel throughout the area, only occasionally having to portage, um to, to, carry the canoe over land a short distance, eh, to another nearby stream. And since the canoes were so light … this wasn’t a difficult task. </transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>b076012026e448b1bc38c43efb990fb5</id>
    <practiceSet>76866578defd49e5be08b21dd869e474</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_HIGHLIGHT_CORRECT_SUMMARY</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Click on paragraph that best relates to the recording.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>5Listening - Highlight Correct Summary – Q7.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>USA responded negatively to the launch of first satellite into orbit Sputnik 1 by Soviet which was unexpected, this is the reason USA made conquest of space a top national priority.</o0>
        <o1>The satellite, named Sputnik 1, transmitted a simple radio signal back to earth for 21 days and remained in orbit for a further 6 months. This marked the beginning of the "space race".</o1>
        <o2>In 1957, Soviet surprised the world with the launch of first satellite into orbit Sputnik 1 and USA responded to this by making the conquest of space a top national priority and this was the beginning of “space race”.</o2>
        <o3>In 1957, Soviet surprised the world with the launch of first satellite into orbit Sputnik 1, which transmitted a simple radio signal back to earth for 21 days and remained in orbit for a further 6 months.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>2</answer>
      <transcript>In 1957, the world was surprised to see the Soviets launch the first satellite into orbit, with most expecting the USA to be the first to do so. The satellite, named Sputnik 1, transmitted a simple radio signal back to earth for 21 days and remained in orbit for a further 6 months. The USA responded to this great technological achievement by making the conquest of space a top national priority. This marked the beginning of the "space race".</transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>39b5fb10746d43c9833a740a1f5f49ea</id>
    <practiceSet>76866578defd49e5be08b21dd869e474</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_HIGHLIGHT_CORRECT_SUMMARY</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Click on paragraph that best relates to the recording.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>5Listening - Highlight Correct Summary – Q8.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>Earthquake struck in mountainous area with 6.2 magnitude and killed 159 people, three quarters of Amatrice was destroyed in the quake except clock tower, a popular pasta festival was scheduled this weekend in Amartice.</o0>
        <o1>As per the clock tower the earth quake struck at 3:36 am and destroyed half of the town, 159 people got injured and many died,  A popular pasta festival was scheduled to occur there this weekend which is cancelled.</o1>
        <o2>Approximately three quarters of the historic town of Amatrice, in the coastal area of Italy, was destroyed in the quake. A popular pasta festival was scheduled to occur there this weekend which is postponed now.</o2>
        <o3>Earthquake struck in mountainous area with 6.2 magnitude and killed 400 people, 1/4th of Amatrice was destroyed in the quake except clock tower, a popular pasta festival was scheduled this weekend in Amartice.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>0</answer>
      <transcript>At least 159 people are dead and up to 400 injured after a 6.2 magnitude earthquake struck in a mountainous area of central Italy this week. Villagers quickly began sifting through the rubble with hands and farm tools to try to find survivors. Approximately three quarters of the historic town of Amatrice was destroyed in the quake. A popular pasta festival was scheduled to occur there this weekend. One of the only things still standing in Amatrice is the clock tower, which stopped at 3:36 am, the exact time the quake struck. </transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>5e7ac9546c4d4f499d5f6445ff61fb70</id>
    <practiceSet>76866578defd49e5be08b21dd869e474</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_CHOICE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple -choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>What element of the plover’s habitat in California was threatened?</title>
      <media>5Listening - Multiple choice, choose single answer – Q9.tpm</media>
      <delay>5</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>The availability of food.</o0>
        <o1>The availability of water.</o1>
        <o2>The safety of nests from human activity.</o2>
        <o3>The protection of nests from predatory birds.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>2</answer>
      <transcript>There’re some key elements that a habitat must contain: food, obviously. Water; and it’s got to have the right climate; and spaces for physical protection. And we saw how important habitat selection is when we looked at habitats where some of these factors are removed, perhaps through habitat destruction. Um, I just read about a shorebird, the plover. The plover lives by the ocean and feeds on small shellfish, insects, and plants. It blends in with the sand, so it’s well camouflaged from predator birds above. But it lays its eggs in shallow depressions in the sand, with very little protection around them. So if there’re people or dogs on the beach, the eggs and fledglings in the nests are really vulnerable. Out in California, where there’s been a lot of human development by the ocean, the plovers are now a threatened species. So, conservationists tried to create a new habitat for them. They made artificial beaches and sandbars in areas inaccessible to people and dogs. And the plover population is up quite a bit in those places.</transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>cc5222f2aaa540b3b3c70389b5bfe975</id>
    <practiceSet>76866578defd49e5be08b21dd869e474</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_CHOICE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple -choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>What is the major concern Steve discusses in the conversation?</title>
      <media>5Listening - Multiple choice, choose single answer – Q10.tpm</media>
      <delay>5</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>He will not be able to finish is degree this year.</o0>
        <o1>He has to do independent study  for both the subjects of History and Shakespeare as nobody is ready to assist him.</o1>
        <o2>Professor is ready to provide one to one discussion but Steve is doubtful whether he will finish work on time.</o2>
        <o3>He is not confident enough that whether he will be able to study independently or not.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>2</answer>
      <transcript>Female student Hey Steve, are you ready for classes to start? Male student Not really. There’s still a big conflict in my course schedule. Female student What’s wrong? Male student This is my last semester, and I’ve still got two required courses left to take in order to finish my literature degree. Female student OK … Male student I have to take both History of the Novel and Shakespeare, or I can’t graduate. Problem is, the two courses meet at the same time! Female student Uh-oh. What’re you gonna do? Male student Well, I talked to the professor who’s gonna teach Shakespeare. He said I could do an independent study to fulfill that requirement. Female student How would that work? Male student I’d read the assigned texts on my own, do all the same assignments, and meet with him when I need to, if I have any questions. Female student Well, that sounds like a good way to fulfill the requirement. Male student Yeah, plus it’d be nice to have one-on-one discussions with the professor. It’s just that … well, working on my own like that … I’m kinda concerned I won’t be able to motivate myself to get the work done on time. It’s easy to put things off when it’s not an actual class, ya know? </transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>2db1f863611e425bb603837facb1c4b1</id>
    <practiceSet>76866578defd49e5be08b21dd869e474</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_SELECT_MISSING_WORD</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording on legal battle between Apple and the FBI. At the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>You will hear a recording on legal battle between Apple and the FBI. At the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>5Listening - Select missing word - Q11.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>fixed services</o0>
        <o1>unravel services</o1>
        <o2>decrypted services</o2>
        <o3>decryption services</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>3</answer>
      <transcript>A legal battle between Apple and the FBI continued on Capitol Hill this week. Apple has refused to comply with a federal judge who ordered the company to help the FBI unlock the iPhone of one of a terrorist. At the congressional hearing, the parties debated modern privacy issues, including encryption and user security. The FBI feels that no company should be able to create a warrant-free space. Apple feels that the government should not be allowed to order a company to provide decryption services.</transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>7f8824b7ec9140db9f0d262fa430d84e</id>
    <practiceSet>76866578defd49e5be08b21dd869e474</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_SELECT_MISSING_WORD</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording on Fashion. At the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>You will hear a recording on Fashion. At the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>5Listening - Select missing word - Q12.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>leaders</o0>
        <o1>individuals</o1>
        <o2>societies</o2>
        <o3>personalities</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>1</answer>
      <transcript>A new clothing store specializing in fashionable, bullet-proof clothing has opened to the general public in the Netherlands. The owner of the shop says that the clothing, which includes suits and ties, is intended for people who work in high-risk locations, such as jewellery stores. He also stated that demand for armored clothing has increased since the recent terrorist attacks in Paris. Last spring, Miguel Cabellero, the Colombian designer of the clothing, caught the world’s attention when he showcased his bullet-proof fashion line at a fashion show in Mexico. Some of Cabellero’s customers include high-profile world leaders. This new store in the Netherlands suggests, however, that the need for bullet-proof protection is no longer limited to high-profile individuals.</transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>3aff87e03f204cbfaa98ee790a920a0c</id>
    <practiceSet>76866578defd49e5be08b21dd869e474</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_HIGHLIGHT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Below is a transcription of the recording. Some words in the transcription differ from what the speaker(s) said. Please click on words that are different.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Europe remains under high alert after terrorists attacked an airport and subway station in Brussels during morning rush hour on Tuesday. Two suicide terrorists killed at least ten people at a departure check-in area at the airport. A third bomb exploded shortly after in a nearby subway killing roughly twenty people. Over two-hundred people were injured in the attacks. A manhunt is presently underway for another suspect who is believed to be on the run. Officers believe Tuesday’s attacks were related to Friday’s arrest of Salah Abdeslam, Europe’s most-wanted fugitive. Abdeslam had been on the run since the Paris terrorist attacks last November. ISIS has taken responsibility for the attacks in Brussels.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>5Listening - Highlight Incorrect Words- Q13.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <answer>terrorists|roughly|presently|Officers|taken</answer>
      <maxWordCount></maxWordCount>
      <transcript>Europe remains under high alert after terrorists attacked an airport and subway station in Brussels during morning rush hour on Tuesday. Two suicide bombers killed at least ten people at a departure check-in area at the airport. A third bomb exploded shortly after in a nearby subway killing approximately twenty people. Over two-hundred people were injured in the attacks. A manhunt is currently underway for another suspect who is believed to be on the run. Officials believe Tuesday’s attacks were related to Friday’s arrest of Salah Abdeslam, Europe’s most-wanted fugitive. Abdeslam had been on the run since the Paris terrorist attacks last November. ISIS has claimed responsibility for the attacks in Brussels.</transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>f74d84bf74c24160911d1c18e59ca43a</id>
    <practiceSet>76866578defd49e5be08b21dd869e474</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_HIGHLIGHT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Below is a transcription of the recording. Some words in the transcription differ from what the speaker(s) said. Please click on words that are different.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>We're going to spend the next few of minutes talking about work and what work meant. In a few minutes, we'll hear from the author of a new book about the Indo American women who found work with NASA and, against all odds, became instrumental to the first manned trip to space. The book is called "Hidden Figures," and my conversation with author Margot Lee Shetterly is coming up. We'll also hear about the performer who gives a voice to working people in song, Bruce Springsteen. He has a new memories, and we'll hear about that. But first, we want to listen to some of the interviews that admired a best-seller and a musical about work more than 30 years ago.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>5Listening - Highlight Incorrect Words- Q14.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <answer>few|meant|Indo|memories|admired|30</answer>
      <maxWordCount></maxWordCount>
      <transcript>We're going to spend the next couple of minutes talking about work and what work means. In a few minutes, we'll hear from the author of a new book about the African-American women who found work with NASA and, against all odds, became instrumental to the first manned trip to space. The book is called "Hidden Figures," and my conversation with author Margot Lee Shetterly is coming up. We'll also hear about the performer who gives a voice to working people in song, Bruce Springsteen. He has a new memoir, and we'll hear about that. But first, we want to listen to some of the interviews that inspired a best-seller and a musical about work more than 40 years ago.</transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>d824737a8a5d476eaddb65bc421d2b05</id>
    <practiceSet>76866578defd49e5be08b21dd869e474</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>5Listening - Write from dictation- Q15.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <answer>After losing a match a team was in an abject mood.</answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>d5e20749d76844cea4eb4540db260e81</id>
    <practiceSet>76866578defd49e5be08b21dd869e474</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>5Listening - Write from dictation- Q16.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <answer>I do not know how to approach a ministry of USA.</answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>e9c4883e0f1c4fdf8fbce54b9b29f624</id>
    <practiceSet>76866578defd49e5be08b21dd869e474</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>5Listening - Write from dictation- Q17.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <answer>His aggressive attitude is the biggest hurdle in his bright future.</answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>b13e9e29a78b4991bc5e0f0be8b0772b</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1f77c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_WRITE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a short lecture. Write a summary for fellow student who was not present at the lecture. You should write 50-70 words. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points presented in the lecture.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>6Listening - Summarize Spoken Text - Q1.tpm</media>
      <delay>0</delay>
      <answer>correct answer is this text here</answer>
      <maxWordCount>70</maxWordCount>
      <transcript>A brand like the ones we heard - McDonalds, Coca Cola, Microsoft – is more than a label, or the name of a product or company. A brand represents a set of values that the company wants the consumer to associate with its products. These values go beyond the need for quality or durability. For example, some companies try and appeal to the youth market and its sense of adventure, whereas others target older consumers who may be more interested in luxury, comfort and prestige. We heard in the report that the biggest brands worldwide are the ones with the highest international brand value. Brand value is becoming increasingly important. It’s about how well regarded a brand is by the consumer or the buyer. It’s measured by looking at the status of the brand in a market and whether people remain loyal - whether they continue to buy the product. The report asks “Is it true that these brands are penetrating deeper into more and more markets around the world?” In other words, are the big American names trying to establish themselves in more countries? </transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>210ada5c789d41cfa860b930732351f9</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1f77c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_WRITE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a short lecture. Write a summary for fellow student who was not present at the lecture. You should write 50-70 words. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points presented in the lecture.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>6Listening - Summarize Spoken Text - Q2.tpm</media>
      <delay>0</delay>
      <answer>correct answer is this text here</answer>
      <maxWordCount>70</maxWordCount>
      <transcript>Plagiarism is using someone else's ideas or someone else's words without acknowledging that they are the source. So it's quite simple to avoid - you avoid it by making sure that when you are writing up your notes from your reading that you do take the correct details, the publication details, and when it comes to the stage of writing up that you make clear in your text which ideas - in fact which quotations - are coming from which source. In terms of how to avoid it it's very simple - the bigger question is why, why should you avoid it. And I'm afraid the answer is and at least in the culture that I work in Britain a student who doesn't acknowledge the source is assumed to be wanting to hide the fact that she or he has used material, in other words that they are trying to present someone else's ideas as their own.</transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>6d2524e6d2f74e9298f715c1cfa3ca82</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1f77c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_SELECT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting  all the correct responses. You will need to select more than one response.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>Which of the following statement is TRUE as per the lecture:-</title>
      <media>6Listening - Multiple choice, choose multiple answers – Q3.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>HP’s value expected to rise in its fourth quarter.</o0>
        <o1>New companies attract investors to invest more.</o1>
        <o2>The value of the stocks is strongly affected by news.</o2>
        <o3>Older companies are known as blue chip stocks in stock market.</o3>
        <o4>Investors put their money in old companies rather than on developments.</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>1|2|3</answer>
      <transcript>We heard the phrase driven up or down. The value of the stocks and shares is strongly affected by news or developments which have an impact on the company’s financial position. For example, the company Hewlett Packard realized it would make less money in its fourth quarter, the last part of the year, than it forecast, or predicted. Forecasts play a key role in the financial world. Investors decide where to put their money based on expectations that companies will perform in a certain way. That can be easier for older, more established companies such as banks - stock markets call them blue chip stocks. But newer industries like computer software or the internet which trade on the Nasdaq are less well-known, they attract investors willing to take more risks. </transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>fd87ac0ae8eb4e6d8d65a044f92c9f37</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1f77c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_SELECT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting  all the correct responses. You will need to select more than one response.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>Which of the following have helped big brands to spread their market?</title>
      <media>6Listening - Multiple choice, choose multiple answers – Q4.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>expansion through global media.</o0>
        <o1>worsened relations between west and china.</o1>
        <o2>influence of western culture.</o2>
        <o3>expansion of communism in eastern Europe.</o3>
        <o4>influence of the technology.</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>0|2</answer>
      <transcript>It’s not just the global media which has helped big brands to spread their appeal. The changing political scene has also played a part. The collapse of Communism in Eastern Europe and the former Soviet Union, and the improvement in relations between the West and China, have meant that vast new markets have opened up for western goods. Big brands have also been able to spread their influence because of the worldwide fascination with certain aspects of western life. Two interviewees from Rahul Sarnaik’s report make this point. Shoba De is a novelist and media commentator based in Bombay in India. Professor Cary Cooper lectures in social psychology at Manchester University in England. They both say that western culture has an “all-pervasive influence” - its influence can be felt everywhere.</transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>82075d0e69874457976878fdec135a4a</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1f77c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_FILL_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Type the missing words in each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>In 1976, Landsmark was a 29-year-old {blank} lawyer. He was a New York transplant working in Boston as an {blank} . He had a background in civil rights work and, at the time, was trying to get more minority contractors into construction. But he hadn't been paying much attention to the {blank} protests, and he had no idea he was about to run directly into one. "I had difficulty finding a parking space in downtown Boston, and I was running a few minutes late for the meeting in city hall. So I was in hurry and perhaps not paying as much {blank} as I might have as I approached a corner, where the young {blank} were coming in the other direction. I did not see them until both they and I were at that corner."</description>
      <title>Limbless Swimmer Links Five Continents</title>
      <media>6Listening - Fill in the blanks – Q5.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <answer>Yale-educated |attorney |||busing |||attention|||demonstrators </answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>b31eac7396704a19a6c55f25b72c8c21</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1f77c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_FILL_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Type the missing words in each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Cloning is copying, it can be applied to many things but here we are talking about copy of a living organism. We are all made from {blank} of cells, and at the centre of each one are the instructions - the blueprint - for building our bodies which is stored in the form of a chemical called {blank}. There are two types of cloning, {blank} cloning where a new baby would be created or therapeutic cloning, that’s about copying just some of the cells. {blank} cloning concentrates on some special cells called stem cells - they’re the powerfully adaptable 'master cells'. Opinion is deeply divided about {blank} or not we should develop this technology. </description>
      <title></title>
      <media>6Listening - Fill in the blanks – Q6.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <answer>billions|DNA|||reproductive|||Therapeutic|||whether</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>e42a3efb89044ecca97a11f90f981f19</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1f77c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_HIGHLIGHT_CORRECT_SUMMARY</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Click on paragraph that best relates to the recording.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>6Listening - Highlight Correct Summary – Q7.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>Research says that money and financial activities are essential, the way technology is developing the contact between countries are growing resulting into the investment in companies with best prospects.</o0>
        <o1>Technology is developing at fast pace, fortunes can be made and lost in minutes. The TV programmes usually include the report on stock markets. Most countries have their own equity or stock and this increases  the value of their shares.</o1>
        <o2>Our world is also becoming a smaller place. Contacts between countries are growing and what happens in one place can have a profound effect around the world. You can hear it when you listen to programmes on business and finance.</o2>
        <o3>You must have probably heard about the Dow Jones in New York, the FTSE in London, Hong Kong’s index is called the Hang Seng and in Japan it’s the Nikkei, these companies are the powerful indices where the investors spend their money.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>0</answer>
      <transcript>Money and financial activity are essential to our world. Technology and communication are now developing at such a fast pace, fortunes can be made and lost in minutes. Our world is also becoming a smaller place. Contacts between countries are growing and what happens in one place can have a profound effect around the world. That’s especially true of money. You can hear it when you listen to programmes on business and finance. They usually include reports on what’s happening on the most important stock markets or stock exchanges. These are places where companies can raise money, by selling a share of their business. Investors try to buy shares in companies with the best prospects. The more profitable the firm, the more the value of the shares will increase. Shareholders are effectively buying a piece of the company, or equity. Most countries have their own equity or stock and they list their most important companies, and the value of their shares, on a list or index. The names of the most powerful indices are famous – you’ve probably heard about the Dow Jones in New York, the FTSE in London, Hong Kong’s index is called the Hang Seng and in Japan it’s the Nikkei. </transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>1a0cedc96667440ba6d78e6bd51fcceb</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1f77c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_HIGHLIGHT_CORRECT_SUMMARY</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Click on paragraph that best relates to the recording.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>6Listening - Highlight Correct Summary – Q8.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>Since last 100 years there is an increase in global temperature and is making difficult for humans and other species to survive on the earth. Earth’s average temperature is now the highest since scientists began measuring it 600 years ago. United States and other industrialized nations have agreed to take a needed action to control the temperature.</o0>
        <o1>In November 2000, delegates from more than 150 countries gathered in The Hague in the Netherlands to discuss how to combat global warming.  Some them agreed on the need for action based on mounting scientific evidence that are affecting the humans. As. Since the middle of the 19th century, global temperatures have risen by 0.5 degrees Celsius.</o1>
        <o2>Research says that increase in global warming is causing chaotic weather, there is an increase in global temperature. Scientists believe that human activities have caused the change and many forms of life on our planet may not survive. Delegates who gathered in The Hague agreed on the need for action based on mounting scientific evidence that humans are to blame.</o2>
        <o3>Global warming is the steady increase in the earth’s temperature. More and more scientists believe that is what’s causing chaotic weather around the world. Earth’s average temperature is now the highest since scientists began measuring it 600 years ago. Since the middle of the 19th century, global temperatures have risen by 0.5 degrees Celsius.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>2</answer>
      <transcript>Global warming is the steady increase in the earth’s temperature. More and more scientists believe that is what’s causing chaotic weather around the world – the hurricanes, droughts, storms, high tides that are striking more and more countries. The earth has never been hotter. Its average temperature is now the highest since scientists began measuring it 600 years ago. Since the middle of the 19th century, global temperatures have risen by 0.5 degrees Celsius. That may not sound like much but the difference between our temperature and an ice age is only about six degrees. The earth has seen major changes in climate before. But most scientists agree this period is different. Many believe the present changes are caused by our own activities, by the way we live. If that doesn’t change, many forms of life on our planet may not survive. In November 2000, delegates from more than 150 countries gathered in The Hague in the Netherlands to discuss how to combat global warming. There was great disagreement, mainly between the United States and other industrialized nations, about what could and should be done. But everyone agreed on the need for action based on mounting scientific evidence that humans are to blame. </transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>ae40bcb3204442e2b36bb47b29d92340</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1f77c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_CHOICE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple -choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>As per the conversation:-</title>
      <media>6Listening - Multiple choice, choose single answer – Q9.tpm</media>
      <delay>5</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>Fracking  has effected oil and gas business badly in US.</o0>
        <o1>As per the scientific data, fracking has contaminated soil.</o1>
        <o2>Fracking is effecting human’s health as it effects soil.</o2>
        <o3>Fracking is resulting into air and water pollution.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>2</answer>
      <transcript>Fracking is among the technologies that reinvigorated the oil and gas business in the U.S. in recent years. But fracking also launched a movement of activists concerned about how this intensive form of drilling affects people and the environment. New York Governor Andrew Cuomo acknowledged the contentious debate over fracking at a Cabinet meeting Wednesday, saying he's not qualified to decide the issue. GOVERNOR ANDREW CUOMO: I'm a lawyer. I'm not a doctor. I'm not an environmentalist. I'm not a scientist. So let's bring the emotion down, and let's ask the qualified experts what their opinion is. BRADY: Cuomo deferred to his environmental and health commissioners, who are recommending a ban on fracking. Acting Commissioner of Health Howard Zucker says there is not enough scientific data yet to say with certainty that fracking is safe. And he says there are red flags raised in some studies on air and water pollution. Zucker says there's also a big gap in data about how drilling and fracking affects soil. HOWARD ZUCKER: There are no relevant studies looking at soil contamination and human health effects. And yet, we grow our fruits and vegetables in that soil. Our cows graze on the grass in that soil, and way closer to our home, our children play there as well. BRADY: Zucker says he asked himself if he would want to live in a community with fracking. ZUCKER: After looking at the plethora of reports, as you see behind me and others that I have in my office, my answer is no. </transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>fb3ab431aef445a1826f718680b40c07</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1f77c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_CHOICE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple -choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>Globalization is:-</title>
      <media>6Listening - Multiple choice, choose single answer – Q10.tpm</media>
      <delay>5</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>economic integration.</o0>
        <o1>international trade.</o1>
        <o2>cinstant communication.</o2>
        <o3>effect of one place on another</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>3</answer>
      <transcript>“Globalisation” has become a kind of catch-all phrase that’s used to describe a process of seemingly ever-greater economic integration – a process in which economic events in one place pretty soon have huge implications almost everywhere else. So there’s lots of different aspects to it. From the consumers’ point of view, increasingly people think in terms of global brands: NIKE sells its “Sneakers” throughout the world, Coca-cola is bought in many different countries of the world. That’s one aspect of it. Then, of course, there’s the sort of… the economists are focused on things like the enormously increased volumes of international trade. And many commentators associate that with this nebulous process of globalisation. And then, of course, there’s just the increasing pace of technological change – the fact that using modern communications via the internet you have instant communications everywhere; and, of course, using jet travel, you can travel from one place to another all over the world. So, increasingly, what happens in one place seems to affect almost everywhere else … and that’s what’s clubbed together as “globalisation”. </transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>f8fb283d25fd4fd89c6850eff812a327</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1f77c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_SELECT_MISSING_WORD</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording on OPEC. At the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>6Listening - Select missing word - Q11.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>to effect economy.</o0>
        <o1>to reduce prices.</o1>
        <o2>to blame.</o2>
        <o3>to control consumption.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>2</answer>
      <transcript>In the last few months of the year 2000, oil was in the headlines again. Protests swept across Europe as truck drivers, farmers, and thousands of other people demonstrated against high oil prices. It was an unprecedented show of strength across the region – a call for governments to reduce high taxes on oil to help bring the prices down. But governments argued the oil producers or OPEC was to blame.</transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>e2302b8985404778b22cb13018f745eb</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1f77c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_SELECT_MISSING_WORD</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording on Library. At the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>6Listening - Select missing word - Q12.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>in which library</o0>
        <o1>on which shelf</o1>
        <o2>in which cupboard</o2>
        <o3>in which category</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>1</answer>
      <transcript>Different universities have different systems to help you locate their books. The principle is the same. You’ll need to do a search: using the title of the book, or by the author’s name, or, perhaps by the subject area. If you’re lucky, your search will result in a sequence of letters and numbers. This classmark is a code that will tell you where to find the book – in which building, in which room, on which shelf.</transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>f1b6dc5c258640c5a395dfa87f052cb4</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1f77c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_HIGHLIGHT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Below is a transcription of the recording. Some words in the transcription differ from what the speaker(s) said. Please click on words that are different.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>The world is all too full of justice. People’s rights are not being respected. And these violations are getting more and more coverage in the society. Our rights are being refused despite international laws meant to protect us – laws, traditions, charters on human rights have existed for centuries but the injustice still exist.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>6Listening - Highlight Incorrect Words- Q13.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <answer>justice|society|refused|traditions|injustice</answer>
      <maxWordCount></maxWordCount>
      <transcript>The world is all too full of injustice. People’s rights are not being respected. And these violations are getting more and more coverage in the media. Our rights are being denied despite international laws meant to protect us – laws, conventions, charters on human rights have existed for centuries but the abuses still exist.</transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>7880d631d3764759a6b448d8d3146bd2</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1f77c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_HIGHLIGHT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Below is a transcription of the recording. Some words in the transcription differ from what the speaker(s) said. Please click on words that are different.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>You find that academic writing becomes difficult with practice. And you find that the more academic reading you do, the more familiar you become with the difference of stylish conventions used by academics in your area, the conventions you need to follow. This may be true for any student in any country, as Tony Lynch pointed out.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>6Listening - Highlight Incorrect Words- Q14.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <answer>difficult|difference|area|may|pointed</answer>
      <maxWordCount></maxWordCount>
      <transcript>You find that academic writing becomes difficult with practice. And you find that the more academic reading you do, the more familiar you become with the difference of stylish conventions used by academics in your area, the conventions you need to follow. This may be true for any student in any country, as Tony Lynch pointed out.</transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>e5573087ba624ff39271465959117697</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1f77c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>6Listening - Write from dictation- Q15.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <answer>Meena has a very charismatic personality.</answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>a546ef458da44397a09d2bedf4984bbf</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1f77c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>6Listening - Write from dictation- Q16.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <answer>We should always keep upbeat attitude.</answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>2f162493dbd64bd0842055d166075dfa</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1f77c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>6Listening - Write from dictation- Q17.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <answer>Sometimes I have a craving for coffee.</answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>6f53465caa1744f5bbb45ffbede96488</id>
    <practiceSet>fc23cb5566904f8a98ee2bbf17a08f47</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_WRITE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a short lecture. Write a summary for fellow student who was not present at the lecture. You should write 50-70 words. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points presented in the lecture.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>7Listening - Summarize Spoken Text - Q1.tpm</media>
      <delay>0</delay>
      <answer>correct answer is this text here</answer>
      <maxWordCount>70</maxWordCount>
      <transcript>Immigration is a crucial, yet controversial global issue, particularly with the refugee crisis currently occurring in the Middle East and Europe, and the highly politicized immigration debates being held in the United States, Japan, and other developed nations. So, what is immigration? Immigration refers to the movement of people from one country, the country of origin, to another country, the host country, where they settle down and live. According to the most recent statistics from the World Bank, over 247 million people, or 3.4 percent of the world population, are immigrants. Most of these people have moved from developing nations, such as India, Mexico, the Philippines, to developed ones, such as the United States, Germany, and France. However, this isn’t always the case. Millions of people have moved from developing to developing countries, such as from Bangladesh to India, or from developed to developed countries, such as from the United Kingdom to Australia. </transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>bf13ffaddbd645a1a5d952fd353cee74</id>
    <practiceSet>fc23cb5566904f8a98ee2bbf17a08f47</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_WRITE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a short lecture. Write a summary for fellow student who was not present at the lecture. You should write 50-70 words. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points presented in the lecture.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>7Listening - Summarize Spoken Text - Q2.tpm</media>
      <delay>0</delay>
      <answer>correct answer is this text here</answer>
      <maxWordCount>70</maxWordCount>
      <transcript>A good manager understands that a hardworking, enthusiastic staff is very  important. In fact, we could say it is essential . . . absolutely essential. All of the employees need to work together. They need to work as a team to make the company successful. And, of course, part of feeling like a team is feeling that what each person does and says is important. Well, as in most work situations, we have a problem here with communication. That is, most managers do not want to hear people complain, and most employees are afraid to come right out and say what they feel. They usually won’t say what they like or don’t like! They may complain to  each other during lunch or after work, but they do not complain directly to the manager.  It is important, however, for a manager to find out if he or she is doing a good job. One way to do this is to give employees a chance to talk. Employees need an opportunity to say what is wrong, what they don’t like about the work situation, and what they would change to make their work better. However, most employees afraid to say what they feel. This is why a manager needs to figure out a safe way for people to talk. By safe, I mean a way to talk where people aren’t afraid something will happen to them if they tell the truth. It has to be safe, or else people just won’t say. </transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>af7f82acaa9543a0bcaca93064f4cbed</id>
    <practiceSet>fc23cb5566904f8a98ee2bbf17a08f47</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_SELECT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting  all the correct responses. You will need to select more than one response.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>Why as per Human Resources, employees should have more than 7 hours sleep?</title>
      <media>7Listening - Multiple choice, choose multiple answers – Q3.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>It will increase the productivity of the company.</o0>
        <o1>It will help them to increase their salary.</o1>
        <o2>It will reduce the economy lose by $63.2 billion.</o2>
        <o3>It will improve employee’s performance.</o3>
        <o4>It will give extra income of $2,280 to one worker.</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>0|3</answer>
      <transcript>Human resources officials say employees will work better if they have slept well. They add that a workforce that is more awake and alert will mean the company will perform better. Staff can either record their sleep automatically using a wrist monitor that connects to Aetna's computers, or manually record how long they have slept every night. There are a number of studies that warn that not sleeping enough can affect our ability to do our job. The American Academy of Sleep Medicine said that the average worker in the USA loses 11.3 working days of productivity a year because of not getting enough sleep. This costs companies about $2,280 for one worker. It estimates that the US economy loses $63.2 billion a year because workers do not sleep more than seven hours a night. </transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>c4097ef2ca6c4acbb93037c73636edb3</id>
    <practiceSet>fc23cb5566904f8a98ee2bbf17a08f47</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_SELECT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting  all the correct responses. You will need to select more than one response.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>As per the lecture:-</title>
      <media>7Listening - Multiple choice, choose multiple answers – Q4.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>Inequality between income and wealth has reduced.</o0>
        <o1>The reasons behind Great recession still exist.</o1>
        <o2>Derivatives have increased since 2007.</o2>
        <o3>Modern banking has created the best system.</o3>
        <o4>Debts have increased instead of reducing.</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>1|2</answer>
      <transcript>I guess going on seven years now since the Great Crash of 2008 and according to the cheerful headlines we are well on the way to recovery. Auto sales are booming, house sales are reasonable and employment is back above its pre-recessionary levels. But if we dig deeper we note that everything that was either the cause of or which exasperated the Great Recession remain with us today. For instance, too-big-to-fail and even to-big-to-jail banks are even bigger. Sovereign debts are higher. In many cases startlingly so. Derivatives are a hundred trillion dollars higher than they were in 2007. Income and wealth inequality are vastly higher today than six years ago. So in short, everything that should have gotten smaller actually got bigger. Now, to students of the so called modern system of banking, which actually began some hundred years ago with the birth of the Federal Reserve, none of this is really surprising. While peddled as the best system for creating wealth fairly and equitably, modern banking is nothing of the sort. It’s actually a system for concentrating power and wealth while providing passable air cover for the idea that it’s doing something more equitable and noble than that.</transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>a119ecce0d1f40c0abde7725e3e02510</id>
    <practiceSet>fc23cb5566904f8a98ee2bbf17a08f47</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_FILL_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Type the missing words in each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>In many {blank} health discussions, people believe in and {blank} the idea that we can simply digitize the data, {blank} transmit it, send it to the cloud, and in the cloud, we can extract meaningful information for interpretation. And indeed, you can do all of that, if you're not worried about some of the energy {blank} .Think about Jane for a moment. She doesn't live in Palo Alto, nor does she live in Beverly Hills. What that means is, we have to be mindful about her data plan and how much it would cost for her to be sending out a {blank} stream of data.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>7Listening - Fill in the blanks – Q5.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <answer>digital |embrace |||wirelessly |||challenges|||continuous </answer>
      <transcript>In many digital health discussions, people believe in and embrace the idea that we can simply digitize the data, wirelessly transmit it, send it to the cloud, and in the cloud, we can extract meaningful information for interpretation. And indeed, you can do all of that, if you're not worried about some of the energy challenges. Think about Jane for a moment. She doesn't live in Palo Alto, nor does she live in Beverly Hills. What that means is, we have to be mindful about her data plan and how much it would cost for her to be sending out a continuous stream of data.</transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>baf8b34490864f8a85f9e369017ccc1d</id>
    <practiceSet>fc23cb5566904f8a98ee2bbf17a08f47</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_FILL_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Type the missing words in each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>{blank}found that on Google, women are less likely than men to be shown job ads for high-paying jobs. And searching for African-American names is more likely to bring up ads suggesting criminal history, even when there is none. Such hidden {blank} and black-box algorithms that researchers uncover sometimes but sometimes we don't know, can have life-altering {blank}. In Wisconsin, a defendant was sentenced to six years in prison for evading the police. You may not know this, but {blank} are increasingly used in parole and sentencing decisions. He wanted to know: How is this score calculated? It's a commercial black box. The company refused to have its algorithm be challenged in open court. But ProPublica, an {blank} nonprofit, audited that very algorithm with what public data they could find, and found that its outcomes were biased and its {blank} power was dismal, barely better than chance, and it was wrongly labeling black defendants as future criminals at twice the rate of white criminals and white {blank}.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>7Listening - Fill in the blanks – Q6.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <answer>Researchers|biases|||consequences|||algorithms|||investigative|||predictive|||defendants</answer>
      <transcript>Researchers found that on Google, women are less likely than men to be shown job ads for high-paying jobs. And searching for African-American names is more likely to bring up ads suggesting criminal history, even when there is none. Such hidden biases and black-box algorithms that researchers uncover sometimes but sometimes we don't know, can have life-altering consequences. In Wisconsin, a defendant was sentenced to six years in prison for evading the police. You may not know this, but algorithms are increasingly used in parole and sentencing decisions. He wanted to know: How is this score calculated? It's a commercial black box. The company refused to have its algorithm be challenged in open court. But ProPublica, an investigative nonprofit, audited that very algorithm with what public data they could find, and found that its outcomes were biased and its predictive power was dismal, barely better than chance, and it was wrongly labeling black defendants as future criminals at twice the rate of white criminals and white defendants. </transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>324d94a1d797474abd39579dd80fa685</id>
    <practiceSet>fc23cb5566904f8a98ee2bbf17a08f47</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_HIGHLIGHT_CORRECT_SUMMARY</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Click on paragraph that best relates to the recording.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>7Listening - Highlight Correct Summary – Q7.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>Verbs come in a mathematical wrapping has been proved my speaker and Erez in one research, it shows a huge difference in usage of language used at the time of the King of England, Alfred The Great and King of Hip Hop Jay-Z.</o0>
        <o1>The usage of grammar in a language has changed overtime, there is a simple mathematical pattern in the usage of verbs which has been followed by the speaker and his collaborator Erez and had been explained by giving the example of the King of England, Alfred The Great and King of Hip Hop Jay-Z.</o1>
        <o2>Mathematics has generated considerable insight in other subjects, which compels you to have a belief in history which cannot be changed, it is clear from the example given of the King of England, Alfred The Great and King of Hip Hop Jay-Z.</o2>
        <o3>Erez and the speaker did a research on irregular verbs used from 12 centuries in English language which has a powerful historical force which can been seen at the time of  the King of England, Alfred The Great and King of Hip Hop Jay-Z.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>1</answer>
      <transcript>So it turns out that mathematics is a very powerful language. It has generated considerable insight in physics, in biology and economics, but not that much in the humanities and in history. I think there's a belief that it's just impossible, that you cannot quantify the doings of mankind, that you cannot measure history. But I don't think that's right. I want to show you a couple of examples why. So my collaborator Erez and I were considering the following fact: that two kings separated by centuries will speak a very different language. That's a powerful historical force. So the king of England, Alfred the Great, will use a vocabulary and grammar that is quite different from the king of hip hop, Jay-Z.(Laughter) Now it's just the way it is. Language changes over time, and it's a powerful force. So Erez and I wanted to know more about that. So we paid attention to a particular grammatical rule, past-tense conjugation. So you just add "ed" to a verb at the end to signify the past. "Today I walk. Yesterday I walked." But some verbs are irregular. "Yesterday I thought." Now what's interesting about that is irregular verbs between Alfred and Jay-Z have become more regular. Like the verb "to wed" that you see here has become regular. So Erez and I followed the fate of over 100 irregular verbs through 12 centuries of English language, and we saw that there's actually a very simple mathematical pattern that captures this complex historical change, namely, if a verb is 100 times more frequent than another, it regularizes 10 times slower. That's a piece of history, but it comes in a mathematical wrapping. </transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>484f0ef7c216466a9c342627bfcaa04f</id>
    <practiceSet>fc23cb5566904f8a98ee2bbf17a08f47</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_HIGHLIGHT_CORRECT_SUMMARY</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Click on paragraph that best relates to the recording.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>7Listening - Highlight Correct Summary – Q8.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>We would like to deal with the sophistication of the modern world through politics, and sadly you can have humane moral principles, being ignorant of history leaves behind in politics. For instance the Spanish didn't sink the battleship Maine, the Lusitania was not an innocent vessel but was loaded with munitions, the North Vietnamese did not attack the Seventh Fleet, and, of course, Saddam Hussein hated al Qaeda.</o0>
        <o1>Young Americans are not aware about the history, literature of the foreign land, they do not know that, Saddam Hussein hated al Qaeda and had nothing to do with it, and yet the administration convinced 45 percent of the people that they were brothers in arms, when he would hang one from the nearest lamppost.</o1>
        <o2>We've noticed, in a trend among young Americans, that they read less history and less literature and less material about foreign lands, and they're essentially a historical. They live in the bubble of the present. They don't know the Korean War from the war in Vietnam. They don't know who was an ally of America in World War II. </o2>
        <o3>Without knowing the history of any country it’s not possible to do politics, we haven’t made progress on all fronts but still 20th century has shown enormous cognitive reserves in ordinary people that we have now realized. , and the aristocracy was convinced that the average person couldn't make it, that they could never share their mindset or their cognitive abilities.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>3</answer>
      <transcript>Now, I should say one thing that's very disheartening. We haven't made progress on all fronts. One of the ways in which we would like to deal with the sophistication of the modern world is through politics, and sadly you can have humane moral principles, you can classify, you can use logic on abstractions, and if you're ignorant of history and of other countries, you can't do politics. We've noticed, in a trend among young Americans, that they read less history and less literature and less material about foreign lands, and they're essentially a historical. They live in the bubble of the present. They don't know the Korean War from the war in Vietnam. They don't know who was an ally of America in World War II. Think how different America would be if every American knew that this is the fifth time Western armies have gone to Afghanistan to put its house in order, and if they had some idea of exactly what had happened on those four previous occasions. (Laughter) And that is, they had barely left, and there wasn't a trace in the sand. Or imagine how different things would be if most Americans knew that we had been lied into four of our last six wars. You know, the Spanish didn't sink the battleship Maine, the Lusitania was not an innocent vessel but was loaded with munitions, the North Vietnamese did not attack the Seventh Fleet, and, of course, Saddam Hussein hated al Qaeda and had nothing to do with it, and yet the administration convinced 45 percent of the people that they were brothers in arms, when he would hang one from the nearest lamppost. But I don't want to end on a pessimistic note. The 20th century has shown enormous cognitive reserves in ordinary people that we have now realized, and the aristocracy was convinced that the average person couldn't make it, that they could never share their mindset or their cognitive abilities. </transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>9c02d8b4d16c436aae0b7f4de70b8739</id>
    <practiceSet>fc23cb5566904f8a98ee2bbf17a08f47</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_CHOICE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple -choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>As per the lecture, what kind of raw material was found to produce nanocellulose?</title>
      <media>7Listening - Multiple choice, choose single answer – Q9.tpm</media>
      <delay>5</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>bark of trees.</o0>
        <o1>sludge of paper industry.</o1>
        <o2>cotton fibers.</o2>
        <o3>fabrics from industries.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>1</answer>
      <transcript>So we at the Hebrew University, together with our partners in Sweden, decided to focus on the development of an industrial-scale process to produce this nanocellulose. And, of course, we didn't want to cut trees. So we were looking for another source of raw material, and we found one -- in fact, the sludge of the paper industry. The reason: there is a lot of it. Europe alone produces 11 million tons of that material annually. It's the equivalent of a mountain three kilometers high, sitting on a soccer field. And we produce this mountain every year. So for everybody, it's an environmental problem, and for us, it's a gold mine. So now, we are actually producing, on an industrial scale in Israel, nanocellulose, and very soon, in Sweden. We can do a lot of things with the material. For example, we have shown that by adding only a small percent of nano cellulose into cotton fibers, the same as my shirt is made of, it increases its strength dramatically. So this can be used for making amazing things, like super-fabrics for industrial and medical applications. </transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>4ced72ea0a1045cd8c67b4735f90f7b1</id>
    <practiceSet>fc23cb5566904f8a98ee2bbf17a08f47</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_CHOICE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple -choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>What changes is speaker expecting in future?</title>
      <media>7Listening - Multiple choice, choose single answer – Q10.tpm</media>
      <delay>5</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>production of resilin.</o0>
        <o1>search ideas from old books.</o1>
        <o2>construction of nanobio buildings.</o2>
        <o3>heart donors.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>2</answer>
      <transcript>So what's for the future? In the future, we believe we'll be able to make many nanobio building blocks that nature provided for us -- collagen, nanocellulose, resilin and many more. And that will enable us to make better machines perform better, even the heart. Now, this heart is not going to be the same as we can get from a donor. It will be better. It actually will perform better and will last longer. My friend Zion Suliman once told me a smart sentence. He said, "If you want a new idea, you should open an old book." And I'm going to say that the book was written. It was written over three billion years of evolution. And the text is the DNA of life. All we have to do is read this text, embrace nature's gift to us and start our progress from here.</transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>2f6d70fbf45c4afd8f62c2b6f312a1ed</id>
    <practiceSet>fc23cb5566904f8a98ee2bbf17a08f47</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_SELECT_MISSING_WORD</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording on medical implants. At the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>7Listening - Select missing word - Q11.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>wonderful</o0>
        <o1>disgusting</o1>
        <o2>amazing</o2>
        <o3>difficult</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>2</answer>
      <transcript>You crush the leaves, you get the juice that contains the collagen. We concentrate the protein, transfer the protein to clean rooms for the final purification, and the end result is a collagen identical to what we have in our body -- untouched, brand new and from which we make different medical implants: bone void fillers, for example, for severe bone fractures, spinal fusion. And more recently, even, we've been able to launch into the market here in Europe a flow able gel that is used for diabetic foot ulcers, that is now approved for use in the clinic. This is not science fiction. This is happening now. We are using plants to make medical implants for replacement parts for human beings. In fact, more recently, we've been able to make collagen fibers which are six times stronger than the Achilles tendon. That's amazing. </transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>ac532dd3b55346db9ae13228a6372159</id>
    <practiceSet>fc23cb5566904f8a98ee2bbf17a08f47</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_SELECT_MISSING_WORD</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording on Climate Change. At the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>7Listening - Select missing word - Q12.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>surroundings</o0>
        <o1>environment</o1>
        <o2>ecosystem</o2>
        <o3>nature</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>3</answer>
      <transcript>We face some pretty grim environmental challenges on this planet. Climate change is among them. There's others too: habitat loss is my favorite thing to freak out about in the middle of the night. But in order to solve them, we need people -- smart, dedicated people -- who care about nature. And the only way we're going to raise up a generation of people who care about nature is by letting them touch nature. I have a Fort Theory of Ecology, Fort Theory of Conservation. Every ecologist I know, every conservation biologist I know, every conservation professional I know, built forts when they were kids. If we have a generation that doesn't know how to build a fort, we'll have a generation that doesn't know how to care about nature.</transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>9d60e725ad174105a61574bcc5cf8118</id>
    <practiceSet>fc23cb5566904f8a98ee2bbf17a08f47</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_HIGHLIGHT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Below is a transcription of the recording. Some words in the transcription differ from what the speaker(s) said. Please click on words that are different.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>When Satya Nadella became the CEO of Microsoft in February 2014, he undertook on an ambitious transformation journey to start the company to compete in a mobile-first, cloud-first world. This consisted changes to strategy, the organization and very importantly, the culture. Microsoft's culture at the time was one of silos and internal competition -- not exactly conducive to learning. Nadella took this head-on. He led his leadership around his vision for a living, learning culture, shifting from a one mindset, where your role was to show up as the smartest person in the room, to a growth mindset, where your role was to listen, to learn and to bring out the best in people. Well, early days, Microsoft employees already noticed this shift in the culture -- clear example of Microsoft putting people first.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>7Listening - Highlight Incorrect Words- Q13.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <answer>undertook|start|consisted|led|one|example</answer>
      <maxWordCount></maxWordCount>
      <transcript>When Satya Nadella became the CEO of Microsoft in February 2014, he embarked on an ambitious transformation journey to prepare the company to compete in a mobile-first, cloud-first world. This included changes to strategy, the organization and very importantly, the culture. Microsoft's culture at the time was one of silos and internal competition -- not exactly conducive to learning. Nadella took this head-on. He rallied his leadership around his vision for a living, learning culture, shifting from a fixed mindset, where your role was to show up as the smartest person in the room, to a growth mindset, where your role was to listen, to learn and to bring out the best in people. Well, early days, Microsoft employees already noticed this shift in the culture -- clear evidence of Microsoft putting people first.</transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>9a15c0dc66694ce1bdfd4e9d681afa78</id>
    <practiceSet>fc23cb5566904f8a98ee2bbf17a08f47</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_HIGHLIGHT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Below is a transcription of the recording. Some words in the transcription differ from what the speaker(s) said. Please click on words that are different.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>In the era of "always-on" transformation, companies are always going to be transforming. But doing so does not have to be exhausting. We own it to ourselves, to our organizations and to society more widely to boldly transform our approach to transformation. To do that, we need to start engaging people first.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>7Listening - Highlight Incorrect Words- Q14.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <answer>companies|own|widely|engaging</answer>
      <maxWordCount></maxWordCount>
      <transcript>In the era of "always-on" transformation, organizations are always going to be transforming. But doing so does not have to be exhausting. We owe it to ourselves, to our organizations and to society more broadly to boldly transform our approach to transformation. To do that, we need to start putting people first.</transcript>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>5babbb39aabc45f2940659892536db65</id>
    <practiceSet>fc23cb5566904f8a98ee2bbf17a08f47</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>7Listening - Write from dictation- Q15.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <answer>Our basketball team is the best in the league.</answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>632264b38ddd4e1f85c30aeb4fa32256</id>
    <practiceSet>fc23cb5566904f8a98ee2bbf17a08f47</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>7Listening - Write from dictation- Q16.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <answer>They have some fabulous players, but one of the key reasons is their head coach, Steve Kerr, is an inclusive leader. </answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>7714be02f6ee45469bcafbd96f44943d</id>
    <practiceSet>fc23cb5566904f8a98ee2bbf17a08f47</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>7Listening - Write from dictation- Q17.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <answer>The Warriors won the game and went on to win the championship.</answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
</questions>