<?xml version = "1.0"?>
<questions>
  <!--TEST 1-->
  <question>
  <id>1b3f96231b9f40e5bdc268fc16f98a76</id>
  <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Avoiding exercise could be bad for our mental health too, pushing us into the pit of depression and causing {blank} at work. Management experts have discovered that employees who {blank} in physical activity are less likely to experience a {blank} of their mental health, including {blank} of burnout and depression.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>symptoms</o0>
        <o1>expertise</o1>
        <o2>impulse</o2>
        <o3>burnout</o3>
        <o4>boost</o4>
        <o5>result</o5>
        <o6>engage</o6>
        <o7>deterioration</o7>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>3|6|7|0</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>4224290345bf427781fae088e9fabdfa</id>
  <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Some of the first clashes of the war {blank} . British, French, and German colonial forces in Africa. On 6-7 August, French and British troops invaded the German protectorate of Togoland and Kamerun. On 10 August, German forces in South-West Africa {blank} South Africa; sporadic and fierce fighting {blank} . for the rest of the war. The German colonial forces in German East Africa, led by Colonel Paul von Lettow-Vorbeck, fought a guerilla warfare campaign during World War I and only two weeks after the armistice took {blank} in Europe.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>involve</o0>
        <o1>involved</o1>
        <o2>continued</o2>
        <o3>surrendered</o3>
        <o4>attacked</o4>
        <o5>defer</o5>
        <o6>effect</o6>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>1|4|2|6</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>3b12467113414cb48b00b07e7d7fcf60</id>
  <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Television programming today can be a powerful {blank} factor in developing value systems and shaping behaviours of individuals. Television {blank} people into the programs to believe that they are important and mean something. Television gives people the wrong impression about how life should be lived. The {blank} of the programs creates a sense of lifestyle that the average viewers {blank} for themselves.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>unrealistic</o0>
        <o1>abjure</o1>
        <o2>unsetting</o2>
        <o3>crave</o3>
        <o4>pragmatic</o4>
        <o5>calming</o5>
        <o6>hooks</o6>
        <o7>dissuade</o7>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>2|6|0|3</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>23a9486551b54edd9c4398e150899979</id>
  <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Since the dawn of human civilization, human beings have consistently been {blank} their dream faculty. In the Aryan society too, the dreams {blank} the human beings. The coming of Christianity itself was a great event in the history of mankind. The crucifixion of Jesus was seen in the dreams of the chosen and {blank} who had fathomless faith in Jesus, they had been informed in the dream that there would be a resurrection of Jesus and his sacrifice for the sins of humanity would not go {blank} .</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>mystified</o0>
        <o1>remembering</o1>
        <o2>blessed</o2>
        <o3>interpreting</o3>
        <o4>believed</o4>
        <o5>wasted</o5>
        <o6>ignore</o6>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>3|0|2|5</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>67f368bce8dc47fbbd4f7adc8aa455ba</id>
  <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>A NEW Scitech is likely to be {blank} in the Perth Cultural Centre in Northbridge, according to Premier Colin Barnett.
The Premier confirmed the State Government was {blank} at a new site for Scitech in the Perth Cultural Centre during budget estimate hearings on Tuesday.
Mr Barnett said the science and {blank} centre would likely be built near the new state museum sometime in the “early 2020s”.
Scitech’s current lease at its West Perth location will expire in 2021.
In the lead up to the 2013 state election, the Liberal Party {blank} plans to relocate Scitech to Burswood to be the part of a new entertainment precinct alongside the Perth Stadium hose plans were scrapped in 2014.
</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>made</o0>
        <o1>built</o1>
        <o2>grabbing</o2>
        <o3>looking</o3>
        <o4>technology</o4>
        <o5>announced</o5>
        <o6>voted</o6>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>1|3|4|5</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>7f2620b4533440248dca80a5de8a494c</id>
  <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Nowadays, sacred texts are not as well regarded as in the past. There are many reasons for this: some terrorists, for instance, refer to the Koran -- the holy book of the Islamic religion --, to justify the atrocious crimes they commit, and some believe that it is the violence which these sacred texts contain which causes the chronic aggressiveness that characterizes some Muslims; some Christians campaign against the teaching of Darwin’s theory of evolution, because they argue it contradicts the biblical history of Creation; the Jews argue that God promised Canaan -- currently, Israel -- to the descendants of Abraham, and that this is the reason their oppressive policies against the Palestinians are legitimate. These issues have sparked a renewed interest in sacred texts which has interfered in the public life of some nations. Some secularist adversaries of religion claim that religious scriptures originate violence, sectarianism, and intolerance; furthermore, they hold that these reading materials also stop people from thinking for themselves and lead to deception. Overall, critics of religion want to know why there is so much hate in sacred texts, taking into account that religion preaches compassion; and they also question if it is possible to be a believer in the present, after science has undermined so many biblical teachings.

Which of the following most accurately summarizes the opinion of the author in the text?
</description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o0>Israel’s policemen oppress the Palestinian people because they argue that God promised Canaan to them.</o0>
      <o1>Some of the acts that some religious people carry out are responsible for some people not having such a good opinion about sacred texts.</o1>
      <o2>Some religious people campaign against the teaching of Darwin’s theory of evolution because they say it contradicts the religious story of Canaan.</o2>
      <o3>Some critics hold that the Koran, the holy book of the Christian religion, leads to violence.</o3>
    </options>
    <picture></picture>
    <answer>1</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>6b4b41ac9b0e420688390a85a417f0e9</id>
  <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>At one time, one could only trace one's family ancestry by writing letters, visiting courthouses, and begging relatives for any crumb of information. However, today with the World Wide Web, the task has become much simpler. Much of the archived history of our lives and our ancestors' lives is readily available online. In addition, there are specific software programs in existence that will walk you through the process of creating a family tree and take you to appropriate internet sites for record information. Another alternative is hiring someone or some company to do your tree for you. Depending on your dedication and time, a method is available for you. You might think about tracing your family roots. It is fun for many and will let you in on your families past. Even if you find a skeleton in the closet, maybe you could just ignore that twig of your family tree.

We may infer from the passage that
</description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o0>When we trace our family's history, we may find bad as well as good things.</o0>
      <o1>Tracing our family tree is not worth the effort.</o1>
      <o2>The records we must search in order to come up with a family tree have changed due to the World Wide Web.</o2>
      <o3>Tracing one's family tree is worthwhile for everyone.</o3>
    </options>
    <picture></picture>
    <answer>0</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>570c23eedf694249a456d9ffda831efe</id>
  <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
  <type>REORDER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description></description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o1>A force of gravitation exists between everybody in the universe.</o1>
      <o2>Normally it is very small but when the one of the bodies is a planet, like earth, the force is considerable.</o2>
      <o3>It has been investigated by many scientists including Galileo and Newton.</o3>
      <o4>Everything on or near the surface of the earth is attracted by the mass of earth.</o4>
      <o5>This gravitational force depends on the mass of the bodies involved.</o5>
      <o6>The greater the mass, the greater is the earth's force of attraction on it. We can call this force of attraction gravity.</o6>
    </options>
    <answer>0|2|4|1|3|5</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>6f6cd707272c432e9b2dec696a4b5d43</id>
  <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
  <type>REORDER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description></description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o1>For some time in his youth Abraham Lincoln was manager for a shop.</o1>
      <o2>Then a chance Customer would come.</o2>
      <o3>Young Lincoln way of keeping shop was entirely unlike anyone else's</o3>
      <o4>Lincoln would jump up and attend to his needs and then revert to his reading.</o4>
      <o5>He used to lie full length on the counter of the shop eagerly reading a book.</o5>
      <o6>Never before had Lincoln had so much time for reading as had then.</o6>
    </options>
    <answer>0|2|4|1|3|5</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>37063d3359514b5494a34ffe5606a3a2</id>
  <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_MULTIPLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct response. More than one response is correct.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description> David Ricardo’s introduction to economic theory was by chance. It is said that he discovered Adam Smith’s The Wealth of Nations during a retreat, in his late twenties. Reading this book made an impact on him, and, as many others in those times, turned him into a convinced follower of Smith’s way of thinking. Ricardo was a self-taught economist, and he was not that young when he actually became one. Be it as it may, he adhered to Smith’s main work, and, from then on, at the same time he took care of his commercial activities, he dedicated himself to writing articles on economics for the British press. Many years later, when he had finally retired from his profession, his friends encouraged him to write a book in which he could formalize his ideas regarding economics. As a consequence, his great work, On the Principles of Political Economy and Taxation, was born. Despite this book being relatively short, it is somewhat complex. Furthermore, it is considered to contain the most systematic and coherent formulation of classical economic thought. Besides Adam Smith and David Ricardo, this movement included other thinkers such as Jean-Baptiste Say, Thomas Robert Malthus, and John Stuart Mill.

Which of the following are true statements about David Ricardo?</description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o0>Reading The Wealth of Nations made a big impact on Adam Smith’s life, since it inspired him to write his greatest work.</o0>
      <o1>Despite David Ricardo not attending economic lessons at any institution, he managed to offer readers a summary of classical economic theories.</o1>
      <o2>Despite David Ricardo’s friends having convinced him to retire from his profession, he decided to write a book.</o2>
      <o3>It is possible that David Ricardo’s friends would have not encouraged him to write a book on economics if David Ricardo would have died before reaching his late twenties.</o3>
    </options>
    <picture></picture>
    <answer>1|3</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>e6625fbbf3fd4025aea88f88d02dbbc9</id>
  <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_MULTIPLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct response. More than one response is correct.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>The Nazi invasion of Denmark began the early morning of April 9th in 1940, when German soldiers entered Copenhagen, despite a nonaggression pact that had been signed by both countries in 1939, in which Denmark had declared its neutrality. After battling against the German troops for only a few hours, the Nordic country surrendered, but not without first declaring it would only bow to foreign occupation if Germany promised not to interfere with Denmark’s integrity and political sovereignty. However, in October of that same year, the invaders openly broke their promises and began to meddle in Denmark’s internal affairs. The Danish people later showed their dissatisfaction towards the invasion through nonviolent strategies which originated from a leaflet that became known as “the ten commandments leaflet”, which inspired several actions: for instance, peaceful strikes, mass gatherings (in which a strong sense of nationalism was displayed), and the decision to protect the Danish Jews. Nevertheless, in 1943, the Germans gave the Danish government a final warning and eventually obliged them to do the following: prohibit strikes and public meetings involving 5 or more people, impose a night curfew, collect weapons, and impose the death penalty for sabotage against the Germans.

Which of the following are true statements about the Nazi invasion of Denmark?</description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o0>The Danish government had to prohibit strikes before the Germans invaded their country.</o0>
      <o1>Denmark’s military was not even able to withstand the German invasion for a single day.</o1>
      <o2>Germany betrayed Denmark.</o2>
      <o3>The German invaders wanted to kill all the Danish Jews.</o3>
    </options>
    <picture></picture>
    <answer>1|2</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>594ca556d0f84a91be309355f60bb608</id>
  <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Instructions: In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>There's ample wind in the United States to {blank} all the country's electricity, according to Mark Z. Jacobson of Stanford University and his colleague Cristina L. Archer. They base that claim on data from about 2,400 locations in North America. Wind power can be {blank} economically if the average wind speed at windmill height {blank} 6.9 meters per second, the researchers note in the July 16 Journal of Geophysical Research (Atmospheres). Wind blows that strong in broad swaths of the Great Plains and the continent's coasts.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>reserve</o0>
        <o1>supply</o1>
        <o2>contribute</o2>
        <o3>share</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>produced</o0>
        <o1>created</o1>
        <o2>developed</o2>
        <o3>producing</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>cross</o0>
        <o1>reached</o1>
        <o2>exceeds</o2>
        <o3>surpass</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>1|0|2</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>246fe9e602c0485fb48aa0bb0ad25cb8</id>
  <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Instructions: In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>In the June 9 Nature, Ronney, Sossina Haile of the California Institute of Technology in Pasadena, and Scott Barnett of Northwestern University in Evanston, Ill., describe their dime-size fuel cells. A {blank} focus of their work was to design a fuel cell that could heat itself up to the 500° to 600°C required to convert propane into electricity. So far, such fuel cells work only when continuously heated by an external source. To build a self-heating feature into their design, the researchers {blank} one of the fuel cell's electrodes with a catalyst—a mixture of ruthenium and cerium dioxide—that enhances the breakdown of propane by oxygen. That reaction {blank} heat and also produces hydrogen and carbon monoxide, which then undergo electrochemical reactions in the fuel cell. The result is electricity, with carbon dioxide and water as waste products.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>Important</o0>
        <o1>crucial</o1>
        <o2>primary</o2>
        <o3>main</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>coated</o0>
        <o1>has been coated</o1>
        <o2>could coat</o2>
        <o3>coat</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>released</o0>
        <o1>will release</o1>
        <o2>releases</o2>
        <o3>emitted</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>2|0|2</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>cd42182d5299476b964de64c7001ef24</id>
  <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Instructions: In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>In his 1874 science fiction tale The Mysterious Island, Jules Verne predicted, "Water will be the coal of the future." It is a vision of infinite clean energy {blank} for people to use. More than 30 years ago, Japanese scientists {blank} a seminal step in that direction. With a piece of titanium dioxide and some sunlight, they split water into hydrogen and oxygen. Although researchers {blank} to refine the process over the years, nobody has come up with a system that is both efficient and inexpensive enough to produce sufficient hydrogen for use as a clean-burning fuel on the roads, in industry, and at home. Recently, {blank} , researchers have picked up the pace of their pursuit of the ultimate water-splitting system.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>approachable</o0>
        <o1>considerable</o1>
        <o2>available</o2>
        <o3>capable</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>took</o0>
        <o1>was taken</o1>
        <o2>will be taken</o2>
        <o3>take</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>have tried</o0>
        <o1>did try</o1>
        <o2>tried</o2>
        <o3>try</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>however</o0>
        <o1>therefore</o1>
        <o2>primarily</o2>
        <o3>in addition</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>2|0|0|0</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>1d180f5aa8db419e864d77a6e0162c42</id>
  <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Instructions: In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>In a process called electrodeposition, a robotic instrument {blank} an electrode into each solution one by one, causing the dissolved materials to form a thin solid film on the titanium-coated glass. Peeling away the Teflon leaves behind 120 thin dots of material, each with a different composition. To test the water-splitting {blank} of the newly created films, a second robotic instrument lowers a tiny chamber onto each dot and fills the chamber with a conductive aqueous solution, or electrolyte. The robot then shines light on the chamber and measures the current the film {blank} . By repeating this quick test on each film, the robot screens the entire array in a matter of hours. The greater the current {blank} by a film when illuminated, the more electrons it gives up, and therefore the greater its potential to split water and generate hydrogen. This technique amounts to an efficient form of trial-and-error. "We can afford to try all sorts of wacky things," says Thomas Jaramillo, one of the investigators {blank} on the project. "That's the real power of this technology."</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>drops</o0>
        <o1>mixes</o1>
        <o2>dips</o2>
        <o3>dissolves</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>important</o0>
        <o1>main</o1>
        <o2>potential</o2>
        <o3>considerable</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>generated</o0>
        <o1>is generated</o1>
        <o2>generates</o2>
        <o3>will generate</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>was produced</o0>
        <o1>produces</o1>
        <o2>produced</o2>
        <o3>has produced</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>is working</o0>
        <o1>was working</o1>
        <o2>will be working</o2>
        <o3>working</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>2|2|2|2|3</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>535e7c8d5c0f4cdb9708d5756bf9896e</id>
  <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Instructions: In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Inspired by the efficiency with which plants convert sunlight into sugar, researchers {blank} a solar cell that uses photosynthetic proteins to convert light into electricity. Although the prototype device can't yet rival commercial solar cells made of silicon, it {blank} a new strategy for making longer-lasting photovoltaic cells. To make the solar cell, a team of biologists and engineers led by Marc Baldo of the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) harvested photosynthetic proteins from spinach and the bacterium Rhodobacter sphaeroides and deposited the proteins onto a glass support. Because the proteins naturally reside in an aqueous environment inside a cell membrane, it took some creative chemistry to keep the {blank} 2 billion isolated proteins functional on a solid surface.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>had fabricated</o0>
        <o1>fabricated</o1>
        <o2>have fabricated</o2>
        <o3>fabricate</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>demonstrates</o0>
        <o1>demonstrated</o1>
        <o2>is being demonstrated</o2>
        <o3>is demonstrated</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>exactly</o0>
        <o1>over</o1>
        <o2>approximately</o2>
        <o3>beyond</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>2|0|2</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<!-- Test 2 -->
<question>
  <id>8df05bd13b4e4743ab81cb231a0bc525</id>
  <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>According to philosopher Ayn Rand from her literary nonfiction genre of work called the Romantic Manifesto, she asserts that there are a set of contradicting dual of art forms which are primarily classified as Naturalism and Romanticism. With the advent of modernization and post Nazi occurrences, the world beheld many Naturalistic forms of art as opposed to mind bending and excessively creative and novel Romantic art forms. Ayn Rand is concerned with the fact that there is an inherent void of balance between these contradicting art forms which puts the art form and human expression at jeopardy. Hence, she wants to let the world know that there ought to be a balance between these art forms and the Romanticism must not be annihilated and the beauty of it must not be lost. Life is all about balance and that elementary notion must not be lost and we must stick to those roots.

Which of the following best describes the passage?</description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o0>Romanticism is getting unpopular and the masses are embracing art works in the realm of naturalism only.</o0>
      <o1>There ought to be a balance between the art forms of Romanticism and Naturalism. Thought naturalism is on a steady rise, we still need to embrace romanticism for what it is.</o1>
      <o2>Ayn Rand wrote a nonfiction book called The Romantic Manifesto.</o2>
      <o3>None of the above.</o3>
    </options>
    <picture></picture>
    <answer>1</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>6e68e551191e4d23bf7fbccdb2034999</id>
  <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>According to philosopher Ayn Rand from her literary nonfiction genre of work called the Romantic Manifesto, she asserts that there are a set of contradicting dual of art forms which are primarily classified as Naturalism and Romanticism. With the advent of modernization and post Nazi occurrences, the world beheld many Naturalistic forms of art as opposed to mind bending and excessively creative and novel Romantic art forms. Ayn Rand is concerned with the fact that there is an inherent void of balance between these contradicting art forms which puts the art form and human expression at jeopardy. Hence, she wants to let the world know that there ought to be a balance between these art forms and the Romanticism must not be annihilated and the beauty of it must not be lost. Life is all about balance and that elementary notion must not be lost and we must stick to those roots.

Which of the following best describes the passage?</description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o0>Romanticism is getting unpopular and the masses are embracing art works in the realm of naturalism only.</o0>
      <o1>There ought to be a balance between the art forms of Romanticism and Naturalism. Thought naturalism is on a steady rise, we still need to embrace romanticism for what it is.</o1>
      <o2>Ayn Rand wrote a nonfiction book called The Romantic Manifesto.</o2>
      <o3>None of the above.</o3>
    </options>
    <picture></picture>
    <answer>1</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>3f74090bff614a87a1301a1bc85f1ed6</id>
  <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_MULTIPLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct response. More than one response is correct.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>The Psychodynamic Approach. Theorists adopting the psychodynamic approach hold that inner conflicts are crucial for understanding human behavior, including aggression. Sigmund Freud, for example, believed that aggressive impulses are inevitable reactions to the frustrations of daily life. Children normally desire to vent aggressive impulses on other people, including their parents, because even the most attentive parents cannot gratify all of their demands immediately. Yet children, also fearing their parents' punishment and the loss of parental love, come to repress most aggressive impulses. The Freudian perspective, in a sense: sees us as "steam engines." By holding in rather than venting "steam," we set the stage for future explosions. Pent-up aggressive impulses demand outlets. They may be expressed toward parents in indirect ways such as destroying furniture, or they may be expressed toward strangers later in life.
According to the paragraph, Freud believed that children experience conflict between a desire to vent aggression on their parents</description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o0>A frustration that their parents do not give them everything they want</o0>
      <o1>A fear that their parents will punish them</o1>
      <o2>A desire to take care of their parents</o2>
      <o3>A desire to vent aggression on other family members</o3>
      <o4>A fear for loss of their parents' love</o4>
    </options>
    <picture></picture>
    <answer>1|4</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>ba7c408856c6487b98eeb678f38254dc</id>
  <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_MULTIPLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct response. More than one response is correct.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>In Southwest France in the 1940's, playing children discovered Lascaux Grotto, a series of narrow cave chambers that contain huge prehistoric paintings of animals. Many of these beasts are as large as 16 feet (almost 5 meters). Some follow each other in solemn parades, but others swirl about, sideways and upside down. The animals are bulls, wild horses, reindeer, bison, and mammoths outlined with charcoal and painted mostly in reds, yellow, and browns. Scientific analysis reveals that the colors were derived from ocher and other iron oxides ground into a fine powder. Methods of applying color varied: some colors were brushed or smeared on rock surfaces and others were blown or sprayed. It is possible that tubes made from animal bones were used for spraying because hollow bones, some stained with pigment, have been found nearby.

What are the bones found in the Lascaux caves believed to indicate?</description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o0>The subjects the artists painted various.</o0>
      <o1>Artists painted pictures on both walls and bones.</o1>
      <o2>Artists ground them into a fine powder to make paint.</o2>
      <o3>Artists developed special techniques for painting the walls.</o3>
    </options>
    <picture></picture>
    <answer>0|3</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>7537bb8616a34f1a9dbe3ce59934c213</id>
  <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
  <type>REORDER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description></description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o1>However, the higher it goes, the less air it meets.</o1>
      <o2>As the rocket goes higher, it travels faster.</o2>
      <o3>For the atmosphere becomes thinner.</o3>
      <o4>As a result there is less friction.</o4>
      <o5>When a satellite is launched, the rocket begins by going slowly upwards through the air.</o5>
      <o6>Consequently, the rocket still does not become too hot.</o6>
    </options>
    <answer>4|1|0|2|3|5</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>c402192562664be9a4bec2b8f6362092</id>
  <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
  <type>REORDER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description></description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o1>There are about four hundred old stone bridges joining the island of Venice.</o1>
      <o2>In this city there are no motor cars, no horses, no buses.</o2>
      <o3>Venice is a strange and beautiful city in the north of Italy.</o3>
      <o4>This is because Venice has no streets.</o4>
      <o5>It is not an island but a hundred and seventeen islands.</o5>
      <o6>These small islands are near one another.</o6>
    </options>
    <answer>2|4|5|0|1|3</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>aff375306a9b472386e76183c5c6b671</id>
  <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each , a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each . To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Humans of New York, the photographic {blank} of the amazing people {blank} around the streets of the Big Apple, was started by Brandon Stanton in the summer of 2010. What began as a journey for a young photographer, {blank} into a visual story, twisting its way through the tourist-filled streets, traffic-packed asphalt and winding subway tunnels of this manic city that millions of {blank} and beautiful individuals call home. Here are the 25 most romantic photos and stories throughout the history of HONY.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>unique</o0>
        <o1>archive</o1>
        <o2>seeing</o2>
        <o3>exploded</o3>
        <o4>roaming</o4>
        <o5>collection</o5>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>1|4|3|0</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>d2501262ead24c668f4b5bcd77d77df8</id>
  <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each , a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each . To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Apple’s disappointing quarter is the latest in a {blank} of bad reports from the biggest technology companies. While the {blank} vary — including the long slump in personal computer sales and slipping {blank} for online ads — a common theme has been that as these companies have grown into giants, it has become harder and harder to keep up the {blank} .</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>rate</o0>
        <o1>reasons</o1>
        <o2>impulse</o2>
        <o3>prices</o3>
        <o4>momentum</o4>
        <o5>string</o5>
        <o6>difference</o6>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>5|1|3|4</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>9868f84f2a5e4036a8e181b540521a12</id>
  <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each , a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each . To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Nearly half of the smartphones {blank} in the United States are iPhones, and Apple may be reaching the {blank} point among potential customers in other developed countries. Rival smartphone makers using Google’s Android operating system {blank} to challenge the company with powerful, less {blank} devices.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>saturation</o0>
        <o1>solid</o1>
        <o2>extend</o2>
        <o3>continue</o3>
        <o4>sale</o4>
        <o5>expensive</o5>
        <o6>costly</o6>
        <o7>exorbitant</o7>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>1|0|3|5</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>4f3a1b0333ca4a0ea2cdeb8d3554eff0</id>
  <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each , a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each . To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Human history is {blank} with instances of how diffusion of general purpose technologies transformed {blank} and society. Take the US where electricity {blank} the way factories were organized in the 19th century, while assembly lines transformed manufacturing. In communications and logistics, the telegraph enabled {blank} conveyance of goods in stock and instructions to employees.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>metamorphosed</o0>
        <o1>rapid</o1>
        <o2>replete</o2>
        <o3>aristocracy</o3>
        <o4>stagnated</o4>
        <o5>commonality</o5>
		<o5>languishing</o5>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>2|5|0|1</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>a53e25fe899343d28047aa5621d847ff</id>
  <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each , a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Twenties” was a period when American economy flourished tremendously. The nation’s total realized income rose from $75 billion in 1923 to $90 billion in 1929. During the economic {blank} of the “Roaring Twenties”, Jazz age challenged the {blank} values of rural America, symbolized by women smoking, drinking and wearing short skirts. Fashion clubs, kitty parties, late night ballet dance was the common life styles of the rich classes and the middle classes were envying the rich to maintain the false respect in the society. The average Americans were busy buying household appliances, automobiles and investing money in the stock market to make huge profits. The American youth were {blank} to get rich overnight and the success mania boosted trade and commerce. The banks were liberal in granting loans and the easy liquidity propelled the bullish phase of the American stock market. Even the poor Americans raised money on loan and invested in the stock market for easy money earnings. The rewards of the 1920s “Coolidge Prosperity” were not equally shared among all Americans. Henry Ford and other business magnates were aware of the inequitable distribution of income between the rich and the poor. The {blank} point of the economy was visible but nobody dared to calculate the repercussions of the fallout.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>Depression</o0>
        <o1>cycle</o1>
        <o2>boom</o2>
        <o3>trend</o3>
        <o4>inflation</o4>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>Traditional</o0>
        <o1>ritual</o1>
        <o2>spiritual</o2>
        <o3>old</o3>
        <o4>dilapidation</o4>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>anxious</o0>
        <o1>Particular</o1>
        <o2>biding</o2>
        <o3>bidding</o3>
        <o4>tensed</o4>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>Top</o0>
        <o1>peak</o1>
        <o2>trough</o2>
        <o3>flat</o3>
        <o4>boiling</o4>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>2|0|0|3</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>c80b6f77ddc244c18c308cbae00dd155</id>
  <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each , a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>In a variety of ways, Americans wanted to get rich, and to do so with little effort. Thorstein Veblen published “The Theory of the Leisure Class” in 1898 and {blank}  the theory of consumerism. The first commercial radio station went on air in the 1920s in Pittsburgh. By 1922, 3 million American households had radios, and the annual sales rose to $850 million by 1929. Motion picture industries became one of the ten largest industries in the US. In 1922, theatres sold 40 million tickets a week. A floodtide of new electric appliances, vacuum cleaners, toasters, washing machines and refrigerators {blank} American houses. The automobiles required better roads, the infrastructure was developed, new highways were built, and filling stations, garages, and roadside restaurants sprang up across the nation. Cars broke down the {blank} between the urban and rural America, a new tradition of “Sunday drive” started, the rural Americans drove into cities to shop and to be entertained. Children could escape parental {blank} as cars turned out to be a sort of “bedroom on wheels”. People became crazy about cars and every income group regarded them a necessity rather than a luxury. People were willing to {blank} their food, clothes and savings in order to buy a car.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>discovered</o0>
        <o1>initiated</o1>
        <o2>propagated</o2>
        <o3>visualized</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>placed</o0>
        <o1>reached</o1>
        <o2>kept</o2>
        <o3>introduced</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>disparity</o0>
        <o1>notion</o1>
        <o2>ill feeling</o2>
        <o3>consistency</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>interference</o0>
        <o1>care</o1>
        <o2>supervision</o2>
        <o3>help</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>save</o0>
        <o1>skip</o1>
        <o2>take</o2>
        <o3>sacrifice</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>2|1|0|2|3</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>ff16006c08254cab95d756aa5d050b22</id>
  <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each , a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Dr. Martin Luther King marked his importance in the civil rights {blank} by mobilizing the Black community during a 382 day bus boycott. He was arrested; his home was bombarded. But the US Supreme Court declared bus segregation unconstitutional and Dr. King became the hero of Negroes. His non-violent {blank} were put to test in Birmingham, during a mass protest rally protesting against the desegregation of department store facilities. Dr. King was arrested and his followers suffered police brutalities Dr. King delivered the most passionate {blank} of his career and “Time” magazine nominated him as its “Person of the Year” for 1963. A few months later he was named the recipient of the 1964 Nobel Peace Prize and the entire story of King’s struggle and his crusade to {blank} the slums of Chicago were reported nationally and internationally.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>evolution</o0>
        <o1>movement</o1>
        <o2>project</o2>
        <o3>committee</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>methods</o0>
        <o1>actions</o1>
        <o2>behavior</o2>
        <o3>thought</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>job</o0>
        <o1>address</o1>
        <o2>dictation</o2>
        <o3>scheme</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>reclaim</o0>
        <o1>deface</o1>
        <o2>rehabilitate</o2>
        <o3>reconstruct</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>1|0|1|2</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>6450603362a24f0ab7f10481d1db3b92</id>
  <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each , a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>By the standards of the 70s, when the {blank} climbing routes were littered with {blank} tents and food packets, Everest is a lot cleaner, with just a smattering of plastic bottles and sweet wrappers on the rocky plateau that is the base camp. But, a Nepali environmental coalition is {blank} the government in Kathmandu to adopt a new management {blank} to safeguard the Himalayas in the {blank} of mass tourism - and to make amends for the {blank} sins of the past.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>main</o0>
        <o1>real</o1>
        <o2>true</o2>
        <o3>minor</o3>
        <o4>firm</o4>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>huge</o0>
        <o1>discarded</o1>
        <o2>exhausted</o2>
        <o3>damaged</o3>
        <o4>small</o4>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>encouraging</o0>
        <o1>discouraging</o1>
        <o2>manipulating</o2>
        <o3>pressing</o3>
        <o4>stimulating</o4>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>method</o0>
        <o1>role</o1>
        <o2>technology</o2>
        <o3>plan</o3>
        <o4>plot</o4>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>scheme</o0>
        <o1>plan</o1>
        <o2>interest</o2>
        <o3>age</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>nature</o0>
        <o1>environment</o1>
        <o2>ecological</o2>
        <o3>many</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>0|1|3|3|3|1</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>2a853cabf6d04f2a9334f4d29815cbd1</id>
  <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each , a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Future vehicles and electric generators {blank} by fuel cells could eventually run on hydrogen derived from corn. Researchers at the University of Minnesota, Twin Cities, have come up with an efficient method of {blank} ethanol, the alcohol produced by the fermentation of corn, into hydrogen fuel. From the breakdown of biomass to the splitting of water using solar energy, researchers around the world have been exploring a host of renewable sources of hydrogen. The main source of hydrogen today is natural gas—a polluting and nonrenewable fossil fuel. To extract hydrogen from ethanol, Lanny Schmidt and his coworkers {blank} a mixture of water and ethanol into a palm-size reaction chamber heated to 140°C. The ethanol and water mixed with air inside the chamber and passed {blank} a porous membrane covered with rhodium and cerium oxide catalysts. As the catalysts stripped the hydrogen atoms from the ethanol, the process generated heat, which {blank} speed up the reaction.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>powered</o0>
        <o1>isolated</o1>
        <o2>handled</o2>
        <o3>supported</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>mixing</o0>
        <o1>producing</o1>
        <o2>converting</o2>
        <o3>creating</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>injected</o0>
        <o1>mixed</o1>
        <o2>dissolved</o2>
        <o3>injected</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>in</o0>
        <o1>by</o1>
        <o2>through</o2>
        <o3>into</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>essentially</o0>
        <o1>importantly</o1>
        <o2>significantly</o2>
        <o3>insignificantly</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>0|2|0|2|2</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<!-- Test 3 -->
<question>
  <id>02f0c58029e545f58cb79d5528773fff</id>
  <practiceSet>88f631b360734b7da3b7c3e6151bd840</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_MULTIPLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct response. More than one response is correct.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>The first English attempts to colonize North America were controlled by individuals rather than companies. Sir Humphrey Gilbert was the first Englishman to send colonists to the New World. His initial expedition, which sailed in 1578 with a patent granted by Queen Elizabeth was defeated by the Spanish. A second attempt ended in disaster in 1583 when Gilbert and his ship were lost in a storm. In the following year, Gilbert’s half brother, Sir Water Raleigh, having obtained a renewal of the patent, sponsored an expedition that explored the coast of the region that he named “Virginia.” Under Raleigh’s direction efforts were then made to establish a colony on Roanoke Island in 1585 and 1587. The survivors of the first settlement on Roanoke returned to England in 1586, but the second group of colonists disappeared without leaving a trace. The failure of the Gilbert and Raleigh ventures made it clear that the tasks they had undertaken were too big for any one colonizer. Within a short time, the trading company had supplanted the individual promoter of colonization.
Which of the following statements can be supported by this text?</description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o0>The first English settlement on Roanoke Island was established in 1587.</o0>
      <o1>Sir Humphrey Gilbert never settled in North America.</o1>
      <o2>Members of the first Roanoke settlement explored the entire coastal region.</o2>
      <o3>Sir Walter Raleigh’s initial expedition set out for North America in 1584.</o3>
      <o4>The first English people established colonies in North America because they were requested to do so by Queen Elizabeth.</o4>
    </options>
    <picture></picture>
    <answer>1|2</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>00445cdf808a4779b7092c18ae3ae252</id>
  <practiceSet>88f631b360734b7da3b7c3e6151bd840</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_MULTIPLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct response. More than one response is correct.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>The crisis begins in the womb with unplanned parenthood. Women with unplanned pregnancies are less likely to seek prenatal care. In the U.S. 80% of teenage pregnancies and 56% of all pregnancies are unplanned. The problems continue after birth where unplanned pregnancies and unstable partnerships often go hand in hand. Since 1950, the number of single-parent families has nearly tripled. More than 25 percent of all births today are to unmarried mothers. As the number of single parent families grows and more women enter the workforce, infants and toddlers are increasingly in the care of people other than their parents. Most disturbingly, recent statistics show that American parents are increasingly neglecting or abusing their children. In only four years from 1987-1991, the number of children in foster care increased by over 50 percent. Babies under the age of one are the fastest growing category of children entering foster care. The crisis affects children under the age of three most severely, the report says. Yet, it is this period from infancy through preschool years that sets the stage for a child’s future.
What can be the possible reasons for the increasing neglect and abuse of children?</description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o0>The immaturity and overburdening of parents.</o0>
      <o1>The babies being left in foster care where a stranger looks after them.</o1>
      <o2>The children being ill mannered and not respecting their parents.</o2>
      <o3>The parents being busy with meeting the financial aspects of the family and not having enough time for the children.</o3>
    </options>
    <picture></picture>
    <answer>0|1|3</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>dd1656fbbd65479cabf1feacd7b58cb1</id>
  <practiceSet>88f631b360734b7da3b7c3e6151bd840</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each . To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>It’s no secret that battlefield trauma can leave  {blank} with deep emotional scars that {blank} their ability to function in civilian life. But new research led by Washington University in St. Louis suggests that military service, even without {blank}, has a subtle {blank} effect on a man’s personality, making it potentially more difficult for veterans to get along with friends, family and co-workers.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>combat</o0>
        <o1>amateurs</o1>
        <o2>soothe</o2>
        <o3>veterans</o3>
        <o4>intermittent</o4>
        <o5>accord</o5>
        <o6>lingering</o6>
        <o7>impact</o7>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>3|7|0|6</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>b58ef04e9ef544e2a5d3789bc01358c4</id>
  <practiceSet>88f631b360734b7da3b7c3e6151bd840</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each . To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>His son was {blank} in a distant place and he returned home for vacation. The rich man wanted to show off to his son how rich his father was and how he made him very proud. But his son wasn’t ever fond of any luxurious {blank} . However, the rich man wanted to make his son realize that his lifestyle was extremely rich and how the poor people did suffer. He planned for a day visit to the entire town to show him off the life of the poor people. The father and the son took a chariot and {blank} the entire town. They returned home after two days. The father was happy that his son was very quiet {blank} seeing the poor people honoring the rich man and after seeing the sufferings of the poor ones due to lack of {blank}.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>playing</o0>
        <o1>studying</o1>
        <o2>after</o2>
        <o3>visited</o3>
        <o4>lifestyle</o4>
        <o5>car</o5>
        <o6>facilities</o6>
        <o7>study</o7>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>1|4|3|2|6</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>951c93b3b07144ec917e001d16c41208</id>
  <practiceSet>88f631b360734b7da3b7c3e6151bd840</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each . To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>There's ample wind in the United States to supply all the country's electricity, according to Mark Z. Jacobson of Stanford University and his colleague Cristina L. Archer. They base that {blank} on data from about 2,400 locations in North America. Wind power can be produced {blank} if the average wind speed at windmill height {blank} 6.9 meters per second, the researchers note in the July 16 Journal of Geophysical Research (Atmospheres). Wind blows that strong in broad swaths of the Great Plains and the continent's {blank} .</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>exceeds</o0>
        <o1>coasts</o1>
        <o2>financially</o2>
        <o3>economically</o3>
        <o4>shore</o4>
        <o5>claim</o5>
        <o6>increases</o6>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>5|3|0|1</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>ffbb654f08c14c858eb9ca3d97658be4</id>
  <practiceSet>88f631b360734b7da3b7c3e6151bd840</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each . To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>West Point researchers found that using a laptop or tablet in the classroom had {blank} an overall drop of roughly one-fifth of a standard deviation. Students who were allowed {blank} use of their laptops or tablets performed with an 18 per cent reduction, while those with a modified tablet access saw a 17 per cent drop. This {blank} a 1.7 point drop on the 100 point scale. The negative effects were seen most heavily in male students, and those who came into the class with a high GPA. The researchers say that both unrestricted and modified use may affect students in a number of ways. It could lead to {blank} , in which students are checking social media or even doing homework for another class, and it may reduce students’ abilities to effectively take notes. The researchers say professors may even change their own {blank} , interacting differently with the class in response to students using devices.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>caused</o0>
        <o1>create</o1>
        <o2>consider</o2>
        <o3>unrestricted</o3>
        <o4>equates</o4>
        <o5>distractions</o5>
        <o6>behavior</o6>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>0|3|4|5|6</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>2ea5fca0f640431a910449a60dd90222</id>
  <practiceSet>88f631b360734b7da3b7c3e6151bd840</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each . To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Event management is particularly challenging from an operational viewpoint. In many cases, events are staged on sites where everything has been set up over a 24-hour period, with all elements carefully {blank} . In contrast, many events are years in the planning: large convention bids are often won five years before the event is held. For the very {blank} bidding process, budgets need to be developed and prices quoted, requiring a good understanding of market, economic and political trends, as well as consumer choices. This long-term view is the basis of strategic management, which is covered in Part 1, and focuses on the event concept, feasibility of the event, legal compliance and financial management. Marketing is a critical {blank} factor and other important topic of this first section, many events (sporting, cultural and arts) involving long- term sponsorship {blank} with key industry players. Relationship building is particularly {blank} since there are so many stakeholders involved in events, including government agencies at many levels.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>arrange</o0>
        <o1>success</o1>
        <o2>challenging</o2>
        <o3>synchronized</o3>
        <o4>competition</o4>
        <o5>succeed</o5>
        <o6>arrangements</o6>
        <o7>competitive</o7>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>3|7|1|6|2</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>d2a2c8119a2e41f7a77e41bc9ccd2335</id>
  <practiceSet>88f631b360734b7da3b7c3e6151bd840</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>The American people have an incorrect understanding of what it means to be at war. At least so argues T.H. Pickett in his conservative interpretation of American military history. Pickett does present a wealth of examples along with a refreshing candid argument that America often goes to war for an abstract ideal such as the democratization of societies, would peace, liberty, or freedom. For instance, the Spanish - American War of 1898 was ostensibly a consequence of national enthusiasm for the cause of Cuban liberty. And, more obviously, America’s entry into World War I stemmed from a desire to “make the world safe for democracy.” Although these observations are supportable, Pickett overstates the cause typically lead to a war hysteria in which American leadership can no longer enforce any measured policies.

Which of the following best states the author’s main point?
</description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o0>Pickett provides a cogent rationale for why America engages in warfare; however, he draws conclusions that the author does not fully support.</o0>
      <o1>Pickett’s study is valuable primarily because it provides a thorough understanding of the causes of American warfare.</o1>
      <o2>The rationale for American warfare is well documented.</o2>
      <o3>Pickett’s analysis of American military history provides the definitive historical record of the period from the Spanish-American War to World War I</o3>
    </options>
    <picture></picture>
    <answer>0</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>00afdee54e394b4d9d5a297ed4133573</id>
  <practiceSet>88f631b360734b7da3b7c3e6151bd840</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>By 1784, Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart was internationally renowned as the composer of The Marriage of Figaro, and consequently received a commission from the Prague Opera House to compose another opera. The resulting product was Don Giovanni, which tells the tale of a criminal and seducer who nevertheless evokes sympathy from audiences, and whose behavior fluctuates from moral crisis to hilarious escapade. While Don Giovanni is widely considered to be Mozart’s greatest achievement, eighteenth century audiences in Vienna — Mozart’s own city — were ambivalent at best. The opera mixed traditions of moralism with those of comedy — a practice heretofore unknown among the composer’s works — creating a production that was not well liked by conservative Viennese audiences. Meanwhile, however, Don Giovanni was performed to much acclaim throughout Europe.

The primary purpose of the passage is to</description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o0>relate the story of a somewhat likable antihero.</o0>
      <o1>discuss how a work of art has been met by diverging responses.</o1>
      <o2>give a history of the work of Mozart.</o2>
      <o3>make a case for the renown of Don Giovanni.</o3>
    </options>
    <picture></picture>
    <answer>1</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>90c24f59e70241f78d13dcd966a43a4c</id>
  <practiceSet>88f631b360734b7da3b7c3e6151bd840</practiceSet>
  <type>REORDER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description></description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o1>Back at Stanford University, Liu, a professor of archaeology, and her students microscopically analyzed pieces of the residue on the funnel and found evidence of ancient grains in the form of phytoliths, fossilized plant parts.</o1>
      <o2>It was 2012 when archaeologist Li Liu noticed an unusual dark residue inside a 5000-year-old pottery funnel from Inner Mongolia.</o2>
      <o3>The observation left her wondering if the funnel might have been used to make alcohol.</o3>
      <o4>The group determined the grain was millet, a common grain used for brewing beer.</o4>
      <o5>If Liu’s hunch proved correct, it would represent the oldest evidence of alcohol production in the Yellow River valley of China.</o5>
    </options>
    <answer>1|2|4|0|3</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>8d26a5fa1e424b09a4b2e70086b2a4f1</id>
  <practiceSet>88f631b360734b7da3b7c3e6151bd840</practiceSet>
  <type>REORDER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description></description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o1>The likelihood of an accident is determined by how carefully the motorist drives and how carefully the pedestrian crosses the street.</o1>
      <o2>An accident involving a motorist and a pedestrian is such a case.</o2>
      <o3>Each must decide how much care to exercise without knowing how careful the other is.</o3>
      <o4>The simplest strategic problem arises when two individuals interact with each other, and each must decide what to do without knowing what the other is doing.</o4>
    </options>
    <answer>3|1|0|2</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>5783eb7a6d714eb186a0ddacba7e85d9</id>
  <practiceSet>88f631b360734b7da3b7c3e6151bd840</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>In the June 9 Nature, Ronney, Sossina Haile of the California Institute of Technology in Pasadena, and Scott Barnett of Northwestern University in Evanston, Ill., describe their dime-size fuel cells. A {blank} focus of their work was to design a fuel cell that could heat itself up to the 500° to 600°C required to convert propane into electricity. So far, such fuel cells work only when {blank} heated by an external source. To build a self-heating feature into their design, the researchers coated one of the fuel cell's electrodes with a catalyst—a mixture of ruthenium and cerium dioxide-that {blank} the breakdown of propane by oxygen. That reaction releases heat and also produces hydrogen and carbon monoxide, which then undergo electrochemical reactions in the fuel cell. The result is electricity, with carbon dioxide and water as {blank} products.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>secondary</o0>
        <o1>primary</o1>
        <o2>primarily</o2>
        <o3>dominant</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>gradually</o0>
        <o1>conditionally</o1>
        <o2>conveniently</o2>
        <o3>continuously</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>enhances</o0>
        <o1>diminishes</o1>
        <o2>covers</o2>
        <o3>uplift</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>debris</o0>
        <o1>contaminated</o1>
        <o2>extra</o2>
        <o3>waste</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>1|3|0|3</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>acb53b0645be40e1ba2f7e54184567a6</id>
  <practiceSet>88f631b360734b7da3b7c3e6151bd840</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Grammar is an example of a combinatorial system, in which a small inventory of elements can be  {blank} by rules into an immense set of distinct objects. Combinatorial systems obey what Miller calls the Exponential Principle: The number of possible {blank} grows exponentially with the size of the combination. Combinatorial systems can generate inconceivably vast numbers of products. Every kind of molecule in the universe is assembled from a hundred-odd chemical elements; every protein building block and catalyst in the living world is assembled from just twenty amino acids. Even when the number of products is smaller, a combinatorial system can {blank} them all and provide enormous savings in storage space. Eight bits define [2.sup.8] = 256 distinct bytes, which is more than enough for all the numerals, punctuation marks, and upper- and lowercase letters in our writing system. This allows computers to be built out of {blank} specks of silicon that can be in just two states, instead of the dozens of pieces of type that once filled typesetters' cases. Billions of years ago life on Earth settled on a code in which a {blank} of three bases in a DNA molecule became the instruction for selecting one amino acid when assembling a protein.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>assembled</o0>
        <o1>created</o1>
        <o2>setup</o2>
        <o3>built</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>collaborations</o0>
        <o1>unity</o1>
        <o2>same</o2>
        <o3>combinations</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>trace</o0>
        <o1>track</o1>
        <o2>capture</o2>
        <o3>trap</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>same</o0>
        <o1>identical</o1>
        <o2>similar</o2>
        <o3>copied</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>string</o0>
        <o1>stack</o1>
        <o2>rosary</o2>
        <o3>row</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>0|3|2|1|0</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>41c89491a82e404191370ea43cc2e81e</id>
  <practiceSet>88f631b360734b7da3b7c3e6151bd840</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>In one of Spike Lee’s most complex films to date, the {blank} of Jungle Fever is dedicated to exploring the consequences of the illicit affair between successful Black architect Flipper Purify (Wesley Snipes) and his Italian-American secretary, Angie Tucci (Annabella Sciorra). Set to a smoldering {blank} by Stevie Wonder, the film follows the smitten pair as they ditch their partners after being discovered in order to move in together. Audiences are treated to {blank} views of Harlem and Bensonhurst through Lee’s powerful lens as Flipper and Angie’s romance proves too weak to survive the scrutiny and violent objections from their families and {blank} .</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>main-part</o0>
        <o1>majority</o1>
        <o2>most</o2>
        <o3>earth-slip</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>music</o0>
        <o1>soundtrack</o1>
        <o2>movie-album</o2>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>haunting</o0>
        <o1>moving</o1>
        <o2>atmospheric</o2>
        <o3>haunt</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>communities</o0>
        <o1>colony</o1>
        <o2>area</o2>
        <o3>circle</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>1|1|0|0</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>f0f3af7c50a742f0a5e961c5b8508f63</id>
  <practiceSet>88f631b360734b7da3b7c3e6151bd840</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Culture has been a part of our society, and way of life, forever. It is almost {blank} to come up with an idea that isn’t {blank} by culture. Picture our lives without cars, television, and computers. This would be an example of everyday life without technology. People could function happily in that type of atmosphere, but technology has changed our lives forever. Technology has changed our {blank} and perspective on education. Students would have to go to libraries and spend a lot of time researching to find out information for class assignments, but with technology students can find almost anything on their home computers and by accessing the internet. Technology has definitely become the authoritative factor in our lives, but culture has {blank} technology. Technology is made and used in such a variety of ways because many people who use the technology of today come from all walks of life and have different necessities, so to compensate for that technology must adapt to all different cultures.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>important</o0>
        <o1>impossible</o1>
        <o2>immature</o2>
        <o3>immediate</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>effected</o0>
        <o1>affected</o1>
        <o2>influenced</o2>
        <o3>impressed</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>view</o0>
        <o1>behavior</o1>
        <o2>conduct</o2>
        <o3>Pace</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>shaped</o0>
        <o1>opposed</o1>
        <o2>debased</o2>
        <o3>face</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>1|2|3|0</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<!-- Test 4 -->
<question>
  <id>93287aaae7d343798446086def352bfc</id>
  <practiceSet>7b04cda952c144788c9d27aa2d5dc710</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Reviving the practice of using elements of popular music in classical composition, an approach that had been in hibernation in the United States during the 1960s, composer Philip Glass (born 1937) embraced the ethos of popular music in his compositions. Glass based two symphonies on music by rock musicians David Bowie and Brian Eno, but the symphonies’ sound is distinctively his. Popular elements do not appear out of place in Glass’s classical music, which from its early days has shared certain harmonies and rhythms with rock music. Yet this use of popular elements has not made Glass a composer of popular music. His music is not a version of popular music packaged to attract classical listeners; it is high art for listeners steeped in rock rather than the classics.

The passage addresses which of the following issues related to Glass’s use of popular elements in his classical compositions?
</description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o0>How it is regarded by listeners who prefer rock to the classics</o0>
      <o1>How it has affected the commercial success of Glass’s music</o1>
      <o2>Whether it has caused certain of Glass’s works to be derivative in quality</o2>
      <o3>Whether it has contributed to a revival of interest among other composers in using popular elements in their compositions</o3>
    </options>
    <picture></picture>
    <answer>2</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>8819babe307f4bf182dd22e70b29abb2</id>
  <practiceSet>7b04cda952c144788c9d27aa2d5dc710</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Future Shock is a book written by the futurist Alvin Toffler in 1970. In the book, Toffler defines the term “future shock” as a certain psychological state of individuals and entire societies. His shortest definition for the term is a personal perception of “too much change in too short a period of time”. The book became an international bestseller, selling over 6 million copies, and has been widely translated. Toffler argued that society is undergoing an enormous structural change, a revolution from an industrial society to a “super-industrial society”. This change overwhelms people, he believed, the accelerated rate of technological and social change leaving people disconnected and suffering from “shattering stress and disorientation” - future shocked. Toffler stated that the majority of social problems are symptoms of future shock. In his discussion of the components of such shock he popularized the term “information overload.”

What would be the most suitable title for the passage?

</description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o0>A shocking vision of the future.</o0>
      <o1>What is “future shock”?</o1>
      <o2>The career of the futurist Alvin Toffler.</o2>
      <o3>A changing society.</o3>
    </options>
    <picture></picture>
    <answer>1</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>3081a32dbb4941ecaf6dc0b053e7dea5</id>
  <practiceSet>7b04cda952c144788c9d27aa2d5dc710</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_MULTIPLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct response. More than one response is correct.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>In 1861, Matthew Brady, a well-known portrait photographer, approached President Lincoln requesting permission to move freely about the country photographing the Civil War. Lincoln granted him permission to travel anywhere with the Union armies, and his record of this conflict brought home to millions the horrors of war.
Brady wasn’t the first official war photographer. Six years earlier, Roger Fenton, a lawyer and amateur photographer, had returned from the Crimea, having been personally chosen by Queen Victoria and Prince Albert. However, his instructions were more likely to have been to send back work that boosted morale back home rather than the terrible realities of war. Brady’s coverage of the war made him a household name, but he had hundreds of assistants, and it’s even possible that he didn’t take any of the 7,000 pictures that were marketed under his name. But no one else could have organized the large army of photographers needed to cover the broad sweep of the war and provided access to many leading generals and politicians.

Which of the following statements are true of Matthew Brady?
</description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o0>He was given permission to travel anywhere in the US.</o0>
      <o1>He was able to give his photographers introductions to politicians.</o1>
      <o2>He took as many as seven thousand pictures of the war.</o2>
      <o3>He was responsible for organizing a large number of photographers.</o3>
      <o4>Before the war he had been an amateur photographer.</o4>
    </options>
    <picture></picture>
    <answer>0|1|4</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>c41e267a5c5d4a3fa5a53ee59701ea25</id>
  <practiceSet>7b04cda952c144788c9d27aa2d5dc710</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_MULTIPLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct response. More than one response is correct.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Psychological researchers generally recognize that facial expressions reflect emotional states. In fact, various emotional states give rise to certain patterns of electrical activity in the facial muscles and in the brain. The facial-feedback hypothesis argues, however, that the causal relationship between emotions and facial expressions can also work in the opposite direction. According to this hypothesis, signals from the facial muscles ("feedback") are sent back to emotion centers of the brain, and so a person's facial expression can influence that person's emotional state. Consider Darwin's words: "The free expression by outward signs of an emotion intensifies it. On the other hand, the repression, as far as possible, of all outward signs softens our emotions." Can smiling give rise to feelings of good will, for example, and frowning to anger?

According to the passage, what did Darwin believe would happen to human emotions that were not expressed?
</description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o0>They would become less intense.</o0>
      <o1>They would last longer than usual.</o1>
      <o2>They would cause problems later.</o2>
      <o3>They would soften our emotions.</o3>
    </options>
    <picture></picture>
    <answer>0|3</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>e6e5339edc48428f8f70ba75e3bb45de</id>
  <practiceSet>7b04cda952c144788c9d27aa2d5dc710</practiceSet>
  <type>REORDER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description></description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o1>However, the authorities there aren’t ready to rest on their laurels, and they’ve decided to carry through a real revolution in their school system.</o1>
      <o2>Finnish officials want to remove school subjects from the curriculum.</o2>
      <o3>There will no longer be any classes in physics, math, literature, history, or geography.</o3>
      <o4>Finland’s education system is considered one of the best in the world.</o4>
      <o5>In international ratings, it’s always in the top ten.</o5>
    </options>
    <answer>3|4|0|1|2</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>e414cbfad0814362bc8d5f370ba74a69</id>
  <practiceSet>7b04cda952c144788c9d27aa2d5dc710</practiceSet>
  <type>REORDER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description></description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o1>The situations in which violence occurs and the nature of that violence tends to be clearly defined at least in theory, as in the proverbial Irishman’s question: ‘Is this a private fight or can anyone join in?</o1>
      <o2>So the actual risk to outsiders, though no doubt higher than our societies, is calculable.</o2>
      <o3>Probably the only uncontrolled applications of force are those of social superiors to social inferiors and even here there are probably some rules.</o3>
      <o4>However binding the obligation to kill, members of feuding families engaged in mutual massacre will be genuinely appalled if by some mischance a bystander or outsider is killed.</o4>
    </options>
    <answer>3|0|1|2</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>1c446b854f074dc588db7eab64b0c8b2</id>
  <practiceSet>7b04cda952c144788c9d27aa2d5dc710</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>In his 1874 science {blank} tale The Mysterious Island, Jules Verne predicted, "Water will be the coal of the future." It is a vision of infinite clean energy available for people to use. More than 30 years ago, Japanese scientists took a seminal step in that direction. With a piece of titanium dioxide and some sunlight, they split water into hydrogen and oxygen. Although researchers have tried to {blank} the process over the years, nobody has come up with a system that is both {blank} and inexpensive enough to produce sufficient hydrogen for use as a clean-burning fuel on the roads, in industry, and at home. Recently, however, researchers have picked up the {blank} of their pursuit of the ultimate water-splitting system.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>strained</o0>
        <o1>pace</o1>
        <o2>refine</o2>
        <o3>fictional</o3>
        <o4>efficient</o4>
        <o5>expensive</o5>
        <o6>fiction</o6>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>6|2|4|1</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>c6ffe490568b4dca9a1a2ad25acb8e09</id>
  <practiceSet>7b04cda952c144788c9d27aa2d5dc710</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>{blank} by the efficiency with which plants convert sunlight into sugar, researchers have fabricated a solar cell that uses photosynthetic proteins to convert light into electricity. Although the prototype device can't yet {blank} commercial solar cells made of silicon, it demonstrates a new strategy for making longer-lasting photovoltaic cells. To make the solar cell, a team of biologists and engineers led by Marc Baldo of the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) {blank} photosynthetic proteins from spinach and the bacterium Rhodobacter sphaeroides and deposited the proteins onto a glass support. Because the proteins naturally reside in an aqueous environment inside a cell membrane, it took some {blank} chemistry to keep the approximately 2 billion isolated proteins functional on a solid surface.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>rival</o0>
        <o1>desired</o1>
        <o2>reaping</o2>
        <o3>harvested</o3>
        <o4>inspired</o4>
        <o5>artistic</o5>
        <o6>creative</o6>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>4|0|3|6</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>420648602a6c40109e9299b42118c0e5</id>
  <practiceSet>7b04cda952c144788c9d27aa2d5dc710</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Scientists {blank} the phenomenon of magnetic resonance (MR) in the 1940s and used it initially for determining chemical structures. Then, in the 1970s, Paul C. Lauterbur, a chemist at the State University of New York in Stony Brook, added a second set of magnets to an MR device. This development led to instruments capable of {blank} images. Lauterbur, who is now at the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, finessed the technique so that it could yield more-detailed, two-dimensional images that {blank} differences between tissues that have varying water concentrations. The work has earned him a share of the prize.
</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>generating</o0>
        <o1>invented</o1>
        <o2>creating</o2>
        <o3>picturing</o3>
        <o4>discovered</o4>
        <o5>portrayed</o5>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>4|0|5</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>a36ca036595c4452918d90b280a2e6f3</id>
  <practiceSet>7b04cda952c144788c9d27aa2d5dc710</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>A popular tree grows twice as well in the New York metropolitan {blank} as in rural New York State, according to a new test. Clones of an Eastern cottonwood (Populus deltoides) in the Bronx and other city spots grew to double the biomass of clones planted outside small towns upstate or on Long Island, says Jillian Gregg, now of the Environmental Protection Agency's western-ecology division in Corvallis, Ore. The {blank} gap comes from ozone damage, she and her New York colleagues report. Ozone chemists have known that {blank} may spike skyscraper high in city air, but during a full 24 hours, rural trees actually get a higher cumulative ozone exposure from urban pollution that blows in and lingers. A series of new experiments now shows that this hang-around ozone is the {blank} factor in tree growth, the researchers say in the July 10 Nature.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>explosion</o0>
        <o1>slump</o1>
        <o2>overwhelming</o2>
        <o3>sprawl</o3>
        <o4>growth</o4>
        <o5>conditions</o5>
        <o6>concentrations</o6>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>3|4|6|2</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>0297c9710ad1491aab934d9ec35da15b</id>
  <practiceSet>7b04cda952c144788c9d27aa2d5dc710</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Most students {blank} legal studies will have some experience of crime, whether directly, as a victim of crime or indirectly through exposure to media coverage. This means that most offenses covered on the syllabus, such as murder, theft and rage will be familiar terms. This tends to give students the impression that they know more about criminal law than they do about other subjects on the syllabus. This can be a real disadvantage in terms of the academic study of criminal law because it tends to lead students to rely on {blank} notions of the nature and scope of the offenses and to reach instinctive, but often legally inaccurate, conclusions. It is absolutely {blank} to success in criminal law that you put aside any prior knowledge of the offenses and focus on the principles of law derived from statutes and cases. By doing this you will soon {blank} just how much difference there is between everyday conceptions of crime and its actuality.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>completed</o0>
        <o1>started</o1>
        <o2>have commenced</o2>
        <o3>commencing</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>preconceived</o0>
        <o1>preconceive</o1>
        <o2>preconceiving</o2>
        <o3>precocity</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>main</o0>
        <o1>concerning</o1>
        <o2>essential</o2>
        <o3>majorly</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>understand</o0>
        <o1>cherish</o1>
        <o2>regarding</o2>
        <o3>appreciate</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>3|0|2|3</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>4cb8a391280d447791098826b5687afe</id>
  <practiceSet>7b04cda952c144788c9d27aa2d5dc710</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Although some prevention efforts have succeeded, many analysts believe that the {blank} solution to the global AIDS crisis is the development of a vaccine that will prevent people from {blank} AIDS in the first place. Many researchers believe that the development of a v vaccine is possible and absolutely necessary in order to eradicate AIDS. However, many pharmaceutical companies do not want to invest in AIDS vaccine research because of the large expense involved and the belief that profits could not be made on the vaccines. Funding for research to develop an AIDS vaccine comes from several sources, mainly the International AIDS Vaccine Initiative (IAVI), UNAIDS, the U.S. National Institutes of Health (NIH), U.S. government agencies, and a few multinational pharmaceutical companies. In the {blank} , AIDS continues to spread in the developing world. Although successes have occurred, many experts contend that much more needs to be done. They argue that the {blank} to AIDS needs to be of greater duration, greater quality, and greater scope to reach the many areas of life which AIDS touches and affects. </description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>first</o0>
        <o1>next</o1>
        <o2>intermediate</o2>
        <o3>important</o3>
        <o4>ultimate</o4>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>passing</o0>
        <o1>repelling</o1>
        <o2>contracting</o2>
        <o3>suffering</o3>
        <o4>useful</o4>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>remedial</o0>
        <o1>curative</o1>
        <o2>antidote</o2>
        <o3>preventive</o3>
        <o4>corrective </o4>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>interim</o0>
        <o1>ultimate</o1>
        <o2>period</o2>
        <o3>instance</o3>
        <o4>meanwhile</o4>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>response</o0>
        <o1>cure</o1>
        <o2>prevention</o2>
        <o3>reply</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>4|2|3|4|0</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>0fe9fb7de1b74e1882f21bb07f52e602</id>
  <practiceSet>7b04cda952c144788c9d27aa2d5dc710</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>The savage, in spite of his membership of a small {blank} , lived a life in which his initiative was not too much hampered by the community. The things that he wanted to do, usually hunting and war, were also the things that his neighbours wanted to do, and if he felt an inclination to become a medicine man he only had to ingratiate himself with some individual already {blank} in that profession, and so, in due course, to succeed to his powers of magic. If he was a man of exceptional talent, he might invent some improvement in weapons, or a new {blank} in hunting. These would not put him into any opposition to the community, but on the contrary, would be welcomed. The modern man lives a very different life. If he sings in the street he will be thought to be {blank} and if he dances a policeman will reprove him for impeding the traffic.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>families</o0>
        <o1>kingdom</o1>
        <o2>community</o2>
        <o3>country</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>ignorant</o0>
        <o1>duped</o1>
        <o2>joined</o2>
        <o3>eminent</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>skill</o0>
        <o1>technology</o1>
        <o2>management</o2>
        <o3>device</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>sinning</o0>
        <o1>drunk</o1>
        <o2>childlike</o2>
        <o3>singer</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>3|3|0|1</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>4288457f511f46b590c9ae9f3da5da11</id>
  <practiceSet>7b04cda952c144788c9d27aa2d5dc710</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>The Chinese worked on the Great Wall for over 1700 years. In turn, all emperors who came to power added pieces of the wall to protect their {blank} . But the wall was not a solid wall. It was a line of {blank} barricades. First Emperor Oin wanted a much better barricade to protect his people from the Mongol invaders to the north. He wanted a {blank} wall 30 feet wide and 50 feet high. First Emperor Qin used peasants, captured enemies, criminals, scholars, and anyone else who irritated him, and put them all to work building the Great Wall. Laborers were not paid for their work. It was {blank} labor.  About 3000 people worked on the wall during the Qin Dynasty. Rocks fell on people. Walls caved in. Workers died of exhaustion and {blank} . Laborers were fed only enough food to keep them alive. There is an old Chinese saying, “Each stone in the wall represents a life lost in the wall’s construction.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>families</o0>
        <o1>society</o1>
        <o2>dynasties</o2>
        <o3>country </o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>divided</o0>
        <o1>disconnected</o1>
        <o2>joined</o2>
        <o3>made </o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>strong</o0>
        <o1>ideal</o1>
        <o2>sound</o2>
        <o3>perfect </o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>slave</o0>
        <o1>captive</o1>
        <o2>victim</o2>
        <o3>servant</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>disease</o0>
        <o1>virus</o1>
        <o2>epidemic</o2>
        <o3>fever </o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>2|1|0|0|3</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>a47dea3635c549bc9eed96b82cbd780e</id>
  <practiceSet>7b04cda952c144788c9d27aa2d5dc710</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>At the corporate level, businesses need to ask themselves {blank} questions such as ‘Which business should we be in?’ At the business level, a business needs to ask itself. ‘How do we {blank} ?’ It is at this latter level that we position our thinking. The organization has decided that it will compete in a certain market and is seeking ways to optimize what it should do in pursuing its goals, in other words, what its strategy should be. How we think about business strategy, has evolved and changed as new and better ideas have become more widely {blank} and accepted as the needs of business have also changed. Business strategy has had many definitions but these are two that give a sense of what is involved, {blank} of where we are in time: Strategy is about matching the competencies of the organization to its environment. A strategy describes how an organization aims to meet its objectives’. </description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>elementary</o0>
        <o1>structural </o1>
        <o2>commercial </o2>
        <o3>fundamental </o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>compete</o0>
        <o1>survive</o1>
        <o2>engage</o2>
        <o3>brilliant</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>appraised</o0>
        <o1>rewarded</o1>
        <o2>known</o2>
        <o3>acknowledged</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>inspite</o0>
        <o1>despite</o1>
        <o2>irrespective</o2>
        <o3>aware</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>3|0|2|2</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<!-- Test 5 -->
<question>
  <id>b5d8bc0e545044499557b8084809c506</id>
  <practiceSet>d9d885229cf64aceb84b19095b1ffd9c</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>There was a/an {blank} when the summit of Mount Everest was about as isolated as you could get, but now climbers who reach the roof of the world will be able to pause to check their {blank} or perhaps surf the internet. A Nepalese telecommunications company has {blank} a 3G mobile phone network around the mountain and says its coverage will even reach the summit. Ncell says the installation of base stations along the {blank} to the mountain has, for the first time, brought a mobile data service to local people, tourists and climbers. When Edmund Hillary and Sherpa Tenzing reached Everest's summit in 1953, expedition leaders had to send runners to carry {blank} to the nearest telegraph office. Satellite, then mobile voice phones have since helped {blank} travel faster, but now a station near Everest base camp in the Khumbu valley has heralded a communications revolution in the Himalayan country, Ncell's parent company, the Swedish-based TeliaSonera, says.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>time</o0>
        <o1>year</o1>
        <o2>occasion</o2>
        <o3>opportunity</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>emails</o0>
        <o1>cards</o1>
        <o2>letters</o2>
        <o3>phones</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>installed</o0>
        <o1>created</o1>
        <o2>built</o2>
        <o3>constituted</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>way</o0>
        <o1>route</o1>
        <o2>track</o2>
        <o3>road</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>letters</o0>
        <o1>script</o1>
        <o2>telegram</o2>
        <o3>messages</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>news</o0>
        <o1>report</o1>
        <o2>message</o2>
        <o3>bulletin</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>0|0|0|1|3|0</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>ed385c9f8f5b41c1ae26fd2ced9fd3c0</id>
  <practiceSet>d9d885229cf64aceb84b19095b1ffd9c</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Before the start of World War I, the Gibson girl was the rage; she did not date, and waited until a proper young man {blank} to her for marriage. However, nearly a whole generation of young men had died in the War leaving a whole {blank} of young women without desirable suitors. They decided not to waste away their young lives waiting idly for spinsterhood but to enjoy life. The new women broke away from the set conventions, turned fashionable, they {blank} the black wool stockings and became crazy about new fashions, wore rayon stockings, feet, ankles, and calves formerly hidden were now on show. Scott Fitzgerald referred to them as a “whole race going hedonistic deciding on pleasure”. The famous film star Louise Brooks became the ideal for young girls, Brook’s exuberant social life, her contacts with the wealthy and her {blank} lifestyle inspired young women to break away from the Victorian traditions of repression and conventionality. The Victorian cult of true womanhood preached “piety and purity” as the cardinal virtues for women. They were supposed to follow the dictates of men and domesticity was the chief ideal to be {blank} to maintain chastity and purity.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>proposed</o0>
        <o1>rejected</o1>
        <o2>denied</o2>
        <o3>agreed</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>creation</o0>
        <o1>lot</o1>
        <o2>society</o2>
        <o3>generation</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>adopted</o0>
        <o1>created</o1>
        <o2>discarded</o2>
        <o3>brought forth</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>lavish</o0>
        <o1>conservative</o1>
        <o2>superficial</o2>
        <o3>ignored</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>shunned</o0>
        <o1>traced</o1>
        <o2>pursued</o2>
        <o3>glamorous</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>0|3|2|0|2</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>f635e1e321a74dcfbec5e091e7a4a51d</id>
  <practiceSet>d9d885229cf64aceb84b19095b1ffd9c</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Millions of people suffering osteoporosis could be {blank} by playing a ‘quiet musical note’ to stem cells in their body, coaxing them into healthy bone, scientists hope. British scientists are about to {blank} on the first human trials of a ground breaking new therapy called ‘nanokicking’ which spurs stem cells into action by blasting them with low frequency vibrations. It could also help protect astronauts whose bones {blank} in microgravity, paving the way for lengthy trips to the Moon or Mars. The technique was discovered by Scottish researchers in 2016, who were struggling to make stem cells turn into bone cells despite recreating all the same conditions within the body. They {blank} found that what was missing was the quiet internal hum of around 1000Hz, which when recreated, turned stem cells into bones at around 28 days. Now scientists plan to test it on patients suffering from spinal injuries whose bones have deteriorated through lack of use.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>curing</o0>
        <o1>damaging</o1>
        <o2>damaged</o2>
        <o3>cured</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>cease</o0>
        <o1>embark</o1>
        <o2>disembark</o2>
        <o3>finish</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>deteriorate</o0>
        <o1>elevate</o1>
        <o2>improve</o2>
        <o3>assist</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>eventually</o0>
        <o1>unexpectedly</o1>
        <o2>mainly</o2>
        <o3>extremely</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>3|1|0|0</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>8152899d6ffd4f1c830dc07ad35dc76c</id>
  <practiceSet>d9d885229cf64aceb84b19095b1ffd9c</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Many of us have become aware that statistically, the majority of Americans are overweight. Although we hear this often in the media, not everybody may realize the implications of this fact for health care and ultimately for our national economy. Not only is excess weight associated with heart disease, a number of different cancers, and other problems; it especially is associated with diabetes. In 2011, 28.5 million of American citizens had diabetes. An additional 66 million Americans had pre-diabetic symptoms. In 2011, medical costs for diabetics were $174 billion per year. Research from a health insurance company projected that by 2020, diabetes would cost America $3.4 trillion per year. The federal government would pay over 60% of that total. Accordingly, some organizations have recommended that losing weight by reducing our intake of high-calorie foods could help save the government money by lowering the risk, and hence the incidence, of diabetes. As a result, improving our physical health also can improve our fiscal health.

Which of the following statements best expresses the main idea of this passage?
</description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o0>More than 28 million Americans had diabetes in 2011.</o0>
      <o1>Losing weight reduces diabetes risk, thereby saving government expense.</o1>
      <o2>The federal deficit must be reduced to allow for medical expense.</o2>
      <o3>Diabetes has become an American epidemic unrelated to weight.</o3>
    </options>
    <picture></picture>
    <answer>1</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>dfcf42a008eb41f4b3e4ad403d6f4cd1</id>
  <practiceSet>d9d885229cf64aceb84b19095b1ffd9c</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Not surprisingly, the crime victims are often called upon to identify the person who robbed or attacked them. For a jury, the victim’s testimony is often proof positive that the accused is guilty. After all, who can better identify the wrongdoer than the person harmed. This is just common sense. Yet as is so often the case, common sense can be misleading. As it turns out, crime victims don’t necessarily make reliable witnesses. Overcome with fear, they often close their eyes or focus fixedly on the weapon being used to threaten them. As a result, they don’t get a good look at the thief or attacker. While it’s not true that crime victim testimony is always inaccurate, it’s also true that one can’t assume a victim’s identification is automatic proof of guilt.

Which of the following most accurately summarizes the opinion of the author in the text?</description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o0>Crime victims do not always correctly identify those who have harmed them.</o0>
      <o1>Crime victim testimony is almost always inaccurate because during the crime, the victim was overcome with terror.</o1>
      <o2>The testimony of crime victims has put far too many people in jail.</o2>
    </options>
    <picture></picture>
    <answer>0</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>e9890475df674bf0a26fc017f893ae1c</id>
  <practiceSet>d9d885229cf64aceb84b19095b1ffd9c</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_MULTIPLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct response. More than one response is correct.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>A Close look at the facts relating to political interference in administration shows that it is not a one-way process. There is often a nexus between power hungry and corrupt politicians and civil servants with convenient principles. Many civil servants are only too anxious to oblige the politicians, and then cash the obligation when they need some special favour. So the attitude of self-righteousness adopted by the civil service is sometimes only a way of covering their own flaws by blaming others.
Every now and then some retired civil servants come out with his memoirs, painting a glorious picture of the heights of administrative efficiency reached during his reign. There is often the suggestion that had there not been so much political interference, things would have been even more fantastic. It is not unusual for the self styled hero to blame not only interfering politicians but also fellow civil servants who are idiots or crooks, for his failures. This attitude of smug self-satisfaction is, unfortunately, developed during the years of service. Self preservation rather than service is encouraged by our whole system of rules and procedures.
The remedy has to be drastic and quickly effective. The over protection now granted to civil servants must end. Today to remove an erring civil servant is just not possible. And the only thing that the highest authority in the Government, both in the State and at the Centre, can do is to transfer an official from one job to another. The rules for taking disciplinary action are so complicated that, in the end, the defaulting civil servants gets away, and gets his full emoluments even for the period of the disciplinary proceedings, thus making it a paid holiday for him.
The result is that the administration has become rule-oriented and not result-oriented. Action is possible against the official who takes some interest in his work, but no action is ever taken against a person who does not deliver the goods. If the country is to adopt a result-oriented approach, it is necessary to link job performance with job retention.

The facts relating to the problem of political interference indicate that:
</description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o0>honest bureaucrats are always being troubled by politicians.</o0>
      <o1>politicians are often misled and trapped by civil servants.</o1>
      <o2>politicians and civil servants co-operate to gain mutual advantages.</o2>
      <o3>politicians and civil servants use interference as an excuse for victimising the common man.</o3>
      <o4>one-way process</o4>
    </options>
    <picture></picture>
    <answer>2|4</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>fc020e1be9e64bedba2ab6dd5beaed02</id>
  <practiceSet>d9d885229cf64aceb84b19095b1ffd9c</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_MULTIPLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct response. More than one response is correct.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Since the 1980s, a standard treatment for diabetic patients has been injections of insulin produced by genetically engineered bacteria. While effective, this type of treatment requires great effort by the patient and can generate large swings in blood sugar levels.
In patients suffering from Type 1 diabetes, the immune system attacks the pancreas, eventually leaving patients without the ability to naturally control blood sugar. These patients must carefully monitor the amount of sugar in their blood, measuring it several times a day and then injecting themselves with insulin to keep their blood sugar levels within a healthy range, which is a challenge for many reasons. Now researchers report that encapsulated pancreatic cells offer possible new diabetes treatment.
The researchers now plan to further test their new materials in nonhuman primates, with the goal of eventually performing clinical trials in diabetic patients. If successful, this approach could provide long-term blood sugar control for such patients. "Our goal is to continue to work hard to translate these promising results into a therapy that can help people," Anderson says.
"Being insulin-independent is the goal," Vegas says. "This would be a state-of-the-art way of doing that, better than any other technology could. Cells are able to detect glucose and release insulin far better than any piece of technology we've been able to develop."
The researchers are also investigating why their new material works so well. They found that the best-performing materials were all modified with molecules containing a triazole group -- a ring containing two carbon atoms and three nitrogen atoms. They suspect this class of molecules may interfere with the immune system's ability to recognize the material as foreign.

Aim of the passage is:
</description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o0>to have insulin-independent diabetic treatment</o0>
      <o1>cells should detect glucose</o1>
      <o2>a standard treatment for diabetic patients</o2>
      <o3>modified with molecules</o3>
    </options>
    <picture></picture>
    <answer>0|2</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>fe09b8228f1548a89ba24ab079f8e000</id>
  <practiceSet>d9d885229cf64aceb84b19095b1ffd9c</practiceSet>
  <type>REORDER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description></description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o1>But this does not mean that death was the Egyptians’ only preoccupation.</o1>
      <o2>Even papyri come mainly from pyramid temples.</o2>
      <o3>Most of our traditional sources of information about the Old Kingdom are monuments of the rich like pyramids and tombs.</o3>
      <o4>Houses in which ordinary Egyptians lived have not been preserved, and when most people died they were buried in simple graves.</o4>
      <o5>We know infinitely more about the wealthy people of Egypt than we do about the ordinary people, as most monuments were made for the rich.</o5>
    </options>
    <answer>4|3|2|1|0</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>c3970b6fac144bf4b3ae19470700a52a</id>
  <practiceSet>d9d885229cf64aceb84b19095b1ffd9c</practiceSet>
  <type>REORDER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description></description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o1>In the case of King Merolchazzar’s courtship of the Princess of the Outer Isles, there occurs a regrettable hitch.</o1>
      <o2>She acknowledges the gifts, but no word of a meeting date follows.</o2>
      <o3>The monarch, hearing good reports of a neighbouring princess, dispatches messengers with gifts to her court, beseeching an interview.</o3>
      <o4>The princess names a date, and a formal meeting takes place; after that everything buzzes along pretty smoothly.</o4>
      <o5>Royal love affairs in olden days were conducted on the correspondence method.</o5>
    </options>
    <answer>4|2|3|0|1</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>43f4efd1489b45ae9350ca75c313ebd7</id>
  <practiceSet>d9d885229cf64aceb84b19095b1ffd9c</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Neanderthals had the intelligence to build and use hunting {blank} that kept them at a safe distance from their prey, archaeologists have found. The discovery was made after scientists at University College London made replicas of 300,000-year-old spears and trained javelin athletes to throw them. They {blank} that the weapons could hit a target at a range of 20 metres with easily enough force to kill a large animal. The finding, published in the {blank} Scientific Reports, further rescues the reputation of the Neanderthal from that of a brutish, unsophisticated early cousin to Homo sapien. It {blank} recent studies which suggested Neanderthalslived as part of supportive social networks, were capable of art, and, contrary to the stereotype, stood up straighter than modern-day humans. The replica handmade javelins were modeled on the Schonigen spears - the {blank} complete set of weapons ever discovered - which were unearthed from an open-cast lignite mine in Germany in the 1990s, along with 16,000 animal bones.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>established</o0>
        <o1>ancient</o1>
        <o2>follows</o2>
        <o3>tool</o3>
        <o4>oldest</o4>
        <o5>weapons</o5>
        <o6>journal</o6>
        <o7>magazine</o7>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>5|0|6|2|4</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>de48e2d41f0b4c8cb359ecc70c2ed5aa</id>
  <practiceSet>d9d885229cf64aceb84b19095b1ffd9c</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>{blank} people should not act as if they are “morally superior” to those struggling with their weight because the likelihood is they simply have lucky genes, new research has found. A groundbreaking study by Cambridge University, which focused on healthy adults with a low body mass index (BMI), {blank} the impact of genetics on body size is greater than previously thought. The results help explain the considerable variation in weight within a population that shares the same high-calorie environment and {blank} lifestyle, the scientists said. The study examined 1,622 thin but healthy volunteers with a BMI of no less than 18, making it the first to examine this group of people in such detail. From saliva samples, the team was able to carry out DNA analysis which revealed {blank} unknown regions of the human genome associated with healthy thinness. They also established that approximately three quarters of people in this cohort had a {blank} history of being thin.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>obese</o0>
        <o1>sedentary</o1>
        <o2>family</o2>
        <o3>skinny</o3>
        <o4>past</o4>
        <o5>reveals</o5>
        <o6>close</o6>
        <o7>previously</o7>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>3|5|1|7|2</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>8ba8ee75a49b46dc98b2f8ddba29aa00</id>
  <practiceSet>d9d885229cf64aceb84b19095b1ffd9c</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Freud was an Austrian neurologist and his psychoanalytical theories had a great {blank} on art, literature, philosophy and criticism. He propounded {blank} of the unconscious mind, mechanism of repression and value of dreams to {blank} the mystery of unconscious desires. Freud’s research concentrated on association, dream {blank} and the hidden conscious.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>exclude</o0>
        <o1>comprehend</o1>
        <o2>impact</o2>
        <o3>reasons</o3>
        <o4>theories</o4>
        <o5>analysis</o5>
        <o6>lesson</o6>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>2|4|1|5</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>6fd74d81d85b4087a99db53ce4ceb4fe</id>
  <practiceSet>d9d885229cf64aceb84b19095b1ffd9c</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>A huge fish that is impervious to piranha attacks could become the {blank} for a new class of ultra-tough composite materials. Its scales are so tough that piranha teeth crack when they {blank} down onto them. Each scale is coated with a rock-hard mineral material, but they have soft {blank} made from strings of stretchy protein. The fish is called the Arapaima, and it's {blank} to Brazil.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>thrill</o0>
        <o1>inspiration</o1>
        <o2>alien</o2>
        <o3>chomp</o3>
        <o4>cores</o4>
        <o5>exterior</o5>
        <o6>native</o6>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>1|3|4|6</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>95c85824cb4d48f6a9254ff5c0cac66c</id>
  <practiceSet>d9d885229cf64aceb84b19095b1ffd9c</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>The environment we are in {blank} our moods, ability to {blank} relationships, effectiveness in work or play -even our health. In addition, the early childhood group environment has a very {blank} role in children’s learning and development. </description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>negative</o0>
        <o1>affects</o1>
        <o2>mitigates</o2>
        <o3>form</o3>
        <o4>try</o4>
        <o5>crucial</o5>
        <o6>stress</o6>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>1|3|5</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<!-- Test 6  -->
<question>
  <id>22b8a38cd6a34522927edce20392bce3</id>
  <practiceSet>5dcbc550333c488996e65d41dad0bfe7</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each . To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Gum disease may play a pivotal role in the {blank} of Alzheimer’s disease, scientists believe, leading to hopes that good dental care or drugs could stave off or halt dementia. Researchers said they now had ‘solid evidence’ that the bacteria which causes periodontitis produces an enzyme which destroys neurons leading to memory loss. The bacteria Porphyromonas gingivalis ( P. gingivalis) is one of the chief causes of gum disease and tooth loss in humans, and has {blank} been associated with heart problems. In a series of experiments, an international team of researchers tested the brains of 53 people with Alzheimer’s and found the bacteria enzyme in 96 per cent. DNA evidence of the bacteria was also found in spinal fluid from seven out of 10 living patients {blank} with Alzheimer's, and it was also present in the saliva of each one.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>previously</o0>
        <o1>growth</o1>
        <o2>earlier</o2>
        <o3>development</o3>
        <o4>diagnosed</o4>
        <o5>exposed</o5>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>3|0|4</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>b7f5188b23f54ce3abbe9e9a9fb00bc4</id>
  <practiceSet>5dcbc550333c488996e65d41dad0bfe7</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each . To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Farmers have been {blank} to loan their rare breeds of cow to a conservation charity so they can grow embryos through IVF and create an ‘ark’ of endangered British cattle. The Rare Breeds Survival Trust has been building a genetic bank since the 1970s, but new technology is now also {blank} them to store animal embryos, which could be implanted if a species becomes extinct. Now they are looking for farmers to loan breeds including Albion, Native Aberdeen Angus, Irish Moiled, Traditional Hereford and White Park. There are fewer than 1500 of each species left, and for some critically {blank} breeds, like the Albion there are just 170 animals remaining. RBST Field Officer Richard Broad said:  “The underlying reason for creating the Gene Bank was to ensure that, given the worst-case scenario of total loss of a breed, we would have sufficient genetics in store to {blank} that breed. “Originally, the only way to do this was to collect semen.  However, science has made enormous strides and it has become both {blank} and scientifically viable to collect and freeze embryos.”
</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>allowing</o0>
        <o1>compelled</o1>
        <o2>recreate</o2>
        <o3>develop</o3>
        <o4>create</o4>
        <o5>economical</o5>
        <o6>urged</o6>
        <o7>endangered</o7>
        <o8>financially </o8>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>6|0|7|2|8</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>b9889b2b38684d6692a4ea4b23ff1db2</id>
  <practiceSet>5dcbc550333c488996e65d41dad0bfe7</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each . To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>The theory that breakfast is the most {blank} meal of the day may not hold true, research suggests. The study, published in the British Medical Journal, found that those who eat breakfast consume {blank} more calories than those who skip the meal - and end up weighing more. For decades, health experts have {blank} people not to miss breakfast, with warnings that those trying to keep their weight down by missing a meal will simply end up snacking more later.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>Huge</o0>
        <o1>exhorted</o1>
        <o2>majorly</o2>
        <o3>significantly</o3>
        <o4>extremely</o4>
        <o5>discouraged</o5>
        <o6>important</o6>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>6|3|1</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>30a4c427cca74434a240254cf501eaa4</id>
  <practiceSet>5dcbc550333c488996e65d41dad0bfe7</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each . To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>General purpose technologies reshape the nature of production and service activities {blank} . They open up new opportunities and {blank} reorganization of production. They share characteristics like {blank} and applicability across a range of uses and potential for use in a variety of products and processes. They alter the skill mix in the economy by biasing it towards higher skilled people. </description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>obstruct</o0>
        <o1>necessitate </o1>
        <o2>irreversibly </o2>
        <o3>disfigurement </o3>
        <o4>factories </o4>
        <o5>elaboration </o5>
        <o6>straightaway</o6>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>2|1|5</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>7621f678bc96403096bb7c6859de49d0</id>
  <practiceSet>5dcbc550333c488996e65d41dad0bfe7</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each . To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>In the 18th century postal system was {blank} ; the coffee houses provided a place for {blank} news and information. Information was gathered from these coffee houses on the major {blank} of the day, victories or defeats in battles or other political upheavals. Sales, auctions, deals, appointments, transfers, were made on the coffee tables by the {blank} of London. </description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>Listening</o0>
        <o1>communicating</o1>
        <o2>private</o2>
        <o3>elite</o3>
        <o4>occasions</o4>
        <o5>events</o5>
        <o6>festivals</o6>
        <o7>unorganized</o7>
        <o8>worst</o8>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>7|1|5|3</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>c6dbcb5d5042413a89b3f3275be44f9f</id>
  <practiceSet>5dcbc550333c488996e65d41dad0bfe7</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct response. More than one response is correct.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Jupiter has 2.5 times more mass than all the other planets of the solar system combined and is 11 times as large as Earth in diameter. Jupiter is so large that scientists believe it almost became a star: as the gasses and dust contracted to the form the planet, gravitational forces created tremendous pressure and the temperature inside the core—as high as tens of thousands of degrees. But there was not enough mass available to create the temperature needed to start a fusion reaction such as that of the Sun (above 27,000,000 Fahrenheit, or 15,000,000 Celsius, at the Sun’s core); thus Jupiter has been cooling down ever since. Even so, Jupiter radiates about as much heat as it receives from the Sun.

The passage is mainly concerned with</description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o0>the size of Jupiter relative to other planets in the solar system</o0>
      <o1>differences between the sun and Jupiter</o1>
      <o2>how Jupiter’s mass has affected its development</o2>
      <o3>the temperature at which a planet’s core can start a fusion reaction</o3>
    </options>
    <picture></picture>
    <answer>2</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>ba5dfa584179471bbb5db5025c14d452</id>
  <practiceSet>5dcbc550333c488996e65d41dad0bfe7</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct response. More than one response is correct.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Stump-Up was invented in 1986 by Tokyo Beverages Owner Okawa Bhery. The name for the product was actually proposed by Okawa’s assistant, Fizzy Brewndon. The name was taken from the two most unusual ingredients in the drink, the Canadian banana leaf and the Asian stump root. The recipe for today’s Stump-Up is very well guarded. Many of the ingredients are known; in addition to banana leaves and stump root, they include strawberry, cocoa, lemon, cinnamon, nuts, vanilla, caramel, salts and sugar. The proportions of the ingredients and the identity of Stump’s secret ingredients are known by only a few of the Stump-Up Company’s very senior scientists and Vice-Presidents.

It can be inferred from the passage that</description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o0>No one knows the exact proportions of ingredients used in Stump-Ups.</o0>
      <o1>The public does not know how many stump roots are used in a batch of Stump-Ups.</o1>
      <o2>The public is not sure that banana leaves are used in Stump-Ups.</o2>
      <o3>The public knows all the ingredients in Stump-Ups.</o3>
    </options>
    <picture></picture>
    <answer>1</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>6751292f7fa5442b94bce18661b716f6</id>
  <practiceSet>5dcbc550333c488996e65d41dad0bfe7</practiceSet>
  <type>REORDER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description></description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o1>The situations in which violence occurs and the nature of that violence tends to be clearly defined at least in theory, as in the proverbial Irishman’s question: ‘Is this a private fight or can anyone join in?’</o1>
      <o2>So the actual risk to outsiders, though no doubt higher than our societies, is calculable.</o2>
      <o3>Probably the only uncontrolled applications of force are those of social superiors to social inferiors and even here there are probably some rules.</o3>
      <o4>However, binding the obligation to kill, members or feuding families engaged in mutual massacre will be genuinely appalled if by some mischance a bystander or outsider is killed.</o4>
    </options>
    <answer>0|2|3|1</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>0b68a17f66384dd3af509d6961aeab78</id>
  <practiceSet>5dcbc550333c488996e65d41dad0bfe7</practiceSet>
  <type>REORDER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description></description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o1>There is a strong manufacturing base for a variety of products.</o1>
      <o2>India has come a long way on the technology front.</o2>
      <o3>But the technology adopted has been largely of foreign origin.</o3>
      <o4>There are, however, areas such as atomic energy, space, agriculture, and defense where significant strides have been made in evolving relevant technologies within the country.</o4>
    </options>
    <answer>1|0|2|3</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>4d7686650b0b43b694dee9fddf71b7c9</id>
  <practiceSet>5dcbc550333c488996e65d41dad0bfe7</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_MULTIPLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct response. More than one response is correct.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Using infant mortality as a key indicator of the status of children, we now begin to have the broad features of a hypothesis as to the causes of higher or lower mortality rates. One aspect is the complex of factors involving the access of mothers to trained personnel and other facilities for child delivery, the nutritional status of pregnant and nursing mothers and the quality of health care and nourishment which babies receive.
The other aspect, indicated by rural-urban differentials, is the possible importance of human settlement patterns in relation to the availability of health care and related facilities such as potable water, excreta disposal systems, etc. Thus, in a special sense, it is much cheaper to make health and other basic services available to a community when it is densely settled rather than widely dispersed. It is possible to argue, however, that both these sets of factors are closely related to a third one, namely, income levels. Poorer mothers and babies have less access to health-care facilities and nourishment than those who are better off; urban communities are on an average much better off than rural communities.
That economic condition plays a crucial role in determining the status of both mother and child, is beyond dispute. But the question really is whether this is the only decisive factor or whether factors such as the availability of medical facilities, healthcare programs, and nutritional programs have an independent role. If so then the settlement patterns which affect service delivery to the mother and child target groups become a relevant consideration. These are clearly issues of some importance for policy and program planning.

Which among the following statements are correct?</description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o0>It is easy and economical to provide health care facilities in dense settlements.</o0>
      <o1>The fact that income has an important role to play in health care is arguable.</o1>
      <o2>A densely settled community has to be supplied with health and basic services after bearing a large cost.</o2>
      <o3>Mothers from well to do families can provide better care and facilities to their babies.</o3>
      <o4>The settlement conditions, income levels, and health facilities are the only influencing factors behind the varying mortality rates.</o4>
    </options>
    <picture></picture>
    <answer>0|3</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>af1f3867baae4946895e3cf525cdb34b</id>
  <practiceSet>5dcbc550333c488996e65d41dad0bfe7</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_MULTIPLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct response. More than one response is correct.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Until the mid-20th century, scientists believed that the chest cavity would implode at around 115 feet. Water pressure, they argued, reaches 65 pounds per square inch at that depth, which is enough to shrink lungs to the size of grapefruits and collapse rib cages like empty soda cans. Their theory went out the window in the 1950’s and early 1960’s, however, when divers like Enzo Maiorca returned from beyond 115-feet with rib cages intact. We now know that water pressure forces blood vessels in the chest to swell, filling the void left by the lungs with an incompressible fluid.
Among the dangers of free diving, the most disconcerting is shallow-water blackout—the brains frightening tendency to shut down within 15 feet of the surface during the ascent. As you descend, water pressure squeezes your lungs, condensing the oxygen and giving you what feels like a second breath. During the return trip, however, your lungs re-expand, dissipating whats left of your oxygen. If levels drop too low, not enough will move into the bloodstream, and the lights go out. Fortunately, the body’s laryngospasm reflex kicks in to tighten the throat and keep water out for up to a minute—just enough time for your dive buddy to drag you to the surface, tilt your head back, and beg, “Breathe, baby.”
Knowing Johnston will be there watching my eyes as I ascend (seeing them roll back in the head is a red flag), I dip below the surface. Staying in the syringe—dive speak for a tight hydrodynamic column—I kick down to 30 feet, my point of neutral buoyancy, and then sink effortlessly to the bottom. I feel good—surprisingly good—thanks to the densely packed oxygen molecules in my lungs.
Lingering a moment, I peer up at the mirrored surface that separates this liquid world from mine. Diving to 55 feet was no sweat. I figure I could dive twice that with a little practice, reaching what scientists thought, not 50 years ago, was the body’s depth limit. Today, however, that boundary has been pushed to at least 531 feet (the current no-limits world record), which begs the question: Just how deep can humans go? “We don’t know that yet,” says Lundgren, adding ominously. “But one day someone will find out

Which of the following is true in respect of the effect of water pressure on humans?
</description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o0>Scientists believed that the chest cavity would blow up at a depth of about 115 feet.</o0>
      <o1>Rib cages will collapse at the water pressure of 65 pounds per square inch.</o1>
      <o2>Blood vessels of the chest enlarge and fill the empty space left by lungs that have been compressed.</o2>
      <o3>It is now known that lungs will not shrink with the increase in water pressure.</o3>
      <o4>It is no longer believed that the chest cavity will cave in at a depth of about 115 feet.</o4>
    </options>
    <picture></picture>
    <answer>2|4</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>894a548ec9624a5586c7542138632777</id>
  <practiceSet>5dcbc550333c488996e65d41dad0bfe7</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each , a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each .</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>The island of Damas is a half-hour boat ride from the Chilean coast. On the island, it's dry and rocky. The Humboldt penguins that live there have no ice slopes to slide down in their black-tie apparel. {blank} , these desert penguins seek out caves to shade their eggs from the sun. If they can't find a spot beneath a boulder, they may {blank} into seabird dung. Sometimes, they nest inside a cactus. To see these penguins, visitors {blank} begin in La Serena, Chile. They drive 40 miles north on a main highway and then cut toward the coast on a gravel road that leads to the fishing village of Punta de Choros. Local fishermen there charge a fee to guide the tourists to Damas by boat. On the island, people are {blank} to walk into the caves where the penguins live. Anyone can watch a mother brooding an egg and snap a picture with a flash camera or a mobile phone.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>eventually</o0>
        <o1>Obviously</o1>
        <o2>Considerably</o2>
        <o3>Instead</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>hollowness</o0>
        <o1>solid</o1>
        <o2>burrow</o2>
        <o3>cave</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>finally</o0>
        <o1>rarely</o1>
        <o2>always</o2>
        <o3>usually</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>restricted</o0>
        <o1>compelled</o1>
        <o2>free</o2>
        <o3>usually </o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>3|2|3|2</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>c32028a7b292407794c100a08963cfe7</id>
  <practiceSet>5dcbc550333c488996e65d41dad0bfe7</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each , a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each .</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>With striking red, black, and white stripes {blank} its body, fins, and some dozen spines along its head, back, and sides, the red lionfish is at once beautiful and frightening. The football-shaped fish can grow up to 18 inches long and is {blank} to the touch. At smaller sizes, this subtropical fish from Asia is extremely popular for hobbyists with saltwater aquariums, but the red lionfish is a major worry to government biologists charged with protecting {blank} species in the wild. In the past decade or so, the lionfish has increasingly shown up along the U.S. coast from North Carolina to Florida, where it could spell big trouble for the domestic fish whose ranges it's {blank} . There are several scenarios by which this fish could have entered the coastal waters. Many biologists point to Hurricane Andrew in 1992 as the agent behind the first release. Its {blank} included an aquarium that had housed six red lionfish in a Miami home on Biscayne Bay. Several of the vividly striped survivors were spotted in the bay shortly thereafter.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>painting</o0>
        <o1>covering</o1>
        <o2>decorating</o2>
        <o3>designing</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>poisonous</o0>
        <o1>threat</o1>
        <o2>injurious</o2>
        <o3>atoxic</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>creditor</o0>
        <o1>withholder</o1>
        <o2>nonnative</o2>
        <o3>native</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>invading</o0>
        <o1>offensively</o1>
        <o2>palatable</o2>
        <o3>defensive</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>destruction</o0>
        <o1>humorless</o1>
        <o2>ruin</o2>
        <o3>continuance</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>2|0|3|0|0</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>37a674b2268e49d697bc4a63b3662eba</id>
  <practiceSet>5dcbc550333c488996e65d41dad0bfe7</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each , a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each .</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>On June 8th, 1924, two British climbers — Mallory and Irvine — were {blank} from below, clambering over one of the major remaining obstacles of their route. The summit of Mt. Everest was only a few hours away. Swirling mists closed in and they were never seen again. Their disappearence left unanswered a question that has {blank} mountaineers ever since: Had they reached the top? Even Sir Edmund Hillary — the first to certainly reach the top (and to return) — looked for signs of any possible predecessors. Early Everesters didn’t think so. Subsequent Pre WWII expeditions during better {blank} and with greater resources were thwarted by the immensity of the challenge. But one thing was left out of the early pessimistic assessments — the effect of the controversial use by the two climbers of “artificial” breathing oxygen. Many contemporaries felt its use was unsporting, and angrily discounted evidence to show that climbing speeds easily doubled with its use. The next expedition, that of 1933, retraced Mallory and Irvine’s steps and {blank} one of their ice axes some 250 yards from the First Step obstacle. For decades, that was the only other clue as to their fate. In the early 1970’s I studied the best available topographic maps of Mt. Everest, and noticed that the site of the ice axe lay above a large snow terrace. Would a falling climber come to rest on the “8200m Snow Terrace”? And if so, would the cameras each of them was known to be carrying, still hold the {blank} of how high they got? After extensive tests, Eastman Kodak thought “fully printable images” could be obtained if the camera was found intact.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>identical</o0>
        <o1>motley</o1>
        <o2>spotted</o2>
        <o3>assorted</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>haunted</o0>
        <o1>agitated</o1>
        <o2>agonized</o2>
        <o3>annoyed</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>climate</o0>
        <o1>weather</o1>
        <o2>condition</o2>
        <o3>atmosphere</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>invented</o0>
        <o1>discovered</o1>
        <o2>uncovered</o2>
        <o3>noticed</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>answer</o0>
        <o1>question</o1>
        <o2>reply</o2>
        <o3>puzzle</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>2|0|1|1|0</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>d97653b576d64c369ea9873c58c5b8dd</id>
  <practiceSet>5dcbc550333c488996e65d41dad0bfe7</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each , a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each .</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Culture has been a part of our society,  and way of life,  forever. It is almost {blank} to come up with an idea that isn’t {blank} by culture. Picture our lives without cars,  television,  and computers. This would be an example of everyday life without technology. People could function happily in that type of atmosphere,  but technology has changed our lives forever. Technology has changed our {blank} and perspective on education. Students would have to go to libraries and spend a lot of time researching to find out information for class assignments,  but with technology students can find almost anything on their home computers and by accessing the internet. Technology has definitely become the authoritative factor in our lives,  but culture has {blank} technology. Technology is made and used in such a variety of ways because many people who use the technology of today come from all walks of life and have different necessities,  so to compensate for that technology must adapt to all different cultures. </description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>important</o0>
        <o1>impossible</o1>
        <o2>immature</o2>
        <o3>immediate</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>effected</o0>
        <o1>affected</o1>
        <o2>influenced</o2>
        <o3>impressed</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>view</o0>
        <o1>behavior</o1>
        <o2>conduct</o2>
        <o3>pace</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>shaped</o0>
        <o1>opposed</o1>
        <o2>debased</o2>
        <o3>faced</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>1|2|3|0</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>252af61b13434f6eb5e1faeba4508a15</id>
  <practiceSet>5dcbc550333c488996e65d41dad0bfe7</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each , a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each .</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>The “Roaring Twenties” was a period when American economy flourished tremendously. The nation’s total realized income rose from $75 billion in 1923 to $90 billion in 1929. During the economic {blank} of the “Roaring Twenties”, Jazz age challenged the {blank} values of rural America, symbolized by women smoking, drinking and wearing short skirts. Fashion clubs,  kitty parties,  late night ballet dances were the common life styles of the rich classes and the middle classes were envying the rich to maintain the false respect in the society. The average Americans were busy buying household appliances, automobiles and investing money in the stock market to make huge profits. The American youth were {blank} to get rich overnight and the success mania boosted trade and commerce. The banks were liberal in granting loans and the easy liquidity propelled the bullish phase of the American stock market. Even the poor Americans raised money on loan and invested in the stock market for easy money earnings. The rewards of the 1920s “Coolidge Prosperity” were not equally shared among all Americans. Henry Ford and other business magnates were aware of the inequitable distribution of income between the rich and the poor. The {blank} point of the economy was visible but nobody dared to calculate the repercussions of the fallout. 
</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>depression</o0>
        <o1>cycles</o1>
        <o2>boom</o2>
        <o3>inflation</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>traditional</o0>
        <o1>ritual</o1>
        <o2>spiritual</o2>
        <o3>dilapidated</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>anxious</o0>
        <o1>particular</o1>
        <o2>bidding</o2>
        <o3>tensed</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>top</o0>
        <o1>peak</o1>
        <o2>through</o2>
        <o3>flat</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>2|0|0|3</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<!-- Test 7 -->
<question>
  <id>26a9d7b087e64ac284b3ef914a788980</id>
  <practiceSet>0b7002c915a441eebdb4448e4388ba5b</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>{blank} to certain pollutants early in life may do lasting harm to the immune system by blocking its response to vaccinations, suggests a study from the Faroe Islands. That archipelago, which lies in the North Atlantic between Scotland and Iceland, makes a unique laboratory for studying the health effects of chemicals called polychlorinated biphenyls (PCBs). The Faroese {blank} hunted pilot whales, and some still eat the animals' blubber, which is heavily contaminated with PCBs. Those organic {blank} linger for years in body fat and are passed from mother to child during pregnancy and through breast-feeding. "Some Faroese have 100-fold higher exposures to PCBs than others," says Philippe Grandjean of the Harvard School of Public Health in Boston and the University of Southern Denmark in Odense. Along with four colleagues in Denmark, Grandjean studied several hundred mothers and their children on the islands. The researchers measured {blank} of PCBs in each mother's blood and milk around the time she gave birth and in the children's blood at either 18 months or 7 years of age. The scientists also tested the children's blood for antibodies that protect against tetanus and diphtheria. All the children had been {blank} against both diseases.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>concentrations</o0>
        <o1>vaccinated</o1>
        <o2>treated</o2>
        <o3>historically</o3>
        <o4>pollutants</o4>
        <o5>exposure</o5>
        <o6>traditionally</o6>
        <o7>explosions</o7>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>5|6|4|0|1</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>7606352754534dd385410a6a935af92b</id>
  <practiceSet>0b7002c915a441eebdb4448e4388ba5b</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>The reason the modern fishing crews didn't do better, {blank} employing fish-spotting sonar and massive nets, is simply that few cod remain to be caught, conclude Andrew A. Rosenberg of the University of New Hampshire and his colleagues in a new analysis. The researchers {blank} Scotian shelf cod stocks of 150 years ago from data on the time that each ship in the Beverly fleet was at sea, the amount of gear used, and the area that each schooner fished. Then, they compared these figures with census data on the region's cod population today. Rosenberg and his team report in the March Frontiers in Ecology and the Environment that 20th-century fishing {blank} the tonnage of adult cod in the North Atlantic to a mere 4 percent of what it had been in 1852. "Most of this drop occurred just since World War II," Rosenberg observes. He estimates that all the adult cod on the Scotian shelf today {blank} fit into the holds of a mere 16 of the historic Beverly fleet's schooners.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>although</o0>
        <o1>exploded</o1>
        <o2>despite</o2>
        <o3>would</o3>
        <o4>will</o4>
        <o5>estimated</o5>
        <o6>reduced</o6>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>2|5|6|3</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>fcb5b4239e274468b314521b55a70247</id>
  <practiceSet>0b7002c915a441eebdb4448e4388ba5b</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Fleets have become so numerous and {blank} sophisticated that they can catch almost all the fish of any species. The result has been globally diminished stocks of desirable fish and, counter productively, {blank} daily yields. Almost invariably, the biggest species - such as tuna, sharks, and cod - in heavily fished areas have been the first to plummet, notes Ransom A. Myers of Dalhousie University in Halifax, Nova Scotia. Fleets target big fish because they yield the highest profits. There is more {blank} meat per landed fish. What's more, big fish tend to have milder flavor and fewer bones per pound than small fish do. Top-of-the-food-chain fish have always been the least {blank} ; so, overfishing such fish quickly sent their populations plummeting.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>huge</o0>
        <o1>marketable</o1>
        <o2>surging</o2>
        <o3>technologically</o3>
        <o4>declining</o4>
        <o5>numerous</o5>
        <o6>systematically</o6>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>3|4|1|5</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>75b90af2d9644e8388cb176e2b3df25a</id>
  <practiceSet>0b7002c915a441eebdb4448e4388ba5b</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>{blank} forests may look lush in photos, but they're only one-tenth as productive as savannahs are in producing animals hunted for their meat, according to data {blank} by Bennett and her colleague John Robinson. If people got all their protein from local wild meat, tropical forests  {blank} couldn't support more than one person per square kilometer over the long term. Yet Bennett reported that, by 2002, hunters in central Africa were taking six times as much meat as would amount to a {blank} harvest.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>deciduous</o0>
        <o1>sustainable</o1>
        <o2>tropical</o2>
        <o3>set up</o3>
        <o4>typically</o4>
        <o5>assembled</o5>
        <o6>extremely</o6>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>2|5|4|1</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>6a602ee7b70944d480acc325338208fa</id>
  <practiceSet>0b7002c915a441eebdb4448e4388ba5b</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Darwin’s theory of “natural selection” captured the attention of philosophers and scientists all over the world. He concluded that women stopped {blank} earlier than men and so were less developed mentally and less suited for education. He said “woman has a head almost too small for intellect, but just big enough for love”. But after the Great War, the theory of Darwinism was rejected and women in America were {blank} many social and political rights. A large number of women started working in the offices and factories throwing off the shackles of Victorian conventions. Many women’s Rights Movements started, the famous National Women Suffrage Association (NWSA) led by Elizabeth Candy Stanton argued that marriage was set up to {blank} men and to disempower women. Many social feminists inspired women to get the right to vote; the radical feminists contended that social environment and not biology determined roles of men and women in society. In 1919, the American Congress passed the Nineteenth Amendment and all the states approved it in 1920. After a long struggle, American women finally won the right to vote. Thus, the image of flapper, an ideal of youth, beauty and freedom of action for women became popular. From Seattle to Portland, Los Angles to Kirkland, the economy quickened and new  {blank} for women to work in factories and offices opened. </description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>evolving</o0>
        <o1>enlarging</o1>
        <o2>obtaining</o2>
        <o3>halting</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>disputed</o0>
        <o1>agreed</o1>
        <o2>conceded</o2>
        <o3>refused</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>annoy</o0>
        <o1>offend</o1>
        <o2>disturb</o2>
        <o3>gratify</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>schemes</o0>
        <o1>model</o1>
        <o2>opportunity</o2>
        <o3>hurdle</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>0|2|3|2</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>9cd5b930c99c457f97f844a12577c77f</id>
  <practiceSet>0b7002c915a441eebdb4448e4388ba5b</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Almost all rural Africans and nearly three-quarters of those in urban centers use some combination of wood, dried dung, and charcoal as their {blank} source of household energy. By exclusively burning charcoal or, better yet, kerosene or another fossil fuel, many Africans could {blank} trim indoor air pollution and prevent as many as 3.7 million premature deaths from lung disease over a 30-year period, says Majid Ezzati of the Harvard School of Public Health in Boston. Indoor pollutants from wood and dung fires cause about 400,000 deaths each year, says Ezzati. From 2000 to 2030, the {blank} death toll from respiratory ailments in sub-Saharan Africa will total more than 9.8 million people, he and his colleagues predict. People have always hunted wild animals for their flesh. What's changed, according to wildlife biologist Elizabeth Bennett of the Wildlife Conservation Society in New York City, is that so many hunters now stalk the tropical forests of the world that animal populations there are {blank} dramatically. In some cases, whole species are at risk.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>major</o0>
        <o1>primary</o1>
        <o2>secondary</o2>
        <o3>every</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>significantly</o0>
        <o1>slightly</o1>
        <o2>insignificantly</o2>
        <o3>unimportantly</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>belatedly</o0>
        <o1>tardily</o1>
        <o2>premature</o2>
        <o3>mature</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>dwindled</o0>
        <o1>being dwindled</o1>
        <o2>dwindling</o2>
        <o3>dwelt</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>1|0|2|2</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>fa1048bfcccc427a9801f4146ee38ab2</id>
  <practiceSet>0b7002c915a441eebdb4448e4388ba5b</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>The first elevator designed for a passenger was built in 1743 for King Louis XV at his palace in France. The one-person contraption went up only one floor, from the first to the second. Known as the Flying Chair, it was on the outside of the building, and was entered by the king via his balcony. The mechanism consisted of a carefully {blank} arrangement of weights and pulleys hanging inside a chimney. Men stationed inside the chimney then raised or lowered the Flying Chair at the king's command. By 1850 steam and hydraulic elevators had been {blank} , but it was in 1852 that the landmark event in elevator history occurred: the invention of the world's first safety elevator by Elisha Graves Otis. The first passenger elevator was {blank} by Otis in New York in 1857. After Otis' death in 1861, his sons, Charles and Norton, built on his heritage, creating Otis Brothers and Co. in 1867. By 1873 over 2,000 Otis elevators were in use in office buildings, hotels and department stores across America, and five years later the first Otis hydraulic passenger elevator was installed. The Era of the Skyscraper {blank} and in 1889 Otis revealed the first successful direct-connected geared electric elevator machines. In 1898 overseas business had added to the company's growth, and Otis Brothers merged with 14 other elevator entities to form the Otis Elevator Company. In 1903 Otis introduced the {blank} that would become the backbone of the elevator industry. The gearless traction, electric elevator, engineered and proven to outlast the building itself. This ushered in the age of high-rise structures, ultimately including New York's Empire State Building, Chicago's John Hancock Centre, and Toronto's CN Tower. Otis is part of United Technologies Corporation, a Fortune 500 company and {blank} leader in the building systems and aerospace industries. With 1.7 million Otis elevators and 110,000 escalators in operation, Otis touches the lives of people in more than 200 countries around the world.
</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>balanced</o0>
        <o1>accorded</o1>
        <o2>opposed</o2>
        <o3>adjusted</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>announced</o0>
        <o1>offered</o1>
        <o2>activated</o2>
        <o3>introduced</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>allotted</o0>
        <o1>assigned</o1>
        <o2>established</o2>
        <o3>installed</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>resulted</o0>
        <o1>followed</o1>
        <o2>emulated</o2>
        <o3>composed</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>sketch</o0>
        <o1>diagram</o1>
        <o2>draft</o2>
        <o3>design</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>creation</o0>
        <o1>universe</o1>
        <o2>world</o2>
        <o3>system</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>0|3|3|1|3|2</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>ee97ee8cfeea42e190bb75da84827a37</id>
  <practiceSet>0b7002c915a441eebdb4448e4388ba5b</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Fleets have overfished boneless fish, {blank} sharks, skates, and rays, along with boned fish, which are virtually all other fish of commercial value. However, the reproductive consequences of overfishing may differ between the groups. Boneless fish tend to produce very few young - in some cases, only two to four every other year. Because many of these species are so {blank} , biologists haven't done experiments to quantify the reproductive impacts of overfishing them. Among the boned fish, {blank} , studies have shown that egg production tends to increase with a female's age. Norse notes that fishery managers have {blank} assumed that a boat taking an older female producing 1 million eggs a year is equivalent, in terms of its effect on a fish stock's health, to taking 10 younger females, each producing 100,000 eggs a year.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>principally</o0>
        <o1>mainly</o1>
        <o2>extremely</o2>
        <o3>consequently</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>evacuated</o0>
        <o1>absorbed</o1>
        <o2>depleted</o2>
        <o3>disrupted</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>contrary</o0>
        <o1>generally</o1>
        <o2>however</o2>
        <o3>contrarily</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>generally</o0>
        <o1>seldom</o1>
        <o2>occasionally</o2>
        <o3>sporadically</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>0|2|2|0</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>014aa79c967d427ca3938c3e3e362821</id>
  <practiceSet>0b7002c915a441eebdb4448e4388ba5b</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Not all New York City love stories have to be romantic. NYC is {blank} in this endlessly re-watchable weepie about the tumultuous friendship between CC Bloom (Bette Midler) and Hillary Whitney (Barbara Hershey). After one {blank} summer at the board walk in Atlantic City, the girls form an unbreakable {blank} that eventually leads them to live together in a nightmare down town apartment. The girls both experience success in NYC—CC becomes a big Broadway star and Hilary becomes a lawyer-and their rapport is temporarily disrupted by a man (of course). While they {blank} find each other again on the left coast, their New York City roots permeate the film.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>quality</o0>
        <o1>featured</o1>
        <o2>characteristic</o2>
        <o3>phenomenon</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>critical</o0>
        <o1>important</o1>
        <o2>fateful</o2>
        <o3>fate</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>relationship</o0>
        <o1>bond</o1>
        <o2>promise</o2>
        <o3>association</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>even</o0>
        <o1>finally</o1>
        <o2>eventually</o2>
        <o3>sometime</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>1|2|1|2</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>2c872340cba149039db0a997d6e95627</id>
  <practiceSet>0b7002c915a441eebdb4448e4388ba5b</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_MULTIPLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct response. More than one response is correct.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>The fossil consists of a complete skull of an archaeocyte, an extinct group of ancestors of modern cetaceans. Although limited to a skull, the Pakicetus fossil provides precious details on the origins of cetaceans. The skull is cetacean-like but its jawbones lack the enlarged space that is filled with fat or oil and used for receiving underwater sound in modern whales. Pakicetus probably detected sound through the ear opening as in land mammals. The skull also lacks a blowhole, another cetacean adaptation for diving. Other features, however, show experts that Pakicetus is a transitional form between a group of extinct flesh-eating mammals, the mesonychids, and cetaceans. It has been suggested that Pakicetus fed on fish in shallow water and was not yet adapted for life in the open ocean. It probably bred and gave birth on land.
Pakicetus and modern cetaceans have similar</description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o0>hearing structures</o0>
      <o1>adaptations for diving</o1>
      <o2>skull shapes</o2>
      <o3>feeding locations</o3>
    </options>
    <picture></picture>
    <answer>2|3</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>43d2a5bef5f847d19d940da1e57bfed1</id>
  <practiceSet>0b7002c915a441eebdb4448e4388ba5b</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_MULTIPLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct response. More than one response is correct.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>In this newly emerging economic order, workers sometimes organized to protect their rights and traditional ways of life. Craft workers such as carpenters, printers, and tailors formed unions, and in 1834 individual unions came together in the National Trades' Union. The labor movement gathered some momentum in the decade before the Panic of 1837, but in the depression that followed, labor's strength collapsed. During hard times, few workers were willing to strike or engage in collective action. And skilled craft workers, who spearheaded the union movement, did not feel a particularly strong bond with semiskilled factory workers and unskilled laborers. More than a decade of agitation did finally bring a workday shortened to 10 hours to most industries by the 1850's, and the courts also recognized workers' right to strike, but these gains had little immediate impact.
Which of the following statements about the labor movement of the 1800's is supported by the paragraph?</description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o0>It went down during times of economic crisis.</o0>
      <o1>Its primary purpose was to benefit unskilled laborers.</o1>
      <o2>It was slow to improve conditions for workers.</o2>
      <o3>It helped workers of all skill levels form a strong bond with each other.</o3>
    </options>
    <picture></picture>
    <answer>0|2</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>a0c5fd686d6e40f5b3572e86e0399d55</id>
  <practiceSet>0b7002c915a441eebdb4448e4388ba5b</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Traditional research has confronted only Mexican and United States interpretations of Mexican-American culture. Now we must also examine the culture as we Mexican Americans have experienced it, passing from a sovereign people to compatriots with newly arriving settlers to, finally, a conquered people—a charter minority on our own land.
When the Spanish first came to Mexico, they intermarried with and absorbed the culture of the indigenous Indians. This policy of colonization through acculturation was continued when Mexico acquired Texas in the early 1800’s and brought the indigenous Indians into Mexican life and government. In the 1820’s, United States citizens migrated to Texas, attracted by land suitable for cotton. As their numbers became more substantial, their policy of acquiring land by subduing native populations began to dominate. The two ideologies clashed repeatedly, culminating in a military conflict that led to victory for the United States. Thus, suddenly deprived of our parent culture, we had to evolve uniquely Mexican-American modes of thought and action in order to survive.
The author’s purpose in writing this passage is primarily to</description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o0>suggest the motives behind Mexican and United States intervention in Texas.</o0>
      <o1>document certain early objectives of the Mexican-American society.</o1>
      <o2>provide a historical perspective for a new analysis of Mexican-American culture.</o2>
      <o3>appeal to both Mexican and United States scholars to give greater consideration to economic interpretations of history.</o3>
    </options>
    <picture></picture>
    <answer>2</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>7873fba77c66496fbab1fe118fa13024</id>
  <practiceSet>0b7002c915a441eebdb4448e4388ba5b</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>The social sciences are less likely than other intellectual enterprises to get credit for their accomplishments. Arguably, this is so because the theories and conceptual constructs of the social sciences are especially accessible: human intelligence apprehends truths about human affairs with a particular facility. And the discoveries of the social sciences, once isolated and labeled, are quickly absorbed into conventional wisdom, whereupon they lose their distinctiveness as scientific advances.
This under-appreciation of the social sciences contrasts oddly with what many see as their over-utilization. Game theory is pressed into service in studies of shifting international alliances. Evaluation research is called upon to demonstrate successes or failures of social programs. Models from economics and demography become the definitive tools for examining the financial base of social security. Yet this rush into practical applications is itself quite understandable: public policy must continually be made, and policymakers rightly feel that even tentative findings and untested theories are better guides to decision-making than no findings and no theories at all.
The author is primarily concerned with</description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o0>advocating a more modest view, and less widespread utilization, of the social sciences.</o0>
      <o1>analyzing the mechanisms for translating discoveries into applications in the social sciences.</o1>
      <o2>dissolving the air of paradox inherent in human beings studying themselves.</o2>
      <o3>explaining a peculiar dilemma that the social sciences are in.</o3>
      <o4>maintaining a strict separation between pure and applied social science.</o4>
    </options>
    <picture></picture>
    <answer>3</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>d0bd94a97a6142a4a03f97bcfda2925f</id>
  <practiceSet>0b7002c915a441eebdb4448e4388ba5b</practiceSet>
  <type>REORDER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description></description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o1>However, the real challenge today is in unlearning which is much harder.</o1>
      <o2>But the new world of business behaves differently from the world in which we grew up.</o2>
      <o3>Learning is important for both people and organizations.</o3>
      <o4>Each of us has’ mental model’ that we vet used over the years to make sense.</o4>
    </options>
    <answer>2|0|3|1</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>c9cb9079855f4fa0a69dd3c0b9666002</id>
  <practiceSet>0b7002c915a441eebdb4448e4388ba5b</practiceSet>
  <type>REORDER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description></description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o1>In fact, during the 1966-67 season in New York, theater-goers could have seen ’Barefoot in the park’;’ The odd Couple’;’ Sweet Charity’ and ‘The Star-Spangled Girl’, which were all running simultaneously.</o1>
      <o2>His first play for Broadway was ‘Come Blow Your Horn’, which had a limited success and encouraged him to write his first real smash Broadway hit, ‘Barefoot in the Park’.</o2>
      <o3>With the advent of television, he progressed to shows like The Ed Sulli van programme and, in particular, two and a half years with the highly successful Bilko series which is still showing throughout the world.</o3>
      <o4>Neil Simon, who is, without a doubt, America’s Leading comedy writer, started his career when only sixteen years old, writing with his brother Daniel, scripts for radio.</o4>
    </options>
    <answer>3|2|1|0</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<!-- Test 8  -->
<question>
  <id>4087a7d353a84fc29e6b2f57f3bdca15</id>
  <practiceSet>05424cf5c42745de8f6fdef719e5351b</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>The first banks were {blank} the religious temples of the ancient world, and were probably established sometime during the 3rd {blank} B.C. Banks probably predated the invention of money. Deposits initially consisted of grain and later other goods including cattle, agricultural implements, and eventually precious metals such as gold, in the form of easy-to-carry compressed plates. Temples and palaces were the {blank} places to store gold as they were constantly attended and well built. As sacred places, temples presented an extra deterrent to would-be thieves. There are extant records of loans from the 18th century BC in Babylon that were made by temple priests to merchants. By the time of Hammurabi's Code, banking was well enough {blank} to justify the promulgation of laws governing banking operations.
</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>probably</o0>
        <o1>developed</o1>
        <o2>safer</o2>
        <o3>million</o3>
        <o4>millennium</o4>
        <o5>safest</o5>
        <o6>finally</o6>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>0|4|5|1</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>9816826841b342aa8dfffe3ab5288258</id>
  <practiceSet>05424cf5c42745de8f6fdef719e5351b</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Global banking and capital market services {blank} during the 1980s and 1990s as a result of a great increase in demand from companies, governments, and financial institutions, but also because financial market conditions were {blank} and, on the whole, bullish. Interest rates in the United States declined from about 15% for two-year U.S. Treasury notes to about 5% during the 20-year period, and financial assets grew then at a rate approximately twice the rate of the world {blank} . Such growth rate would have been lower, in the last twenty years, were it not for the profound effects of the internationalization of financial markets especially U.S. Foreign investments, {blank} from Japan, who not only provided the funds to corporations in the U.S., but also helped finance the federal government; thus, {blank} the U.S. stock market by far into the largest in the world.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>buoyant</o0>
        <o1>profit</o1>
        <o2>transform </o2>
        <o3>transforming</o3>
        <o4>finances</o4>
        <o5>proliferated</o5>
        <o6>particularly</o6>
		<o6>economy</o6>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>5|0|7|6|3</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>4e86bb6c8f224f2fa5aff7ceed2ab36b</id>
  <practiceSet>05424cf5c42745de8f6fdef719e5351b</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>In their paper Bioscience, tow researchers showed that reintroducing the wolves was {blank}{blank} with increased growth of willow and cottonwood in the park. The reason is that grazing animals such as elk were {blank} sites from which they couldn’t easily escape, the scientists {blank} and as the woody plants and thicker, beaver {blank} expanded.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>Avoiding</o0>
        <o1>seeking</o1>
        <o2>colonies</o2>
        <o3>populating</o3>
        <o4>claimed</o4>
        <o5>denied </o5>
        <o6>correlated</o6>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>6|0|4|2</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>e1f264fbf6ab4eea9ae1ac36b07686df</id>
  <practiceSet>05424cf5c42745de8f6fdef719e5351b</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Fingerprints can {blank} that a suspect was actually at the scene of a crime. As long as a human entered a crime scene, there will be traces of DNA. DNA can help the police to {blank} an individual to crack a case. An institute in London can help {blank} DNA and be used to match with the {blank} taken from the crime scenes.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
	<blank>
        <o0>demonstrates</o0>
        <o1>reserve</o1>
        <o2>evidence</o2>
        <o3>retains</o3>
        <o4>prove</o4>
        <o5>identify</o5>
        <o6>samples</o6>
      </blank>
	  </blanks>
    <answer>4|5|1|6</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>205b3a943fef424198b6de92da2af854</id>
  <practiceSet>05424cf5c42745de8f6fdef719e5351b</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Individuals suffering from chronic fatigue tend to be more {blank} , distressed and are also more likely to suppress these emotions than people who do not have this {blank} , says a study. In addition, when under stress, chronic fatigue {blank} patients show greater activation of the biological “fight or flight” mechanism, which may add to their fatigue, the study said.
“Patients with chronic fatigue syndrome often tell us that {blank} worsens their symptoms, but this study demonstrates a possible biological mechanism underlying this effect,” said lead study author Katharine Rimes from King’s College London. The findings appeared in the journal Health Psychology.
The research that involved {blank} 160 people in Britain relied on self and observer reports, as well as physiological responses that were collected before, during or after the participants watched a distressing film clip.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>worried</o0>
        <o1>anxious</o1>
        <o2>condition</o2>
        <o3>tension</o3>
        <o4>syndrome</o4>
        <o5>stress</o5>
        <o6>examining</o6>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>1|2|4|5|6</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>9a70421a8b984b98a3e0700ff2ed3023</id>
  <practiceSet>05424cf5c42745de8f6fdef719e5351b</practiceSet>
  <type>REORDER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description></description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o1>Her comprehension of language is therefore very high.</o1>
      <o2>According to recent research, the critical period for developing language skills is between the ages of three and five and a half years.</o2>
      <o3>The read-to child already has a large vocabulary and a sense of grammar and sentence structure.</o3>
      <o4>Children who are read to in these years have a far better chance of reading well in school, indeed, of doing well in all their subjects.</o4>
      <o5>And the reason is actually quite simple.</o5>
      <o6>This correlation is far and away the highest yet found between home influences and school success.</o6>
    </options>
    <answer>1|3|5|4|2|0</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>3d3d9aa315b34846baa01c11556b4bc5</id>
  <practiceSet>05424cf5c42745de8f6fdef719e5351b</practiceSet>
  <type>REORDER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description></description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o1>Never stop thinking of ways to make your products better, but don’t get stuck trying to achieve perfection.</o1>
      <o2>Release the product and, at the same time, continue to refine it.</o2>
      <o3>I’m not suggesting that it is ever acceptable to deliver shoddy products.</o3>
      <o4>The longer you hold out for perfection, the less likely you are to achieve it, and you’ll lose whatever competitive edge you may have.</o4>
      <o5>The product that beats the competition is seldom the best, and it’s never perfect.</o5>
    </options>
    <answer>4|3|2|0|1</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>c1f3f6c846f840628536c54ab599f5b3</id>
  <practiceSet>05424cf5c42745de8f6fdef719e5351b</practiceSet>
  <type>REORDER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description></description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o1>With these, hunters could approach Belugas within hunting range and profit from its inner skin and blubber.</o1>
      <o2>Belugas seem to have used their well-known sensitivity to noise to evolve an ‘avoidance’ strategy to outsmart hunters and their powerful technologies.</o2>
      <o3>To escape an approaching motor, Belugas have learned to dive to the ocean bottom and stay there for up to 20 minutes, by which time the confused predator has left.</o3>
      <o4>Today, however, even with much more powerful engines, it is difficult to come close, because the whales seem to disappear suddenly just when you thought you had them in your sights.</o4>
      <o5>High-powered outboard motors were considered to be one of the major threats to the survival of the Beluga whales.</o5>
      <o6>When the first outboard engines arrived in the early 1930s, one came across 4 and 8 HP motors.
</o6>
    </options>
    <answer>4|5|0|3|2|1</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>d3f55f696aca498cbbe49b8b2862d1b6</id>
  <practiceSet>05424cf5c42745de8f6fdef719e5351b</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Not all New York City love stories have to be romantic. NYC is {blank} in this endlessly re-watchable weepie about the tumultuous friendship between CC Bloom (Bette Midler) and Hillary Whitney (Barbara Hershey). After one {blank} summer at the board walk in Atlantic City, the girls form an unbreakable {blank} that eventually leads them to live together in a nightmare down town apartment. The girls both experience success in NYC—CC becomes a big Broadway star and Hilary becomes a lawyer—and their rapport is temporarily disrupted by a man (of course). While they {blank} find each other again on the left coast, their New York City roots permeate the film.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>quality</o0>
        <o1>featured</o1>
        <o2>characteristic</o2>
        <o3>phenomenon</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>critical</o0>
        <o1>important</o1>
        <o2>fateful</o2>
        <o3>fate</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>relationship</o0>
        <o1>bond</o1>
        <o2>promise</o2>
        <o3>association</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>even</o0>
        <o1>finally</o1>
        <o2>eventually</o2>
        <o3>sometime</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>1|2|1|2</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>9e4fc24c02f14162bf69a7f69683e91f</id>
  <practiceSet>05424cf5c42745de8f6fdef719e5351b</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Sales fell faster in greater China, which includes Hong Kong and Taiwan, than in any other {blank} , down 26 percent compared with the previous year sales in mainland China, Apple’s second-largest market after the United States, fell 11 percent as the country struggled with a slowing economy. Apple’s prospects there remain {blank} since the government recently shut down Apple’s e-book and digital movie services without {blank} Apple’s forecast for the current quarter did not make Wall Street more confident. The company projected revenue of $41 billion to $43 billion. That is much worse than Wall Street had been {blank} .
</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>zone</o0>
        <o1>location</o1>
        <o2>region</o2>
        <o3>country</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>debatable</o0>
        <o1>ambivalent</o1>
        <o2>uncertain</o2>
        <o3>doubtful</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>explanation</o0>
        <o1>clarification</o1>
        <o2>explain</o2>
        <o3>account</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>conjecture</o0>
        <o1>picture</o1>
        <o2>painting</o2>
        <o3>predicting</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>2|2|0|3</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>df2139f35eef41c7bbb3dfd812aa243d</id>
  <practiceSet>05424cf5c42745de8f6fdef719e5351b</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>The players the Cincinnati Reds trotted out on Wednesday {blank} a prime opportunity for Harvey to regain his form. But against the first batter of the game, Zack Cozart, Harvey gave up a home run. Next up, Ivan De Jesus Jr. lined a single off Harvey’s backside.Harvey escaped the first inning without further {blank} by striking out the next three batters, setting the cadence for his night.
Like a ship wading through rough waters, Harvey encountered his share of whitecaps, but he finished in good {blank} , striking out seven in six innings while allowing two runs and seven hits, as the Mets defeated the Reds, 5-2, at Citi Field.“This is the best I think he’s thrown all year,” Manager Terry Collins said. “I think he’s making {blank} .”Neil Walker drove in two runs to support Harvey, with one of the R.B.I. coming in the third on his ninth home run, which tied him for the franchise record for April. Last {blank} with the Pittsburgh Pirates, Walker did not hit his ninth homer until July 26.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>present</o0>
        <o1>furnish</o1>
        <o2>propose</o2>
        <o3>prefer</o3>
        <o4>presented</o4>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>destruction</o0>
        <o1>damage</o1>
        <o2>injurious</o2>
        <o3>wounding</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>condition</o0>
        <o1>time</o1>
        <o2>state</o2>
        <o3>express</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>stalk</o0>
        <o1>strides</o1>
        <o2>ride</o2>
        <o3>step</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>season</o0>
        <o1>time</o1>
        <o2>moment</o2>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>4|1|0|1|0</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>de4d3bccf82047de9700ba1b53ee332c</id>
  <practiceSet>05424cf5c42745de8f6fdef719e5351b</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>The stones we see today represent Stonehenge in ruin. Many of the original stones have fallen or been removed by previous generations for home construction or road repair. There has been serious {blank} to some of the smaller bluestones resulting from close visitor contact (prohibited since 1978) and the prehistoric carvings on the larger sarsen stones show signs of {blank} wear.
In its day, the construction of Stonehenge was an impressive engineering feat, requiring commitment, {blank} and vast amounts of manual labour. In its first phase, Stonehenge was a large earthwork; a bank and ditch arrangement called a henge, constructed approximately 5,000 years ago. It is believed that the {blank} was dug with tools made from the antlers of red deer and, possibly, wood. The underlying chalk was loosened with picks and shovelled with the shoulder blades of cattle. It was then {blank} into baskets and carried away. Modern experiments have shown that these tools were more than {blank} to the great task of earth digging and moving.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>Injury</o0>
        <o1>loss</o1>
        <o2>damage</o2>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>Meaningless</o0>
        <o1>important</o1>
        <o2>significant</o2>
        <o3>rich</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>Time</o0>
        <o1>annule</o1>
        <o2>period</o2>
        <o3>method</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>Pond</o0>
        <o1>ditch</o1>
        <o2>area</o2>
        <o3>land</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>Loaded</o0>
        <o1>covered</o1>
        <o2>carried</o2>
        <o3>made</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>Equal</o0>
        <o1>alike</o1>
        <o2>different</o2>
        <o3>even</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>2|2|0|1|0|0</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>1731a7b99d8146eea3879b8b413eea40</id>
  <practiceSet>05424cf5c42745de8f6fdef719e5351b</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>The sleep cycle {blank} of four stages and lasts about 90 to 120 minutes. Dreams can occur in any of the four stages of sleep. In 5 percent cases, dreams occur in the last stage of sleep {blank} to as REM sleep stage. Often the sleep cycle repeats after an hour and the process continues. That is how a person has several different dreams in one night. Most people remember dreams that occur in the morning when they are about to wake up. But, some persons can’t remember their dreams. The stages in the sleep cycle are {blank} by the changes in the specific brain activity. In stage one, man is in NREM when muscle relaxation, lowered body temperature and slowed heart rate is observed. In the dreaming process, adrenaline is secreted, blood pressure increases and heart beats become faster. People with a weak heart may die in sleep. Researchers have shown that people who are deprived from REM, exhibit symptoms of {blank} and anxiety. Deprivation of REM sleep causes over-senility, lack of concentration and memory loss. So, dreaming helps tackle stress, the mind is recharged and the body is revitalized. Dreaming transcends the mere unconscious aspects of social, emotional and personal awareness.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>comprises</o0>
        <o1>formalizes</o1>
        <o2>initiates</o2>
        <o3>speaks</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>differed</o0>
        <o1>addressed</o1>
        <o2>referred</o2>
        <o3>given</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>organised</o0>
        <o1>recognised</o1>
        <o2>stirred</o2>
        <o3>linked</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>emotions</o0>
        <o1>irritability</o1>
        <o2>desirability</o2>
        <o3>love</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>0|2|0|1</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>9cc12a105a1e4244bc38e82add87fcb6</id>
  <practiceSet>05424cf5c42745de8f6fdef719e5351b</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Jupiter has 2.5 times more mass than all the other planets of the solar system combined and is 11 times as large as Earth in diameter. Jupiter is so large that scientists believe it almost became a star: as the gasses and dust contracted to the form the planet, gravitational forces created tremendous pressure and the temperature inside the core—as high as tens of thousands of degrees. But there was not enough mass available to create the temperature needed to start a fusion reaction such as that of the Sun (above 27,000,000 Fahrenheit, or 15,000,000 Celsius, at the Sun’s core); thus Jupiter has been cooling down ever since. Even so, Jupiter radiates about as much heat as it receives from the Sun.

Ques 1. The passage is mainly concerned with
</description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o0>the size of Jupiter relative to other planets in the solar system.</o0>
      <o1>differences between the sun and Jupiter.</o1>
      <o2>how Jupiter’s mass has affected its development.</o2>
      <o3>the temperature at which a planet’s core can start a fusion reaction.</o3>
    </options>
    <picture></picture>
    <answer>2</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>92987328f0064a9988beb61c9bd2ebee</id>
  <practiceSet>05424cf5c42745de8f6fdef719e5351b</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Stump-Up was invented in 1986 by Tokyo Beverages Owner Okawa Bhery. The name for the product was actually proposed by Okawa’s assistant, Fizzy Brewndon. The name was taken from the two most unusual ingredients in the drink, the Canadian banana leaf and the Asian stump root. The recipe for today’s Stump-Up is very well guarded. Many of the ingredients are known; in addition to banana leaves and stump root, they include strawberry, cocoa, lemon, cinnamon, nuts, vanilla, caramel, salts and sugar. The proportions of the ingredients and the identity of Stump’s secret ingredients are known by only a few of the Stump-Up Company’s very senior scientists and Vice-Presidents.

It can be inferred from the passage that
</description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o0>No one knows the exact proportions of ingredients used in Stump-Ups.</o0>
      <o1>The public does not know how many stump roots are used in a batch of Stump-Ups.</o1>
      <o2>The public is not sure that banana leaves are used in Stump-Ups.</o2>
      <o3>The public knows all the ingredients in Stump-Ups.</o3>
    </options>
    <picture></picture>
    <answer>1</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>dd48ce611ee843f685479a1b67713dbe</id>
  <practiceSet>05424cf5c42745de8f6fdef719e5351b</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_MULTIPLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct response. More than one response is correct.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Using infant mortality as a key indicator of the status of children, we now begin to have the broad features of a hypothesis as to the causes of higher or lower mortality rates. One aspect is the complex of factors involving the access of mothers to trained personnel and other facilities for child delivery, the nutritional status of pregnant and nursing mothers and the quality of health care and nourishment which babies receive.
The other aspect, indicated by rural-urban differentials, is the possible importance of human settlement patterns in relation to the availability of health care and related facilities such as potable water, excreta disposal systems, etc. Thus, in a special sense, it is much cheaper to make health and other basic services available to a community when it is densely settled rather than widely dispersed. It is possible to argue, however, that both these sets of factors are closely related to a third one, namely, income levels. Poorer mothers and babies have less access to health-care facilities and nourishment than those who are better off; urban communities are on an average much better off than rural communities.
That economic condition plays a crucial role in determining the status of both mother and child, is beyond dispute. But the question really is whether this is the only decisive factor or whether factors such as the availability of medical facilities, healthcare programs, and nutritional programs have an independent role. If so then the settlement patterns which affect service delivery to the mother and child target groups become a relevant consideration. These are clearly issues of some importance for policy and program planning.

Which among the following statements are correct?
</description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o0>It is easy and economical to provide health care facilities in dense settlements.</o0>
      <o1>The fact that income has an important role to play in health care is arguable.</o1>
      <o2>A densely settled community has to be supplied with health and basic services after bearing a large cost.</o2>
      <o3>Mothers from well to do families can provide better care and facilities to their babies.</o3>
      <o4>The settlement conditions, income levels, and health facilities are the only influencing factors behind the varying mortality rates.</o4>
    </options>
    <picture></picture>
    <answer>0|3</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>2d6ae624bd864680b2ae9ef26040da2e</id>
  <practiceSet>05424cf5c42745de8f6fdef719e5351b</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_MULTIPLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct response. More than one response is correct.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Until the mid-20th century, scientists believed that the chest cavity would implode at around 115 feet. Water pressure, they argued, reaches 65 pounds per square inch at that depth, which is enough to shrink lungs to the size of grapefruits and collapse rib cages like empty soda cans. Their theory went out the window in the 1950’s and early 1960’s, however, when divers like Enzo Maiorca returned from beyond 115-feet with rib cages intact. We now know that water pressure forces blood vessels in the chest to swell, filling the void left by the lungs with an incompressible fluid.
Among the dangers of free diving, the most disconcerting is shallow-water blackout—the brains frightening tendency to shut down within 15 feet of the surface during the ascent. As you descend, water pressure squeezes your lungs, condensing the oxygen and giving you what feels like a second breath. During the return trip, however, your lungs re-expand, dissipating whats left of your oxygen. If levels drop too low, not enough will move into the bloodstream, and the lights go out. Fortunately, the body’s laryngospasm reflex kicks in to tighten the throat and keep water out for up to a minute—just enough time for your dive buddy to drag you to the surface, tilt your head back, and beg, “Breathe, baby.”
Knowing Johnston will be there watching my eyes as I ascend (seeing them roll back in the head is a red flag), I dip below the surface. Staying in the syringe—dive speak for a tight hydrodynamic column—I kick down to 30 feet, my point of neutral buoyancy, and then sink effortlessly to the bottom. I feel good—surprisingly good—thanks to the densely packed oxygen molecules in my lungs.
Lingering a moment, I peer up at the mirrored surface that separates this liquid world from mine. Diving to 55 feet was no sweat. I figure I could dive twice that with a little practice, reaching what scientists thought, not 50 years ago, was the body’s depth limit. Today, however, that boundary has been pushed to at least 531 feet (the current no-limits world record), which begs the question: Just how deep can humans go? “We don’t know that yet,” says Lundgren, adding ominously. “But one day someone will find out

Which of the following is true in respect of the effect of water pressure on humans?

</description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o0>Scientists believed that the chest cavity would blow up at a depth of about 115 feet.</o0>
      <o1>Rib cages will collapse at the water pressure of 65 pounds per square inch.</o1>
      <o2>Blood vessels of the chest enlarge and fill the empty space left by lungs that have been compressed.</o2>
      <o3>It is now known that lungs will not shrink with the increase in water pressure.</o3>
      <o4>It is no longer believed that the chest cavity will cave in at a depth of about 115 feet.</o4>
    </options>
    <picture></picture>
    <answer>2|4</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<!-- Test 9 -->
<question>
  <id>25d410ad81c54c609366bed0399858b7</id>
  <practiceSet>db28642c43f44f048e0e1be5cf8984f6</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>In a sequence of bestsellers, including The Language Instinct and How the Mind Works, Pinker has argued the swathes of our mental, social and emotional lives may have {blank} as evolutionary adaptations, well suited to the lives our ancestors eked out on the Pleistocene savannah. Sometimes it seems as if nothing is {blank} from being explained this way. Road rage, adultery, marriage, altruism, our tendency to reward senior executives with corner offices on the top floor, and the smaller number of women who become mechanical engineers—all may have their {blank} in natural selection, Pinker claims. The controversial implications are obvious: that men and women might {blank} in their inborn abilities at performing certain tasks, for example, or that parenting may have {blank} influence on personality.
</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>origin</o0>
        <o1>originating</o1>
        <o2>originate</o2>
        <o3>originated</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>protected</o0>
        <o1>immune</o1>
        <o2>convinced</o2>
        <o3>prohibited</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>roots</o0>
        <o1>values</o1>
        <o2>demands</o2>
        <o3>needs</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>differ</o0>
        <o1>interested</o1>
        <o2>complicate</o2>
        <o3>indulge</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>little</o0>
        <o1>many</o1>
        <o2>a few</o2>
        <o3>few</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>3|1|0|0|0</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>fb30ad2185b7401b8030d50f4b412354</id>
  <practiceSet>db28642c43f44f048e0e1be5cf8984f6</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Never has the carbon footprint of multi-national corporations been under such intense scrutiny. Inter-city train journeys and long-haul flights to {blank} face-to-face business meetings contribute significantly to greenhouse gases and the resulting {blank} on the environment. The Anglo-US Company Teliris has introduced a new video-conferencing technology and partnered With the Carbon Neutral Company, enabling corporate outfits to become more environmentally responsible. The innovation allows simulated face-to-face meetings to be held across continents without the time {blank} or environmental burden of international travel. Previous designs have enabled video-conferencing on a point-to-point, dual-location basis. The firm's VirtuaLive technology, however, can bring people together from up to five {blank} locations anywhere in the world - with {blank} transmission quality.
</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>produce</o0>
        <o1>generate</o1>
        <o2>create</o2>
        <o3>conduct</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>gases</o0>
        <o1>steam</o1>
        <o2>strain</o2>
        <o3>affect</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>stress</o0>
        <o1>limit</o1>
        <o2>pressure</o2>
        <o3>press</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>separate</o0>
        <o1>each</o1>
        <o2>respectively</o2>
        <o3>single</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>unreliable</o0>
        <o1>unrivalled</o1>
        <o2>unrealistic</o2>
        <o3>unreasonable</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>3|2|2|0|1</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>133e9e453b1c4a1a89e8fc46425c3a7d</id>
  <practiceSet>db28642c43f44f048e0e1be5cf8984f6</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Financing of Australian higher education has undergone dramatic change since the early 1970s. Although the Australian Government provided regular funding for universities from the late 1950s, in 1974 it {blank} full responsibility for funding higher education - {blank} tuition fees with the intention of making university {blank} to all Australians who had the {blank} and who wished to participate in higher education. Since the late 1980s, there has been a move towards greater private contributions, {blank} student fees. In 1989, the Australian Government introduced the Higher Education Contribution Scheme (HECS) which included a loans scheme to help students finance their contributions. This enabled university to remain accessible to students by delaying their payments until they could afford to pay off their loans. In 2002, the Australian Government {blank} a scheme similar to HECS for postgraduate students - the Postgraduate Education Loan Scheme (PELS). Funding for higher education comes from various sources. This article examines the three main
sources - Australian Government funding, student fees and charges, and HECS. While the proportion of total {blank} raised through HECS is relatively small, HECS payments are a significant component of students' university costs, with many students carrying a HECS debt for several years after leaving university. This article also focuses on characteristics of university students based on their HECS liability status, and the level of accumulated HECS debt.
</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>assumed</o0>
        <o1>represented</o1>
        <o2>clarified</o2>
        <o3>paid</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>including</o0>
        <o1>abolishing</o1>
        <o2>combining</o2>
        <o3>accomplishing</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>achievable</o0>
        <o1>reliable</o1>
        <o2>accepted</o2>
        <o3>accessible</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>ability</o0>
        <o1>liability</o1>
        <o2>responsibility</o2>
        <o3>reality</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>specially</o0>
        <o1>without</o1>
        <o2>particularly</o2>
        <o3>with</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>introduced</o0>
        <o1>produced</o1>
        <o2>remembered</o2>
        <o3>carried</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>expenses</o0>
        <o1>revenue</o1>
        <o2>expenditure</o2>
        <o3>profit</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>0|1|3|0|2|0|1</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>7d10ff9d9b7e47a980ddc2165add13ce</id>
  <practiceSet>db28642c43f44f048e0e1be5cf8984f6</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>
Sound depressing, even apocalyptic? Well, it could be the future. If government {blank} are right, about 20 years from now, two out of five households will be single {blank} . And there is evidence the situation is already {blank} . According to a report, Social Isolation in America, published in the American Sociological Review in 2006, the average American today has only two close friends. Twenty-five per cent of those surveyed said they do not have anyone to talk with about important things---And yet, while some are {blank} a crisis in our ability to make friends, others are saying exactly the opposite. For example, MSN's Anatomy of Friendship Report, published last November, suggests that the average Briton has 54 friends - a {blank} rise of 64 per cent since 2003.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>forecasts</o0>
        <o1>prediction</o1>
        <o2>goals</o2>
        <o3>aims</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>occupancy</o0>
        <o1>occupied</o1>
        <o2>household</o2>
        <o3>family</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>deteriorating</o0>
        <o1>improving</o1>
        <o2>damaging</o2>
        <o3>recovering</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>declaring</o0>
        <o1>requiring</o1>
        <o2>announcing</o2>
        <o3>releasing</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>spectacular</o0>
        <o1>amazing</o1>
        <o2>special</o2>
        <o3>applausive</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>0|0|0|0|0</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>dbad8892c578451489149ab059a4993f</id>
  <practiceSet>db28642c43f44f048e0e1be5cf8984f6</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Thomas Alva Edison was both a scientist and an inventor. Born in 1847, Edison would see {blank} change take place in his lifetime. He was also to be responsible for making many of those changes occur. When Edison was born, society still thought of electricity as a {blank} , a fad. By the time he died, entire cities were lit by electricity. Much of the {blank} for that progress goes to Edison. In his lifetime, Edison {blank} 1,093 inventions, earning him the nickname “The Wizard of Menlo Park.” The most famous of his inventions was the incandescent light bulb. Besides the light bulb, Edison developed the phonograph and the “kinetoscope,” a small box for viewing moving films. Thomas Edison is also the first person in the US to make his own filmstrips. He also improved upon the original design of the stock ticker, the telegraph, and Alexander Graham Bell’s telephone. He believed in hard work, sometimes working twenty hours a day. Edison was quoted as saying, “Genius is one percent inspiration and 99 percent perspiration.” In tribute to this important American, electric lights in the United States were {blank} for one minute on October 21, 1931, a few days after his death.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>peculiar</o0>
        <o1>tremendous</o1>
        <o2>particular</o2>
        <o3>brilliant</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>new</o0>
        <o1>miracle</o1>
        <o2>tradition</o2>
        <o3>novelty</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>credit</o0>
        <o1>achievement</o1>
        <o2>contribution</o2>
        <o3>establishment</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>copyright</o0>
        <o1>patented</o1>
        <o2>processed</o2>
        <o3>made</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>dimmed</o0>
        <o1>lighted</o1>
        <o2>blurred</o2>
        <o3>developed</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>1|3|0|1|0</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>21f4f75bcab24af18928b683c4c74539</id>
  <practiceSet>db28642c43f44f048e0e1be5cf8984f6</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_MULTIPLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct response. More than one response is correct.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>The crisis begins in the womb with unplanned parenthood. Women with unplanned pregnancies are less likely to seek prenatal care. In the U.S. 80% of teenage pregnancies and 56% of all pregnancies are unplanned. The problems continue after birth where unplanned pregnancies and unstable partnerships often go hand in hand. Since 1950, the number of single-parent families has nearly tripled. More than 25 percent of all births today are to unmarried mothers. As the number of single-parent families grows and more women enter the workforce, infants and toddlers are increasingly in the care of people other than their parents. Most disturbingly, recent statistics show that American parents are increasingly neglecting or abusing their children. In only four years from 1987-1991, the number of children in foster care increased by over 50 percent. Babies under the age of one are the fastest growing category of children entering foster care. The crisis affects children under the age of three most severely, the report says. Yet, it is this period from infancy through preschool years that set the stage for a child's future.

What can be the possible reasons for the increasing neglect and abuse of children?</description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o0>The immaturity and overburdening of parents.</o0>
      <o1>The babies being left in foster care where a stranger looks after them.</o1>
      <o2>The children being ill mannered and not respecting their parents.</o2>
      <o3>The parents being busy with meeting the financial aspects of the family and not having enough time for the children.</o3>
    </options>
    <picture></picture>
    <answer>0|1|3</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>7863921cf85f4221a2a0c23553475b5e</id>
  <practiceSet>db28642c43f44f048e0e1be5cf8984f6</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_MULTIPLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct response. More than one response is correct.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>In the past, learning English as a separate subject seemed relatively easy. The textbook selected and graded items of language which were put into context and then practised intensively. New items were carefully controlled so that the student could cope quite easily. Now that English is used as a medium of instruction, however, all this has changed. Unknown items of grammar and vocabulary appear in texts which attempt to explain new and often difficult information. Difficulties with the language interact with difficulties as regards the subject matter. The student's reading in his own subject slows down, and his comprehension becomes less secure. He expresses himself slowly and often fails to convey his ideas exactly. He is disappointed to find that under pressure he makes a lot of unnecessary mistakes in areas where he knows the correct language forms. His social relations are difficult as he cannot find the right phrase quickly enough to keep a conversation going, so his language often betrays him into dullness, coldness, or worst of all, rudeness. Instead of the student being in control of the language, the language seems now to be in control of the student. All this can be very depressing and the student can start to feel anxious. Working in a foreign language is also very tiring, and the concentration and self-¬discipline required to correct one's mistake is very great indeed.

Which of the following statements about learning English can be supported from the text?</description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o0>Learning of English as a subject is the more difficult part.</o0>
      <o1>Learning of English as a medium of instruction is the more difficult part.</o1>
      <o2>Language may hinder understanding of the subject.</o2>
      <o3>Learning of English as a medium of instruction is the easier part.</o3>
      <o4>Learning of English as a subject is the easier part.</o4>
    </options>
    <picture></picture>
    <answer>1|2|4</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>59c4552183904f03a367cad83b3d4184</id>
  <practiceSet>db28642c43f44f048e0e1be5cf8984f6</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting  the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Researchers suggest that there are creatures that do not know what light means at the bottom of the sea.They don’t have either eyes or ears; they can only feel.There is no day or night for them. There are no winters, no summers, no sun, no moon, and no stars. It is as if a child spent its life in darkness in bed, with nothing to see or hear. How different our own life is! Sight shows us the ground beneath our feet and the heavens above us - the sun, moon, and stars, shooting stars, lightning, and the sunset. It shows us day and night. We are able to hear voices, the sound of the sea, and music. We feel we taste, we smell. How fortunate we are!

Judging from the passage, we can say that this story is mainly about?</description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o0>life of sea creatures at the bottom of the sea.</o0>
      <o1>how changes in the seasons are perceived by the deep-sea creatures.</o1>
      <o2>how wonderful our lives were and will be.</o2>
      <o3>the differences among creatures of the earth and those of the sea.</o3>
      <o4>the superiority of human beings over some creatures in terms of senses.</o4>
    </options>
    <picture></picture>
    <answer>4</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>4937bea53ad44253893fd9666c5883aa</id>
  <practiceSet>db28642c43f44f048e0e1be5cf8984f6</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting  the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>The American people have an incorrect understanding of what it means to be at war. At least so argues T.H. Pickett in his conservative interpretation of American military history.
Pickett does present a wealth of examples along with a refreshing candid argument that America often goes to war for an abstract ideal such as the democratization of societies, world peace, liberty, or freedom. For instance, the Spanish - American War of 1898 was ostensibly a consequence of national enthusiasm for the cause of Cuban liberty. And, more obviously, America’s entry into World War I stemmed from a desire to “make the world safe for democracy.”
Although these observations are supportable, Pickett overstates the cause typically lead to a war hysteria in which American leadership can no longer enforce any measured policies.

Which of the following best states the author’s main point?
</description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o0>Pickett provides a cogent rationale for why America engages in warfare; however, he draws conclusions that the author does not fully support.</o0>
      <o1>Pickett’s study is valuable primarily because it provides a thorough understanding of the causes of American warfare.</o1>
      <o2>The rationale for American warfare is well documented.</o2>
      <o3>Pickett’s analysis of American military history provides the definitive historical record of the period from the Spanish-American War to World War I.</o3>
    </options>
    <picture></picture>
    <answer>0</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>1b324f1dece14813b12aae19b2f57a5a</id>
  <practiceSet>db28642c43f44f048e0e1be5cf8984f6</practiceSet>
  <type>REORDER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description></description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o1>Reread with the idea that you are measuring what you have gained from the process</o1>
      <o2>It is a review of what you are supposed to accomplish not what you are going to do.</o2>
      <o3>A review is a survey of what you have covered</o3>
      <o4>Rereading is an important part of the review process.</o4>
    </options>
    <answer>2|1|3|0</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>26eafbd0ab40418380a4f2778a958f6d</id>
  <practiceSet>db28642c43f44f048e0e1be5cf8984f6</practiceSet>
  <type>REORDER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description></description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o1>The hole in the body is then filled with linen and spices and the body is covered with salt to become dry.</o1>
      <o2>The first step is to push a sharp rod up the nose and into the brain.
</o2>
      <o3>Next, they make a hole in the body to remove all the organs except the heart.
</o3>
      <o4>Jars which had the heads of Gods on top were used to store the organs</o4>
      <o5>It takes about 70 days to completely mummify a dead body.
</o5>
      <o6>From there, the brain is broken up into tiny pieces and removed through the nose.</o6>
      <o7>After the mummifying process is complete, a mask is placed over the head so it can be known in the afterlife.
</o7>
    </options>
    <answer>4|1|5|2|3|0|6</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>4bcedf4cd88b4a5680dcbcdeb99378c3</id>
  <practiceSet>db28642c43f44f048e0e1be5cf8984f6</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.
</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>According to two physicians at Children’s Hospital Boston and Harvard Medical School (HMS) who have been {blank} the unique structure and chemistry of the {blank} brain. “The teenage brain is not just an adult brain with fewer miles on it,” says Frances E. Jensen, a professor of neurology. “It’s a paradoxical time of {blank} . These are people with very {blank} brains, but they’re not quite sure what to do with them.” In animals, movement is coordinated by a cluster of neurons in the spinal cord called the Central Pattern Generator (CPG). This produces signals that drive muscles to contract rhythmically in a way that produces running or walking, depending on the {blank} of pulses. A simple signal from the brain instructs the CPG to switch between different {blank} , such as going from a standstill to walking.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>development</o0>
        <o1>developing</o1>
        <o2>explored</o2>
        <o3>chemical</o3>
        <o4>modes</o4>
        <o5>pattern</o5>
        <o6>sharp</o6>
        <o7>exploring</o7>
        <o8>adolescent</o8>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>7|8|0|6|5|4</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>4d13e8ea392c4bc29c4cb33129a1dd2d</id>
  <practiceSet>db28642c43f44f048e0e1be5cf8984f6</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Now that doesn't mean that plainness is the only good style, or that you should become a slave to spare, unadorned writing. Formality and ornateness have their place, and in {blank} hands complexity can carry us on a dizzying, breathtaking journey. But most students, most of the time, should {blank} to be sensibly simple, to develop a baseline style of short words, active verbs, and relatively simple sentences {blank} clear actions or identities. It's faster, it makes arguments easier to follow, it increases the chances a busy reader will bother to pay attention, and it lets you focus more attention on your moments of rhetorical flourish, which I do not advise {blank} altogether.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>expert</o0>
        <o1>competent</o1>
        <o2>strive</o2>
        <o3>conveying</o3>
        <o4>abandoning</o4>
        <o5>developing</o5>
        <o6>saying</o6>
        <o7>combining</o7>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>1|2|3|4</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>b5b014e9fef3465fa1ed4870a305c794</id>
  <practiceSet>db28642c43f44f048e0e1be5cf8984f6</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.
</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>University science is now in real crisis - particularly the non-telegenic, non-ology bits of it such as chemistry. Since 1996, 28 universities have stopped offering chemistry degrees, according to the Royal Society of Chemistry.
The society {blank} that as few as six departments (those at Durham, Cambridge, Imperial, UCL, Bristol and Oxford) could remain open by 2014. Most recently Exeter University closed down its chemistry department, {blank} it on "market forces", and Bristol took in some of the refugees The closures have been blamed on a fall in student applications, but money is a {blank} : chemistry degrees are expensive to provide - compared with English, for example - and some scientists say that the way the government concentrates research {blank} on a small number of top departments, such as Bristol, exacerbates the {blank} .</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>predicts</o0>
        <o1>focusing</o1>
        <o2>blaming</o2>
        <o3>projects</o3>
        <o4>prosperous</o4>
        <o5>factor</o5>
        <o6>funding</o6>
        <o7>problem</o7>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>0|2|5|6|7</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>32b79d20ba444664bc26ba9b3d65b863</id>
  <practiceSet>db28642c43f44f048e0e1be5cf8984f6</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Sportswomen's records are important and need to be preserved. And if the paper records don't {blank} , we need to get out and start interviewing people, not to put too fine a {blank} on it, while we still have a {blank} . After all, if the records aren't kept in some form or another, then the stories are {blank} too.
</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>appear</o0>
        <o1>admit</o1>
        <o2>exist</o2>
        <o3>opportunity</o3>
        <o4>point</o4>
        <o5>chance</o5>
        <o6>lost</o6>
        <o7>disappear</o7>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>2|4|5|6</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>5e1d812f002f42b68086328b8877d0ee</id>
  <practiceSet>db28642c43f44f048e0e1be5cf8984f6</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Almost all public spaces nowadays have advertisements in sight, and all forms of media, from newspapers to the cinema to the Internet, are filled with adverts. This all-pervasive presence {blank} the value of advertising to us. Without it, businesses of all types and sizes would {blank} to inform potential customers about the products or services they provide, and consumers would be unable to make {blank} assessments when looking for products to buy and services to use. Without advertising, the promotion of products and {blank} that contribute to our physical and psychological well-being-medicines to treat minor ailments, insurance schemes to protect us, clothes and cosmetics to make us look and feel better- would be {blank} more problematic than it is. And without advertisements and the {blank} represented in them, the world would be a far {blank} place.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>infinitely</o0>
        <o1>problematic</o1>
        <o2>aspirations</o2>
        <o3>reflects</o3>
        <o4>struggle</o4>
        <o5>convinces</o5>
        <o6>thriving</o6>
        <o7>duller</o7>
        <o8>practices</o8>
        <o9>informed</o9>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>3|4|9|8|0|2|7</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<!-- Test 10 -->
<question>
  <id>0bd6864b3b134cb6b862a1e7cc275fba</id>
  <practiceSet>4e1a53fbe93d491289754abda2ea6984</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_MULTIPLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct response. More than one response is correct.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>There are currently 275 open stations and over 253 miles (408 km) of active lines, with three million passenger journeys made each day (927 million journeys made 1999-2000; there are number of stations and tunnels now closed) Lines on the underground can be classified into two types: sub-surface and deep level. The sub-surface lines were dug by the cut-and-cover method, with the tracks running about 5 meters below the surface. Trains on the sub-surface lines have the same loading gauge as British mainline trains. The deep-level or ‘tube’ lines, bared using a tunnelling shield, run about 20 meters below the surface (although this varies considerably), with each track running in separate tunnel lined with cast-iron rings. This tunnel can have a diameter as small as 356m (lift 8.25 in) and the loading gauge is thus considerably smaller than on the sub-surface lines, though standard gauge track is used. Lines of both types usually emerge onto the surface outside the central area. The exceptions being the Victoria line which is in tunnel for its entire length save for a maintenance depot, and the Waterloo and city line which, being very short, has no non-central part and no surface line. Each station displays the underground logo containing the station’s name in place of the word ‘Underground’ both at entrance to the station and repeatedly along the station walls so that they can easily be seen by passengers on arriving trains.

According to the text, which areas have exceptions for surface lines?
</description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o0>Victoria line</o0>
      <o1>Waterloo</o1>
      <o2>Central area</o2>
      <o3>Non-central part</o3>
      <o4>Trains</o4>
    </options>
    <picture></picture>
    <answer>0|1</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>3f6bf019573e4b4ba26e8aad8e8a34f0</id>
  <practiceSet>4e1a53fbe93d491289754abda2ea6984</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_MULTIPLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct response. More than one response is correct.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>The red telephone box, a public telephone kiosk designed by Sir Giles Gilbert Scott, was a once familiar sight on the streets of the United Kingdom. It has all but disappeared in recent years, replaced by a number of different designs. The few kiosks that remain have not been replaced because they are regarded as being of special architectural and historical interest. The first standard public telephone kiosk introduced by the United Kingdom Post Office was produced by Somerville S. Company in 1920 and was designated K1 (Kiosk no. 1). This design was not of the same family OS the familiar red telephone boxes. The red telephone box was the result of a competition in 1924 to design a new grander kiosk. The competition attracted designs from a number of noted architects. The Fine Arts Commission judged the competition and selected the design submitted by Sir Giles Gilbert Scott as the winner. The Post Office made a request that the material used for the design be changed from mild steel to cast iron, and that a slight modification be made to the door; after these changes, the design was designated K2 from 1927 K2 was mainly deployed in and around London. K3 designed in 1930. again by Gilbert Scott was similar to K2 but was constructed from concrete and intended for rural areas. K4 (designed by the Post Office Engineering Department and proposed in 1923) incorporated a machine for buying postage stamps on the exterior. Only 50 kiosks of this design were built. 1(5 was a plywood construction introduced in 1934 and designed to be assembled and dismantled and used at exhibitions. In 1935 K6 was designed to commemorate the silver jubilee of King George V K6 was the first standard telephone kiosk to be used throughout the country.

According to the text, which of the designs were almost same?
</description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o0>K6</o0>
      <o1>K3</o1>
      <o2>K2</o2>
      <o3>K4</o3>
    </options>
    <picture></picture>
    <answer>1|2</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>2373668742c046c9ace73486c5be5ccf</id>
  <practiceSet>4e1a53fbe93d491289754abda2ea6984</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Male lions are rather reticent about expanding their energy in hunting more than three quarters of kills are made by lionesses are in front, tensely scanning ahead, the cubs lag playfully behind and the males bring up the rear, walking slowly, their massive heads nodding with each step as if they were bored with the whole matter. But slothfulness may have survival value. With lionesses busy hunting, the males function as guard for the cubs, protecting them particularly from hyenas.

According to the passage male lions generally do not go for hunting because
</description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o0>they do not like it.</o0>
      <o1>they want lioness to get training</o1>
      <o2>they wish to save their vigour for other things</o2>
      <o3>they are very lazy</o3>
    </options>
    <picture></picture>
    <answer>2</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>af6b6bbac3f341858c992b1dd899b154</id>
  <practiceSet>4e1a53fbe93d491289754abda2ea6984</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>At this stage of civilization, when many nations are brought in to close and vital contact for good and evil, it is essential, as never before, that their gross ignorance of one another should be diminished, that they should begin to understand a little of one another's historical experience and resulting mentality. It is the fault of the English to expect the people of other countries to react as they do, to political and international situations. Our genuine goodwill and good intentions are often brought to nothing, because we expect other people to be like us. This would be corrected if we knew the history, not necessarily in detail but in broad outlines, of the social and political conditions which have given to each nation its present character.

Englishmen like others to react to political situations like
</description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o0>us</o0>
      <o1>themselves</o1>
      <o2>others</o2>
      <o3>each others</o3>
    </options>
    <picture></picture>
    <answer>1</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>9f505e4d866047338574bcefcdd50858</id>
  <practiceSet>4e1a53fbe93d491289754abda2ea6984</practiceSet>
  <type>REORDER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description></description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o1>In 1571, it became the capital of La Florida.</o1>
      <o2>He erected fort San Marcos in six days in defense against a Native American attack such as the one that forced the abandonment of the town a year earlier.</o2>
      <o3>The town had flourished, nearing 400 residents, since its establishment more than a decade earlier in 1566 by Pedro Menendez de Aviles who had founded La Florida and St. Augustine the year before.</o3>
      <o4>Marquez arrived in October 1577 at the abandoned town of Santa Elena with two ships carrying pre-fabricated posts and heavy planking.</o4>
    </options>
    <answer>3|1|2|0</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>01ed6bb122f84bda82570e2d2353a202</id>
  <practiceSet>4e1a53fbe93d491289754abda2ea6984</practiceSet>
  <type>REORDER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description></description>
    <title></title>
    <options>
      <o1>Researchers have developed a system that can 3-D print the basic structure of an entire building.</o1>
      <o2>Ultimately, the scientist say, this approach could enable the design and the construction of new buildings that would not be feasible with traditional building methods.</o2>
      <o3>Even the internal structure could be modified in new ways; different materials could be incorporated as the process goes along.</o3>
      <o4>Structure built with this system could be produced faster and less expensively than traditional construction methods allow.</o4>
    </options>
    <answer>0|3|2|1</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>cd0ec36928e940a6b9db3e87b88c0bde</id>
  <practiceSet>4e1a53fbe93d491289754abda2ea6984</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>A blueprint for a city park in Penrith’s CBD has gone on {blank} for public comment. The plan seeks to rezone land {blank} bound by Station Street, Henry Street, Allen Place and Woodriff Street so Penrith City Council can {blank} a city park precinct. The rezoning will allow greater flexibility regarding use of the site and design, a statement from the council said.A city park has been part of council’s planning since it was included in the Penrith City Centre {blank} in 2006, and was identified as one of Penrith Progression’s first priorities.
transform our city centre. A contemporary public space, surrounded by a mix of housing and specialist retail {blank} , will in turn foster redevelopment of private land in the area.
</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>Raise</o0>
        <o1>display</o1>
        <o2>make</o2>
        <o3>develop</o3>
        <o4>policy</o4>
        <o5>strategy</o5>
        <o6>supported</o6>
        <o7>business</o7>
        <o8>opportunities</o8>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>1|3|5|6|8</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>35c014e0f7a54312a6666df23519e06a</id>
  <practiceSet>4e1a53fbe93d491289754abda2ea6984</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>West Point researchers found that using a laptop or tablet in the classroom had {blank} an overall drop of roughly one-fifth of a standard deviation. Students who were allowed {blank} use of their laptops or tablets performed with an 18 per cent reduction, while those with a modified tablet access saw a 17 per cent drop. This {blank} a 1.7 point drop on the 100 point scale. The negative effects were seen most heavily in male students, and those who came into the class with a high GPA. The researchers say that both unrestricted and modified use may affect students in a number of ways. It could lead to {blank} , in which students are checking social media or even doing homework for another class, and it may reduce students’ abilities to effectively take notes. The researchers say professors may even change their own {blank} , interacting differently with the class in response to students using devices.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>caused</o0>
        <o1>create</o1>
        <o2>consider</o2>
        <o3>unrestricted</o3>
        <o4>equates</o4>
        <o5>distractions</o5>
        <o6>behavior</o6>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>0|3|4|5|6</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>19f4a3b236b249e98c2f929a4de59682</id>
  <practiceSet>4e1a53fbe93d491289754abda2ea6984</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>California on Wednesday suspended its mandatory statewide 25 percent reduction in urban water use, telling local {blank} to set their own conservation standards after a relatively wet winter and a year of {blank} savings in urban water use.
The new rules are a sharp change in policy for a state {blank} to manage one of the worst droughts in its history. They came after a winter in which El Niño storms fell short of what meteorologists projected — particularly in the southern part of the state — but still partly filled {blank} reservoirs in Northern California and, more critically, partly replenished the mountain snowpacks that provide water into the spring and summer.
</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>area</o0>
        <o1>communities</o1>
        <o2>parched</o2>
        <o3>enormous</o3>
        <o4>huge</o4>
        <o5>struggling</o5>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>1|3|5|2</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>25697d5e00c544c6bfb8e8dc03abc816</id>
  <practiceSet>4e1a53fbe93d491289754abda2ea6984</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>In the Eastern Front, on 22 June, the great Soviet offensive, codenamed Operation Bagration, almost {blank} the German Army Group Centre. Soon the Germans were forced to defend Ukraine and Poland . Arriving Soviet troops caused uprisings {blank} German government in Eastern European countries, but all of those failed to succeed unless helped by the Soviets. Then another Soviet offensive {blank} Romania and Bulgaria to join the Allies. Communist Serbs partisans under Josip Broz Tit {blank} Belgrade with some help from Bulgaria and the Soviet Union. By early 1945, the Soviets {blank} many German-occupied countries: Greece, Albania, Yugoslavia and Hungary. Finland switched to the side of the Soviets and Allies.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>forced</o0>
        <o1>attacked</o1>
        <o2>destroyed</o2>
        <o3>retook</o3>
        <o4>against</o4>
        <o5>took</o5>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>2|4|0|3|1</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>011f1b04ab5e4c2993a7153524a38e82</id>
  <practiceSet>4e1a53fbe93d491289754abda2ea6984</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>The humble brick home, the cornerstone of Australian dwellings since the early 1800s, has been through many {blank} in the past 200 years.
From pre-Victorian homes, to post-war homes all the way to the new Australian dream: a three-bedroom brick home on a fair chunk of land. Here are three houses from around the region that exemplify the {blank} of the brick home.
{blank} to the 1850s, 270 Latrobe Tce, Newtown doesn’t look much like it did when it was first built, with white paint covering the facade, giving it a Hamptons feel.
Inside, the four-bedroom home is full of period charm, with {blank} wood trimmings, a wrought iron balcony at the rear of the home, and an exposed beam ceiling in the upstairs bedroom.
Set on one of Newtown’s most affluent streets, the kitchen is {blank} with high-end appliances and looks out over the backyard and entertaining area. The lifestyle doesn’t come cheap though, with the expected price range of $745,000 to $815,000.
</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>timed</o0>
        <o1>evolution</o1>
        <o2>dated</o2>
        <o3>polished</o3>
        <o4>stunning</o4>
        <o5>incarnations</o5>
        <o6>beautiful</o6>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>5|1|2|3|4</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>160ef679fc514090bb9b13da26805e62</id>
  <practiceSet>4e1a53fbe93d491289754abda2ea6984</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>The most {blank} ingredient in Indian cooking, the {blank} element with which all dishes begin and, normally, the cheapest vegetable available, the pink onion is an essential item in the shopping basket of families of all classes. A popular saying holds that you will never starve because you can always afford a roti (a piece of simple, flat bread) and an onion.
But in recent weeks, the onion has started to seem an unaffordable {blank} for India's poor.
Over the past few days, another sharp {blank} in prices has begun to unsettle the influential urban middle classes. The sudden {blank} in prices has been caused by large exports to neighboring countries and a shortage of {blank} . With its capacity for bringing down governments and scarring political careers, the onion plays an {blank} role in Indian politics. This week reports of rising onion prices have made front-page news and absorbed the attention of the governing elite.
</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>vital</o0>
        <o1>impressive</o1>
        <o2>affordable</o2>
        <o3>ordinary</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>simple</o0>
        <o1>basic</o1>
        <o2>great</o2>
        <o3>only</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>material</o0>
        <o1>luxury</o1>
        <o2>element</o2>
        <o3>ingredients</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>surge</o0>
        <o1>plummet</o1>
        <o2>decreases</o2>
        <o3>fluctuation</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>spike</o0>
        <o1>climb</o1>
        <o2>progress</o2>
        <o3>improvement</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>supply</o0>
        <o1>need</o1>
        <o2>demand</o2>
        <o3>price</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>explosive</o0>
        <o1>vital</o1>
        <o2>amazing</o2>
        <o3>expensive</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>0|1|1|0|0|0|0</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>faa4cc66367a46468bd88c9b7dc00516</id>
  <practiceSet>4e1a53fbe93d491289754abda2ea6984</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Impressionism was a nineteenth century art movement that began as a loose association of Paris-based artists who started publicly exhibiting their art in the 1860s. Characteristics of Impressionist painting include visible brush strokes, light colours, open composition, {blank} on light in its changing qualities (often accentuating the effects of the passage of time), ordinary subject matter, and unusual visual angles. The name of the movement is {blank} from Claude.
Monet's Impression, Sunrise (Impression, soleil levant). Critic Louis Leroy inadvertently coined the term in a satiric review published in Le Charivari. Radicals in their time, early Impressionists broke the rules of academic painting. They began by giving colours, freely brushed, primacy over line, drawing {blank} from the work of painters, such as Eugene Delacroix. They also took the {blank} of painting out of the studio and into the world. Previously, not only still-lives and portraits, but also landscapes had been painted indoors, but the Impressionists found that they could {blank} the momentary and transient effects of sunlight by painting air (in plain air).
</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>emphasized</o0>
        <o1>emphasis</o1>
        <o2>rely</o2>
        <o3>depending</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>derived</o0>
        <o1>come</o1>
        <o2>attribute</o2>
        <o3>related</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>paintings</o0>
        <o1>lines</o1>
        <o2>inspiration</o2>
        <o3>enlightenment</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>fact</o0>
        <o1>act</o1>
        <o2>notion</o2>
        <o3>thought</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>remember</o0>
        <o1>capture</o1>
        <o2>memorize</o2>
        <o3>notice</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>1|0|2|1|1</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>9098a812f2aa4d26b23bf13bb598065b</id>
  <practiceSet>4e1a53fbe93d491289754abda2ea6984</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>All approaches aim to increase blood flow to areas of tension and to release painful knots {blank} muscle known as "trigger points". "Trigger points are tense areas of muscle that are almost constantly contracting," says Kippen. "The contraction causes pain, which in turn causes contraction, so you have a vicious circle. This is what deep tissue massage aims to break. "The way to do this, as I found out under Ogedengbe's elbow, is to apply pressure {blank} the point, stopping the blood flow, and then to release, which causes the brain to flood the affected area  {blank} blood, encouraging the muscle to relax. At the same time, says Kippen, you can fool the tensed muscle into relaxing {blank} applying pressure to a complementary one nearby. "If you cause any muscle to contract, its opposite will expand. So you try to trick the body {blank} relaxing the muscle that is in spasm."</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>to</o0>
        <o1>on</o1>
        <o2>of</o2>
        <o3>from</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>to</o0>
        <o1>in</o1>
        <o2>on</o2>
        <o3>for</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>of</o0>
        <o1>in</o1>
        <o2>by</o2>
        <o3>with</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>from</o0>
        <o1>by</o1>
        <o2>to</o2>
        <o3>with</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>into</o0>
        <o1>with</o1>
        <o2>for</o2>
        <o3>to</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>2|0|3|1|0</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>2382335e011545d58319e6e50510caf9</id>
  <practiceSet>4e1a53fbe93d491289754abda2ea6984</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Measuring poverty on a global scale {blank} establishing a uniform poverty level across extremely divergent economies, which can result in only rough comparisons. The World Bank has defined the international poverty line as U.S. $1 and $2 per day in 1993 Purchasing Power Parity (PPP), which adjusts for differences in the {blank} of goods and services between countries. The $1 per day level is generally used for the {blank} developed countries, primarily African; the $2-per-day level is used for {blank} economies such as those of East Asia and Latin America.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>requires</o0>
        <o1>wants</o1>
        <o2>asks</o2>
        <o3>relates</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>expenses</o0>
        <o1>prices</o1>
        <o2>quantity</o2>
        <o3>quality</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>most</o0>
        <o1>limited</o1>
        <o2>least</o2>
        <o3>more</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>medium-income</o0>
        <o1>middle-income</o1>
        <o2>lowest-income</o2>
        <o3>high-income</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>0|1|2|1</answer>
  </template>
</question><question>
  <id>3e526c0c047143798d061ee27c3139be</id>
  <practiceSet>4e1a53fbe93d491289754abda2ea6984</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Imagine the skyline of a modern {blank} if the elevator did not exist. Buildings would be limited to five or six stories. Most of the architecture of the 20th and 21st century would be impossible. Office towers, hotels and high-rise apartments would hardly stand in their present form.The need for {blank} transport is as old as civilization. Over the centuries, mankind has employed ingenious forms of lifting. The earliest lifts used man, animal and water power to raise the load. Lifting devices relied on these basic {blank} of power from the early agricultural societies until the dawn of the Industrial Revolution from ancient times through the Middle Ages, and into the 13th century, man or animal power was the driving {blank} behind hoisting devices. In ancient Greece, Archimedes developed an {blank} lifting device operated by ropes and pulleys, in which the hoisting ropes were coiled around a winding drum by a capstan and levers. By A.D. 80, gladiators and wild animals rode crude elevators up to the arena level of the Roman Coliseum. Medieval records contain numerous drawings of hoists lifting men and supplies to isolated locations. Among the most famous is the hoist at the monastery of St. Barlaam in Greece. The monastery stood on a pinnacle approximately (200 ft) above the ground. Its hoist, which employed a basket or cargo net, was the only means up or down.</description>
    <title></title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>world</o0>
        <o1>city</o1>
        <o2>planet</o2>
        <o3>earth</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>horizontal</o0>
        <o1>steep</o1>
        <o2>perpendicular</o2>
        <o3>vertical</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>designs</o0>
        <o1>models</o1>
        <o2>forms</o2>
        <o3>systems</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>strength</o0>
        <o1>skill</o1>
        <o2>ability</o2>
        <o3>force</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>improved</o0>
        <o1>elevated</o1>
        <o2>amended</o2>
        <o3>enhanced</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>1|3|2|3|0</answer>
  </template>
</question>

</questions>