<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<questions>  
  <question>
    <id>ad1a8b8f950447b69a17c4cf7d5828a6</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1fd7c</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of  your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>In the 1980s the United States Department of Energy was looking for suitable sites to bury radioactive waste material generated by its nuclear energy programs. The government was considering burying the dangerous waste in deep underground chambers in remote desert areas. The problem, however, was that nuclear waste remains highly radioactive for thousands of years. The commission entrusted with tackling the problem of waste disposal was aware that the dangers posed by radioactive emissions must be communicated to our descendants of at least 10,000 years hence. So the task became one of finding a way to tell future societies about the risk posed by these deadly deposits.Of course, human society in the distant future may be well aware of the hazards of radiation. Technological advances may one day provide solutions to this dilemma. But the belief in constant technological advancement is based on our perceptions of advances made throughout history and prehistory. We cannot be sure that society won't have slipped backward into an age of barbarism due to any of several catastrophic events, whether the result of nature such as the onset of a new ice age or perhaps humankind's failure to solve the scourges of war and pollution. In the event of global catastrophe, it is quite possible that humans of the distant future will be on the far side of a broken link of communication and technological understanding.</description>
      <title>Communicating with the Future</title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>9d9ca268754a40d89ba7db8c55a4d081</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1fd7c</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>Conflicts between parents and their children at bedtime are common. For adults, sleep is welcome rest. For children, it's lost time, time when they could be doing something fun like playing computer games or finishing a drawing of their cartoon hero. So the youngsters often resist it. And in families where both parents work, the nightly ritual of putting the children to bed can be even more of a tussle. Most parents don't get home until at least seven in the evening, and there's little slack between bath, dinner, homework and bedtime. Whatever the situation, a growing child still requires a decent amount of sleep, and for young schoolchildren and toddlers, that's between 10 and 12 hours a night.But what happens when children fight it every step of the way, from taking a bath to putting on pyjamas to getting into bed? When they refuse to sleep alone in bed or wake up repeatedly, or need to be rocked for an hour before nodding off? It's usually not hard to tell when a child doesn't get enough sleep. "He can be irritable, whiny, more clumsy," says paediatrician Dr Leigh Shapleigh. "And when a child has any sort of behaviour problem, it is just exacerbated by lack of sleep." Children - especially small children - thrive on routine, so the more regular their bedtime is the better it is for the entire family.</description>
      <title></title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
    <question>
    <id>b494e8d9c2874dc7a31f3df26dd70b03</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1fd7c</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will have 20 minutes to plan, write and revise an essay about the topic below. Your response will be judged on how well you develop a position, organize your ideas, present supporting details and control the elements of standard written English. You should write 200-300 words.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:20:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>Information revolution has changed the ways of mass communication and had some negative and positive effects on individuals’ lives as well as on society. To what extent you are agree or disagree?</description>
      <title></title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question> 
 <question>
    <id>a02b0437357f4c9fa9763bff7f7eb8ea</id>
    <practiceSet>89e5ed3d303847b48535195f410d564a</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>One of the most captivating applications of micro-arrays is the detection of differential expression of particular genes in disease states. The opportunities to compare hundreds of thousands of genes in their normal and diseased states present enormous prospects. For example,the pharmaceutical industry is already using micro-arrays in an effort to identify targets for pharmacological intervention and cure. An alluring hope is that one day, the technique will prove useful for early diagnosis of various cancers. Likewise, micro-array technology is revolutionizing basic molecular biology research.Using the technique and mining the vast amount of data, researchers are making rapid progress in the understanding of developmental regulation, devising a myriad of schemes defining how genes are turned on or off in response to different signals. Undoubtedly, these discoveries will reap fruit in our understanding and eventual treatment of various human diseases. Despite the great excitement, the new technology is not without its challenges, chief among them being expense.</description>
      <title></title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>408e9dc454cd49b9aea2d7591246e183</id>
    <practiceSet>89e5ed3d303847b48535195f410d564a</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>The Mediterranean Sea sedimentary record reveals intermittent black sediment layers that seem to represent environmental changes over time.These layers, darkened by organic matter, rare in most ocean sediments, indicate the presence of a strong, physical control.  Some geologists credit "reverse circulation," wherein waters flowing inward from the Atlantic Ocean are flushed back out in a reverse flow by the constant influx of fresh water from the several rivers that feed the sea.  As surface waters evaporate, the heavily salted remnant, containing less dissolved oxygen, sinks.  During intensely wet periods, soil nutrients fertilize the surface, phytoplankton production increases, and evaporation dissipates, creating an organically rich environment.  However, sedimentary records show bottom-dwellers coexisting with the dark layers were oxygen-stressed, so, reverse circulation could not have existed. Milankovitch Cycles, associated with earth- sun positional relationships, which change the dates of the equinoxes/solstices in 20,000 year cycles, are more likely. Climatic effects include intense rainy seasons depending on the earth's tilt, orbital eccentricity, and distance from the sun. Additionally, the 20,000 year cycles match the spacing of dark layers in the Mediterranean record.</description>
      <title></title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>61153aedda8f428a9c24888849d9eb95</id>
    <practiceSet>89e5ed3d303847b48535195f410d564a</practiceSet>
    <type>WRITE_ESSAY</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will have 20 minutes to plan, write and revise an essay about the topic below. Your response will be judged on how well you develop a position, organize your ideas, present supporting details and control the elements of standard written English. You should write 200-300 words.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:20:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>Television has two roles: to inform and to entertain. Explain which of these roles you see as more important. To what extent do you think that TV today performs each of these roles in an effective way? Support your point of view with details from your own experiences, observations or reading.</description>
      <title></title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
<question>
    <id>3aab02be0d3748ed98b480f1362610c6</id>
    <practiceSet>a540452272644faab9254ea73290cb9d</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>Deforestation is occurring in Earth's forests on a massive scale, often resulting in damage to the quality of the land. Agriculture is the largest global driver of deforestation. Farmers cut forests to provide more room for planting crops or grazing livestock. Many small farmers will each clear a few acres by cutting down trees and burning them in a process known as “slash and burn” agriculture. To provide wood and paper products loggers cut down a large number of trees each year. Wildfires and overgrazing also prevent the growth of young trees.The quickest solution to deforestation would be to simply stop cutting down trees or to manage forest resources. Reforestation efforts are a vital way to undo some of the damage that has already been done. Reforestation has many positive effects on the environment. One of the most dramatic impacts is an increase of habitat for millions of organisms. Adding trees allows the forest to expand its canopy, which blocks the sun’s rays during the day and holds in warm air at night. Forest soils are moist, and protection by sun-blocking tree cover keeps them from drying out. Without this coverage plants and animals would experience extreme temperature swings that could be harmful.Reforestation also impacts climate change. Trees play an important role in absorbing the greenhouse gas, carbon dioxide that fuels global climate change - this is called carbon sequestration. Greenhouse gases trap heat from the sun in Earth's atmosphere, which can lead to global climate change. Adding trees can reduce the amount of carbon dioxide in the atmosphere.</description>
      <title></title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>72de2e3744bb476eb0eeb4e53d4b0928</id>
    <practiceSet>a540452272644faab9254ea73290cb9d</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.Bacteria are the smallest living things with a cellular structure; each individual bacterium consisting of one single colorless cell, which is usually either spherical or rod-shaped. Individual bacteria measure from 0.0001 inches to 0.00001 inches in length, so they can be seen only with the help of a high-power microscope. They are so small that they can float in the atmosphere, usually as 'passengers' on dust particles, up to a height of several thousand feet, except immediately after a heavy downpour, when the air is washed clean.Bacteria are present in all natural as well as in drinking water that has not been purified or bailed. A large number of bacteria live in the soil, down to a depth of several feet, and they are particularly abundant in faeces and sewage. Thus, living bacteria are always present on the surface of our bodies and on everything around us, but they are seldom found inside the tissues of healthy plants and animals.Since most kinds of bacteria contain no chlorophyll, they cannot use light energy and Synthesize their food. They have to get their food in other ways, mostly ready-made by other living things. Like plants, it can only take in dissolved food. A majority get their supply from dead remains of other organisms. Bacteria reproduce by dividing into two, and these new individuals grow so quickly that they are ready to divide again in about half an hour. Hence, in ten hours, under the most favourable conditions, a single bacterium can produce over a million bacteria. That is one reason for it being so difficult to ensure any object is completely free from any kind of living organisms. In addition, some forms of bacteria have a waxy envelope outside their cell wall and are thus more difficult to kill.</description>
      <title></title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
    <question>
    <id>fb934fbc41324ba8b427e94eb961e3c7</id>
    <practiceSet>a540452272644faab9254ea73290cb9d</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>There’s good news for people who have depression – it’s very treatable! Like many medical problems, it can be managed by taking a comprehensive approach to health care that involves healthy lifestyle changes, therapy, and the thoughtful use of medications.Finding a compassionate doctor, or psychiatrist, is the first step. Psychiatrists are medical doctors who are specifically trained in diseases of the brain. They are skilled at treating people and getting them back on a path towards health and happiness. A mental illness such as depression might alter one’s trajectory, but it does not have to define it.Even for those people who have a tricky form of depression – one that is seemingly resistant to medication and therapy – there is still hope. Electroconvulsive therapy (ECT) is an extremely effective tool that can change a person’s life. Check out more information about innovative therapies such as ECT on the National Alliance of Mental Illness (NAMI) website. And in some cases, a brief stay at the psychiatric hospital can be a life-saving experience. Most of these psychiatric admissions are voluntary, but in some cases, when personal or public safety is at risk, there is an option for involuntary commitment. Regardless of the circumstances, the goal is the same for professionals and patients alike – recovery and healing. No matter the extent of one’s depression, there is always hope.</description>
      <title></title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>a0cec612e6114eb183ebc45562881adb</id>
    <practiceSet>a540452272644faab9254ea73290cb9d</practiceSet>
    <type>WRITE_ESSAY</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will have 20 minutes to plan, write and revise an essay about the topic below. Your response will be judged on how well you develop a position, organize your ideas, present supporting details and control the elements of standard written English. You should write 200-300 words.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:20:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>The costs of international travel are decreasing and tourism is growing. What are the advantages and disadvantages of increasing tourism activity in different countries? Choose which position you most agree with and discuss why you chose that position. Support your point of view with details form your own experiences, observations or reading.</description>
      <title></title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question> 
  
  <!--New tests 25022017-->
  <question>
    <id>fabe6ef27bba43f5902bdc055d808f93</id>
    <practiceSet>39d265f15f41481891312961d73f01bf</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of  your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>There are lots of different kinds of ants: carpenter ants, leaf‐cutter ants, sweet ants, fire ants, and many more. They are different colors, too. They can be red, or brown, or black. Some are very, very small, and some are rather big. Whatever their differences, though, all ants are social creatures. They live in large groups called colonies. Some ant colonies are big and have millions of ants. There are different types of ants in the colony, and they each have different jobs. The queen lays eggs. Soldier ants protect the queen and the colony. They also gather food and attack other colonies if they need new nesting space. Worker ants take care of babies, look for food, and build ant homes (anthills or mounds). Soldier and worker ants are female. Male ants’ only job is to mate with the queen in order to produce eggs, which hatch into baby ants.   Ants are busy little insects. It’s easy to see them moving quickly here and there. Sometimes you can see them carrying a small piece of something, or dragging part of a leaf somewhere. Sometimes you even see two ants helping each other carry the same crumb. But where are they going and what are they doing?  Ants may seem to be just running around, but they are actually important parts of their ecosystem, their world under our feet.   One thing ants do to help their ecosystem is to keep soil healthy. By constantly digging through the soil, they create spaces in it. Soil needs space inside it for air and water. Without air and water in soil, the tiny creatures that live in soil would not survive.   Ants also help bring nutrients to soil. When they bring food particles to their nests, they add nutrients to soil because they don’t eat everything they bring. Their leftovers stay in the soil and break down into nutrients for other creatures living in the soil.</description>
      <title></title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>e4d1f82886724224a8e9c63290035bea</id>
    <practiceSet>39d265f15f41481891312961d73f01bf</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>This suit of armor, along with six similar armors, were made in 1612 for a German ruler named Johann Georg I of Saxony (Saxony is now the city of Dresden). His wife, Magdalena Sibylla, presented all seven sets of armor to him as a Christmas gift. We know that they were actually used on July 4, 1613, in a tournament celebrating the baptism of the couple's son and heir, also named Johann Georg. In this particular military sporting event, the contestants fought on foot with swords instead of on horseback with lances. The men who made plate armor like this suit were highly skilled craftspeople. To produce suits of armor, they hammered bars of iron and steel into flat plates. Then they created patterns based on their customers' bodies and shaped the metal pieces to fit exactly. This armor is densely covered with intricate designs—intertwining leaves, flowers, and fruits, as well as four fierce lion faces on the breastplate and the back plate, and on each cowter (elbow defense). Artists who collaborated with the armor makers created the designs by etching (cutting into) the metal with acid, blackening the surface with paint or varnish, then wiping and polishing it, leaving the ink in the etched lines only. This suit of armor weighs sixty‐three pounds and provides both protection and mobility. Although plate armor looks inflexible, parts of it like the cuisses (kweeses) (plates covering the front thighs) are made of many separate pieces, like the shell covering the tail of a lobster, to allow a full range of movement.</description>
      <title></title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>634e32c2a8694eb5bc98ba635ee72fad</id>
    <practiceSet>39d265f15f41481891312961d73f01bf</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will have 20 minutes to plan, write and revise an essay about the topic below. Your response will be judged on how well you develop a position, organize your ideas, present supporting details and control the elements of standard written English. You should write 200-300 words.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:20:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>Advances in science and technology and other areas of society in the last 100 years have transformed the way we live as well as postponing the day we die. There is no better time to be alive than now. To what extent do you agree or disagree with this opinion?</description>
      <title></title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>f43ae8b097eb4bcfbea046f05fa3dc94</id>
    <practiceSet>dffc4ce9224b4f05b2d81e9a523be1d7</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of  your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>Thousands of years ago in ancient Egypt, pharaohs were buried inside huge pyramids. Before burial, however, their bodies were preserved. 1 To do this, the ancient Egyptians would mummify their kings. Mummification was a very careful process. In fact, it took 70 days to complete. First, embalmers2 would remove organs from the body. They removed the brain by sticking a hook up the pharaoh’s nose. This would loosen up the brain so it could be pulled out through the nose. The ancient Egyptians didn’t think the brain was important, so it was thrown away. The stomach, liver, intestines, and lungs were also removed. These organs were carefully wrapped and kept in jars. They thought the heart was most important. They left the heart in its place. The body was now a shell. The embalmers stuffed it with fabric and sawdust. Then it was covered in salt, which dried it out. When the body was completely dry, it was wrapped in layers and layers of linen3 bandages. Then it was placed in a coffin. Sometimes, the coffin was placed inside another coffin. These coffins were made out of wood or stone. They were either shaped like a rectangle or like the mummy itself. The coffin was placed in a tomb. Next to it were many objects for the mummy to use in the afterlife.</description>
      <title></title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>02a550a64f2242449066395b4618f162</id>
    <practiceSet>dffc4ce9224b4f05b2d81e9a523be1d7</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>{newline} The structure of the feet and legs varies greatly among frog species, depending in part on whether they live primarily on the ground, in water, in trees, or in burrows. Frogs must be able to move quickly through their environment to catch prey and escape predators, and numerous adaptations help them do so.  Many frogs, especially those that live in water, have webbed toes. The degree to which the toes are webbed is directly proportional to the amount of time the species lives in the water. For example, the completely aquatic African dwarf frog has fully webbed toes, whereas the toes of White's tree frog , an arboreal species, are only a half or a quarter webbed. {newline} Arboreal frogs have "toe pads" to help grip vertical surfaces. These pads, located on the ends of the toes, do not work by suction. Rather, the surface of the pad consists of interlocking cells, with a small gap between adjacent cells. When the frog applies pressure to the toe pads, the interlocking cells grip irregularities on the substrate. The small gaps between the cells drain away all but a thin layer of moisture on the pad, and maintain a grip through capillarity. This allows the frog to grip smooth surfaces, and does not function when the pads are excessively wet.{newline} In many arboreal frogs, a small "intercalary structure" in each toe increases the surface area touching the substrate. Furthermore, since hopping through trees can be dangerous, many arboreal frogs have hip joints that allow both hopping and walking. Some frogs that live high in trees even possess an elaborate degree of webbing between their toes, as do aquatic frogs. In these arboreal frogs, the webs allow the frogs to "parachute" or control their glide from one position in the canopy to another. Ground-dwelling frogs generally lack the adaptations of aquatic and arboreal frogs. Most have smaller toe pads, if any, and little webbing. Some burrowing frogs have a toe extension—a metatarsal tubercle—that helps them to burrow. The hind legs of ground dwellers are more muscular than those of aqueous and tree-dwelling frogs.</description>
      <title></title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>bf0e5e1d34e34600b6f2e5e9092deea1</id>
    <practiceSet>dffc4ce9224b4f05b2d81e9a523be1d7</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will have 20 minutes to plan, write and revise an essay about the topic below. Your response will be judged on how well you develop a position, organize your ideas, present supporting details and control the elements of standard written English. You should write 200-300 words.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:20:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>Some people believe that the Earth is being harmed (damaged) by human activity. Others feel that human activity makes the Earth a better place to live. What is your opinion? Use specific reasons and examples to support your answer.</description>
      <title></title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>07967bcaf02340ab83d375a2b34902d1</id>
    <practiceSet>e8c3b7b66171443e874f972f432c4103</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of  your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>Brazil’s flag symbolizes the government of the people. The banner that stretches across the middle of the sphere reads: “Ordem e Progresso.” This means “Order and Progress” in the language of Portuguese. Portugese is the official language of Brazil. The flag also symbolizes the lush landscape1 of Brazil. Brazil also has beautiful natural resources. 2 The blue sphere around the stars in the flag resembles the bright blue sky over Brazil. Only in tropical climates is the sky so blue. The yellow in the flag in the shape of a diamond represents gold and diamonds. The early wealth of Brazil came from gold and diamond mining. The green in the flag symbolizes the country’s deep forests and fertile fields. Brazil also has profited from its sugar plantations, 3 coffee plantations, and rubber making businesses. These natural resources helped determine the social and economic character of Brazil. In the colonial era, many Portuguese adventurers came to Brazil. The Portuguese brought slaves from West Africa to work on sugar plantations. Today, Brazil’s population is a mixture of these groups – West Africans, Portuguese, and also Native Americans.</description>
      <title></title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>3e61cc96c56e46f897eb3d90514b67c4</id>
    <practiceSet>e8c3b7b66171443e874f972f432c4103</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>{newline} Fleas are perfectly designed by nature to feast on anything containing blood. Like a shark in the water or a wolf in the woods, fleas are ideally equipped to do what they do, making them very difficult to defeat. The bodies of these tiny parasites are extremely hardy and well-suited for their job. A flea has a very hard exoskeleton, which means the body is covered by a tough, tile-like plate called a sclerite. Because of these plates, fleas are almost impossible to squish. The exoskeletons of fleas are also waterproof and shock resistant, and therefore fleas are highly resistant to the sprays and chemicals used to kill them.{newline} Fleas are some of the best jumpers in the natural world. Fleas can jump 30,000 times in a row without stopping, and they are able to accelerate through the air at an incredibly high rate—a rate which is over ten times what humans can withstand in an airplane. Fleas have very long rear legs with huge thigh muscles and multiple joints. When they get ready to jump, they fold their long legs up and crouch like a runner on a starting block. Several of their joints contain a protein called resilin, which helps catapult fleas into the air as they jump, similar to the way a rubber band provides momentum to a slingshot. Outward facing claws on the bottom of their legs grip anything they touch when they land. {newline} The adult female flea mates after her first blood meal and begins producing eggs in just 1 to 2 days. In the cocoon state, fleas are fully developed adults, and will hatch immediately if conditions are favorable. Fleas can detect warmth, movement, and carbon dioxide in exhaled breath, and these three factors stimulate them to emerge as new adults. Fleas are intimidating opponents. The best way to control fleas, therefore, is to take steps to prevent an infestation from ever occurring.</description>
      <title></title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>d2127bfd6e5347d9a2f2193fae73804c</id>
    <practiceSet>e8c3b7b66171443e874f972f432c4103</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will have 20 minutes to plan, write and revise an essay about the topic below. Your response will be judged on how well you develop a position, organize your ideas, present supporting details and control the elements of standard written English. You should write 200-300 words.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:20:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>Nowadays the way many people interact with each other has changed because of technology and has affected the relationships both negatively and positively. Give reasons for your answer and include any relevant examples from your own knowledge or experience.</description>
      <title></title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>e684076e0dec4a1c80b85908f3555c96</id>
    <practiceSet>a2dc026da5a84119be23ddaab151b4fc</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of  your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>Water, the saying goes, will find its way. And so it seems to be the case in West Africa. Rising sea levels and erosion along the coast are threatening the homes and jobs of hundreds of thousands of people across West Africa. Grand-Lahou is one example. The Ivory Coast tourist town is about 100 kilometers west of Abidjan. The waves are swallowing the coastline of Grand-Lahou’s old town at a rate of one to two meters a year.{newline} It is a problem along much of West Africa’s coast. The effects could be serious. One-third of the area’s people live by the sea. The coastal areas contribute about half of the area’s GDP, or gross domestic product. Eugene Koffi has spent all his life on a shrinking patch of land between the sea and lagoon. It is called Lahou-Kpanda. Pointing out across the water, Koffi says the sea used to be back there, two kilometers away. But now, it comes up to just a few meters away from where he stands. He says there used to be people living there, and coconut trees. But now, many houses have been abandoned along the coast. Residents moved inland. Coastal erosion is not new. It is a natural event. But experts say human activity is speeding up the process. With global warming, the sea levels are rising around the world. Grand-Lahou has been hurt by nearby government dams and the practice of taking sand to build houses. Many buildings from the early 20th century have washed away.{newline} Barthelemy Bamba is the director of the Center for Ocean Research in Abidjan. They work on prevention and awareness issues. They also advise the Ivorian government on developing future structures like coastal roads. </description>
      <title></title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>5909510b7fec4ad784f7ea5f418dac40</id>
    <practiceSet>a2dc026da5a84119be23ddaab151b4fc</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>Obesity is a medical condition in which excess body fat has accumulated to the extent that it may have an adverse effect on health, leading to reduced life expectancy and/or increased health problems. Body mass index (BMI), a measurement which compares weight and height, defines people as overweight (pre-obese) when their BMI is between 25 kg/m2 and 30 kg/m2, and obese when it is greater than 30 kg/m2. {newline} Obesity increases the likelihood of various diseases, particularly heart disease, type 2 diabetes, breathing difficulties during sleep, certain types of cancer, and osteoarthritis. Obesity is most commonly caused by a combination of excessive dietary calories, lack of physical activity, and genetic susceptibility, although a few cases are caused primarily by genes, endocrine disorders, medications or psychiatric illness. Evidence to support the view that some obese people eat little yet gain weight due to a slow metabolism is limited; on average obese people have a greater energy expenditure than their thin counterparts due to the energy required to maintain an increased body mass. {newline} The primary treatment for obesity is dieting and physical exercise. To supplement this, or in case of failure, anti-obesity drugs may be taken to reduce appetite or inhibit fat absorption. In severe cases, surgery is performed or an intragastric balloon is placed to reduce stomach volume and/or bowel length, leading to earlier satiation and reduced ability to absorb nutrients from food. Obesity is a leading preventable cause of death worldwide, with increasing prevalence in adults and children, and authorities view it as one of the most serious public health problems of the 21st century. Obesity is stigmatized in much of the modern world (particularly in the Western world), though it was widely perceived as a symbol of wealth and fertility at other times in history, and still is in some parts of the world.</description>
      <title></title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>843c7c21fbd5461e83c74650591c3ac3</id>
    <practiceSet>a2dc026da5a84119be23ddaab151b4fc</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will have 20 minutes to plan, write and revise an essay about the topic below. Your response will be judged on how well you develop a position, organize your ideas, present supporting details and control the elements of standard written English. You should write 200-300 words.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:20:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>Some people believe that dangerous sports should be banned. To what extent do you agree or disagree?</description>
      <title></title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>c496aa0c14c04546af28a3086cd94b55</id>
    <practiceSet>76866578defd49e5be08b21dd869e474</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of  your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>Students are responsible for familiarizing themselves with the University Code of Student  Conduct, as on enrollment with the University  the Student has placed themselves under the policies and regulations of the University and all of its duly constituted bodies. Disciplinary authority is exercised through the Student’s  Conduct Committee. The Committee has procedures in place for hearing allegations of misconduct. Copies of the Student  conduct code are available at the Student Services Office. {newline} Academic dishonesty is never condoned by the University. This includes cheating and plagiarism, which violate the Student Conduct Code and could result in expulsion or failing the course. Cheating includes but is not limited to obtaining or giving unauthorized help during an examination, getting unauthorized information about the contents of an examination before it is administered, using unauthorized sources of information during an examination, altering or falsifying the record of any grades, altering or supplying answers after an examination has been handed in, falsifying any official University record, and misrepresenting the facts to get exemptions from or extensions to course requirements. {newline} Plagiarism includes but is not limited to submitting any paper or other document, to satisfy an academic requirement, which has been copied either in whole or in part from someone else’s work without identifying that person; failing to identify as a quotation a documented idea that has not been thoroughly assimilated into the Student's language and style, or paraphrasing a passage so closely that the reader could be misled as to the source; submitting the same written or oral material in different courses without obtaining authorization from the lecturers involved; or 'dry-labbing', which includes obtaining and using experimental data from fellow Students without the express consent of the lecturer, utilizing experimental data and laboratory write-ups from other parts of the course or from previous terms during which the course was conducted, and fabricating data to fit the expected results.</description>
      <title></title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>eb67ff02227442eaa4d5c77ee7a778eb</id>
    <practiceSet>76866578defd49e5be08b21dd869e474</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>Surging oil prices, driving up the cost of jet fuel, are behind the cuts. For the first time in aviation history, airlines are forced to reduce the number of flights offered and eliminate some destinations even as demand for their services remains high. It will be harder for many Americans to get from where they are to where they want to go, planes will remain elbow-room-only packed, and ticket prices will soar higher. The aviation reductions will also produce economic ripples that extend far beyond those airports with newly empty tarmacs, some aviation experts warn. "This is not about Butte. This is about the national economy," says Roger Cohen, president of the Regional Airline Association. "Commercial air service is part of the backbone of the American economy.... All of the industries that have grown up with cheap, competitive airfares over the last decade will be affected." {newline} The impact of the service cuts probably won't be felt until 2009, because most aren't slated to go into effect until fall. The summer schedule has been pretty much set and sold for months. But here's the rub: Most of the tickets for the peak summer season were sold before oil skyrocketed above $130 a barrel. That means that even as passengers are packed like sardines into planes and it would appear that the airlines should be raking in huge profits, the carriers are actually losing money. {newline} To make up the losses, airlines must ensure that in the future they fly only very profitable routes. As a result, some communities where airlines rely on regional jets that guzzle a lot of fuel will see service cuts, even though plenty of passengers may still want to fly from there.</description>
      <title></title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>c8dbfda92e8a47669df150596b27367a</id>
    <practiceSet>76866578defd49e5be08b21dd869e474</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>As part of an ongoing campaign against polyvinyl chloride, a Virginia-based environmental advocacy group called on manufacturers and retailers to phase out its use in shower curtains. To buttress its case, the group, the Center for Health, Environment and Justice, released the results of a small study indicating that PVC-containing shower curtains are capable of emitting scores of volatile organic compounds, as well as phthalates, lead, and other potentially harmful materials, into people's bathrooms. A previous study, conducted by Environmental Protection Agency researchers, also found that plastic shower curtains can emit toxic compounds into the air. {newline} There's still debate among scientists about just how serious the health effects are that have been associated with exposure to some of the chemicals highlighted as dangerous, especially at low doses. However, CHEJ, which has particularly strong concerns about the environmental and health toll in communities with factories that manufacture PVC, urges consumers to avoid using PVC shower curtains, as well as many other PVC products, particularly those that are flexible. For people who are concerned about their shower curtains, there are alternatives. IKEA phased out PVC shower curtains 11 years ago, switching to ethylene vinyl acetate. Bed Bath and Beyond, JC Penney, and Macy's are shifting toward PVC-free shower curtains, according to the report, but have not set goals or a time frame for completely eliminating the products. Manufacturers are not required to label shower curtains, but some do list "PVC" or "vinyl" on the packaging. The recycling code "3" or sometimes "V" also indicates the presence of polyvinyl chloride. Numerous online retailers sell shower curtains--primarily cotton or hemp--that are free of PVC. Without good ventilation, however, mildew can be a problem with cotton and hemp products. In response to such problems, Health goods sell a recycled polyester plastic shower curtain that it claims is superior to the fabric options. </description>
      <title></title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>9f635983ab58475b8c99cf8a3141408f</id>
    <practiceSet>76866578defd49e5be08b21dd869e474</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will have 20 minutes to plan, write and revise an essay about the topic below. Your response will be judged on how well you develop a position, organize your ideas, present supporting details and control the elements of standard written English. You should write 200-300 words.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:20:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>Do you agree or disagree with the following statement? Television, newspapers, magazines, and other media pay too much attention to the personal lives of famous people such as public figures and celebrities. Use specific reasons and details to explain your opinion.</description>
      <title></title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>3d844695228a4b33aea6a0ec490daff8</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1f77c</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of  your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>Responsive Web Design – Why the change? Because existing on the internet became a standard. Everyone was there. And if you weren’t, you were losing to competitors who were. The same plot has rung true with mobility and multi-device support for websites and cloud-based applications. We are at an “essentialness” point, as Google has made it crystal clear that websites should be responsive. Just like some companies didn’t think they needed to utilize the web, some think they’re better off without a mobile-friendly site. Although 31% of global internet page views occur on mobile devices, 88.2% of websites are poorly designed for these experiences. {newline} Since the birth of the mobile web browser on flip phones in the early 2000’s, and with every added layer of “smart,” marketers have had the complex job of managing how websites look across mobile devices. To be fair, the vast majority of these sizes easily fall into a handful of categories such as laptop, tablet, or Smartphone. {newline} You need two things to make a website: HTML and CSS. HTML are the parts of your website that make up the walls of your house, while CSS are the things that make it look pretty. Before mobile usage of the internet, developers enjoyed being able to create gorgeous websites with one set of bricks and paint. They designed sites for large desktop or laptop computers only, and did not have to worry about any experience smaller than that. When the first mobile browsers hit the stage, people put up with ugly mobile experiences because it was just cool to have the internet on your phone. Eventually, the fine people of this world demanded a better experience, so developers started to create entirely separate websites hosted on separate web addresses. </description>
      <title></title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>5002f57d70054078a9c16a57b931179e</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1f77c</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>Fast food is food which is prepared and served quickly at outlets called fast-food restaurants. It is a multi-billion dollar industry which continues to grow rapidly in many countries. Fast-food outlets are take-away or take-out providers, often with a "drive-thru" service which allows customers to order and pick up food from their cars; but most also have a seating area in which customers can eat the food on the premises. {newline} The modern history of fast-food in America is connected with the history of the hamburger, as the earliest fast-food outlets sold hamburgers as their primary product. The American company White Castle is generally credited with opening the first fast-food outlet in Topeka, Kansas in 1921, selling hamburgers for five cents apiece. Among its innovations, the company allowed customers to see the food being prepared. White Castle later added five holes to each beef patty to increase its surface area and speed cooking times. White Castle was successful from its inception and spawned numerous competitors. {newline}McDonald's, a noted fast-food supplier, opened its first franchised restaurant in 1955. It has become a phenomenally successful enterprise in terms of financial growth, brand-name recognition, and worldwide expansion. Ray Kroc, who bought the franchising license from the McDonald brothers, pioneered many concepts which emphasized standardization. He introduced uniform products, identical in all respects at each outlet, to increase sales. At the same time, Kroc also insisted on cutting food costs as much as possible, eventually using the McDonald's Corporation's size to force suppliers to conform to this ethos. </description>
      <title></title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>3c13943e40724c92a9e37a6e06080daa</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1f77c</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>Deforestation is the rapid loss of forests by cutting plants regularly without replanting. It is endangering the wildlife, human health and environment. Increasing human population, increasing crowd, increasing competition in the world force human being to cut the forests and establish well developed cities or farms or land for harvesting. In such a competitive world, every nation want to overlap other developed and advanced countries to go ahead and make them powerful. People are in need to cut the forests to make houses, parks, multiplexes, industries, public infrastructure, paper production, fuel, etc. Some greedy people are cutting forests for earning more money by selling woods and increasing the danger to the wildlife and human life. {newline}Wild animals are migrating and dying, original flora and fauna are lasting, environment is changing negatively and disturbing the human life. Natural habitat of the most important animals is destroying because of this some are migrating to other areas or entering to the human areas or dying. We need to preserve trees by stopping the forest cutting or replanting the plants in order to save the animal sanctuary and maintaining the natural cycles of the environment to save the life here in future. Preservation of forests is also necessary to get fresh and healthy oxygen as well as reducing the amount of carbon dioxide gas. {newline}Deforestation lead to increasing air pollution, increasing level of poisonous gases in the environment, increasing soil and water pollution, increasing environmental heat, and many more. All the negative effects of deforestation cause many health disorders and most importantly lungs and respiratory problems. </description>
      <title></title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>3c13943e40724c92a9e37a6e06080d9a</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1f77c</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will have 20 minutes to plan, write and revise an essay about the topic below. Your response will be judged on how well you develop a position, organize your ideas, present supporting details and control the elements of standard written English. You should write 200-300 words.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:20:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>If you could travel back in time to meet a famous person from history, what person would you like to meet? Use specific reasons and examples to support your choice.</description>
      <title></title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>   
  <question>
    <id>3576acbda6a6493194324fee6c246303</id>
    <practiceSet>fc23cb5566904f8a98ee2bbf17a08f47</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of  your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>In the early days of space exploration, visits were restricted to ‘fly-bys’, such as those by the Mariner probes, whereby craft would simply pass the planet, taking pictures and obtaining data as they went. The Viking ‘orbiters’ were next, and later craft in the Viking series, known as ‘Landers’, began to probe the mysteries of its surface, equipped with instruments which continued to relay data about the environment until they stopped working. {newline}The more recent ‘Rovers’ move around the planet’s surface as they gather information. Current proposals include missions to study terrain, climate, and soil components, in order to determine, amongst other things, whether the planet can ever have supported carbon-based life forms. Scientists now believe that at some stage the planet cooled dramatically, resulting in the near-loss of its atmosphere and, thanks to erosion features, mineral deposits and other factors, it is also believed that liquid water once flowed there. {newline}One of the most recent craft is Phoenix, a Rover which landed in November 2008. Named after the mythological bird, Phoenix’s mission was to obtain samples from beneath the surface by digging into the arctic ice, while its high-resolution camera provided geological data and other equipment scanned the atmosphere, measuring temperature and pressure in a bid to discover whether the chemicals necessary for life might exist beneath the surface. The craft was expected to send back data for three months, but managed to hold out for a further two. {newline}An especially important part of the project was the need to maintain sterility of the equipment, in order to ensure that any organic material collected was not contaminated by ‘hitchhiking’ terrestrial microbes. In the future manned landings may be possible – and though it may seem an outrageously difficult undertaking, plans have already been discussed for the ‘terra forming’ of the planet - giving it an atmosphere, oceans and a terrain similar to earth, with the possibility of human colonization. </description>
      <title></title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>933f25d1ca364ed0873e9d38cc09978f</id>
    <practiceSet>fc23cb5566904f8a98ee2bbf17a08f47</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>The implication of science and technology to the people’s life is very old from the time of Indus Valley Civilization. It was almost first invention when came to know about fire and wheel. Both of the inventions are considered as the mother of all the technological innovations of the modern time. Through the invention of fire people knew about the power of energy first time. Since then, people’s curiosity was increased and they started trying their hard to research about various measures to make life style easy and simple. {newline}India is a most famous country all over the world from the ancient time however after its slavery by the British rule, it had lost its recognition and strength. After getting freedom in 1947, it again had started getting its lost recognition in the crowd. It is the science and technology which has helped India to get its real recognition all over the world. India has become a highly growing country through the new inventions in science and technological advancement. Science and technologies are playing great role in meeting the needs and requirements of the modern people. Some examples of the advancement in the technologies are establishment of railway system, metro system, railway reservation system, internet, super computers, mobiles, smart phones, online access of people in almost every area, etc. Government of India is creating more opportunity to the space organization and several academic institutions (Indian Association for the Advancement of Science) for the better technological growth and development in the country. Endangered animals are basically those animals whose population is reducing at an alarming rate. This drastic reduction in numbers can be attributed to a number of things and it is therefore prudent to carefully learn about some of the possible causes of extinction. There are couple of reasons that may result into wildlife extinction. </description>
      <title></title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>c160fa3b7232451facca553b60b8cf60</id>
    <practiceSet>fc23cb5566904f8a98ee2bbf17a08f47</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will have 20 minutes to plan, write and revise an essay about the topic below. Your response will be judged on how well you develop a position, organize your ideas, present supporting details and control the elements of standard written English. You should write 200-300 words.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:20:00</attemptTime>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <template>
      <description>The illiterate of the 21st century will not be those who cannot read and write, but those who cannot learn, unlearn and relearn. Do you agree or disagree with the given statement? </description>
      <title></title>
      <answer></answer>
      <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
    </template>
  </question>
  <!-- Changes done as per new request from Sharan -->
   <!-- <question> -->
    <!-- <id>0c2642bc11db47e288d8a40398a55127</id> -->
    <!-- <practiceSet>fc23cb5566904f8a98ee2bbf17a08f47</practiceSet> -->
    <!-- <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type> -->
    <!-- <itemType>WRITING</itemType> -->
    <!-- <instruction>You will have 20 minutes to plan, write and revise an essay about the topic below. Your response will be judged on how well you develop a position, organize your ideas, present supporting details and control the elements of standard written English. You should write 200-300 words.</instruction> -->
    <!-- <attemptTime>00:20:00</attemptTime> -->
    <!-- <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime> -->
    <!-- <template> -->
      <!-- <description>If you could travel back in time to meet a famous person from history, what person would you like to meet? Use specific reasons and examples to support your choice.</description> -->
      <!-- <title></title> -->
      <!-- <answer></answer> -->
      <!-- <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount> -->
    <!-- </template> -->
  <!-- </question>   -->
  </questions>


