<?xml version = "1.0"?>
<questions>
<!--TEST 1-->
<question>
  <id>fdae660df3d0425aafab39a7fd882be9</id>
  <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
  <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
  <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Pollution is an environmental concern for people throughout the world. One university study suggests that pollutants in the water, air, and soil cause up to 40% of the premature deaths in the world's population. The majority of these deaths occur in developing countries. Water in many third world countries is contaminated with toxic chemicals, also known as toxins. The World Health Organization (WHO) estimates that 1.1 billion people have little or no access to clean water. In many of these regions the water that is used for drinking, cooking, and washing is the same water that is used for dumping sewage and hazardous waste.
Air pollution is a growing problem throughout the world. Indoor air pollution is one of the leading causes of lung cancer. Families in developing countries use open stoves for cooking and heating their homes. The smoke, which is full of chemicals and carcinogens, gets trapped inside where families eat and sleep. Outdoor pollution also causes disease and illness, especially in industrial cities such as Beijing, China, where cancer is the leading cause of death. China relies heavily on coal, which is considered the dirtiest source of energy. According to the European Union, only 1% of urban dwellers in China breathe clean air on an average day. Neighboring countries including Japan and Korea receive much of China's pollution in the form of acid rain. 
Soil pollution is also a major concern, both in industrial and developing countries. Pollutants such as metals and pesticides seep into the earth's soil and contaminate the food supply. Soil pollution causes major health risks to entire ecosystems. This type of pollution reduces the amount of land suitable for agricultural production and contributes to global food shortages.  As more people move to urban centres, premature deaths caused by pollution are expected to increase worldwide. Today, the developed nations who achieved their wealth at the expense of the environment will be held accountable for protecting the earth's resources for future generations.</description>
    <title>Writing - Summarize Written Text - Q1</title>
    <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
    <answer></answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>246b15d97afc4f249d36bef19f7fbc0a</id>
  <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
  <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
  <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>A fair number of agribusiness executives, agricultural and ecological scientists, and international agriculture experts believe that a large-scale shift to organic farming would not only increase the world's food supply, but might be the only way to eradicate hunger. This probably comes as a surprise. After all, organic farmers scorn the pesticides, synthetic fertilizers, and other tools that have become synonymous with high-yield agriculture. Instead, organic farmers depend on raising animals for manure, growing beans, clover, or other nitrogen-fixing legumes, or making compost and other sources of fertilizer that cannot be manufactured in a chemical plant but are instead grown-which consumes land, water, and other resources. Since organic farmers can't use synthetic pesticides, one can imagine that their fields suffer from a scourge of crop-munching bugs, fruit-rotting blights, and plant-choking weeds. And because organic farmers depend on rotating crops to help control pest problems, the same field won't grow corn or wheat or some other staple as often.
As a result, the argument goes, a world dependent on organic farming would have to farm more land than it does today-even if it meant less pollution, fewer abused farm animals, and fewer carcinogenic residues on our vegetables. "We aren't going to feed 6 billion people with organic fertilizer," said Nobel Prize-winning plant breeder Norman Borlaug at a 2002 conference. "If we tried to do it, we would level most of our forest and many of those lands would be productive only for a short period of time." 
In recent years, organic farming has attracted new scrutiny, not just from critics who fear that a large-scale shift in its direction would cause billions to starve, but also from farmers and development agencies who actually suspect that such a shift could better satisfy hungry populations. Unfortunately, no one had ever systematically analyzed whether in fact a widespread shift to organic farming would run up against a shortage of nutrients and a lack of yields-until recently. The results are striking.</description>
    <title>Writing - Summarize Written Text - Q2</title>
    <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
    <answer></answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>2d3d347c692b4dfa90c2416efacfdbe4</id>
  <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
  <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
  <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Climate change has been a constant reality for many Filipinos, with impacts ranging from extreme weather events to periodic droughts and food scarcity. The most affected populations are coastal residents and rural communities that lack proper disaster preparedness. According to the Center for Global Development, the Philippines is the world’s fourth most vulnerable country to the direct impacts of extreme weather events. Averaging 20 tropical cyclones a year, it may be the world’s most storm-exposed nation. Last November, Super typhoon Haiyan, the most intense tropical cyclone ever recorded, claimed more than 10,000 lives, affected over 9 million people, and left over 600,000 Filipinos homeless. With both the oceans and the atmosphere warming, there is broad scientific consensus that typhoons are now increasing in strength. Like most developing countries, the Philippines plays a minor role in global carbon emissions yet suffers an inordinately higher cost. With over a third of its population living in poverty, the country emits just 0.9 metric tons of carbon per capita, compared to the United States’ 17.6 metric tons. “We lose 5% of our economy every year to storms,” observes Philippine Climate Change Commissioner Naderev Sano. 
It is widely argued that taking early action against climate change through mitigation efforts outweigh the costs and economic impacts of inaction. In the Philippines, transitioning to a low-carbon economy has many challenges, but it also offers strong prospects for growth and development. The country has tremendous mitigation opportunities and is graced with significant renewable energy resources. According to the Philippine Department of Energy, renewable energy already provides 40 percent of the country’s primary energy requirements, and much of its potential has yet to be tapped. To achieve an environmentally secure future, the Philippines must not only rebuild more sustainably but also create a sustainable pathway for future development. With one of the most progressive energy laws in Asia, the country has committed to a renewable energy target of 50 percent by 2030 under its Renewable Energy Act.
</description>
    <title>Writing - Summarize Written Text - Q3</title>
    <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
    <answer></answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>b7ad2f04758545b2b39b50cc54c24380</id>
  <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
  <type>WRITE_ESSAY</type>
  <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
  <instruction>You will have 20 minutes to plan, write and revise an essay about the topic below. Your response will be judged on how well you develop a position, organize your ideas, present supporting details and control the elements of standard written English. You should write 200-300 words.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:20:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>In a war of ideas, it is people who get killed”. Does a common man suffer from a group’s ideology? Express your opinion, and support the same with reasons and examples.</description>
    <title>Writing - Essay Writing - Q4</title>
    <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
    <answer></answer>
  </template>
</question>
<!--TEST 1 END-->
  
<!--TEST 2-->
  <question>
  <id>ff270fd938b0447cbee2f1f735429e09</id>
  <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
  <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
  <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>A new study shows that having a low social status can be bad for our health. The study was on monkeys. Researchers from Duke University in the USA looked at the behaviour and health of 45 female monkeys and found that those with a lower social status had more health problems. The monkeys were split up into five groups of nine. The researchers gave the monkeys in each group time to get to know each other. Then they took one monkey from each group and put her into another group. This meant she was the "new girl" and was at the bottom of the group. When scientists checked the health of the monkeys, they found that the "new girl" was unhealthier than the other monkeys.
The researchers said that although their study focused on monkeys, the findings could also be true for humans because we share a lot of our DNA with monkeys. Professor Graham Rook, from University College London, told the BBC News that the findings of the study may also apply to humans. He said governments must understand that people with a lower social status suffer more from health problems. He said that just because "people at the bottom" have got cars and TVs, it does not mean they are happy. If they feel they are at the bottom compared with richer people, their health will worsen. People who are richer can live up to two decades longer than those who are poorer.
</description>
    <title>Writing - Summarize Written Text - Q1</title>
    <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
    <answer></answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>8464bee38c6e459f85b05478493074a9</id>
  <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
  <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
  <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>The USA has put into space the world's most advanced and powerful weather satellite. Scientists say it will revolutionize how we predict the weather and how we look at weather events. The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) said its $1 billion Geostationary Operational Environmental Satellite (GOES-R) will take weather photographs five times faster than other satellites, and with four times higher image quality. The NOAA said: "Without a doubt, GOES-R will revolutionize weather forecasting as we know it." A weather forecaster said the difference in the speed and quality of the satellite's images is like the difference between old black and white TV pictures and today's HD televisions. The new satellite will give us powerful, real-time images and information. These will make the world a safer place. Airline pilots will receive better data to stay away from turbulence. The satellite will be able to zoom in on severe weather events to get much more detailed and accurate pictures. This will help emergency services to warn people more quickly and reduce the costs to human life and property. People will have better information about hurricanes, tornadoes, flooding, volcanic ash clouds, and wildfires. A scientist at the NOAA said: "It will give the weather as it's looking now rather than the weather that happened 15 to 30 minutes ago." The NOAA said weather forecasters couldn't wait to use it.</description>
    <title>Writing - Summarize Written Text - Q2</title>
    <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
    <answer></answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>ed7031b4a91c49f499da9c8b06cae24e</id>
  <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
  <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
  <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>The residents of a town cut off by last week's New Zealand earthquake have received a somewhat unusual but welcome air delivery - enough fast food to feed a small army. The mercy mission to the town of Kaikoura was organized by a plasterer from the town of Nelson 130 kilometres to the north. Robert Coombes, 49, spent three days gathering donations from people and bought as much fast food as he could with the cash. He filled a friend's light aircraft with 400 pieces of Kentucky Fried Chicken, 300 McDonald's burgers, 50 Domino's pizzas, and hundreds of candies. His cargo of tasty treats landed in Kaikoura in time for lunch on Friday. Kaikoura was the town worst hit by the magnitude 7.8 quake.
Mr Coombes explained to reporters that he wanted to "put a smile on people's faces, even if it's only for one day". He added: "There's necessities, but with kids, you need a bit more than bread and water. I just thought I'd fill the plane with junk food and bring a little bit of happiness to the place…. It's just being a good human being." Coombes said the manager of KFC and McDonald's supported his idea and their staff started work two hours earlier to prepare the goodies. Main roads and rail links to Kaikoura have been severed by massive landslides. There have been well over 2,000 aftershocks since Monday and the government is warning that there are likely to be more.
</description>
    <title>Writing - Summarize Written Text - Q3</title>
    <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
    <answer></answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>d159a19fcdb14854b3421f951e077a3d</id>
  <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
  <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
  <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
  <instruction>You will have 20 minutes to plan, write and revise an essay about the topic below. Your response will be judged on how well you develop a position, organize your ideas, present supporting details and control the elements of standard written English. You should write 200-300 words.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>In some countries, the crime rate by youngsters is growing. Some people think that regardless of age, the youngsters who commit major crimes such as murder, rape should receive adult punishment.
To what extent do you agree or disagree?</description>
    <title>Writing - Summarize Written Text - Q4</title>
    <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
    <answer></answer>
  </template>
</question>
<!--TEST 2 END-->
  <!--TEST 4 -->
  <question>
    <id>400070868ea74232adcadfe0f0df3b12</id>
    <practiceSet>7b04cda952c144788c9d27aa2d5dc710</practiceSet>
    <type>WRITE_ESSAY</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will have 20 minutes to plan, write and revise an essay about the topic below. Your response will be judged on how well you develop a position, organize your ideas, present supporting details and control the elements of standard written English. You should write 200-300 words.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:20:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Cycling is more environmentally friendly than other forms of transport. Why is it not popular in many places? And how to increase its popularity?</description>
      <title>Writing - Essay Writing - Q3</title>
      <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
      <answer></answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>b89aa41a60194e54b72bf88b3b5a47e2</id>
    <practiceSet>7b04cda952c144788c9d27aa2d5dc710</practiceSet>
    <type>WRITE_ESSAY</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will have 20 minutes to plan, write and revise an essay about the topic below. Your response will be judged on how well you develop a position, organize your ideas, present supporting details and control the elements of standard written English. You should write 200-300 words.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:20:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>In many countries, governments are spending a large amount of money on improving internet access. Why is it happening and do you think it is the most appropriate use of government money?</description>
      <title>Writing - Essay Writing - Q4</title>
      <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
      <answer></answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>2d277613cbb34b358be3123fc9e3e48e</id>
    <practiceSet>7b04cda952c144788c9d27aa2d5dc710</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Life begins and ends with two words: birth and death. People say live in a way that you feel the tingle of life all the time. There is an expression that when we had given birth we as babies were crying and others were laughing but we should live in a way that when we are dying we laugh and other's cry. But when I think about my life time and the happiest moments of my life I think I remember my childhood. The reason's are I didn't have any responsibilities, I felt secure and I had very close and good relationships.

The first thing that makes a life happier is not having responsibilities. When someone is child, during the childhood that person doesn't have any responsibilities. Not about the future and not about the past. In grownup world you had a past that sometimes makes you responsible about the future or you have a present time that require you to take many actions about that. Such as taking care of others or paying for mortgage and other life necessities. In grownup life sometimes you work very hard to achieve a goal but you don't get the result and you fail on that.

Another thing that makes life happier during the childhood is that most of the time parent's on that age take care of children. So children feel secure and free to spend their life the way they want. When someone is child their demands are limited so they feel they have what they want and that's a good feeling. When you become a grownup your needs become bigger and sometimes not possible to achieve.

The third reason that childhood was the pleasant time of my childhood was because I had very good friends. Friendships in childhood are very close and not based on what you do or who you are. Its pure feeling that makes the friendship. I think all people when they remember their childhood find it as happiest period of their life time because when you don't feel stress and you feel secure that makes a life very happy.
      </description>
      <title>Writing - Summarize Written Text - Q1</title>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>Life begins and ends with two words: birth and death and live in a way that you feel the tingle of life all the time, however, the best way to make a life happier is not having responsibilities and another thing that makes life happier during the childhood is the care from the parent and the third reason that childhood is the pleasant one when you have friends, security plays the major role.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>0090b8e4150c415e979f33710ac65b1b</id>
    <practiceSet>7b04cda952c144788c9d27aa2d5dc710</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>An important management principle is that when behavior is rewarded, it tends to be repeated. It follows that in many business enterprises, the approach to getting employees to work hard or improve productivity is to reward them with money or company stock. In addition, some enterprises use other forms of compensation such as special privileges or perhaps promotion or job reassignments or even company-paid luxury vacations and other bonuses in kind. All such rewards are usually tied in to some index of performance, which precisely calculates the relative amount of increased productivity.

Whatever the type of reward given, managerial consultants point out that the promise of such incentives improves employee attitudes, motivation, and productivity. Typical business handbooks describing compensation methods advocate giving the greatest rewards to those who perform the best. For example, a well-known academic text on incentives points out that "the closer the link between job performance and rewards, the greater the motivational effect."
Advocates of improving productivity through rewards tacitly accept that people are rather like physical bodies that require the application of some external motivating force to be set in motion. Furthermore, they argue that any such incentives must have a high perceived value to the employee and must also be perceived as within the reach of that person. If the productivity goal appears beyond the reach of the person striving for the reward, then the motivational effect will be lower and productivity may decline. But if the reward system is correctly structured, productivity experts argue, it is possible to persuade people to achieve remarkable results.
      </description>
      <title>Writing - Summarize Written Text - Q2</title>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>An important management principle is that when some business enterprises reward their employees with money or company stock and some provide special privileges, whatever the type of reward is given, managerial consultants agree that such incentives improves employee attitudes, motivation, and productivity but productivity goal should be within reach as it will persuade people to achieve remarkable results otherwise it will demotivate them.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <!--TEST 4 END -->

  <!--TEST 8-->
  <question>
    <id>6d54c6528ba54fe9894124d272f53c0c</id>
    <practiceSet>05424cf5c42745de8f6fdef719e5351b</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>From the conditions of frontier life came intellectual traits of profound importance. The work of travelers along each frontier from colonial days onward describe certain common traits, and these traits have while softening down, still persisted as survivals in the place of their origin, even when a higher social organization succeeded. The result is that to the frontier the American intellect owes its striking characteristics. That coarseness and strength combined with acuteness and acquisitiveness; that practical, inventive turn of mind, quick to find expedients; that masterful grasp of material things, lacking in the artistic but powerful to effect great ends; that restless, nervous energy; that dominant individualism, working for good and for evil, and withal that buoyancy and exuberance which comes with freedom—these are traits of the frontier, or traits called out elsewhere because of the existence of the frontier.</description>
      <title>Writing - Summarize Written Text - Q1</title>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>The work of the travelers had revealed the traits of the frontier life which survives even today and these traits highly influenced the American intellectuals.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>85fd515959ec480c9d8e608325ac10f1</id>
    <practiceSet>05424cf5c42745de8f6fdef719e5351b</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>At first, it was little more than a trickle. For a long time the Norman conquerors did not mix much with their Saxon subjects. There are plenty of indications of this; for the languages, too, moved side by side in parallel channels. The custom of having one name for a live beast grazing in the field and another for the same beast, when it is killed and cooked, is often supposed to be due to our English squeamishness and hypocrisy. Whether or not the survival of this custom through ten centuries is due to the national characteristics in question it would be hard to say, but they have certainly nothing to do with its origin.
That is a much more blame-less affair. For the Saxon Neatherd who had spent a hard day tending his oxen, sheep, calves and swine, probably saw little enough of the beef, mutton, veal, pork and bacon, which were gobbled at night by his Norman masters. There is something a little pathetic, too, in the thought that the homely old word, stool, could be used to express any kind of seat, however magnificent, until it was, so to speak, hustled into the kitchen by the smart French chair. Even the police, however, continued to use the old word in the idiom ‘to fall between two stools’.
      </description>
      <title>Writing - Summarize Written Text - Q2</title>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>Answer: Norman and Saxon usage of English words has no relation with the origin of customs as differences are clearly visible in their usages for living and dead animals, moreover, particularly the usage of the word stool instead of chair. </answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>d6628fba56a84064858f5e00c5e077d0</id>
    <practiceSet>05424cf5c42745de8f6fdef719e5351b</practiceSet>
    <type>WRITE_ESSAY</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will have 20 minutes to plan, write and revise an essay about the topic below. Your response will be judged on how well you develop a position, organize your ideas, present supporting details and control the elements of standard written English. You should write 200-300 words.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:20:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Some people think that schools should select students according to their academic abilities, while others believe that it is better to have students with different abilities studying together. Discuss both views and state your own opinion.</description>
      <title>Writing - Essay Writing - Q3</title>
      <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
      <answer></answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <!--TEST 8 END -->

  <!--TEST 9-->
  <question>
    <id>242220cc353147549693dda9465a78ac</id>
    <practiceSet>db28642c43f44f048e0e1be5cf8984f6</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>By the beginning of the 15th century, after a hundred years of construction, Florence Cathedral was still missing its dome. The building required an octagonal dome which would be higher and wider than any that had ever been built, with no external buttresses to keep it from spreading and falling under its own weight.

The building of such a masonry dome posed many technical problems. Filippo Brunelleschi, who is now seen as a key figure in architecture and perhaps the first modern engineer, looked to the great dome of the Pantheon in Rome for solutions. The dome of the Pantheon is a single shell of concrete, the formula for which had long since been forgotten. Soil filled with silver coins had held the Pantheon dome aloft while its concrete set. This could not be the solution in the case of the Florence Cathedral dome, due to its size. Another possible solution, the use of scaffolding, was also impractical because there was not enough timber in the whole of the region of Tuscany.

Brunelleschi would have to build the dome out of brick, due to its light weight compared to stone and being easier to form, and with nothing under it during construction. His eventual success can be attributed, in no small degree, to his technical and mathematical genius. Brunelleschi used more than four million bricks to create what is still the largest masonry dome in the world.
      </description>
      <title>Writing - Summarize Written Text - Q2</title>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>Florence Cathedral architecture wasn’t getting succeed to build a dome. On the other hand, Filippo Brunelleschi has built largest masonry dome in the world.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>6bf5a373a3ad4ce6ae384e2c8ae31bcb</id>
    <practiceSet>db28642c43f44f048e0e1be5cf8984f6</practiceSet>
    <type>WRITE_ESSAY</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will have 20 minutes to plan, write and revise an essay about the topic below. Your response will be judged on how well you develop a position, organize your ideas, present supporting details and control the elements of standard written English. You should write 200-300 words.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:20:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>In some countries around the world, voting is compulsory. Do you agree with the notion of compulsory voting? If voting is compulsory in a democratic society, what are some conclusions we can draw about the nature of democracy?</description>
      <title>Writing - Essay Writing - Q3</title>
      <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
      <answer></answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>44aafe491a4345a4a235f3a3b3bda52f</id>
    <practiceSet>db28642c43f44f048e0e1be5cf8984f6</practiceSet>
    <type>WRITE_ESSAY</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will have 20 minutes to plan, write and revise an essay about the topic below. Your response will be judged on how well you develop a position, organize your ideas, present supporting details and control the elements of standard written English. You should write 200-300 words.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:20:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Education is critical element of the prosperity(success) of any nation. The more educated the people of the country are, more successful their nation become.Support your point of view with reasons and / or examples from your own experience or observations?</description>
      <title>Writing - Essay Writing - Q4</title>
      <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
      <answer></answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>63a30f49541c467aa21e5e8bca2712e0</id>
    <practiceSet>db28642c43f44f048e0e1be5cf8984f6</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Clients who can use art therapy may have a wide range of difficulties, disabilities or diagnoses. These include, for example, emotional, behavioral or mental health problems, learning or physical disabilities, life-limiting conditions, brain-injury or neurological conditions and physical illness. Art therapy may be provided for groups, or for individuals, depending on clients’ needs. It is not a recreational activity or an art lesson, although the sessions can be enjoyable. Clients do not need to have any previous experience or expertise in art. Art therapy is a mental health profession that uses the creative process of art making to improve and enhance the physical, mental and emotional well-being of individuals of all ages. It is based on the belief that the creative process involved in artistic self-expression helps people to resolve conflicts and problems, develop interpersonal skills, manage behavior, reduce stress, increase self-esteem and self-awareness, and achieve insight. Art therapy integrates the fields of human development, visual art (drawing, painting, sculpture, and other art forms), and the creative process with models of counseling and psychotherapy.</description>
      <title>Writing - Summarize Written Text - Q1</title>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>Clients who can use art therapy may have a wide range of difficultiesWhich may include emotional, behavioral or mental health problems, or any disabilities, or neurological conditions, art therapy may be provided for groups, or for individuals as it enhances the physical, mental and emotional well-being of individuals of all ages and the creative process with models of counseling and psychotherapy are built.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <!--TEST 9 END -->
  
  <!--TEST 5-->
  <question>
  <id>cca1f6c43b7c46c0becca6895fee53f6</id>
  <practiceSet>d9d885229cf64aceb84b19095b1ffd9c</practiceSet>
  <type>WRITE_ESSAY</type>
  <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
  <instruction>You will have 20 minutes to plan, write and revise an essay about the topic below. Your response will be judged on how well you develop a position, organize your ideas, present supporting details and control the elements of standard written English. You should write 200-300 words.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:20</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>A good sense of humor is one of the most important human qualities.

Use specific reasons and examples to support your opinion.
</description>
    <title>Do you agree or disagree with the following statement?</title>
    <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
    <answer></answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>4674c8cd6c2d417892985e21f671d1a4</id>
  <practiceSet>d9d885229cf64aceb84b19095b1ffd9c</practiceSet>
  <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
  <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:10</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Much archaeological evidence supports the widely held view that the first people to migrate to the American continent entered through a land bridge, which at one time joined Eastern Asia with North America. This land bridge, known as Beringia, was a wide expanse of terrain that emerged from the ocean as the sea levels dropped due to widespread glaciation at the time of the last Ice Age. Groups of humans could have slowly migrated across the grassy tundra of Beringia, feeding on herds of animals or coastal marine life. At the time, much of North America including what is now Canada, would have been covered with thick ice sheets making further movement southward a physical impossibility. 
At a later period, the ice receded and humans would have been able to traverse an ice-free corridor in a southerly direction, and gradually settle the vast uninhabited continent. The ending of the Ice Age also caused the ocean levels to rise, thus submerging Beringia and isolating the new migrants from peoples on the Asian side. During the next centuries the descendents of the pioneers who crossed Beringia gradually peopled the entire landmass of the Americas. This view of the origins of the first Americans is often known as the Clovis-first theory (named after the site in New Mexico where stone artifacts made by these settlers were first found). Many subsequent finds of Clovis tools demonstrate this culture's extensive penetration throughout the continent.</description>
    <title>Writing - Summarize Written Text - Q3</title>
    <maxWordCount>70</maxWordCount>
    <answer>As per archaeological evidence the first people to migrate to the American continent entered through a land bridge, known as Beringia, emerged from the ocean as the sea levels dropped due to widespread glaciations at the time of the last Ice Age and during the next centuries the descendents of the pioneers who crossed Beringia gradually peopled the entire landmass of the Americas known as the Clovis-first theory.</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>9ea2662b797b492c83f998334d640d1c</id>
  <practiceSet>d9d885229cf64aceb84b19095b1ffd9c</practiceSet>
  <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
  <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:10</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Most researchers today agree that both nature and nurture play some part in the development of personality and in physical and mental well-being, although there is still a great deal of heated debate about how much is contributed by each. In the attempt to unravel the relative significance of the contributions of nature and nurture to human behavior and personality, researchers often conduct studies of the characteristics of identical (monozygotic) and fraternal (dizygotic) twins.

It has been found that identical twins, who have an identical genetic makeup, often display very similar behavior and other character traits. This is true even for those identical twins who have been separated at birth and brought up in different family environments. In the classic twin study, researchers compare various characteristics of identical twins with fraternal twins. The latter group share 50 percent of their genetic makeup, just like non-twin siblings. If the identical twins display more similarities with regard to a particular characteristic than members of the fraternal or dizygotic group, then it is concluded that heredity plays a part in that behavior or feature of personality. The magnitude of the varying contributions of genetic factors and environmental factors can then be assessed.
Advocates of twin studies argue that this research tool can be used to calculate the heritability of a huge range of medical conditions and psychological disorders, and also the heritability of traits like musical or mathematical understanding or other intellectual abilities.
</description>
    <title>Writing - Summarize Written Text - Q2</title>
    <maxWordCount>70</maxWordCount>
    <answer>Nature and nurture play some part in the development of personality and to unravel this researchers often conduct studies of the characteristics of identical and fraternal twins, identical twins display very similar behavior and other character traits and the latter group shares 50 percent of their genetic makeup, this research can be used to calculate the heritability medical and psychological disorders, and also the heritability traits.</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>2e540a92dcc64100bfa3e2453a3bbf18</id>
  <practiceSet>d9d885229cf64aceb84b19095b1ffd9c</practiceSet>
  <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
  <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:10</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Technology is available to exploit the potential energy formed by tides for the generation of electrical energy. The basic structure is a barrage or dam built across a river estuary or at the mouth of a bay. This dam is similar to that used in hydroelectric power plants built across flowing rivers. At regular intervals along the dam, gates and turbines are installed. When the tide is rising, the gates are opened. This allows water to flow into the area behind the barrage, raising the water level there. When the water has reached its highest level, the gates are closed. Then the tide drops on the seaward side, and this trapped water is several meters above the sea level. The gates are then opened, allowing the water to discharge out. The force of the flow turns the turbines and generates electricity. It is also possible to use tidal energy when the water flows in the other direction - through the gates into the estuary from the sea.

In this way, four periods of energy production are possible every day, since coastal regions experience two high and two low tides in just over 24 hours. In order for practical amounts of electricity to be generated, the difference between high and low tides must be at least five meters. Tidal power is renewable, non-polluting, and contributes no greenhouse gases to the atmosphere. This kind of system can provide a useful energy supplement to other sources in an era of diminishing fossil fuel reserves.
</description>
    <title>Writing - Summarize Written Text - Q1</title>
    <maxWordCount>70</maxWordCount>
    <answer>The dam is built across a river estuary similar to that used in hydroelectric power plants built across flowing rivers to exploit the potential energy formed by tides for the generation of electrical energy because tidal power is renewable, non-polluting, and contributes no greenhouse gases to the atmosphere and provides useful energy supplement to other sources.</answer>
  </template>
</question>

  <!--TEST 5 END-->
  
  <!--TEST 6-->
  <question>
    <id>5dbc01b51d63486bb7641adc3c2ef956</id>
    <practiceSet>5dcbc550333c488996e65d41dad0bfe7</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Public figures include politicians and other public officials such as judges and civil servants as well as celebrities such as film stars, musicians and sports stars. The very nature of these roles opens these people to scrutiny by the press. The extent to which the media are legally free to investigate and publish details of public figures’ private lives varies from country to country. Countries like France are much stricter on protecting personal privacy than, for example, Britain.

People have a right to know about those in power. Whether through taxes, in the case of politicians and civil servants, or by revenue generated by films, music, TV, sporting appearances or concerts in the case of celebrities—these people’s income is dependent on the general public.

People have the right to make informed judgments about the kind of leaders they have. Attempts to restrict what may be reported about public figures in the press could easily become a conspiracy to keep voters in the dark and to manipulate them. All elections are to a greater or lesser extent about the character of the leading politicians involved. Unless the voters are allowed insights into their private lives they will lack the information needed to make a fair decision at the polling booth. For example, some people believe that a politician who betrayed his wife in an affair was equally capable of breaking his promises and lying to his country.

Exposing corruption and dishonesty on the part of public officials and businesses is a critical part of the function of a free press, and it is essential to the functioning of a free-market economy. If investigative journalists are prevented from scrutinizing the private lives of public figures, then corruption and crime will be much easier to hide.
Public figures know that with fame comes a price and that price is constant scrutiny. In fact, many celebrities actively seek media exposure in order to advance their careers, revealing to the media many aspects of their personal lives. Once success has been bought in such a fashion it is then somewhat hypocritical to complain of “press intrusion” into those few aspects the star would prefer to remain hidden
      </description>
      <title></title>
      <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
      <answer></answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>bca2ba178f6e48898ef58f3f41acf90e</id>
    <practiceSet>5dcbc550333c488996e65d41dad0bfe7</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Education is universally recognized as a pillar for both economic and social growth in any society. Government spending on education in Australia reflects our priority of investing in the future of this country, allowing for economic advancement as well as productivity and social wellbeing for the individual and society as a whole.
Given the importance of education in social and economic advancement, the student learning environment has become increasingly significant. In an age where teaching practice and technology have changed and developed faster than ever before, the question of whether or not our learning environments are supporting or hindering our educational processes has never been more pertinent. While there have been changes to learning outcomes through updates to the syllabuses, technology has been driving more significant changes at a high rate.
      </description>
      <title></title>
      <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
      <answer></answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>97364fa4dc824a35b5302206ddd4c6df</id>
    <practiceSet>5dcbc550333c488996e65d41dad0bfe7</practiceSet>
    <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>When people describe themselves as ‘tone deaf’, ‘having no rhythm’ or ‘no ear for music’, they generally think of these things as defining characteristics. They are talents you are born with or not. However, there is a variety of research on skill development which questions this. Carol Dweck’s research shows that people who believe that skill can be developed will be far more successful, evidence supporting the old saying, ‘Whether you believe you can or can’t, you’re right.’
Along similar lines, Anders Ericsson found that what separates the experts from the amateurs in any field is about 10,000 hours of deliberate practice. The most important lesson, of course, is that change is possible. People can become something they aren’t and change who they are. Talent, even one like music, can be cultivated. However, this is not to say that natural talent does not exist.
One often overlooked study by Edwin Gordon showed that talent accounted for about half the differences in musical skill development in a group of students after three years of studying. So although anyone can become a musician, not everyone can become the best musician.
      </description>
      <title></title>
      <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
      <answer></answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>534eb42a16e34097ab3f5b75c41683d7</id>
    <practiceSet>5dcbc550333c488996e65d41dad0bfe7</practiceSet>
    <type>WRITE_ESSAY</type>
    <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will have 20 minutes to plan, write and revise an essay about the topic below. Your response will be judged on how well you develop a position, organize your ideas, present supporting details and control the elements of standard written English. You should write 200-300 words.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>It is argued that getting married before finishing school or getting a job is not a good choice. To what extent do you agree or disagree?</description>
      <title></title>
      <maxWordCount>400</maxWordCount>
      <answer></answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <!-- TEST 6 END-->
  
  <!--TEST 7-->
  <question>
  <id>e8fdec217410495d8fbd68b4b771bcdf</id>
  <practiceSet>0b7002c915a441eebdb4448e4388ba5b</practiceSet>
  <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
  <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Toronto’s economy remains healthy and growing, with construction, transportation, warehousing, retail, wholesale, and manufacturing all contributing to this growth. According to the Conference Board of Canada, Toronto’s construction sector growth achieved a 14-year high thanks to a 46 percent rise in housing starts—most of those multifamily units—with GDP forecast to remain steady at 2.6 percent in 2016 and 2017.
Optimism is the predominant attitude regarding the Toronto real estate market, though it is tempered by a measure of caution. The residential market generally remains strong, with solid sales volumes and rising prices, buoyed by a strong local economy, steady immigration, and low-interest rates. Few if any foresee the situation reversing anytime soon, barring an unexpected hike in interest rates, an economic shock, or a sharp drop in immigration. The lack of supply of available land is seen as a key factor contributing to the market’s rapidly rising house prices. Due to the high cost of moving, more homeowners are choosing to stay put and invest in renovations; one interviewee remarked that there have been record numbers of requests for permits to renovate existing homes. With no real factors reducing demand, developers and builders will continue to face supply-side issues. Many respondents believe that government land use policies are a factor holding back supply. Some developers are also holding back on releasing new projects until all costs are fixed and to shorten the gap between sales and delivery; this will put more pressure on supply in the near future.</description>
    <title></title>
    <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
    <answer></answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>1a8b9f7e59514d6daf8aeeb504825bb6</id>
  <practiceSet>0b7002c915a441eebdb4448e4388ba5b</practiceSet>
  <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
  <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>The last decade’s doubling of capital expenditures has helped accomplish some critical upgrades to the US electric and natural gas infrastructure. It is already beginning to make the electric grid more reliable, resilient, flexible, and clean. Similarly, gas infrastructure investment is enhancing pipeline safety, bringing new shale supplies to market and sharply reducing natural gas and electricity commodity prices for customers. In several areas of investment, like grid modernization and upgrading the gas distribution system, there is still a long way to go and substantial additional investment will be needed over many years. But most of these investments will bring future benefits by enabling the flexible grid of the future, and helping to avoid costly and potentially tragic disasters such as long-term, large-scale electricity outages or gas system explosions.
So far, these investments have been partially offset by lower fuel costs enabled by the shale revolution and the general downturn in oil and gas prices. Most utility customers have not seen sharp increases in their bills, but that could change. Factors such as rising natural gas prices could increase customer bills and make state utility commissions less amenable to rate hikes to cover capital investment programs.</description>
    <title></title>
    <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
    <answer></answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>404b3764b2b24dffb6d814a4657be0cf</id>
  <practiceSet>0b7002c915a441eebdb4448e4388ba5b</practiceSet>
  <type>WRITE_ESSAY</type>
  <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
  <instruction>You will have 20 minutes to plan, write and revise an essay about the topic below. Your response will be judged on how well you develop a position, organize your ideas, present supporting details and control the elements of standard written English. You should write 200-300 words.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Without capital punishment (the death penalty) our lives are less secure and crimes of violence increase. Capital punishment is essential to control violence in society. To what extent do you agree or disagree with this opinion?</description>
    <title></title>
    <maxWordCount>500</maxWordCount>
    <answer></answer>
  </template>
</question>
  <!--TEST 7 END-->
  <!-- TEST 10-->
  <question>
  <id>416387a437df45e393ad2416ac0e472e</id>
  <practiceSet>4e1a53fbe93d491289754abda2ea6984</practiceSet>
  <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
  <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>From the conditions of frontier life came intellectual traits of profound importance. The work of travelers along each frontier from colonial days onward describe certain common traits, and these traits have while softening down, still persisted as survivals in the place of their origin, even when a higher social organization succeeded. The result is that to the frontier the American intellect owes its striking characteristics. That coarseness and strength combined with acuteness and acquisitiveness; that practical, inventive turn of mind, quick to find expedients; that masterful grasp of material things, lacking in the artistic but powerful to effect great ends; that restless, nervous energy; that dominant individualism, working for good and for evil, and withal that buoyancy and exuberance which comes with freedom—these are traits of the frontier, or traits called out elsewhere because of the existence of the frontier.</description>
    <title></title>
    <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
    <answer></answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>b94fbd21a5c54afb804af1351719d81c</id>
  <practiceSet>4e1a53fbe93d491289754abda2ea6984</practiceSet>
  <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
  <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>At first, it was little more than a trickle. For a long time the Norman conquerors did not mix much with their Saxon subjects. There are plenty of indications of this; for the languages, too, moved side by side in parallel channels. The custom of having one name for a live beast grazing in the field and another for the same beast, when it is killed and cooked, is often supposed to be due to our English squeamishness and hypocrisy. Whether or not the survival of this custom through ten centuries is due to the national characteristics in question it would be hard to say, but they have certainly nothing to do with its origin.
That is a much more blame-less affair. For the Saxon neatherd who had spent a hard day tending his oxen, sheep, calves and swine, probably saw little enough of the beef, mutton, veal, pork and bacon, which were gobbled at night by his Norman masters. There is something a little pathetic, too, in the thought that the homely old word, stool, could be used to express any kind of seat, however magnificent, until it was, so to speak, hustled into the kitchen by the smart French chair. Even the police, however, continued to use the old word in the idiom ‘to fall between two stools’.
</description>
    <title></title>
    <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
    <answer></answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>fcaa42db6cf44de8b7955a540b7b32a9</id>
  <practiceSet>4e1a53fbe93d491289754abda2ea6984</practiceSet>
  <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
  <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>The NSW taxi network forms an integral part of the State’s public transport network. The ubiquitous door-to-door service provided by taxis complements other forms of public transport throughout Sydney and regional NSW. Taxi services are particularly valuable for those with special transport needs, but they are also used by a large cross section of the community and have substantial flow-on effects for the efficient functioning of the NSW economy. This study examines the economic contribution of the NSW taxi industry and its role in connecting people, promoting social inclusion and supporting economic activity.
There is a range of activity that takes place ‘behind the scenes’ to ensure that taxi services are efficiently provided and meet users’ needs. Authorised taxi networks maintain call centres to collect and dispatch bookings, monitor the safety of drivers and passengers, and assist the NSW Government in ensuring compliance with regulatory standards. Taxi owners, operators and drivers all play a vital role in providing a range of services to the travelling public. Various businesses fit out and maintain the taxi vehicles and Authorised Taxi Inspection Stations perform regular safety checks.
</description>
    <title></title>
    <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
    <answer></answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>5a02f1c01071422ea0569cb1cffb21dc</id>
  <practiceSet>4e1a53fbe93d491289754abda2ea6984</practiceSet>
  <type>WRITE_ESSAY</type>
  <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
  <instruction>You will have 20 minutes to plan, write and revise an essay about the topic below. Your response will be judged on how well you develop a position, organize your ideas, present supporting details and control the elements of standard written English. You should write 200-300 words.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Some people earn name and fame at very young age. Would you consider it to be positive or negative effect on once personality?</description>
    <title></title>
    <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
    <answer></answer>
  </template>
</question>
  <!-- TEST 10 END-->
  
  
  
  <!-- TEST 3-->
  <question>
  <id>8166ac7511d04b18a7936b7ce32f2192</id>
  <practiceSet>88f631b360734b7da3b7c3e6151bd840</practiceSet>
  <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
  <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>This jovial farmer - or Mr IR8 as he became affectionately known - had inadvertently kick-started one of the greatest revolutions the world has ever seen. Not a political or social upheaval but a "Green Revolution", a revolution in the way the world farmed. It is thought that IR8 saved many millions of lives and transformed the lives of hundreds of millions of people. Back in the 1950s it was obvious that Asia, home to half the world's population, faced an impending food crisis. 
Rice accounts for 80% of the calories consumed in the region and you only needed to plot population growth against rice production to see that, within a few years, there would not be enough to go around.
Something needed to be done and in 1960 two American charities, the Ford and Rockefeller Foundations, joined forces to found the International Rice Research Institute (IRRI) in the Philippines. They reckoned promising developments in the science of plant breeding might just be the trick that would avert the impending disaster. The new team began patiently cross-breeding the 10,000 different varieties they had collected. This is usually a laborious process, Dr Gurdev Singh Khush tells me. He is an agronomist and geneticist who joined the team that developed IR8 in 1967.
"Normally we get 1 or 2% yield increase every year," he says. IR8 was different. It married a tall high-yielding strain from Indonesia (PETA) with a sturdy dwarf variety from China (DGWG) with astounding results. "There was never any instance in the history of the world where rice yields doubled in one step," says Dr Khush, clearly still amazed by what his team achieved.
In fact, according to some studies, IR8 yields in optimal conditions could be as much as 10 times that of traditional varieties. "Genetics is fantastic when it works like that," agrees the current head of IRRI, Matthew Morell.
</description>
    <title></title>
    <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
    <answer></answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>7f2ca1bdb4ef4ef8b12fd4c7e96238dc</id>
  <practiceSet>88f631b360734b7da3b7c3e6151bd840</practiceSet>
  <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
  <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>China has introduced an additional 10% tax on "super cars", including Ferrari, Bentley, Aston Martin and Rolls-Royce. The tax, affecting cars that cost more than 1.3m yuan ($189,000; £151,024), is aimed at curbing lavish spending and reducing emissions, authorities said.
It is part of a wider effort by Chinese authorities against flashy demonstrations of wealth, which has already hit other luxury brands. China is a key market for high-end carmakers.
Automakers have in recent years increasingly tailored their luxury models to appeal to Chinese buyers. Both Rolls-Royce and Aston Martin are planning to release SUV models in the next year, seen as a response to a Chinese preference for large cars over sports vehicles.
"In order to guide rational consumption, and promote energy-saving emission reductions, the state Council has approved an additional consumption levy on ultra-luxury cars," a statement by the Ministry of Finance said.
The tax goes into effect on Thursday, although observers say it is unlikely to be a major deterrent for the super rich. Chinese President Xi Jinping has made a campaign against corruption a centre piece of his governing agenda, and has cracked down on luxury spending as part of that.</description>
    <title></title>
    <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
    <answer></answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>2eba8d1d8ddc47e5b1f2f917f97cae98</id>
  <practiceSet>88f631b360734b7da3b7c3e6151bd840</practiceSet>
  <type>WRITE_ESSAY</type>
  <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
  <instruction>You will have 20 minutes to plan, write and revise an essay about the topic below. Your response will be judged on how well you develop a position, organize your ideas, present supporting details and control the elements of standard written English. You should write 200-300 words.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Countries, businesses, and schools are three areas that need good leaders. Choose one of these three areas and describe the most important qualities of a leader in that area. Explain why these qualities are important, using specific examples and details.</description>
    <title></title>
    <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
    <answer></answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>1ad06373d956464f977ace1f9f76de41</id>
  <practiceSet>88f631b360734b7da3b7c3e6151bd840</practiceSet>
  <type>WRITE_ESSAY</type>
  <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
  <instruction>You will have 20 minutes to plan, write and revise an essay about the topic below. Your response will be judged on how well you develop a position, organize your ideas, present supporting details and control the elements of standard written English. You should write 200-300 words.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Playing games teaches us about life.Do you agree or disagree with the following statement? Use specific reasons and examples to support your answer.</description>
    <title></title>
    <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
    <answer></answer>
  </template>
</question>
  <!-- TEST 3 END-->
  
</questions>