<?xml version = "1.0"?>
<questions>
<question>
  <id>fdae660df3d0425aafab39a7fd882be9</id>
  <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
  <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
  <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Pollution is an environmental concern for people throughout the world. One university study suggests that pollutants in the water, air, and soil cause up to 40% of the premature deaths in the world's population. The majority of these deaths occur in developing countries. Water in many third world countries is contaminated with toxic chemicals, also known as toxins. The World Health Organization (WHO) estimates that 1.1 billion people have little or no access to clean water. In many of these regions the water that is used for drinking, cooking, and washing is the same water that is used for dumping sewage and hazardous waste.
Air pollution is a growing problem throughout the world. Indoor air pollution is one of the leading causes of lung cancer. Families in developing countries use open stoves for cooking and heating their homes. The smoke, which is full of chemicals and carcinogens, gets trapped inside where families eat and sleep. Outdoor pollution also causes disease and illness, especially in industrial cities such as Beijing, China, where cancer is the leading cause of death. China relies heavily on coal, which is considered the dirtiest source of energy. According to the European Union, only 1% of urban dwellers in China breathe clean air on an average day. Neighboring countries including Japan and Korea receive much of China's pollution in the form of acid rain. 
Soil pollution is also a major concern, both in industrial and developing countries. Pollutants such as metals and pesticides seep into the earth's soil and contaminate the food supply. Soil pollution causes major health risks to entire ecosystems. This type of pollution reduces the amount of land suitable for agricultural production and contributes to global food shortages.  As more people move to urban centres, premature deaths caused by pollution are expected to increase worldwide. Today, the developed nations who achieved their wealth at the expense of the environment will be held accountable for protecting the earth's resources for future generations.</description>
    <title>Writing - Summarize Written Text - Q1</title>
    <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
    <answer></answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>246b15d97afc4f249d36bef19f7fbc0a</id>
  <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
  <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
  <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>A fair number of agribusiness executives, agricultural and ecological scientists, and international agriculture experts believe that a large-scale shift to organic farming would not only increase the world's food supply, but might be the only way to eradicate hunger. This probably comes as a surprise. After all, organic farmers scorn the pesticides, synthetic fertilizers, and other tools that have become synonymous with high-yield agriculture. Instead, organic farmers depend on raising animals for manure, growing beans, clover, or other nitrogen-fixing legumes, or making compost and other sources of fertilizer that cannot be manufactured in a chemical plant but are instead grown-which consumes land, water, and other resources. Since organic farmers can't use synthetic pesticides, one can imagine that their fields suffer from a scourge of crop-munching bugs, fruit-rotting blights, and plant-choking weeds. And because organic farmers depend on rotating crops to help control pest problems, the same field won't grow corn or wheat or some other staple as often.
As a result, the argument goes, a world dependent on organic farming would have to farm more land than it does today-even if it meant less pollution, fewer abused farm animals, and fewer carcinogenic residues on our vegetables. "We aren't going to feed 6 billion people with organic fertilizer," said Nobel Prize-winning plant breeder Norman Borlaug at a 2002 conference. "If we tried to do it, we would level most of our forest and many of those lands would be productive only for a short period of time." 
In recent years, organic farming has attracted new scrutiny, not just from critics who fear that a large-scale shift in its direction would cause billions to starve, but also from farmers and development agencies who actually suspect that such a shift could better satisfy hungry populations. Unfortunately, no one had ever systematically analyzed whether in fact a widespread shift to organic farming would run up against a shortage of nutrients and a lack of yields-until recently. The results are striking.</description>
    <title>Writing - Summarize Written Text - Q2</title>
    <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
    <answer></answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>2d3d347c692b4dfa90c2416efacfdbe4</id>
  <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
  <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
  <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Climate change has been a constant reality for many Filipinos, with impacts ranging from extreme weather events to periodic droughts and food scarcity. The most affected populations are coastal residents and rural communities that lack proper disaster preparedness. According to the Center for Global Development, the Philippines is the world’s fourth most vulnerable country to the direct impacts of extreme weather events. Averaging 20 tropical cyclones a year, it may be the world’s most storm-exposed nation. Last November, Super typhoon Haiyan, the most intense tropical cyclone ever recorded, claimed more than 10,000 lives, affected over 9 million people, and left over 600,000 Filipinos homeless. With both the oceans and the atmosphere warming, there is broad scientific consensus that typhoons are now increasing in strength. Like most developing countries, the Philippines plays a minor role in global carbon emissions yet suffers an inordinately higher cost. With over a third of its population living in poverty, the country emits just 0.9 metric tons of carbon per capita, compared to the United States’ 17.6 metric tons. “We lose 5% of our economy every year to storms,” observes Philippine Climate Change Commissioner Naderev Sano. 
It is widely argued that taking early action against climate change through mitigation efforts outweigh the costs and economic impacts of inaction. In the Philippines, transitioning to a low-carbon economy has many challenges, but it also offers strong prospects for growth and development. The country has tremendous mitigation opportunities and is graced with significant renewable energy resources. According to the Philippine Department of Energy, renewable energy already provides 40 percent of the country’s primary energy requirements, and much of its potential has yet to be tapped. To achieve an environmentally secure future, the Philippines must not only rebuild more sustainably but also create a sustainable pathway for future development. With one of the most progressive energy laws in Asia, the country has committed to a renewable energy target of 50 percent by 2030 under its Renewable Energy Act.
</description>
    <title>Writing - Summarize Written Text - Q3</title>
    <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
    <answer></answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>b7ad2f04758545b2b39b50cc54c24380</id>
  <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
  <type>WRITE_ESSAY</type>
  <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
  <instruction>You will have 20 minutes to plan, write and revise an essay about the topic below. Your response will be judged on how well you develop a position, organize your ideas, present supporting details and control the elements of standard written English. You should write 200-300 words.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:20:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>In a war of ideas, it is people who get killed”. Does a common man suffer from a group’s ideology? Express your opinion, and support the same with reasons and examples.</description>
    <title>Writing - Essay Writing - Q4</title>
    <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
    <answer></answer>
  </template>
</question>
---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
<question>
  <id>ff270fd938b0447cbee2f1f735429e09</id>
  <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
  <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
  <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>A new study shows that having a low social status can be bad for our health. The study was on monkeys. Researchers from Duke University in the USA looked at the behaviour and health of 45 female monkeys and found that those with a lower social status had more health problems. The monkeys were split up into five groups of nine. The researchers gave the monkeys in each group time to get to know each other. Then they took one monkey from each group and put her into another group. This meant she was the "new girl" and was at the bottom of the group. When scientists checked the health of the monkeys, they found that the "new girl" was unhealthier than the other monkeys.
The researchers said that although their study focused on monkeys, the findings could also be true for humans because we share a lot of our DNA with monkeys. Professor Graham Rook, from University College London, told the BBC News that the findings of the study may also apply to humans. He said governments must understand that people with a lower social status suffer more from health problems. He said that just because "people at the bottom" have got cars and TVs, it does not mean they are happy. If they feel they are at the bottom compared with richer people, their health will worsen. People who are richer can live up to two decades longer than those who are poorer.
</description>
    <title>Writing - Summarize Written Text - Q1</title>
    <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
    <answer></answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>8464bee38c6e459f85b05478493074a9</id>
  <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
  <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
  <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>The USA has put into space the world's most advanced and powerful weather satellite. Scientists say it will revolutionize how we predict the weather and how we look at weather events. The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) said its $1 billion Geostationary Operational Environmental Satellite (GOES-R) will take weather photographs five times faster than other satellites, and with four times higher image quality. The NOAA said: "Without a doubt, GOES-R will revolutionize weather forecasting as we know it." A weather forecaster said the difference in the speed and quality of the satellite's images is like the difference between old black and white TV pictures and today's HD televisions. The new satellite will give us powerful, real-time images and information. These will make the world a safer place. Airline pilots will receive better data to stay away from turbulence. The satellite will be able to zoom in on severe weather events to get much more detailed and accurate pictures. This will help emergency services to warn people more quickly and reduce the costs to human life and property. People will have better information about hurricanes, tornadoes, flooding, volcanic ash clouds, and wildfires. A scientist at the NOAA said: "It will give the weather as it's looking now rather than the weather that happened 15 to 30 minutes ago." The NOAA said weather forecasters couldn't wait to use it.</description>
    <title>Writing - Summarize Written Text - Q2</title>
    <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
    <answer></answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>ed7031b4a91c49f499da9c8b06cae24e</id>
  <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
  <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
  <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the passage below and summarize it using one sentence. Type your response in the box at the bottom of the screen. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points in the passage.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>The residents of a town cut off by last week's New Zealand earthquake have received a somewhat unusual but welcome air delivery - enough fast food to feed a small army. The mercy mission to the town of Kaikoura was organized by a plasterer from the town of Nelson 130 kilometres to the north. Robert Coombes, 49, spent three days gathering donations from people and bought as much fast food as he could with the cash. He filled a friend's light aircraft with 400 pieces of Kentucky Fried Chicken, 300 McDonald's burgers, 50 Domino's pizzas, and hundreds of candies. His cargo of tasty treats landed in Kaikoura in time for lunch on Friday. Kaikoura was the town worst hit by the magnitude 7.8 quake.
Mr Coombes explained to reporters that he wanted to "put a smile on people's faces, even if it's only for one day". He added: "There's necessities, but with kids, you need a bit more than bread and water. I just thought I'd fill the plane with junk food and bring a little bit of happiness to the place…. It's just being a good human being." Coombes said the manager of KFC and McDonald's supported his idea and their staff started work two hours earlier to prepare the goodies. Main roads and rail links to Kaikoura have been severed by massive landslides. There have been well over 2,000 aftershocks since Monday and the government is warning that there are likely to be more.
</description>
    <title>Writing - Summarize Written Text - Q3</title>
    <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
    <answer></answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>d159a19fcdb14854b3421f951e077a3d</id>
  <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
  <type>SUMMARIZE_TEXT</type>
  <itemType>WRITING</itemType>
  <instruction>You will have 20 minutes to plan, write and revise an essay about the topic below. Your response will be judged on how well you develop a position, organize your ideas, present supporting details and control the elements of standard written English. You should write 200-300 words.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>In some countries, the crime rate by youngsters is growing. Some people think that regardless of age, the youngsters who commit major crimes such as murder, rape should receive adult punishment.
To what extent do you agree or disagree?</description>
    <title>Writing - Summarize Written Text - Q4</title>
    <maxWordCount>300</maxWordCount>
    <answer></answer>
  </template>
</question>
</questions>