<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<questions>

  <question>
    <id>9326bd6c834a46f087d4934cacb23966</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1fd7c</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description> Giant pandas are black-and-white Chinese bears that are on the verge of {blank}. These large, cuddly-looking mammals have a big head, a heavy body, rounded ears, and a short tail. Most bears' eyes have round pupils. The {blank} is the giant panda, whose pupils are vertical slits, like cats' eyes, these unusual eyes {blank} the Chinese to call the panda the "giant cat bear."</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>indication</o1>
          <o2>speculation</o2>
          <o3>inspired</o3>
          <o4>predicted</o4>
          <o5>exception</o5>
          <o6>extinction</o6>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>5|4|2</answer>
    </template>
  </question> 
    <question>
    <id>3003d6042ec6443d8cdea1e451ca9a30</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1fd7c</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Although the population of England in the nineteenth century was rising at an {blank} rate, that of the cities was increasing by leaps. This was due to the  effects of the industrial revolution; people were {blank} into the towns and cities in search of employment; for some, it was also the call of the unknown, {blank} and a better way of life. This period is known to be the beginning of many new things.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>crepuscular</o1>
          <o2>flocking</o2>
          <o3>pliable</o3>
          <o4>unprecedented</o4>
          <o5>escapade</o5>
       </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>3|1|4</answer>
    </template>
  </question>  
     <question>
    <id>18ede94c57954165aa6baf5d255113a5</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1fd7c</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Central to the success of this rapidly emerging field lies the {blank} of researchers to devise satisfactory methods for eliciting linguistic data from children. The problems that have to be faced are quite different from those encountered when working with adults. Many of the linguist’s routine {blank} of enquiry cannot be used with children. It is not possible to carry out certain kinds of experiments, because aspects of children’s cognitive development – such as their ability to pay attention, or to remember instructions – may not be {blank} advanced.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>term </o1>
          <o2>ability</o2>
          <o3>to</o3>
          <o4>have</o4>
          <o5>techniques</o5>
          <o6>sufficiently</o6>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>1|4|5</answer>
    </template>
  </question> 
       <question>
    <id>26016f0500ac4e17a49d4e328f0cafc8</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1fd7c</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>At the height of his powers, Henry James{blank} intricate novels that featured {blank} realized characters. He was remarkable for his ability to dispense with commentary or subjectivity within his narratives. The reader sees the events{blank} the eyes of the characters; James the author makes himself as invisible as{blank}.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>crafted</o1>
          <o2>possible</o2>
          <o3>from</o3>
          <o4>completely</o4>
          <o5>through</o5>
          <o6>possible</o6>
		  <o7>complete</o7>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>0|3|4|5</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
 <question>
    <id>bbf511ffad644026969787ab81a5e037</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1fd7c</practiceSet>
    <type>MULTI_CHOICE_MULTIPLE_ANSWER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct response. More than one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:02:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>What are the good parts of our civilization? First and foremost there are order and safety. If today I have a quarrel with another man, I do not get beaten merely because I am physically weaker and he can kick me down. I go to law, and the law will decide as fairly as it can between the two of us. Thus in disputes between man and man right has taken the place of might. Moreover, the law protects me from robbery and violence. Nobody may come and break into my house, steal my goods or run off with my children. Of course, there are burglars, but they are very rare, and the law punishes them whenever it catches them. It is difficult for us to realize how much this safety means. Without safety these higher activities of mankind which make up civilization could not go on. The inventor could not invent, the scientist find out or the artist make beautiful things. Hence, order and safety, although they are not themselves civilization are things without which civilization would be impossible. They are as necessary to our civilization as the air we breathe is to us; and we have grown so used to them that we do not notice them any more than we notice the air.Another great achievement of our civilization is that today civilized men are largely free from the fear of pain. They still fall ill, but illness is no longer the terrible thing it used to be.... Not only do men and women enjoy better health; they live longer than they ever did before, and they have a much better chance of growing up.... Thirdly, our civilization is more secure than any that have gone before it. This is because it is much more widely spread.... Previous civilizations were specialized and limited, they were like oases in a desert.</description>
      <title>What is the first merit of our civilization?</title>
      <options>
        <o0>Material advancement</o0>
        <o1>Cultural advancement</o1>
        <o2>Development of science</o2>
        <o3>Order and safety</o3>
        <o4>Spiritualism has become a way of life</o4>
      </options>
      <picture></picture>
      <answer>0|3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
   <question>
    <id>76147017882d446494afb182a2f41a92</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1fd7c</practiceSet>
    <type>MULTI_CHOICE_MULTIPLE_ANSWER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct response. More than one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:02:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>One of the factors that keeps electric vehicles from wide adoption is range anxiety. Though battery technologies have come a long way in the last decade, with 100 miles on a charge being common and Teslas easily topping 200 miles, people still want to know they can take off on a family vacation or a weekend away. A French company has a cute solution to this problem: EP Tender, a generator housed in a little two-wheeled trailer pulled by your EV(electronic vehicle). It’s just over 4 feet long and over 400 pounds, which seems like a lot for an EV to pull. That might seem like a heavy piece of equipment to tow behind an EV, but the idea isn’t to tow a generator behind your car all day every day. It’s meant to be a range extender that owners can rent for longer trips. It’s even got a rack on top for your extra gear or vacation luggage. The company is also planning on making both gasoline-fueled and fuel-cell versions of the generator so drivers can choose between easy convenience and eco-friendliness. You’re probably wondering how you’d park this thing, but EP Tender has already thought of that and engineered their way out of the problem. The EV pulls into a parking space with the EP Tender and inches to spare. Then, to leave the space, the EP Tender deploys its secondary set of smaller wheels and lifts the larger rear wheels off the ground. They can then track with the car as it backs up. When the driver is ready to drive forward, the EP Tender puts its regular wheels down and lifts that secondary set up, and it’s ready to go. This wheel design is actually the subject of the EP Tender’s patent.</description>
      <title>Which of the following statements are true about the EP Tender?</title>
      <options>
        <o0>It is designed so that users can tow it behind their car every day.</o0>
        <o1>It has a patented wheel design that is used during parking.</o1>
        <o2>It has two sets of wheels, one large and one small.</o2>
        <o3>It has a gasoline-fuelled version meant for eco-friendliness</o3>
      </options>
      <picture></picture>
      <answer>1|3</answer>
    </template>
  </question> 
 <question>
    <id>9e06a62e66944a32985c58cd541ab50e</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1fd7c</practiceSet>
    <type>REORDER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:02:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Arrange the options.</description>
      <title></title>
      <options>
        <o0>Both parties use capital and labour in the struggle to secure property rights.</o0>
        <o1>The thief spends time and money in his attempt to steal (he buys wire cutters) and the legitimate property owner expends resources to prevent the theft (he buys locks).</o1>
        <o2>A social cost of theft is that both the thief and the potential victim use resources to gain or maintain control over property.</o2>
        <o3>These costs may escalate as a type of technological arms race unfolds.</o3>
		<o4>A bank may purchase more and more complicated and sophisticated safes, forcing safecrackers to invest further in safecracking equipment.</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>2|0|1|3|4</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
   <question>
    <id>df90e91215b8442e9c8689025b66e4a4</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1fd7c</practiceSet>
    <type>REORDER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:02:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Arrange the options.</description>
      <title></title>
      <options>
        <o0>Picture a termite colony, occupying a tall mud hump on an African plain.</o0>
        <o1>Hungry predators often invade the colony and unsettle the balance.</o1>
        <o2>The colony flourishes only if the proportion of soldiers to workers remains roughly the same, so that the queen and workers can be protected by the soldiers, and the queen and soldiers can be serviced by the workers.</o2>
        <o3>But its fortunes are presently restored, because the immobile queen, walled in well below ground level, lays eggs not only in large enough numbers, but also in the varying proportions required.</o3>
		<o4>The hump is alive with worker termites and soldier termites going about their distinct kinds of business.</o4>
		<o5>How can we account for her mysterious ability to respond like this to events on the distant surface?</o5>
      </options>
      <answer>0|4|2|1|3|5</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
   <question>
    <id>df90e91215b8442e9c8689025b66e4a4</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1fd7c</practiceSet>
    <type>REORDER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:02:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Arrange the options.</description>
      <title></title>
      <options>
        <o0>With that,I swallowed the shampoo, and obtained most realistic results on the spot.</o0>
        <o1>The man shuffled away into the back regions to make up a prescription, and after a moment I got through on the shop telephone to the Consulate, intimating my location.</o1>
        <o2>Then, while the pharmacist was wrapping up a six-ounce bottle of the mixture, I groaned and inquired whether he could give me something for acute gastric cramp.</o2>
        <o3>I intended to stage a sharp gastric attack, and entering an old-fashioned pharmacy, I asked for a popular shampoo mixture, consisting of olive and flaked soap.</o3>
	</options>
      <answer>3|2|1|0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>   
  <question>
    <id>ffbc8a16865e44e8a8ad371c74f7e79f</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1fd7c</practiceSet>
    <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:59</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>In the Neolithic period, starting around 10,000 years ago, perhaps the most important economic revolution in human history occurred - the commencement of agriculture and the domestication of animals for human consumption. From this point in time, people could start to rely on a more consistent and much increased food supply. As a corollary of this, considerably larger populations could be supported and people could settle in one place without the need to migrate in search of food supplies. Equally important, the surpluses of crops and animals meant that not all the population needed to dedicate their time and energy to farming; some could now learn specialized skills such as crafts or trade. The building of permanent settlements where skills could be developed brought about the conditions necessary for the first growth of towns. But several thousand years elapsed between the beginnings of agriculture and the rise of what we call civilization about 6,000 years ago.</description>
      <title>What condition allowed people to learn specialized skills?</title>
      <options>
        <o0>The ability to migrate</o0>
        <o1>The growth of population</o1>
        <o2>The surplus of farm products</o2>
        <o3>The spread of settlements</o3>
      </options>
      <picture></picture>
      <answer>2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
    <question>
    <id>0cead6cc9d8e4232957c946d0abce610</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1fd7c</practiceSet>
    <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:59</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>The nineteenth century brought with it a burst of new discoveries and inventions that revolutionized the candle industry and made lighting available to all. In the early-to-mid-nineteenth century, a process was developed to refine tallow (fat from animals) with alkali and sulfuric acid. The result was a product called stearin. Stearin is harder and burns longer than unrefined tallow. This breakthrough meant that it was possible to make tallow candles that would not produce the usual smoke and rancid odor. Stearins were also derived from palm oils, so vegetable waxes as well as animal fats could be used to make candles.</description>
      <title>Which of the following can be inferred from paragraph about candles before the nineteenth century?</title>
      <options>
        <o0>They did not smoke when they were burned.</o0>
        <o1>They produced a pleasant odor as they burned.</o1>
        <o2>They were not available to all.</o2>
        <o3>They contained sulfuric acid.</o3>
      </options>
      <picture></picture>
      <answer>2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
      <question>
    <id>10937d9e5c1247c89d8444cdce472c4d</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1fd7c</practiceSet>
    <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:59</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Until the end of his first year at school, Cyril retained many of the pleasures and pursuits he had brought with him from home, and he kept an old interest in butterflies and fossils. His grandmother had presented him with a fine bird's eggs cabinet, but he could never bring himself to risk in climbing trees. Once or twice he dissected dead birds from sheer determination to overcome his horror of the operation. Probably it was his envy of those physically unlike himself that brought on a phase during which he drew massive athletes with thick necks and square shoulders. Again he was pitying himself for what he could never be.</description>
      <title>Cyril dissected dead birds</title>
      <options>
        <o0>to see if he would like to become a doctor</o0>
        <o1>to please his grandmother</o1>
        <o2>because he enjoyed performing operations</o2>
        <o3>to overcome the fear of act</o3>		
      </options>
      <picture></picture>
      <answer>3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>  
  <question>
    <id>f82c14f4bef948bf8ddf9a739575c458</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1fd7c</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>The Basset Hound appeared in France in the first part of the 16th century. The breed got its name from a French word "bas," which means "low." The rich, who had a strong {blank} for hunting, developed a breed {blank} animals in dense brush. The breed was recognized in 1885. However, it did not enter the ten top widely spread dogs in the US. No sooner than in the second half of the 20th century did Basset Hounds acquired popularity. Now, the breed is loved for its appearance and {blank} personality.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>predilection</o1>
          <o2>collaboration</o2>
          <o3>temperance</o3>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>guilty of violating</o1>
          <o2>capable of pursuing</o2>
          <o3>power of entitlement</o3>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>amiable</o1>
          <o2>despondent</o2>
          <o3>mischievous</o3>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>0|1|0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>391b86d84ca542429d3113d679405851</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1fd7c</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>It is a well-established myth that some people have  “mathematical mind” while others do not. Interestingly, this  is {blank} to mathematics; you never hear, for example, that  someone with a historical mind. It is a general belief {blank} us that if we do not learn something it is because we cannot.  In fact mathematical ideas that are difficult at an early age are much easier to {blank} a few years later, if we give them another try.{newline}Another handicap (followed/shown/ borne) by the math anxious seems to be a distrust of their own {blank}. An immediate right formula or give up the problem is  the real action on the part of a mathematician. Mathematicians trust their intuition in solving problems and they cannot be able to function without it. Another {blank} distinction between the mathematics anxious and people who are not good at figures is a difference in attitude.{newline}So the persons with guessing and estimating {blank} and having intuitive thinking should be encouraged and rewarded in the class. This helps in learning word problems, coping with equations and confronting theorems and thereby overpowering the mythical lack of mathematics.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>limited</o1>
          <o2>restricted </o2>
          <o3>perpetuated</o3>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>amongst</o1>
          <o2>against</o2>
          <o3>with</o3>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>derive </o1>
          <o2>comprehend</o2>
          <o3>deduce</o3>
        </blank>
		 <blank>
          <o1>sensibility</o1>
          <o2>intuition</o2>
          <o3>Debility</o3>
        </blank>
		<blank>
          <o1>obvious</o1>
          <o2>tangible</o2>
          <o3>glaring</o3>
        </blank>
		<blank>
          <o1>perception</o1>
          <o2>attitude</o2>
          <o3>outlook</o3>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>1|0|1|1|1|1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>  
   <question>
    <id>41c5a7308c0f4da79dce4e1cd59e3eae</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1fd7c</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Of the hundreds of San Blas islands that dot the Caribbean coast of Ponnama, only 50 are inhabited, primarily by the Cuna people. The chief claim to fame of the {blank} of these islands lies with the women; leisure magazines, travelogues and movies often featuring their dazzling {blank} beauty, complete with nose rings and beaded ankles and wrists. If the women are their society’s ambassadors to the world, then the mola cloths that they create and wear are their flags. The {blank} theme represented in mola design is nature. The earliest examples were abstract interpretations of the texture of brain coral.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>denizens</o1>
          <o2>remnants</o2>
          <o3>landscape</o3>
		  <o4>animals</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>exhaustive</o1>
          <o2>different</o2>
          <o3>exotic</o3>
		  <o4>gory</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>paramount</o1>
          <o2>underlying</o2>
          <o3>passing away quickly </o3>
		  <o4>exotic</o4>
        </blank>
	 </blanks>
      <answer>0|2|1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
    <question>
    <id>a423be0aa39c49cfa37dc216ee142912</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1fd7c</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Children need to be  made know that there is no free flow of money but money is made available to  them for their all essential requirements only so that they have a fair  judgment of how much and where to spend. Parents who do not teach their kids the value of money at an early stage and do not limit their spending of money, invariably {blank} such lifelong damage that children sometimes ruin their lives by spending beyond their resources. Surplus or unaccounted money given to children can lead to abuse of money, poor attention to their studies and falling {blank} to bad company. This all happens only when a child is never taught the value for money at right time and feels no pain in wasting it. That is why it is important to catch children young. {blank} planning and spending is essential to make the  kids responsible adults who can manage their lives well.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>inflict</o1>
          <o2>effect</o2>
          <o3>impact</o3>
		  <o4>shield</o4>
		  <o5>cause</o5>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>reason</o1>
          <o2>cause</o2>
          <o3>victim</o3>
		  <o4>influence</o4>
		  <o5>prey</o5>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>Judicious</o1>
          <o2>intelligent</o2>
          <o3>clever</o3>
		  <o4>shrewd</o4>
		  <o5>active</o5>
        </blank>
	 </blanks>
      <answer>0|4|0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>5dc2a3078ed94308ad1950346075ca5e</id>
    <practiceSet>89e5ed3d303847b48535195f410d564a</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Cellular slime molds are extraordinary life forms that exhibit features of both fungi and protozoa, although often classed for convenience with fungi. At one time they were regarded as organisms of {blank} taxonomic status, but more recent analysis of DNA sequences has shown that slime molds should be regarded as inhabiting their own separate kingdom. Their uniqueness lies in their unusual life cycle, which alternates between a feeding stage in which the organism is essentially unicellular and a reproductive stage in which the organism adopts a multicellular structure. At the first stage they are free-living, separate amoebae, usually inhabiting the forest floor and ingesting bacteria found in rotting wood, dung, or damp soil. But their food supplies are relatively easily {blank} since the cells' movements are restricted and their food requirements rather large.When the cells become {blank} of nutrition, the organism initiates a new genetic program that permits the cells to eventually find a new, food-rich environment. At this point, the single-celled amoebae combine together to form what will eventually become a multicellular creature. The mechanism by which the individual members become a single {blank} is essentially chemical in nature. At first, a few of the amoebae start to produce periodic chemical pulses that are detected, amplified, and relayed to the surrounding members, which then move toward the pulse origin. In time, these cells form many streams of cells, which then come together to form a single hemispherical mass. This mass sticks together through the secretion of adhesion molecules.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>completely</o1>
          <o2>ambiguous</o2>
          <o3>nebulous</o3>
		  <o4>wooly</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>exhausted</o1>
          <o2>pooped</o2>
          <o3>drain</o3>
		  <o4>replenish</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>famish</o1>
          <o2>deprived</o2>
          <o3>full</o3>
		  <o4>starved</o4>
        </blank>
		 <blank>
          <o1>entity</o1>
          <o2>thing</o2>
          <o3>mania</o3>
		  <o4>member</o4>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>1|0|3|0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>88a4c3c36dda481d98090441344d7bff</id>
    <practiceSet>89e5ed3d303847b48535195f410d564a</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Nanotechnology is the science of ‘miniature’. It is the engineering of working systems at the molecular level. Due to advancement in  technology area, nanotechnology is the {blank} field that  interests many people. From the clothes and sunglasses we wear to  computer drives and even cleaning products, nanotechnology which is {blank}by natural world,  plays a big part in manufacturing many familiar products of our daily use. It enhances our sunscreen’s ability to reflect harmful ultra violet radiation, armours our designer shades against unwanted scratches. It increases the capacity of our computer gadgets for storage of data and photos for our use. Nanotechnology, very broad in its size, {blank}in itself diverse fields of sciences like surface science, organic chemistry, molecular biology and semiconductor science etc. Similarly the research and applications associated to it are also equally {blank}.Realising its commercial viability, the scientific institutions in India have started carrying out research and development work in this filed. It is now fast becoming a powerful technology that aids the development of products with {blank}performance. The two major categories of nanotechnology are nano-scale technology and molecular manufacturing.The former covers small structures and can be used for introducing stronger, better medicines and faster computers and so on. Molecular manufacturing is an attempt at building mechanical and chemical manufacturing systems that join molecules together.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>impending</o1>
          <o2>forthcoming</o2>
          <o3>upcoming</o3>
		  <o4>awaiting</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>transpired</o1>
          <o2>emerged</o2>
          <o3>inspired</o3>
		  <o4>revealed</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>absorbs</o1>
          <o2>shows</o2>
          <o3>portrays</o3>
		  <o4>imbibes</o4>
        </blank>
		 <blank>
          <o1>useful</o1>
          <o2>diverse</o2>
          <o3>beneficial</o3>
		  <o4>indifferent</o4>
        </blank>
		<blank>
          <o1>major</o1>
          <o2>futuristic</o2>
          <o3>trivial</o3>
		  <o4>strong</o4>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>2|2|3|1|1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>  
   <question>
    <id>4e58dd176e9a4f49a1fd1236cc0d9d1b</id>
    <practiceSet>89e5ed3d303847b48535195f410d564a</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Global warming caused by global climate change is the  single – most important challenge humanity is facing today. It is a far bigger threat to humanity’s {blank} than any other. Its ill effects attributed largely to  industrialization, were taken serious note for the first time at the “Earth Summit” of 1992, held in Rio de Janerio, Brazil. The participating countries resolved to undertake measures to reduce the volume of emissions of greenhouse gases to the level of 1990 by the year 2000. The Kyoto Protocol of 1997, that became operative in 2005, {blank} the goals set at the Rio Summit and fixed the target of reducing the emissions of greenhouse gases to the tune of 5.2 percent from the level of 1990, by the year 2012. It adopted the principle of “common but differentiated responsibility” according to which the countries that were prime {blank} for causing damage to the ecology would contribute more for its mitigation agenda. It was understood that rich industrialized countries would provide modern technology for switching over to cleaner sources of energy which was the key to halting global warming. However success remained {blank} as the volume of greenhouse gases continued to increase and damage the environment in alarming proportions. Such emissions have increased by about 16 percent from the level of 1990</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>endurance</o1>
          <o2>existence</o2>
          <o3>survival</o3>
		  </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>fixed</o1>
          <o2>determined</o2>
          <o3>reiterated</o3>
		 </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>participants</o1>
          <o2>culprits</o2>
          <o3>observers</o3>
		</blank>
		 <blank>
          <o1>elusive</o1>
          <o2>obscure</o2>
          <o3>vague</o3>
	 </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>2|2|1|0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
   <question>
    <id>b7d96d3d6a7e44599c1f9ed000dd45ad</id>
    <practiceSet>89e5ed3d303847b48535195f410d564a</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Once upon a time, there lived a poor orphan who was an exceptional artist and would often draw pictures of rivers, mountains and people. One day, a fairy gifted him golden paint brush and to his great {blank}whatever he painted with the brush came to life. His fame  spread and he was brought to the king's {blank}.The king and his ministers took the boy into the fields.{blank} an ocean here! 'ordered the king. The boy protested that it wasn't right and the fields and houses would be {blank}.But the king ordered him to paint the ocean and a  storm. the boy painted {blank}and the storm was so violent that the boat in which the king and his ministers were overturned, killing them.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>sorrow</o1>
          <o2>doubt</o2>
          <o3>miracle</o3>
		  <o4>surprise</o4>
		  <o5>problem</o5>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>court</o1>
          <o2>dilemma</o2>
          <o3>justice</o3>
		  <o4>favour</o4>
		  <o5>riches</o5>
        </blank>
        <blank>
         <o1>origin</o1>
          <o2>find</o2>
          <o3>cry</o3>
		  <o4>sail</o4>
		  <o5>create</o5>
        </blank>
		 <blank>
          <o1>form</o1>
          <o2>destroyed</o2>
          <o3>damage</o3>
		  <o4>hurt</o4>
		  <o5>wiped</o5>
        </blank>
		<blank>
          <o1>skillful</o1>
          <o2>similar</o2>
          <o3>accordingly</o3>
		  <o4>slowly</o4>
		  <o5>equally</o5>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>3|0|4|1|2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>b791dc94c9c8467b870c5389ee9b965f</id>
    <practiceSet>89e5ed3d303847b48535195f410d564a</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Creativity research has long been polarized between the ‘romantic’ view that major creative achievements are sparked by imaginative and uniquely {blank} individuals at the margin of an intellectual field. Although this remains the dominant approach when examining individual creativity, an increasingly large number of studies have {blank} the importance of also looking at social factors. Following this line of thought and drawing more explicitly from research by sociologists and socio psychologists, organizational scholars have increasingly recognized the {blank} of the network side of individual creativity.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>present</o1>
          <o2>gifted</o2>
          <o3>awards</o3>
		  <o4>grants</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>authentic</o1>
          <o2>distinguish</o2>
          <o3>recognized</o3>
		  <o4>accepted</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>value</o1>
          <o2>importance</o2>
          <o3>meaning</o3>
		  <o4>significant</o4>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>1|2|1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>  
    <question>
    <id>293958d69745465e9545fbcd0263dceb</id>
    <practiceSet>89e5ed3d303847b48535195f410d564a</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Fossils are the preserved {blank} or traces of animals, plants and other organisms. They vary in size from microscopic, such as single cells, to gigantic, such as dinosaurs. A fossil normally preserves only portion of the {blank} organism, usually that portion was partially mineralized during life. Fossils may also {blank} of the marks left behind by the organism while it was alive.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>maledictions</o1>
          <o2>pretentious</o2>
          <o3>deceased</o3>
          <o4>consist</o4>
          <o5>insist</o5>
          <o6>remnants</o6>
		  <o7>pretentious</o7>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>5|2|3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>  
     <question>
    <id>ed8740b6d1854d09b4d7b693cb1e1c54</id>
    <practiceSet>89e5ed3d303847b48535195f410d564a</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Salmon live in both the Atlantic and Pacific Oceans, {blank} great lakes and rivers. Typically, they live in the sea mostly but {blank} in fresh water. They are born in fresh water; migrate to the ocean, then return to fresh water to reproduce. This means the fish return to the exact spot where they were born to {blank}.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>just as </o1>
          <o2>segregate</o2>
          <o3>spawn</o3>
          <o4>modify</o4>
          <o5>breed</o5>
          <o6>devour</o6>
		  <o7>as well as</o7>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>6|4|2</answer>
    </template>
  </question> 
       <question>
    <id>f32cdd02293e4a9a91a42b985e069203</id>
    <practiceSet>89e5ed3d303847b48535195f410d564a</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>After the publication of the article, Bill Joy {blank}assessing technologies to gauge their implicit dangers, as well as having scientists refuse to work on technologies that have the potential to cause harm. In the 15th Anniversary issue of Wired in 2008, Lucas Graves's article {blank}that the genetics, nanotechnology, and robotics {blank}have not reached the level that would make Bill Joy's scenario come true.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>reported</o1>
          <o2>technique</o2>
          <o3>suggest</o3>
          <o4>form</o4>
          <o5>technologies</o5>
          <o6>suggested</o6>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>5|0|4</answer>
    </template>
  </question> 
       <question>
    <id>8ead93d415c44e9da5c54ccf6214ea72</id>
    <practiceSet>89e5ed3d303847b48535195f410d564a</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>During the {blank},  if government announces rebates in corporation tax, sales tax, excise duty, customs duty, etc; Sensex would rise as such measures would help in rise in {blank} sales. Even in case of direct taxes, reduction of tax would always have positive impact. For instance, if income tax exemption limit is increased, it would mean that {blank} have more disposable income in their hand which would ultimately result in the increased demand for the company’s products thus helping in the latter’s {blank}.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>growth</o1>
          <o2>people</o2>
          <o3>part</o3>
          <o4>budget</o4>
          <o5>overall</o5>
          <o6>companies</o6>
		  <o7>increase</o7>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>3|5|1|0</answer>
    </template>
  </question> 
       <question>
    <id>2c7e80ed562241c6a72ef8c6ecf7f751</id>
    <practiceSet>89e5ed3d303847b48535195f410d564a</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>The stakeholders must{blank} that in a growing industry, individual skill as well as group skill of the whole organization greatly improves with continued action. Under the process of continued {blank} the average man can make a fair showing and with a reasonable degree of moral support will make good, while without it the ablest man will have a hard time and even fail if he is{blank} to accept changes that disturb continuity of action.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>ready</o1>
          <o2>forced</o2>
          <o3>real</o3>
          <o4>below</o4>
          <o5>action</o5>
          <o6>remember</o6>
		 </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>5|4|1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>  
   <question>
    <id>2349a9c985c2464c8f54332182500945</id>
    <practiceSet>89e5ed3d303847b48535195f410d564a</practiceSet>
    <type>REORDER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:02:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Arrange the options.</description>
      <title></title>
      <options>
        <o0>Although there is not yet a cure for the illness, there may be hope for a cure with a protein called nerve growth factor.</o0>
        <o1>Alzheimer’s disease impairs a person’s ability to recall memories, both distant memories and memories as recent as a few hours before.</o1>
        <o2>Using a group of rats with impaired memory, the scientists gave half of the rats doses of nerve growth factor while giving the other half a blood protein as a placebo, thus creating a control group.</o2>
        <o3>Based on this relationship, scientists from the University of Lund in Sweden and the University of California at San Diego designed an experiment to test whether doses of nerve growth factor could reverse the effects of memory loss caused by Alzheimer’s.</o3>
		<o4>The protein is produced by nerve cells in the same region of the brain where Alzheimer’s occurs.</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>1|0|4|3|2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
   <question>
    <id>5b60ca523dbf43529630c7c20ea40d65</id>
    <practiceSet>89e5ed3d303847b48535195f410d564a</practiceSet>
    <type>REORDER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:02:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Arrange the options.</description>
      <title></title>
      <options>
        <o0>After doing so, the heart of your cash flow will be strong and healthy.</o0>
        <o1>Cash is your business’s lifeblood.</o1>
        <o2>If managed poorly, then your company could go into cardiac arrest.</o2>
        <o3>To prevent your business from suffering heart attacks, you should learn to manage cash flow in a well thought-out manner.</o3>
		<o4>Several ways to do this is by generating a project rate of returns as well as determining possible problems with liquidity.</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>1|2|3|4|0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
   <question>
    <id>2cd6b181f33f49f7860ce2eeb3140adf</id>
    <practiceSet>89e5ed3d303847b48535195f410d564a</practiceSet>
    <type>REORDER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:02:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Arrange the options.</description>
      <title></title>
      <options>
        <o0>Today, the study of the fruit fly has expanded to research for human diseases.</o0>
        <o1>This is because the fruit fly’s robust genetic system makes it an invaluable tool for scientists studying current inheritance diseases.</o1>
        <o2>These diseases include Alzheimer’s, Parkinson’s and Huntington’s disease.</o2>
        <o3>In past decades, scientists have used the fruit fly as a model organism for examining biological systems.</o3>
	 </options>
      <answer>3|0|1|2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>   
 <question>
    <id>da496eace98649a18da7de161761ad64</id>
    <practiceSet>89e5ed3d303847b48535195f410d564a</practiceSet>
    <type>MULTI_CHOICE_MULTIPLE_ANSWER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct response. More than one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:02:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>A cross-section of the skin reveals a top layer of epidermis, or cuticle, followed by derma, and finally, subcutaneous cellular tissue. Sprouting through all three layers are hairs, with hair follicles and erector pili muscles embedded deep within the subcutaneous tissue. Sweat (sudoriferous) glands, fat cells, and sebaceous glands are scattered throughout, while papillae, which are conical and extremely sensitive, can be found directly beneath the superficial layer. The skin is the primary organ of the sense of touch. It can excrete substances as well as absorb them, and it plays a vital role in regulating body temperature and in protecting the tissues that lie beneath it. The epidermis has no veins or arteries and varies considerably both in thickness and in depth or fineness of its furrows. On the palm, for example, the skin is quite thick, or horny, and is marked by deep furrows or lines. On the back of the hand, however, the skin is less thick, and has only a faint network of lines crisscrossing it. The pigment found in the epidermis gives whatever color there is to the skin; this pigment is similar to that found in the retina of the eye. One layer down, in the derma, there is similar variation in thickness, mostly to protect underlying tissue.In the derma lies the vascular system, which includes nerves, blood vessels, and lymphatics. The derma is divided into two sub-layers: the reticular layer and the papillary layer, which is closer to the epidermis. The less sensitive the skin, the fewer papillae reside there; in the most sensitive places, such as the fingertips and the nipples, the papillae are long, large, and grouped closely together to form parallel arcs with ducts to sweat glands lying in between. Under the papillary layer, and conforming to it, is the reticular layer, composed of fibrous bands and elastic tissue, and interlaced by fat and sudoriferous glands.The basic functions of muscular contraction, vascular transport, nerve communication, and protection all take place in the various layers of the skin, so that understanding the components of the skin and how they work together is a helpful step in understanding the complex anatomy of the human body.</description>
      <title>The passage states which of the following are found in the skin</title>
      <options>
        <o0>fat cells</o0>
        <o1>lymphatics</o1>
        <o2>veins</o2>
        <o3>pigmentation</o3>
        <o4>ligaments</o4>
      </options>
      <picture></picture>
      <answer>0|1|2|3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
   <question>
    <id>41b3d6b552204c5c9d8cb9397dc4a586</id>
    <practiceSet>89e5ed3d303847b48535195f410d564a</practiceSet>
    <type>MULTI_CHOICE_MULTIPLE_ANSWER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct response. More than one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:02:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>The Viking/Norse settlement of Greenland was of relatively short duration (ca AD 1000-1500), yet the Norse abandonment of Greenland has become an iconic episode in the history of the North Atlantic, attracting commentary from many disciplines. The causes advanced for the end of European colonization – ’a catastrophe of total cultural and biological extinction’ – are multi-faceted, including: climate change – especially the accentuation of climate cooling within the so-called Little Ice Age, together with shorter growing seasons and shifting patterns in animal migration; biogeomorphic impacts – vegetation mat destruction and soil erosion consequent upon the imposition of shrub clearance and pastoral agriculture; economic and social collapse – relating to climatically-caused loss of contact with Iceland and mainland Europe (e.g. from enhanced sea-ice), economic change in Europe, and possible conflict with Inuit (Thule) groups over access to natural resources. The episode of Norse occupation is clearly visible in, for instance, the microfossil- and sedimentologically-based palaeoecological and archaeological records. Many of the above causes can be investigated directly and indirectly by a range of approaches including palynology, palaeoentomology, sedimentology, radiocarbon age modelling, tephrochronology and environmental archaeology.</description>
      <title>The episode of Norse occupation is</title>
      <options>
       <o0>clear</o0>
        <o1>opaque</o1>
        <o2>archaeologically available</o2>
        <o3>patterned</o3>
		<o4>seasonal</o4>
      </options>
      <picture></picture>
      <answer>0|2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
 <question>
    <id>7890f59c8f704af5b2d1b3e24f526447</id>
    <practiceSet>89e5ed3d303847b48535195f410d564a</practiceSet>
    <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:59</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Scientists believe that some birds navigate by use of star positions; this has been established with at least one species. In a series of studies, caged birds were subjected to the projection of the nighttime Northern Hemisphere inside a planetarium. All stars rotate around Polaris, the pole star, and this movement seemed to give the birds the information they needed to orientate themselves in the correct direction. However, some recent research contradicts this. Perhaps it is not the lack of movement of the pole star but rather the constellation patterns that guide them. It has also been found that when fewer stars were visible on the planetarium ceiling, the birds' sense of direction became poorer. And this, too, implies that the general star pattern does have some bearing on orientation.</description>
      <title>How do some birds navigate during the night?</title>
      <options>
        <o0>By using a projection of the star positions</o0>
        <o1>By circling around the pole star</o1>
        <o2>By orientating themselves using the constellations</o2>
        <o3>By getting their bearings from a few visible stars</o3>
      </options>
      <picture></picture>
      <answer>2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
    <question>
    <id>fc236261a45546f6b2312982f3878452</id>
    <practiceSet>89e5ed3d303847b48535195f410d564a</practiceSet>
    <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:59</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>In June 1863, a Confederate army under the command of General Lee encountered a Union army commanded by General Meade near the town of Gettysburg, Pennsylvania. The ensuing battle, which lasted three days, is considered the most important single engagement of the American Civil War in that it effectually ended the Confederates' last major invasion of the North. Once the Southern Confederate army's offensive strategy was destroyed at Gettysburg, the Southern states were forced to fight a defensive war in which their weaker manufacturing capacity and transportation infrastructure led ultimately to defeat.General Lee had ordered his Confederate army to invade the northern state of Pennsylvania in the hope of enticing the Union army into a vulnerable position. The strategy was also aimed at increasing the war weariness of the North and ultimately at leading Abraham Lincoln's government into concluding a peace deal and recognizing the independence of the Confederate South.</description>
      <title>The author suggests that the confederates lost the Civil War largely because their</title>
      <options>
        <o0>leaders were ineffective</o0>
        <o1>industrial capacity was weaker</o1>
        <o2>soldiers were unprofessional</o2>
        <o3>strategy was poorly planned</o3>		
      </options>
      <picture></picture>
      <answer>1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
    <question>
    <id>d124f013c81043ac8e67ea519dda3ab4</id>
    <practiceSet>89e5ed3d303847b48535195f410d564a</practiceSet>
    <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:59</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Many sociologists have argued that there is a functional relationship between education and the economic system. They point out to the fact that mass formal education began in industrial society. They note that the expansion of the economies of industrial societies is accompanied by a corresponding expansion of their educational systems. They explain this correspondence in terms of the needs of industry for skilled and trained manpower, needs which are met by the educational system. Thus, the provision of mass elementary education in Britain in 1870 can be seen as a response to the needs of industry for a literate and numerate workforce at a time when industrial processes were becoming more complex and the demand for technical skills was steadily growing.</description>
      <title>The industry needs a literate work-force because </title>
      <options>
        <o0>its expansion needs sound learning</o0>
        <o1>it relies heavily on expertise </o1>
        <o2>it promotes a competitive spirit</o2>
        <o3>its operations need intricate technical knowledge</o3>	
      </options>
      <picture></picture>
      <answer>1</answer>
    </template>
  </question> 
   <question>
    <id>ffbc8a16865e44e8a8ad371c74f7e79f</id>
    <practiceSet>a540452272644faab9254ea73290cb9d</practiceSet>
    <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:59</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>It is shocking to note that the majority of our schools do not even have the buildings. The classes are taken under the trees. These schools cannot afford the luxury of games. Sports activities in are nonexistent as the schools and colleges do not have infrastructure to give students the proper training. The hockey stick is present but the ball absent; the football is in front of us but without air. Sports generate sportsman spirit in the child, the ability to take decisions according to the situations and to struggle in situations that do not favor them.</description>
      <title>Which of the following most accurately summarizes the opinion of the author in the text?</title>
      <options>
        <o0>Sports and games generate a feeling of competition in the child and strengthen it.</o0>
        <o1>The schools lack sports infrastructure.</o1>
        <o2>The school education often fails to cover an important aspect of child education.</o2>
        <o3>The school curriculums need to be revisited to include sports as an important part.</o3>
      </options>
      <picture></picture>
      <answer>2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
    <question>
    <id>0cead6cc9d8e4232957c946d0abce610</id>
    <practiceSet>a540452272644faab9254ea73290cb9d</practiceSet>
    <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:59</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Fictional stories about people who have extraordinary abilities have always attracted people's attention. One of them is the story of Vera Petrova, who is able to perceive things with different parts of her skin, and through solid walls. One day she comes into his father's office and puts her hands on he door of a locked safe. Suddenly she asks her fa her why he keeps so many old newspapers locked away there. Vera's curious talent is brought to the notice of a scientific research institute and she is given a series of tests by a special commission. During these tests she manages to read a newspaper through an opaque screen and then she describes he figures and colors of a picture hidden under a carpet. During all these tests Vera is blindfold; and, indeed, except when blindfold she lacks the ability to perceive things with her skin. It was also found that although she could perceive things with her fingers this ability ceased the moment her hands were wet.</description>
      <title>As we understand from the reading, Vera Petrova ______.</title>
      <options>
        <o0>can only perceive things with her fingers.</o0>
        <o1>is a curious child.</o1>
        <o2>is not the only fictional character who has extraordinary abilities.</o2>
        <o3>fails most of the tests administered by a special commission.</o3>
		<o4>perceives the objects only when her fingers are wet.</o4>
      </options>
      <picture></picture>
      <answer>2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
      <question>
    <id>10937d9e5c1247c89d8444cdce472c4d</id>
    <practiceSet>a540452272644faab9254ea73290cb9d</practiceSet>
    <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:59</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Most people don’t mind working out a bit, but are discouraged by the thought of exercising hard. The idea of sweating buckets is so daunting that they avoid exercising.  Fortunately, exercise is not a matter of all or nothing. There is some reward at every level of effort, provided it is regular. Spend at least 30 minutes a day in action like brisk walking to errands climbing stairs, carrying heavy shopping or children, doing outdoor gardening. Your rewards will not be immediate, but you can expect a reduced risk of problems like brittle bones, heart disease and poor blood circulation. You work up a decent appetite and sleep well, but improvement in body-shape will be minimal.Light regular exercise helps your heart. Such activity can include anything from brisk walking, jogging, cycling, swimming, any light sport or even disco dancing. The reward is immunity to colds and flu, less stress, slightly healthier levels of cholesterol and blood pressure. The figure trims down a little but only gradually.</description>
      <title>Which of the following statements about light exercise can be supported from the text?</title>
      <options>
        <o0>Even some routine activities can serve as light exercise.</o0>
        <o1>If putting your body into complete shape is your aim, you might be in for some disappointment.</o1>
        <o2>It is necessary to exercise different parts of the body daily.</o2>
        <o3>Put in some aerobic activity for working up a sweat.</o3>
		<o4>It builds resistance to chronic diseases and infections, and your heart performs strongly.</o4>
      </options>
      <picture></picture>
      <answer>0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>  
  
  <question>
    <id>bbf511ffad644026969787ab81a5e037</id>
    <practiceSet>a540452272644faab9254ea73290cb9d</practiceSet>
    <type>MULTI_CHOICE_MULTIPLE_ANSWER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct response. More than one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:02:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>It is a strange that, according to his position in life, an extravagant man is admired or despised. A successful businessman does nothing to increase his popularity by being careful with his money. He is expected to display his success, to have smart car, an expensive life, and to be lavish with his hospitality. If he is not so, he is considered mean and his reputation in business may even suffer in consequence. The paradox remains that if he had not been careful with his money in the first place, he would never have achieved his present wealth. Among the two income groups, a different set of values exists. The young clerk who makes his wife a present of a new dress when he hadn’t paid his house rent, is condemned as extravagant. Carefullness with money to the point of meanness is applauded as a virtue. Nothing in his life is considered more worthy than paying his bills. The ideal wife for such a man separates her housekeeping money into joyless little piles- so much for rent, for food, for the children’s shoes; she is able to face the milkman with equanimity and never knows the guilt of buying something she can’t really afford. As for myself, I fall into neither of these categories. If I have money to spare, I can be extravagant, but when, as is usually the case, I am hard up, then I am the meanest man imaginable.</description>
      <title>In the opinion of the writer, a successful businessman:</title>
      <options>
        <o0>is more popular if he appears to be doing nothing.</o0>
        <o1>should not bother about his popularity.</o1>
        <o2>must be extravagant before achieving success.</o2>
        <o3>is expected to have expensive tastes.</o3>
        <o4>admired or despised</o4>
      </options>
      <picture></picture>
      <answer>3|4</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
   <question>
    <id>76147017882d446494afb182a2f41a92</id>
    <practiceSet>a540452272644faab9254ea73290cb9d</practiceSet>
    <type>MULTI_CHOICE_MULTIPLE_ANSWER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct response. More than one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:02:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>True, it is the function of the army to maintain law and order in abnormal times. But in normal times there is another force that compels citizens to obey the laws and to act with due regard to the rights of others. The force also protects the lives and the properties of law abiding men. Laws are made to secure the personal safety of its subjects and to prevent murder and crimes of violence. They are made to secure the property of the citizens against theft and damage to protect the rights of communities and castes to carry out their customs and ceremonies, so long as they do not conflict with the rights of others. Now the good citizen, of his own free will obey these laws and he takes care that everything he does is done with due regard to the rights and well-being of others. But the bad citizen is only restrained from breaking these laws by fear of the consequence of his actions. And the necessary steps to compel the bad citizen to act as a good citizen are taken by this force. The supreme control of law and order in a State is in the hands of a Minister who is  responsible to the State Assembly and acts through the Inspector General of Police.</description>
      <title>The expression 'customs and ceremonies' means :</title>
      <options>
       <o0>fairs and festivals.</o0>
        <o1>habits and traditions.</o1>
        <o2>usual practices and religious rites.</o2>
        <o3>superstitions and formalities.</o3>
      </options>
      <picture></picture>
      <answer>1|2</answer>
    </template>
  </question> 
  
  <question>
    <id>9e06a62e66944a32985c58cd541ab50e</id>
    <practiceSet>a540452272644faab9254ea73290cb9d</practiceSet>
    <type>REORDER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:02:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Arrange the options.</description>
      <title></title>
      <options>
        <o0>Adam Smith is often described as the “founding father of economics”.</o0>
        <o1>One prominent book he wrote was “Theory of Moral Sentiments”.</o1>
        <o2>A great deal of what is now considered standard theory about markets was developed by Adam Smith.</o2>
        <o3>It is a very important text in the history of moral and political thought because he talks about individual freedom.</o3>
		<o4>According to Smith, this freedom is rooted in self-reliance and the ability of an individual to pursue his self-interest.</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>0|2|1|3|4</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
   <question>
    <id>df90e91215b8442e9c8689025b66e4a4</id>
    <practiceSet>a540452272644faab9254ea73290cb9d</practiceSet>
    <type>REORDER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:02:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Arrange the options.</description>
      <title></title>
      <options>
        <o0>Based on these findings such as these, scientists agree that we will soon discover intelligent alien life and make contact with it.</o0>
        <o1>But this complacency has all changed.</o1>
        <o2>Until recently, we have looked at life in a pretty conservative way.</o2>
        <o3>In just the past three or four years, biologists have discovered that life on Earth can exist in the most extreme places, and in the most bizarre forms.</o3>
		<o4>For example, microbes have been found down boreholes two kilometres deep.</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>2|1|3|4|0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
    
   <question>
    <id>9326bd6c834a46f087d4934cacb23966</id>
    <practiceSet>a540452272644faab9254ea73290cb9d</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description> The international community is {blank} to embark on this ambitious new agenda as the number of {blank} and young adolescents out of school climbs. The data send a stark warning: we must reach the most marginalised children who are at risk of continued neglect as attention shifts to higher {blank} of education.  
      </description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>child</o1>
          <o2>preparing</o2>
          <o3>children</o3>
          <o4>level</o4>
          <o5>data</o5>
          <o6>levels</o6>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>1|2|3</answer>
    </template>
  </question> 
    <question>
    <id>3003d6042ec6443d8cdea1e451ca9a30</id>
    <practiceSet>a540452272644faab9254ea73290cb9d</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description> To a great extent, suburban layouts ignored environmental considerations, making little provision for open space, producing {blank}.   rows of resource-consuming and fertilizer-dependent lawns, contaminating groundwater through leaking septic tanks, and absorbing excessive amounts of fresh water and energy. The growth of the outer city since the 1970s reflected a continued preference on the part of many people in the western world for space-intensive single-family houses {blank}. by lawns, for private automobiles over public transit, and for the development of previously untouched areas. Without better planning for land use and environmental protection, urban life will, as it has in the past, continue to damage and stress the {blank} environment. 
      </description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>surrounded</o1>
          <o2>grounded</o2>
          <o3>endless</o3>
          <o4>limited</o4>
          <o5>clean</o5>
          <o6>natural</o6>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>2|0|5</answer>
    </template>
  </question>  
     <question>
    <id>18ede94c57954165aa6baf5d255113a5</id>
    <practiceSet>a540452272644faab9254ea73290cb9d</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description> Procedures again were at fault, as an additional reason for the officers’ reluctance to lower the lifeboats at full capacity was that they feared the lifeboats {blank} buckle under the weight of 65 people. They had not been informed that the lifeboats {blank} been fully tested prior to departure. Such procedures as assigning passengers and crew to the lifeboats and lifeboat loading drills were simply not part of the standard operation of ships nor were they {blank} in crew training at this time. 
      </description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>included </o1>
          <o2>will</o2>
          <o3>would</o3>
          <o4>includes</o4>
          <o5>had</o5>
          <o6>have</o6>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>2|4|0</answer>
    </template>
  </question> 
       <question>
    <id>26016f0500ac4e17a49d4e328f0cafc8</id>
    <practiceSet>a540452272644faab9254ea73290cb9d</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>The overriding concern of all realist fiction is with character. Specifically, {blank} struggled to create intricate and layered characters who, as much as possible, felt as {blank} they could be flesh and blood creatures. Much of this effect was {blank} through internal monologues and a keen understanding of {blank} psychology. 
      </description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>human </o1>
          <o2>common</o2>
          <o3>though</o3>
          <o4>doubted</o4>
          <o5>novelists</o5>
          <o6>achieved</o6>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>4|2|5|0</answer>
    </template>
  </question> 
       <question>
    <id>6117e4ba820a491cb239fe2c413f6f31</id>
    <practiceSet>a540452272644faab9254ea73290cb9d</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Pseudohistory is a term applied to texts which purport to be historical in nature but which depart from standard historiographical conventions in a way which {blank} their conclusions. Closely related to {blank} historical revisionism, works which draw controversial conclusions from new, speculative, or disputed historical evidence, particularly in the fields of national, political, military, and religious {blank}, are often rejected as pseudo{blank}.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>history</o1>
          <o2>deceptive</o2>
          <o3>behaviour</o3>
          <o4>affairs</o4>
          <o5>affair</o5>
          <o6>undermines</o6>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>5|1|3|0</answer>
    </template>
  </question> 
  <question>
    <id>f82c14f4bef948bf8ddf9a739575c458</id>
    <practiceSet>a540452272644faab9254ea73290cb9d</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>“The roots of all our modern academic fields can be found within the pages of literature.” Literature in all its forms can be seen as written records, whether the literature itself be {blank} or fictional, it is still quite possible to decipher facts through things like characters’ actions and words or the authors’ style of writing and the intent behind the words. The plot is for {blank} than just entertainment purposes; within it lies information about economics, psychology, science, religions, politics, cultures, and social {blank}. Studying and analyzing literature becomes very important in terms of learning about our {blank}.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>fact</o1>
          <o2>factual</o2>
          <o3>facts</o3>
		  <o4>real</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>more</o1>
          <o2>mere</o2>
          <o3>extra</o3>
		  <o4>less</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>deep</o1>
          <o2>deeps</o2>
          <o3>depth</o3>
		  <o4>deepen</o4>
        </blank>
		 <blank>
          <o1>story</o1>
          <o2>history</o2>
          <o3>science</o3>
		  <o4>all</o4>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>1|0|2|1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>391b86d84ca542429d3113d679405851</id>
    <practiceSet>a540452272644faab9254ea73290cb9d</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>The Society for Social Studies of Science members also include government and {blank} officials concerned with research and development as well as science and technology policy; scientists and engineers who wish to better understand the social embeddedness of their professional practice; and citizens concerned about the {blank} of science and {blank} in their lives. Proposals have been made to add the word "technology" to the association's name, thereby reflecting its stature as the leading STS professional society, but there seems to be widespread sentiment that the name is long enough as {blank}.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>factory</o1>
          <o2>industry</o2>
          <o3>industries</o3>
		  <o4>organization</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>empact</o1>
          <o2>impact</o2>
          <o3>empacts</o3>
		  <o4>impacts</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>technique</o1>
          <o2>technology</o2>
          <o3>techniques</o3>
		  <o4>technologies</o4>
        </blank>
		 <blank>
          <o1>it</o1>
          <o2>it is</o2>
          <o3>is</o3>
		  <o4>sufficient</o4>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>1|1|1|1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>  
   <question>
    <id>6203cd371ab0482697fca60ffe41fc44</id>
    <practiceSet>a540452272644faab9254ea73290cb9d</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>English syntax relies on auxiliary verbs for many functions including the {blank} of tense, aspect and mood. Auxiliary verbs form main clauses, and the main verbs function as heads of a subordinate clause of the auxiliary verb. For example in the {blank}__ the dog did not find its bone, the clause find its bone is the complement of the negated {blank} did not. Subject–auxiliary inversion is used in many constructions, including focus, negation, and interrogative {blank}.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>express</o1>
          <o2>expression</o2>
          <o3>experience</o3>
		  <o4>method</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>severe</o1>
          <o2>several</o2>
          <o3>sentence</o3>
		  <o4>serene</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>noun</o1>
          <o2>verb</o2>
          <o3>adjective</o3>
		  <o4>modals</o4>
        </blank>
		 <blank>
          <o1>real</o1>
          <o2>reality</o2>
          <o3>constructions</o3>
		  <o4>propogation</o4>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>1|2|1|2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
    <question>
    <id>7911d655e61a4a2e81a6799c6947ad91</id>
    <practiceSet>a540452272644faab9254ea73290cb9d</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Speaking in public is a form of an art as its other forms like singing, writing or acting are. The speaker is required to be careful or rather more careful because one of its most important requirement is to appear {blank} to the audience. In ancient times, the great speakers used to prepare their speeches before a {blank} of their known persons and noticed  their own shortcomings and reaction of the spectators. Their audience {blank} their trusted friends, critics and mentors. They repeated their speech a number of times in order to make a good command over their words, speech and way of speaking. This made their speaking perfect and {blank} and also made their way of speaking perfect and faultless. This all appeared not only highly perfect product but also a genuine way of expression. This is the reason that we still study the speeches of great men to gain experience and perfection in  our acts of speaking in public more {blank}and flawlessly.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>impulsive</o1>
          <o2>prudent</o2>
          <o3>discreet</o3>
		  <o4>subtle</o4>
		  <o5>spontaneous</o5>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>assembly</o1>
          <o2>crowd</o2>
          <o3>horde</o3>
		  <o4>gathering</o4>
		  <o5>multitude</o5>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>included</o1>
          <o2>involved</o2>
          <o3>contained</o3>
		  <o4>comprised</o4>
		  <o5>gathered</o5>
        </blank>
		 <blank>
          <o1>clean</o1>
          <o2>neat</o2>
          <o3>foolproof</o3>
		  <o4>immaculate</o4>
		  <o5>secure</o5>
        </blank>
		<blank>
          <o1>efficiently</o1>
          <o2>well</o2>
          <o3>competently</o3>
		  <o4>ably</o4>
		  <o5>proficiently</o5>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>4|3|0|3|0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
   <question>
    <id>b13f466121bb4a79a4986ef2287b0a23</id>
    <practiceSet>a540452272644faab9254ea73290cb9d</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Parenting a child is not formally taught anywhere. All learn from their own experiences. This also depends on how well {blank} a person is. For a person it can be a very skillful job and the other can leave the child to grow without proper guidance for becoming a good citizen. Some parents believe in giving total {blank} and insist that a child must not be checked for anything in formative years. It may appear true for the  present day generation but it is firmly believed that a child must be taught to  distinguish between  right and wrong. There is a dire need of {blank} for a child at every step. Children learn most of life skills at an early stage. It is  very easy to pamper children with money and material gifts but a prudent parent one has to draw a line as to which demand of children  is to be met and what is politely and firmly declined. There is no need to {blank} to the pressure of a child’s demand.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>trained</o1>
          <o2>guided</o2>
          <o3>educated</o3>
		  <o4>cultured</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>autonomy</o1>
          <o2>sovereignty</o2>
          <o3>independence</o3>
		  <o4>freedom</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>guidance</o1>
          <o2>supervision</o2>
          <o3>direction</o3>
		  <o4>regulation</o4>
        </blank>
		 <blank>
          <o1>accept</o1>
          <o2>shoulder</o2>
          <o3>succumb</o3>
		  <o4>support</o4>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>2|3|0|2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  
  <!--New tests 25022017-->
  <question>
    <id>f3a67ebbd92c44e69ae630e4584f254d</id>
    <practiceSet>39d265f15f41481891312961d73f01bf</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Detractors may take this opportunity to remind readers about how {blank} English Ivy can be. For what ivy {blank} hasn't been cautioned about its ability to burrow holes, fracture windows, and even {blank}  brick? But be warned. Oftentimes, this suggestion is taken to the {blank} extreme. Naysayers take a strange pleasure in spinning yarns about a particularly malevolent strand of ivy—one that slips in through the cracks on a hot summer night, silently {blank} homeowners in their sleep.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>restrained</o1>
          <o2>enthusiast</o2>
          <o3>strangling</o3>
          <o4>joking</o4>
          <o5>detractor</o5>
          <o6>deteriorate</o6>
          <o7>invasive</o7>
          <o8>comical</o8>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>6|1|5|7|2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>c70e1fb1fd6240b69bc92238d81a91b1</id>
    <practiceSet>39d265f15f41481891312961d73f01bf</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>The novel is {blank} not the finest example of its genre, but I object to the {blank} preface written by a supposed expert on detective fiction from whom we might have expected at least one or two {blank} comments.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>perceptive </o1>
          <o2>intelligent </o2>
          <o3>unobservant</o3>
          <o4>admittedly</o4>
          <o5>vacuous </o5>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>3|4|0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>d316c40186aa41cd880f5dccedb9d515</id>
    <practiceSet>39d265f15f41481891312961d73f01bf</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>How many really suffer as a result of labor market {blank}? This is one of the most critical yet {blank} social policy questions. In many ways, our social statistics {blank} the degree of hardship. Unemployment does not have the same dire consequences today as it did in the 1930’s when most of the unemployed were primary {blank} , when income and earnings were usually much closer to the margin of {blank} , and when there were no {blank} social programs for those failing in the labor market.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>contentious </o1>
          <o2>addicted</o2>
          <o3>countervailing</o3>
          <o4>exaggerate</o4>
          <o5>reducing</o5>
          <o6>breadwinners</o6>
          <o7>problems</o7>
          <o8>disagreed</o8>
          <o9>subsistence</o9>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>6|0|3|5|8|2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>ad38eba42aec496a9eea4e1ef108f3c0</id>
    <practiceSet>39d265f15f41481891312961d73f01bf</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>The game of chess is an example of a {blank} information system: the pieces sit {blank} on the board until the players move them according to {blank} rules.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>known</o1>
          <o2>passive</o2>
          <o3>called</o3>
          <o4>dynamic</o4>
          <o5>inertly</o5>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>1|4|0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>5907e602fba84259857b347d080c52a3</id>
    <practiceSet>39d265f15f41481891312961d73f01bf</practiceSet>
    <type>MULTI_CHOICE_MULTIPLE_ANSWER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct response. More than one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:02:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>In Asia and much of the third World, trees are still destroyed in the old-fashioned way: they are cut down for fuel and cropland. In Europe, there is a new and potentially more deadly culprit. The German call it 'Waldsterben', the dying forest syndrome. But the disease is far more than a German phenomenon. Since it was first observed by German scientists in the autumn of 1980, the mysterious malady has raced across Europe, blighting woods in countries as far apart as Sweden and Italy. Explanations for the epidemic range from a cyclic change in the environment to a baffling form of tree cancer. But the most convincing evidence points to air pollution. Indeed, saving the rapidly deteriorating forests of Europe will probably require a two-pronged strategy: an offensive campaign that includes the breeding of pollution-immune trees and a defensive scheme that calls for reductions in toxic emissions. But both will require more money than is currently being spent on such measures, as well as total commitment to protecting the environment.</description>
      <title>Why do you think the narrator calls the reasons for cutting the trees in the third world countries, 'old fashioned'?</title>
      <options>
        <o0>As the countries he is referring to are known as the third world, or under-developed countries.</o0>
        <o1>Since science has made available modern and much developed methods to satisfy these requirements.</o1>
        <o2>As the reasons for which the trees are cut are no longer valid in today's scenario.</o2>
        <o3>It is a biased comment on the part of the narrator as it seems he belongs to a highly developed nation or society.</o3>
        <o4>As there are modern solutions for the requirement of fuel and cropland available to us now.</o4>
      </options>
      <picture></picture>
      <answer>1|4</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>53ada3d639184aeb84de312d6dec948a</id>
    <practiceSet>39d265f15f41481891312961d73f01bf</practiceSet>
    <type>MULTI_CHOICE_MULTIPLE_ANSWER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct response. More than one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:02:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>An enlightened aspect of the policy is its recognition that actual change in the status of women cannot be brought about by the mere enactment of socially progressive legislation. Accordingly, it focuses on reorienting development programs and sensitizing administrations to address specific situations as, for instance, the growing number of households headed by women, which is a consequence of rural-urban migration. The proposal to create an equal-opportunity police force and give women greater control of police stations is an acknowledgement of the biases and callousness displayed by the generally all male law enforcement authorities in cases of dowry and domestic violence. While the mere enunciation of such a policy has the salutary effect of sensitizing the administration as a whole, it does not make the task of its implementation any easier. This is because the changes it envisages in the political and economic status of women strike at the root of power structures in society and the basis of man-woman relationships. There is also the danger that reservation for women in public life, while necessary for their greater visibility, could lapse into tokenism or become a tool in the hands of vote seeking politicians. Much will depend on the dissemination of the policy and the ability of elected representatives and government agencies to reorder their priorities.</description>
      <title>What has been termed as a resulting effect of the migration between rural and urban areas?</title>
      <options>
        <o0>The rising number of households that are being led by women.</o0>
        <o1>The rising amount of population in cities.</o1>
        <o2>The power struggle in the urban areas getting worse.</o2>
        <o3>Women taking control of the decisions taken in their houses as they are more empowered.</o3>
        <o4>Narrowing down of the difference between the two major types of population.</o4>
      </options>
      <picture></picture>
      <answer>0|3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>8e208824379842a5a7680bbe9cef51cb</id>
    <practiceSet>39d265f15f41481891312961d73f01bf</practiceSet>
    <type>REORDER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:02:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Arrange the options.</description>
      <title></title>
      <options>
        <o0>Later on, people began to write on pieces of leather, which were rolled into scrolls.</o0>
        <o1>In the earliest times, people carved or painted messages on rocks.</o1>
        <o2>In the Middle Ages, heavy paper called parchment was used for writing and books were laboriously copied by hand.</o2>
        <o3>With the invention of the printing press in the middle of the fifteenth century, the modern printing industry was born.</o3>
        <o4>Some form of written communication has been used throughout the centuries.</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>4|1|0|3|2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>7d5bfc4e0b7a4eaeaed91bf6c885ffbe</id>
    <practiceSet>39d265f15f41481891312961d73f01bf</practiceSet>
    <type>REORDER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:02:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Arrange the options.</description>
      <title></title>
      <options>
        <o0>Almost a century ago, when the father of the modern automobile industry, Henry Ford, sold the first Model  A car, he decided that only the best would do for his customers.</o0>
        <o1>Today, it is committed to delivering the finest quality with over six million vehicles a year in over 200 countries across the world.</o1>
        <o2>And for over ninety years, this philosophy has endured in the Ford Motor Company.</o2>
        <o3>A vehicle is ready for the customer only if it passes the Ford ‘Zero Defect Programme’.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>0|2|3|1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>9bae0250bfc248b39233d3a0f6721578</id>
    <practiceSet>39d265f15f41481891312961d73f01bf</practiceSet>
    <type>REORDER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:02:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Arrange the options.</description>
      <title></title>
      <options>
        <o0>Good advertising can make people buy your product even if it sucks.</o0>
        <o1>A dollar spent on brainwashing is more cost-effective than a dollar spent on product improvement.</o1>
        <o2>That’s important because it takes pressure off you to make good products.</o2>
        <o3>Obviously, there’s a minimum quality that every product has to achieve: it should be able to withstand the shipping process without becoming unrecognizable.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>0|2|1|3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>f398c375206a4a059dbb788abff69e57</id>
    <practiceSet>39d265f15f41481891312961d73f01bf</practiceSet>
    <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:59</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Have you ever heard someone use the phrase “once in a blue moon?” People use this expression to describe something that they do not do very often. For example, someone might say that he tries to avoid eating sweets because they are unhealthy, but will eat chocolate “once in a blue moon.” Or someone who does not usually like to go to the beach might say “I visit the shore once in a blue moon.” While many people use this phrase, not everyone knows the meaning behind it. The first thing to know is that the moon itself is never actually blue. This is just an expression. The phrase “blue moon” actually has to do with the shape of the moon, not the color. As the moon travels around the earth, it appears to change shape. We associate certain names with certain shapes of the moon. For example, when we can see a small part of the moon, it is called a crescent moon. A crescent is a shape that looks like the tip of a fingernail. When we cannot see the moon at all, it is called a new moon. When we can see the entire moon, it is called a full moon. Usually, there is only one full moon every month. Sometimes, however, there will be two full moons in one month. When this happens, the second full moon is called a “blue moon.” Over the next 20 years, there will only be 15 blue moons. As you can see, a blue moon is a very rare event. This fact has led people to use the expression “once in a blue moon” to describe other very rare events in their lives. </description>
      <title>Which of the following would be a good example of someone doing something “once in a blue moon”? </title>
      <options>
        <o0>Mary likes to go to the mountains every weekend. Mary goes to the mountains once in a blue moon.</o0>
        <o1>Tom rarely remembers to take out the trash. Tom takes out the trash once in a blue moon.</o1>
        <o2>Cindy hates to wash the dishes. Nevertheless, she does it every day. Cindy washes the dishes once in a blue moon.</o2>
        <o3>Ming sometimes forgets to do his homework. Ming forgets to do his homework once in a blue moon.</o3>
      </options>
      <picture></picture>
      <answer>1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>7391fe145aa5452c98530ca4f7feff82</id>
    <practiceSet>39d265f15f41481891312961d73f01bf</practiceSet>
    <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:59</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>An ecosystem is a group of animals and plants living in a specific region and interacting with one another and with their physical environment. Ecosystems include physical and chemical components, such as soils, water, and nutrients that support the organisms living there. These organisms may range from large animals to microscopic bacteria. Ecosystems also can be thought of as the interactions among all organisms in a given habitat; for instance, one species may serve as food for another. People are part of the ecosystems where they live and work. Human activities can harm or destroy local ecosystems unless actions such as land development for housing or businesses are carefully planned to conserve and sustain the ecology of the area. An important part of ecosystem management involves finding ways to protect and enhance economic and social well-being while protecting local ecosystems.</description>
      <title>Which of the following best sums up activities within an ecosystem?</title>
      <options>
        <o0>predator-prey relationships</o0>
        <o1>interactions among all members </o1>
        <o2>human-animal interactions </o2>
        <o3>human relationship with the environment</o3>
      </options>
      <picture></picture>
      <answer>1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>43c6e276765a4e85bd5972c9d29f8eae</id>
    <practiceSet>39d265f15f41481891312961d73f01bf</practiceSet>
    <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:59</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Why have so many patients turned to alternative therapies? Many are frustrated by the time constraints of managed care and alienated by conventional medicine’s focus on technology. Others feel that a holistic approach to healthcare better reflects their beliefs and values. Others seek therapies that relieve symptoms associated with chronic disease; symptoms that mainstream medicine cannot treat. Some alternative therapies have even crossed the line into mainstream medicine, as scientific investigation has confirmed their safety and efficacy. For example, physicians may currently prescribe acupuncture for pain management or to control the nausea associated with chemotherapy. Additionally, many U.S. medical schools teach courses in alternative therapies, and many health insurance companies offer some alternative medicine benefits.</description>
      <title>According to the passage, which practice would not be defined as alternative medicine?</title>
      <options>
        <o0>pain management</o0>
        <o1>acupuncture </o1>
        <o2>taking herbal garlic supplements</o2>
        <o3>massage therapy</o3>
      </options>
      <picture></picture>
      <answer>0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>4211ba6dd089438ca83b94cb33663df3</id>
    <practiceSet>39d265f15f41481891312961d73f01bf</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Banks have been {blank} conduct loan melas to disburse loans {blank} quality of loaning process and banks have been forced to {blank} loans so that vote banks of ruling party is {blank} and become greater. Banks have been used to {blank} all non-productive services like tax collection or salary payment or disbursing subsidy  oriented loans under various government sponsored schemes.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>Coerced</o1>
          <o2>catered</o2>
          <o3>forced to</o3>
          <o4>induced</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>forfeiting</o1>
          <o2>yielding</o2>
          <o3>sacrificing</o3>
          <o4>denouncing</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>marking off</o1>
          <o2>writing off</o2>
          <o3>diminishing</o3>
          <o4>trimming</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>protected</o1>
          <o2>secured</o2>
          <o3>safe</o3>
          <o4>thriving shelter</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>transmit</o1>
          <o2>carry out</o2>
          <o3>transact</o3>
          <o4>conduct</o4>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>2|2|1|2|1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>bb1dcf10fcbe4c1a92a7d84b44f11364</id>
    <practiceSet>39d265f15f41481891312961d73f01bf</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Stress-induced amnesia is a rare and {blank} phenomenon; it strikes the patient apparently without warning and the memory loss can be as {blank} as that induced by {blank} trauma.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>devastating</o1>
          <o2>venial</o2>
          <o3>pervasive</o3>
          <o4>destructed</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>generic</o1>
          <o2>limited</o2>
          <o3>complete</o3>
          <o4>accomplishing</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>unexpected </o1>
          <o2>mental</o2>
          <o3>physical</o3>
          <o4>emotional</o4>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>0|2|2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>c5562f9889e4429cbb141c5643f2758a</id>
    <practiceSet>39d265f15f41481891312961d73f01bf</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Major philosophical {blank} about morality, identity and {blank} , for example, can often be {blank} by thought experiments: short and simple expositions that pose an abstract and complex problem in a concrete manner with all the {blank} factors removed.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>certitudes</o1>
          <o2>laws</o2>
          <o3>dilemmas</o3>
          <o4>dogmas</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>rationality</o1>
          <o2>formality</o2>
          <o3>equality</o3>
          <o4>illogical</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>mimicked</o1>
          <o2>illuminated</o2>
          <o3>diffusing</o3>
          <o4>evoked</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>integral</o1>
          <o2>inherent</o2>
          <o3>pivotal</o3>
          <o4>extraneous</o4>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>2|0|1|3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>756a9d25e38541218eef39da7e00c5ad</id>
    <practiceSet>39d265f15f41481891312961d73f01bf</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>{blank}high above the land-living dinosaurs were the pterosaurs, which means “winged reptiles”. The pterosaurs were relatives of dinosaurs, but they were not dinosaurs themselves. All had slim, hollow bones and wings made of skin that stretched between long finger-bones and the legs. Pterosaurs first {blank} at the same time as the dinosaurs and lived alongside them until they too died out at the end of the Cretaceous Period. They were the supreme rulers of Earth’s prehistoric skies, {blank} their wings over land and sea. Pterodactylus was an agile flyer which {blank} fed on insects. Unlike other pterosaurs that had long tails, the tail of Pterodactylus was little more than a short, stubby point. Just 30 cm (12 in) long, it had a lightly built skeleton and thin, hollow bones. Perhaps these weight-saving features were designed to give Pterodactylus greater flight control, helping it to fly fast and giving it the ability to swoop and turn with {blank}.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>Soaring</o1>
          <o2>Moving</o2>
          <o3>Reaching</o3>
          <o4>Targeting</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>existed</o1>
          <o2>seen</o2>
          <o3>noticed</o3>
          <o4>appeared</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>moving</o1>
          <o2>expanding</o2>
          <o3>flapping</o3>
          <o4>opening</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>probably</o1>
          <o2>mostly</o2>
          <o3>alternatively</o3>
          <o4>literally</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>ease</o1>
          <o2>efforts</o2>
          <o3>smoothly</o3>
          <o4>softly</o4>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>0|3|2|0|0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
    <question>
    <id>756a9d25e38541218eef39da7e00c5an</id>
    <practiceSet>39d265f15f41481891312961d73f01bf</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>A team of computer scientists and paleontologists from Sandia National Laboratories and the New Mexico Museum of Natural History and Science Museum {blank} the sound that a Parasaurolophus dinosaur made when it lived during the late Cretaceous period. The team accomplished this feat by using a rare 4.5 foot long fossil of the dinosaur's skull, computed tomography (CT) scans, and {blank} supercomputers. The Parasaurolophus had a bony tubular crest that extended back from the top of its head. Many scientists believed the crest, containing a labyrinth of air cavities and shaped like a trombone, might have been used to produce {blank} sounds. Once a 3-D model of the crest was created, the computer was able to simulate blowing air through it to {blank} the tones it was capable of making. As expected, the dinosaur apparently emitted a {blank} low-frequency rumbling sound that could change in pitch.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>created</o1>
          <o2>has developed</o2>
          <o3>has recreated</o3>
          <o4>discovered</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>huge</o1>
          <o2>powerful</o2>
          <o3>large</o3>
          <o4>complicated</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>unique</o1>
          <o2>distinctive</o2>
          <o3>familiar</o3>
          <o4>similar</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>apply</o1>
          <o2>create</o2>
          <o3>amplify</o3>
          <o4>play</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>resonating</o1>
          <o2>resonate</o2>
          <o3>tremble</o3>
          <o4>quiet</o4>
        </blank> 		
      </blanks>
      <answer>2|1|1|2|0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>4ed02b13326443d7a382f1edcbb27829</id>
    <practiceSet>dffc4ce9224b4f05b2d81e9a523be1d7</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>When precipitation falls in hot deserts, it quickly {blank} back into the atmosphere. The air over Antarctica is too cold to hold water vapor, so there is very little evaporation. Due to this low rate of evaporation, most of the snow that falls to the ground remains there permanently, {blank} building up into thick ice sheets. Any snow that does not freeze into ice sheets becomes caught up in the {blank} winds that constantly blow over Antarctica. These snow-filled winds can make it look as if it is snowing. Even though snowfall is very rare there, {blank} are actually very common on Antarctica.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>eventually</o1>
          <o2>swelter </o2>
          <o3>evaporates</o3>
          <o4>immediately</o4>
          <o5>blizzards</o5>
          <o6>strong</o6>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>2|0|5|4</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>a79df4a6e3764372afea6a6d388c4d3a</id>
    <practiceSet>dffc4ce9224b4f05b2d81e9a523be1d7</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Fleas have very long rear legs with {blank} thigh muscles and multiple joints. When they get ready to jump, they fold their long legs up and {blank} like a runner on a starting block. Several of their joints contain a protein called resilin, which helps {blank} fleas into the air as they jump, similar to the way a rubber band provides {blank} to a slingshot. Outward facing claws on the bottom of their legs {blank} anything they touch when they land.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>crouch </o1>
          <o2>itsy </o2>
          <o3>grip</o3>
          <o4>huge</o4>
          <o5>hurled </o5>
          <o6>momentum</o6>
          <o7>catapult</o7>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>3|0|6|5|2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>3fc5bcea2639407b892db97796c3d00c</id>
    <practiceSet>dffc4ce9224b4f05b2d81e9a523be1d7</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>The painter Roy Lichtenstein helped to define pop art—the movement that {blank} commonplace objects and commercial-art {blank} into paintings—by paraphrasing the style of comic books in his work. His {blank} of a popular genre with the forms and intentions of fine art generated a complex result: while poking fun at the {blank} of the art world, Lichtenstein’s work also managed to convey a seriousness of theme that enabled it to {blank} mere parody.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>techniques </o1>
          <o2>retreated </o2>
          <o3>incorporated</o3>
          <o4>pretensions</o4>
          <o5>hooked up</o5>
          <o6>transcend </o6>
          <o7>merger</o7>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>2|0|6|3|5</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>7c69e6afeb684b4e8048f19b965166ff</id>
    <practiceSet>dffc4ce9224b4f05b2d81e9a523be1d7</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>According to scientific {blank} , furthermore, sea-level rise resulting from global warming will reach 3 feet (1 meter) within the next century. Such a rise could {blank} vast coastal areas, with potentially {blank} consequences.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>submerge</o1>
          <o2>irreversible</o2>
          <o3>permanent</o3>
          <o4>predicted</o4>
          <o5>estimates</o5>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>4|0|1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>a9f258a84d8646d2b49473d8dbbb4c15</id>
    <practiceSet>dffc4ce9224b4f05b2d81e9a523be1d7</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Monet’s paintings of water lilies were extremely {blank} to 20th -century modern artists. In these paintings, Monet used the landscape merely as a starting point, creating abstract fields of vibrant color. These paintings relied on broad, thick brushstrokes. The {blank} of these brushstrokes gave the canvases a {blank} quality that contrasted sharply with the smooth canvases produced by more traditional artists. Though he struggled financially throughout his life, when Monet died in 1926, he was one of the most {blank} and influential painters in the world.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>tactile</o1>
          <o2>texture</o2>
          <o3>parting</o3>
          <o4>influential</o4>
          <o5>famous</o5>
          <o6>dominating</o6>
          <o7>known</o7>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>3|1|0|4</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>7aca10b097b543b5a4a04d5eb2ca44d7</id>
    <practiceSet>dffc4ce9224b4f05b2d81e9a523be1d7</practiceSet>
    <type>MULTI_CHOICE_MULTIPLE_ANSWER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct response. More than one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:02:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Now the question arises what is the secret of the longevity and imperishability of Indian culture? Why is it that such great empires and nations as Babylon, Assyria, Greece, Rome and Persia could not last more than the foot prints of a camel on the shifting sands of the deserts while India which faced the same ups and downs, the same mighty and cruel hand of time, is still alive and with the same halo of glory and splendor? The answer is given by Prof. J. B. Pratt of America. According to him Hindu religion is 'self-perpetuating and self-renewing!' Unlike other religions 'not death, but development' has been the fate of Hinduism. Not only Hindu religion but the whole culture of the Hindus has been growing, changing, and developing in accordance with the needs of times and circumstances without losing its essentially imperishable spirit. The culture of the Vedic ages, of the ages of the Upanishads, the various philosophical systems, the Mahabharata, the Smritis, the Puranas, various scholarly commentators, the medieval saints and the age of modern reformers is the same in spirit and yet very different in form. Its basic principles are so broad-based that they can be adapted to almost any environment of development.</description>
      <title>What is implied by the use of the metaphor of camel's footprints?</title>
      <options>
        <o0>A reference to the nature of desert sand.</o0>
        <o1>The short life span of the empires and nations.</o1>
        <o2>The replacement of one empire with the rise of another.</o2>
        <o3>The fast-fading traces of the empires from the world map.</o3>
        <o4>The reference to a camel's gait in the desert.</o4>
      </options>
      <picture></picture>
      <answer>1|3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>f26e17a3a9b74ab6bdac46e24dea8710</id>
    <practiceSet>dffc4ce9224b4f05b2d81e9a523be1d7</practiceSet>
    <type>MULTI_CHOICE_MULTIPLE_ANSWER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct response. More than one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:02:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>The crisis begins in the womb with unplanned parenthood. Women with unplanned pregnancies are less likely to seek prenatal care. In the U.S. 80% of teenage pregnancies and 56% of all pregnancies are unplanned. The problems continue after birth where unplanned pregnancies and unstable partnerships often go hand in hand. Since 1950, the number of single parent families has nearly tripled. More than 25 percent of all births today are to unmarried mothers. As the number of single parent families grows and more women enter the work force, infants and toddlers are increasingly in the care of people other than their parents. Most disturbingly, recent statistics show that American parents are increasingly neglecting or abusing their children. In only four years from 1987-1991 the number of children in foster care increased by over 50 percent. Babies under the age of one are the fastest growing category of children entering foster care. The crisis affects children under the age of three most severely, the report says. Yet, it is this period-from infancy through preschool years-that sets the stage for a child's future.</description>
      <title>What can be the possible reasons for the increasing neglect and abuse of children?</title>
      <options>
        <o0>The immaturity and overburdening of parents.</o0>
        <o1>The babies being left in foster care where a stranger looks after them.</o1>
        <o2>The children being ill mannered and not respecting their parents.</o2>
        <o3>The parents being busy with meeting the financial aspects of the family and not having enough time for the children.</o3>
        <o4>The parents being  prepared emotionally and physically for this responsibility.</o4>
      </options>
      <picture></picture>
      <answer>0|1|3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>014b693f166e48eeb6bda262a9ee057e</id>
    <practiceSet>dffc4ce9224b4f05b2d81e9a523be1d7</practiceSet>
    <type>REORDER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:02:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Arrange the options.</description>
      <title></title>
      <options>
        <o0>With the passage of  time, vices become more apparent and virtues become objects of  jealousy and envy, thereby causing contempt and hatred in the hearts of each  other.</o0>
        <o1>They become familiar with not only strengths but also weaknesses of each other's characters.</o1>
        <o2>Generally people think that familiarity should breed love, mutual understanding and tolerance.</o2>
        <o3>They expect that coming together of two persons should bring them closer and forge the bond of kinship between them. </o3>
        <o4>But when two persons come closer, they come to know not only strengths but also weaknesses of each other's character. </o4>
      </options>
      <answer>2|3|4|1|0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>dc60611128cc4c319743aa721d6e4714</id>
    <practiceSet>dffc4ce9224b4f05b2d81e9a523be1d7</practiceSet>
    <type>REORDER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:02:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Arrange the options.</description>
      <title></title>
      <options>
        <o0>He cannot achieve wealth and fortune unless he works hard and unless he has a powerful will.</o0>
        <o1>It follows from it that he is the builder of his own fortune.</o1>
        <o2>A person must be persevering and must exert himself if he wants to shape out his destiny.</o2>
        <o3>He can also bring misery and sufferings upon himself if he has not the wish to labour.</o3>
        <o4>He can make his fortune if he wishes to do so by being industrious and persevering.</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>2|0|1|4|3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>2057a9e0ee91444ab497e70c2c78227b</id>
    <practiceSet>dffc4ce9224b4f05b2d81e9a523be1d7</practiceSet>
    <type>REORDER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:02:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Arrange the options.</description>
      <title></title>
      <options>
        <o0>The belief in evil spirits, though still common, is probably less wide spread than it was.</o0>
        <o1>They live in terror of germs and practice  elaborate antiseptic rites in order to counteract their influence.</o1>
        <o2>Evil spirits being out of fashion, it must therefore find expression in other beliefs. The forms change but the substance remains.</o2>
        <o3>With many people especially women, bacilli have taken the place of spirits and microbes for them are personification of evil.</o3>
        <o4>But the human tendency to oversize its sense of value is still as strong as ever.</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>0|4|1|3|2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>a8ab419e2f1749d881a2abb93f7b0769</id>
    <practiceSet>dffc4ce9224b4f05b2d81e9a523be1d7</practiceSet>
    <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:59</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Kwanzaa is a holiday celebrated by many African Americans from December 26 to January 1. It pays tribute to the rich cultural roots of Americans of African ancestry, and celebrates family, community, and culture. Kwanzaa means the first or the first fruits of the harvest and is based on the ancient African first-fruit harvest celebrations. The modern holiday of Kwanzaa was founded in 1966 by Dr. Maulana Karenga, a professor at the California State University in Long Beach, California. The seven-day celebration encourages people to think about their African roots as well as their life in present-day America. The seven fundamental principles on which Kwanzaa is based are referred to as the Nguzo Saba. These rules consist of unity, self-determination, collective work and responsibility, cooperative economics, purpose, creativity, and faith. Participants celebrate by performing rituals such as lighting the kinara. The kinara is symbolic of the continental Africans. Each of its seven candles represents a distinct principle beginning with unity, the black center candle. Talking with family, drumming, singing, and dancing are all part of the celebration activities.</description>
      <title>According to the passage, the holiday of Kwanzaa was created in order to</title>
      <options>
        <o0>celebrate African Americans’ harvesting skills. </o0>
        <o1>honor Dr. Maulana Karenga.</o1>
        <o2>encourage African Americans to think about their roots. </o2>
        <o3>light the individual candles of the kinara.</o3>
      </options>
      <picture></picture>
      <answer>2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>1a94f25f0030451dbbc9a3d001de7375</id>
    <practiceSet>dffc4ce9224b4f05b2d81e9a523be1d7</practiceSet>
    <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:59</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>In 1519, Hernando Cortez led his army of Spanish Conquistadors into Mexico. Equipped with horses, shining armor, and the most advanced weapons of the sixteenth century, he fought his way from the flat coastal area into the mountainous highlands. Cortez was looking for gold, and he was sure that Indian groups in Mexico had mined large amounts of the precious metal. First, he conquered the groups and then seized their precious gold. His methods were very organized. Initially, Cortez defeated the Tlascalans, and then formed an alliance with them to defeat the Aztecs, their enemies. Because of an Aztec prophecy about the return of Quetzacoatl, a legendary god-king who was light skinned and bearded, Cortez was believed to be a god and was received by the Aztecs with honor. Later, this warm welcome turned to mistrust and hatred when the Spaniards mistreated the Aztec people. Eventually, the Aztec capital, Tenochtitlan, fell to the Spaniards. Cortez had Tenochtitlan razed and built Mexico City on its ruins.</description>
      <title>According to the passage, what was Cortez’s major goal in his exploits?</title>
      <options>
        <o0>to befriend the Aztecs</o0>
        <o1>to get married </o1>
        <o2>to return to Spain </o2>
        <o3>to gain wealth and power.</o3>
      </options>
      <picture></picture>
      <answer>3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>14832506f9eb413aa29e2973cdc8d86d</id>
    <practiceSet>dffc4ce9224b4f05b2d81e9a523be1d7</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Speaking in public is a form of an art as its other forms like singing, writing or acting are. The speaker is required to be careful or rather more {blank} because one of its most important requirement is to appear {blank} to the audience. In ancient times, the great speakers used to prepare their  speeches before a {blank}  of their known persons and  noticed  their own {blank} and  {blank} of the spectators. Their audience  {blank} their trusted friends, critics and mentors.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>careful</o1>
          <o2>cautious</o2>
          <o3>vigilant</o3>
          <o4>thoughtful</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>impulsive</o1>
          <o2>spontaneous </o2>
          <o3>discreet</o3>
          <o4>subtle</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>assembly</o1>
          <o2>crowd</o2>
          <o3>horde </o3>
          <o4>gathering </o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>defects </o1>
          <o2>shortcomings </o2>
          <o3>faults</o3>
          <o4>imperfections </o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>reply</o1>
          <o2>response</o2>
          <o3>reaction</o3>
          <o4>answer</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>included</o1>
          <o2>involved</o2>
          <o3>contained</o3>
          <o4>comprised</o4>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>0|1|3|1|2|0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>747d77397b1f4d14958ef1f90721bcab</id>
    <practiceSet>dffc4ce9224b4f05b2d81e9a523be1d7</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>E-readers are {blank} to printed books because they save space. The average e-reader can store thousands of digital books, providing a {blank} library at your fingertips. What is more, being the size and weight of a thin hardback, the e-reader itself is relatively {blank}. It is easy to hold and can fit in a pocketbook or briefcase easily. This makes handling {blank} behemoths such as War and Peace, Anna Karenina, and Les Misérables a breeze. {blank} the only drawback to the space-saving aspect of an e-reader is that it requires you to find new things to put on your shelves.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>qualified</o1>
          <o2>superior </o2>
          <o3>subordinate</o3>
          <o4>conceited</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>questionable</o1>
          <o2>fact</o2>
          <o3>credit</o3>
          <o4>veritable</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>young </o1>
          <o2>petite</o2>
          <o3>smaller</o3>
          <o4>huge</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>oppressive </o1>
          <o2>ponderous</o2>
          <o3>substantial</o3>
          <o4>lumbering</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>Indeed </o1>
          <o2>Surmise</o2>
          <o3>Perhaps</o3>
          <o4>Definitely </o4>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>1|3|1|1|2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>260f4a9d8b5c43fe9347fc6f88da8970</id>
    <practiceSet>dffc4ce9224b4f05b2d81e9a523be1d7</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>In its early years, the book set its sights on satisfying man's innate {blank} about the natural world around him.  Its two principal fact finders, twins Norris and Ross McWhirter,  {blank} the globe to collect {blank} facts. It was their task to find and document aspects of life that can be sensed or observed, things that can be quantified or measured. But not just any things. They were only interested in {blank}: the biggest and the best. It was during this period that some of the hallmark Guinness Records were   {blank}, answering such questions as "What is the brightest star?" and "What is the biggest spider?"</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>interested</o1>
          <o2>unusually</o2>
          <o3>curiosity</o3>
          <o4>sensible</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>scoured</o1>
          <o2>adulterated</o2>
          <o3>overlooked</o3>
          <o4>pumice</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>theoretic</o1>
          <o2>speculated</o2>
          <o3>unproved</o3>
          <o4>empirical</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>exceptional</o1>
          <o2>terribly</o2>
          <o3>superlatives</o3>
          <o4>vast</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>documented</o1>
          <o2>confirm</o2>
          <o3>certify</o3>
          <o4>cross check</o4>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>2|0|3|2|0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>992a018951534110957dbf879675314b</id>
    <practiceSet>dffc4ce9224b4f05b2d81e9a523be1d7</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Today, the world has become a much smaller place, thanks to the adventures and miracles of science, foreign nations have become our {blank} neighbors. {blank} of population is bringing about an {blank} of thought. We are slowly {blank} that the world is a single cooperative group.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>next door</o1>
          <o2>favorite</o2>
          <o3>great</o3>
          <o4>amazed</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>Socialized</o1>
          <o2>Mingling</o2>
          <o3>Associate</o3>
          <o4>Blend </o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>amalgamation</o1>
          <o2>exchanged</o2>
          <o3>ambiguity</o3>
          <o4>interchange</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>realizing</o1>
          <o2>achieving</o2>
          <o3>performing</o3>
          <o4>arriving</o4>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>0|1|3|0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>3f394d37bd504ddf8270a44b02c35559</id>
    <practiceSet>dffc4ce9224b4f05b2d81e9a523be1d7</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Scientists {blank} the presence of water on Psyche, the largest metallic asteroid in our solar system and the target of a proposed NASA mission. Previous observations of Psyche had shown no {blank} of water-rich minerals on its surface. However, new observations from the NASA Infrared Telescope Facility in Hawaii show evidence of water or hydroxyl on its surface. While the source of these molecules on Psyche remains a mystery, scientists propose a few possible {blank} for its formation. Water-rich minerals detected on Psyche may have been {blank} by carbonaceous asteroids that impacted Psyche in the distant past, said researchers including Joshua Emery, from University of Tennessee in the US. </description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>will detect</o1>
          <o2>detected</o2>
          <o3>are detecting</o3>
          <o4>have detected</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>evidence</o1>
          <o2>alternative</o2>
          <o3>prescribed way</o3>
          <o4>substitute </o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>sources</o1>
          <o2>sloths</o2>
          <o3>mechanisms</o3>
          <o4>conditions</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>delivered</o1>
          <o2>invented</o2>
          <o3>searched</o3>
          <o4>proposed</o4>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>3|0|2|0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>ef94d45a12c7422ea7c312788c40ba87</id>
    <practiceSet>e8c3b7b66171443e874f972f432c4103</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Take a walk around some of the poorest neighborhoods in Philadelphia, neighborhoods full of broken windows and {blank} front steps, and you will find beautiful works of art on the sides and fronts of buildings. Of course the murals are not just in poor neighborhoods, but more {blank} ones as well. Special buses take tourists to different parts of the city to see the various murals, which range from huge {blank} of historical heroes, to cityscapes, to scenes {blank} the diverse {blank} groups that call Philadelphia home.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>ethnic</o1>
          <o2>affluent </o2>
          <o3>clutter </o3>
          <o4>depicting</o4>
          <o5>described</o5>
          <o6>portraits </o6>
          <o7>littered </o7>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>6|1|5|3|0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>f0dcf585fae9411baa63be4367f596d3</id>
    <practiceSet>e8c3b7b66171443e874f972f432c4103</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Official reports are oddly {blank} , but what they do not explain, gossip does. {blank} had it that there was tension between the men because Byrnes {blank} the other two of being involved with his young wife. There is little {blank} that he, like the other operators, knew exactly what would happen when he {blank} the control rod.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>determined</o1>
          <o2>certainty</o2>
          <o3>yanked</o3>
          <o4>ambiguous</o4>
          <o5>rumors</o5>
          <o6>suspected</o6>
          <o7>doubt</o7>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>3|4|5|6|2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>f1f95c8007664942a1640fcf0e0b626b</id>
    <practiceSet>e8c3b7b66171443e874f972f432c4103</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>According to Greek mythology, Atlas was a Titan of {blank} strength. After being defeated by the god Zeus, Atlas was forced to carry the earth and the sky for an {blank}. In {blank} of Atlas, he is shown as a {blank} figure carrying the globe on his shoulders. Because of his association with the globe, maps began to be decorated with this image of Atlas.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>hugely</o1>
          <o2>stooped </o2>
          <o3>immortal</o3>
          <o4>enormous </o4>
          <o5>curve</o5>
          <o6>eternity</o6>
          <o7>depictions</o7>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>3|5|6|1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>ebd84e7408d349cf93b03bba8d76a585</id>
    <practiceSet>e8c3b7b66171443e874f972f432c4103</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Although most websites or network systems allow users to {blank} or change lost passwords by providing email addresses or answering a {blank} , this process can waste time and cause further {blank}. What is more, recovering a forgotten password is only a temporary solution; it does not address the larger problem of password {blank}.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>prompt</o1>
          <o2>exhausted</o2>
          <o3>recover</o3>
          <o4>frustration</o4>
          <o5>forfeit</o5>
          <o6>fatigue</o6>
          <o7>sluggish</o7>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>2|0|3|5</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>811c57a9936140eda01df27b47861877</id>
    <practiceSet>e8c3b7b66171443e874f972f432c4103</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>English Ivy {blank} its poor reputation as a {blank} by its unparalleled ability to provide shade. By seamlessly covering the exterior of a building, it works as a natural {blank} , blocking the sun and decreasing air conditioning {blank}. </description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>nuisance</o1>
          <o2>influences</o2>
          <o3>famous </o3>
          <o4>amounts</o4>
          <o5>costs</o5>
          <o6>betrays</o6>
          <o7>insulator</o7>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>5|0|6|4</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>ab0c2f1303fb489faf8183ab909962a8</id>
    <practiceSet>e8c3b7b66171443e874f972f432c4103</practiceSet>
    <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:02:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Charles Darwin was born in 1809 in Shrewsbury, England. He was a biologist whose famous theory of evolution is important to philosophy for the effect it has had on ideas relating to the nature of men. After many years of careful study, Darwin attempted to show that higher species came into existence as a result of the gradual transformation of lower species, and that the process of transformation could be explained through the selective effect of the natural environment upon organisms. He concluded that the principles of natural selection and survival of the fittest govern all life. Darwin’s explanation of these principles is that because of the food supply problem, the young of any species compete for survival. Those young that survive to produce the next generation tend to embody favorable natural changes that are passed on by heredity. His major work that contained these theories is On the Origin of the Species, written in 1859. Many religious opponents condemned this work.</description>
      <title>Which of the following statements supports Darwin’s belief about the origin of all species? </title>
      <options>
        <o0>Man is descended from monkeys.</o0>
        <o1>All life forms developed slowly over time from lower life forms.</o1>
        <o2>Natural forces do not affect life on Earth. </o2>
        <o3>All species were individually created.</o3>
      </options>
      <picture></picture>
      <answer>1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>cc9a55bac5d04348a6cdb7c59807695e</id>
    <practiceSet>e8c3b7b66171443e874f972f432c4103</practiceSet>
    <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:02:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Firefighters are often asked to speak to school and community groups about the importance of fire safety, particularly fire prevention and detection. Because smoke detectors reduce the risk of dying in a fire by half, firefighters often provide audiences with information on how to install these protective devices in their homes. Specifically, they tell them these things: A smoke detector should be placed on each floor of a home. While sleeping, people are in particular danger of an emergent fire, and there must be a detector outside each sleeping area. A good site for a detector would be a hallway that runs between living spaces and bedrooms. Because of the dead-air space that might be missed by turbulent hot air bouncing around above a fire, smoke detectors should be installed either on the ceiling at least four inches from the nearest wall, or high on a wall at least four, but no further than twelve, inches from the ceiling. Detectors should not be mounted near windows, exterior doors, or other places where drafts might direct the smoke away from the unit. Nor should they be placed in kitchens and garages, where cooking and gas fumes are likely to cause false alarms.</description>
      <title>What is the main focus of this passage? </title>
      <options>
        <o0>how firefighters carry out their responsibilities.</o0>
        <o1>the proper installation of home smoke detectors </o1>
        <o2>the detection of dead-air space on walls and ceilings</o2>
        <o3>how smoke detectors prevent fires in homes</o3>
      </options>
      <picture></picture>
      <answer>1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>5170243a878841c99fed9c69fac9b5a4</id>
    <practiceSet>e8c3b7b66171443e874f972f432c4103</practiceSet>
    <type>REORDER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:02:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Arrange the options.</description>
      <title></title>
      <options>
        <o0>Good advertising can make people buy your product even if it sucks.</o0>
        <o1>A dollar spent on brainwashing is more cost-effective than a dollar spent on product improvement.</o1>
        <o2>That’s important because it takes pressure off you to make good products.</o2>
        <o3>Obviously, there’s a minimum quality that every product has to achieve: it should be able to withstand the shipping process without becoming unrecognizable.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>0|2|1|3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>731d51646a1747f18188dc3dc8024fbf</id>
    <practiceSet>e8c3b7b66171443e874f972f432c4103</practiceSet>
    <type>REORDER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:02:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Arrange the options.</description>
      <title></title>
      <options>
        <o0>Michael Hofman, a poet and translator, accepts this sorry fact without approval or complaint.</o0>
        <o1>But thanklessness and impossibility do not daunt him.</o1>
        <o2>He acknowledges too—in fact he returns to the point often—that best translators of poetry always fail at some level.</o2>
        <o3>Hofman feels passionately about his work, and this is clear from his writings.</o3>
        <o4>In terms of the gap between worth and rewards, translators come somewhere near nurses and street-cleaners.</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>4|0|2|1|3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>00261685a4d54f6fa80ab68b7d1d078e</id>
    <practiceSet>e8c3b7b66171443e874f972f432c4103</practiceSet>
    <type>MULTI_CHOICE_MULTIPLE_ANSWER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct response. More than one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:59</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description> Philadelphia is a city known for many things. It is where the Declaration of Independence was signed in 1776, and it was also the first capital of the United States. But one fact about Philadelphia is not so well-known: it is home to nearly 3,000 murals painted on the sides of homes and buildings around the city. In fact, it is said that Philadelphia has more murals than any other city in the world, with the exception of Rome. How did this come to be? More than 20 years ago, a New Jersey artist named Jane Golden started a program pairing troubled youth with artists to paint murals on a few buildings around the city. From this small project, something magical happened. The young people involved helped to create magnificent pieces of art, but there were other, perhaps more important benefits. The young people learned to collaborate and get along with many different kinds of people during the various steps required to paint and design a mural. They learned to be responsible, because they needed to follow a schedule to make sure the murals were completed. They also learned to take pride in their community. It is hard for any resident to see the spectacular designs and not feel proud to be a part of Philadelphia. Take a walk around some of the poorest neighborhoods in Philadelphia, neighborhoods full of broken windows and littered front steps, and you will find beautiful works of art on the sides and fronts of buildings. Of course the murals are not just in poor neighborhoods, but more affluent ones as well. Special buses take tourists to different parts of the city to see the various murals, which range from huge portraits of historical heroes, to cityscapes, to scenes depicting the diverse ethnic groups that call Philadelphia home. As a result of its success, the mural program created by Jane Golden has now become the nation’s largest public art program and a model for other cities throughout the country seeking to help troubled youth.</description>
      <title>According to the passage, the murals in Philadelphia</title>
      <options>
        <o0>drew tourists who want to see them.</o0>
        <o1>instilled responsibility and pride in the people who painted them. </o1>
        <o2>seek to help the people in trouble.</o2>
        <o3>are only  in poor neighborhoods.</o3>
        <o4>were solely designed by the youth who painted them.</o4>
      </options>
      <picture></picture>
      <answer>1|2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>f76b5245bf0e4b7ca0b2d53ec6cb517e</id>
    <practiceSet>e8c3b7b66171443e874f972f432c4103</practiceSet>
    <type>MULTI_CHOICE_MULTIPLE_ANSWER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct response. More than one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:59</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Since the late nineteenth century, fingerprint identification methods have been used by police agencies around the world to identify suspected criminals as well as the victims of crime. The basis of the traditional fingerprinting technique is simple. The skin on the palmar surface of the hands and feet forms ridges, so-called papillary ridges, in patterns that are unique to each individual and which do not change over time. Even identical twins (who share their DNA) do not have identical fingerprints. The best way to render latent fingerprints visible, so that they can be photographed, can be complex and may depend, for example, on the type of surfaces on which they have been left. It is generally necessary to use a ‘developer’, usually a powder or chemical reagent, to produce a high degree of visual contrast between the ridge patterns and the surface on which a fingerprint has been deposited. Developing agents depend on the presence of organic materials or inorganic salts for their effectiveness, although the water deposited may also take a key role. Fingerprints are typically formed from the aqueous-based secretions of the eccrine glands of the fingers and palms with additional material from sebaceous glands primarily from the forehead. This latter contamination results from the common human behaviors of touching the face and hair. The resulting latent fingerprints consist usually of a substantial proportion of water with small traces of amino acids and chlorides mixed with a fatty, sebaceous component that contains a number of fatty acids and triglycerides. Detection of a small proportion of reactive organic substances such as urea and amino acids is far from easy.</description>
      <title>According to the passage, which statements are TRUE?</title>
      <options>
        <o0>Usage of developer is minimum to produce a high degree of visual contrast.</o0>
        <o1>Effectiveness of organic materials is required for developing agents.</o1>
        <o2>Identical fingerprints can be found in twins.</o2>
        <o3>Papillary ridges do not change over the time.</o3>
        <o4>Touching of the face and hair can result into contamination.</o4>
      </options>
      <picture></picture>
      <answer>1|3|4</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>5429598a3a1847bebdfc07437b2b9020</id>
    <practiceSet>e8c3b7b66171443e874f972f432c4103</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>The seeming acceptance of active forms of euthanasia {blank}, but we face a bigger, more {blank} threat from passive forms of euthanasia. Every year, in hospitals and nursing homes around the country, there are growing numbers of documented deaths caused by caregivers with holding life {blank} care, including food and water, from {blank} patients who cannot speak for themselves.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>were alarming</o1>
          <o2>has been alarming</o2>
          <o3>is alarming</o3>
          <o4>alarmed</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>honest</o1>
          <o2>crooked </o2>
          <o3>straight</o3>
          <o4>insidious</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>sustaining</o1>
          <o2>buttress</o2>
          <o3>hindering </o3>
          <o4>ignoring </o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>strong </o1>
          <o2>sustained </o2>
          <o3>healthy</o3>
          <o4>vulnerable</o4>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>2|3|0|3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>a1f9ae2b47134ad7a05d4f14503ecaae</id>
    <practiceSet>e8c3b7b66171443e874f972f432c4103</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Josiah {blank} to New Orleans to do a public service. He had come up with the idea to {blank} a play for children affected by Hurricane Katrina, and he had secured a {blank} grant from the government to do so. But he hadn’t accounted for the major {blank} he would face: {blank} heat in August with no clean water to drink.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>had come</o1>
          <o2>came </o2>
          <o3>was coming</o3>
          <o4>have come</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>circumscribe</o1>
          <o2>compress</o2>
          <o3>develop</o3>
          <o4>continue</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>modest </o1>
          <o2>bold</o2>
          <o3>late</o3>
          <o4>assured</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>struggle </o1>
          <o2>interference</o2>
          <o3>limitations</o3>
          <o4>hindrance</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>blistering </o1>
          <o2>scald</o2>
          <o3>scorched</o3>
          <o4>intense</o4>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>0|2|0|3|0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>b149df6cfb1d4cc5a716c8e5172e75fc</id>
    <practiceSet>e8c3b7b66171443e874f972f432c4103</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Recent years {blank} minority-owned businesses in the United States unprecedented opportunities—as well as new and {blank} risks. Civil rights activists have long argued that one of the {blank} reasons why Blacks, Hispanics, and other minority groups have difficulty establishing themselves in business is that they lack {blank} to the sizable orders and subcontracts that {blank} by large companies.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>brought</o1>
          <o2>had brought</o2>
          <o3>are bringing</o3>
          <o4>have brought</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>important</o1>
          <o2>significant</o2>
          <o3>updated</o3>
          <o4>well known</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>principal</o1>
          <o2>important</o2>
          <o3>necessary</o3>
          <o4>unfair</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>hold</o1>
          <o2>outlet</o2>
          <o3>access</o3>
          <o4>permit</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>are generated</o1>
          <o2>generated</o2>
          <o3>have been generated</o3>
          <o4>is generated</o4>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>3|1|0|2|0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>c1015b420254443bb832ff30c7d09bd0</id>
    <practiceSet>e8c3b7b66171443e874f972f432c4103</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Woodrow Wilson {blank} to the liberal idea of the economic market when he said that the free enterprise system is the most {blank} economic system. Maximum freedom means maximum {blank} ; our “openness” is to be the measure of our stability. Fascination with this ideal has made Americans defy the “Old World” categories of settled {blank}  versus unsettling deprivation, the cupidity of retention versus the cupidity of seizure, a “status quo” defended or attacked. The United States, it {blank} , had no status quo ante.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>referred</o1>
          <o2>was referred</o2>
          <o3>in reference</o3>
          <o4>was referring</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>efficient</o1>
          <o2>honest</o2>
          <o3>reliable</o3>
          <o4>result oriented </o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>production</o1>
          <o2>produced</o2>
          <o3>productiveness</o3>
          <o4>prolific</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>devotion</o1>
          <o2>aversion</o2>
          <o3>possessiveness</o3>
          <o4>bond</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>believed</o1>
          <o2>has been believing</o2>
          <o3>were believed</o3>
          <o4>was believed</o4>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>3|0|2|2|0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>9bd271a971184ffbb0f8d735411cbe20</id>
    <practiceSet>e8c3b7b66171443e874f972f432c4103</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Scientists have developed a self-driving scooter, using the same technology that {blank} autonomous cars, which could help mobility-impaired people move around even in indoor spaces. The researchers had previously used the same sensor configuration and software in trials of autonomous cars and golf carts, so the new trial completes the demonstration of a {blank} autonomous mobility system. mobility-impaired user {blank} use a scooter to get down the hall and through the lobby of an apartment building, take a golf cart across the building's parking lot, and pick up an autonomous car on the public roads. The new {blank} establishes that the researchers' control algorithms work indoors as well as out.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>discovered</o1>
          <o2>invented</o2>
          <o3>researches</o3>
          <o4>powers</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>detailed</o1>
          <o2>specific</o2>
          <o3>selective</o3>
          <o4>comprehensive </o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>may</o1>
          <o2>could</o2>
          <o3>should</o3>
          <o4>can</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>trial</o1>
          <o2>amenities</o2>
          <o3>source</o3>
          <o4>research </o4>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>3|3|1|0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>9326bd6c834a46f087d4934cacb23966</id>
    <practiceSet>a2dc026da5a84119be23ddaab151b4fc</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>{blank}adherence to outdated political ideas and {blank} sects characterized the last years of a man who had, surprisingly, been one of the most {blank} thinkers of the 1920s.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>departed</o1>
          <o2>dogged</o2>
          <o3>flexible</o3>
          <o4>defunct</o4>
          <o5>resolves</o5>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>1|3|2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>3003d6042ec6443d8cdea1e451ca9a30</id>
    <practiceSet>a2dc026da5a84119be23ddaab151b4fc</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>When staying in a hotel, Bernard would {blank} for his valet to bring him his newspaper in the dining room so that everyone would {blank} that he had a {blank} ; this {blank} embarrassed his nephew who, though equally rich, preferred a more {blank} life-style.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>understated</o1>
          <o2>scattered</o2>
          <o3>realize</o3>
          <o4>manservant</o4>
          <o5>reservation</o5>
          <o6>ostentation</o6>
          <o7>arrange</o7>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>6|2|3|5|0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>18ede94c57954165aa6baf5d255113a5</id>
    <practiceSet>a2dc026da5a84119be23ddaab151b4fc</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>The {blank} and virtuosity required of a jazz player make jazz seem to lack {blank} structure; this apparently  {blank} flow can make it hard for people with traditional expectations of musical stability to {blank} a taste for this genre.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>acquire</o1>
          <o2>amorphous </o2>
          <o3>inventiveness</o3>
          <o4>distinct	</o4>
          <o5>inherent </o5>
          <o6>auxiliary </o6>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>2|4|1|0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>26016f0500ac4e17a49d4e328f0cafc8</id>
    <practiceSet>a2dc026da5a84119be23ddaab151b4fc</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Most economists in the United States seem {blank} by the spell of the free market. {blank}, nothing seems good or normal that does not accord with the requirements of the free market. A price that is {blank} by the seller or, for that matter, established by anyone other than the aggregate of consumers seems {blank} Accordingly, it requires a major act of will to think of price-fixing (the determination of prices by the seller) as both “normal” and having a valuable economic function. In fact, price-fixing is normal in all {blank} societies because the industrial system itself provides, as an {blank} consequence of its own development, the price-fixing that it requires.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>captivated</o1>
          <o2>advantageous</o2>
          <o3>consequently</o3>
          <o4>pernicious</o4>
          <o5>industrialized</o5>
          <o6>determined</o6>
          <o7>effortless</o7>
          <o8>streamline</o8>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>0|2|5|3|4|6</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>26016f0500ac4e17a49d4e328f0cafc8</id>
    <practiceSet>a2dc026da5a84119be23ddaab151b4fc</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>The majority of successful senior managers do not closely follow the {blank} rational model of first clarifying goals, {blank} the problem, formulating options, estimating likelihoods of success, making a decision, and only then taking action to {blank} the decision. Rather, in their day-by-day {blank} maneuvers, these senior executives rely on what is  termed “intuition” to manage a network of interrelated problems that require them to deal with ambiguity, {blank} , novelty, and surprise; and to integrate action into the process of thinking.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>inconsistency</o1>
          <o2>complicated</o2>
          <o3>implement</o3>
          <o4>checked</o4>
          <o5>classical</o5>
          <o6>assessing</o6>
          <o7>vaguely</o7>
		  <o8>tactical</o8>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>4|5|2|7|0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>bbf511ffad644026969787ab81a5e037</id>
    <practiceSet>a2dc026da5a84119be23ddaab151b4fc</practiceSet>
    <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:02:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Mental and physical health professionals may consider referring clients and patients to a music therapist for a number of reasons. It seems a particularly good choice for the social worker who is coordinating a client’s case. Music therapists use music to establish a relationship with the patient and to improve the patient’s health, using highly structured musical interactions. Patients and therapists may sing, play instruments, dance, compose, or simply listen to music. The course of training for music therapists is comprehensive. In addition to formal musical and therapy training, music therapists are taught to discern what kinds of interventions will be most beneficial for each individual patient. Because each patient is different and has different goals, the music therapist must be able to understand the patient’s situation and choose the music and activities that will do the most toward helping the patient achieve his or her goals. The referring social worker can help this process by clearly communicating each client’s history. Although patients may develop their musical skills, that is not the main goal of music therapy. Any client who needs particular work on communication or on academic, emotional, and social skills, and who is not responding to traditional therapy, is an excellent candidate for music therapy.</description>
      <title>According to information presented in the passage, music therapy can be prescribed for social work clients who</title>
      <options>
        <o0>need to develop coping skills.</o0>
        <o1>were orphaned as children.</o1>
        <o2>need to resolve family issues. </o2>
        <o3>need to improve social skills. </o3>
      </options>
      <picture></picture>
      <answer>3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>76147017882d446494afb182a2f41a92</id>
    <practiceSet>a2dc026da5a84119be23ddaab151b4fc</practiceSet>
    <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:02:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Coral reefs are among the most diverse and productive ecosystems on Earth. Consisting of both living and non-living components, this type of ecosystem is found in the warm, clear, shallow waters of tropical oceans worldwide. The functionality of the reefs ranges from providing food and shelter to fish and other forms of marine life to protecting the shore from the ill effects of erosion and putrefaction. In fact, reefs actually create land in tropical areas by formulating islands and contributing mass to continental shorelines. Although coral looks like a plant, it is mainly comprised of the limestone skeleton of a tiny animal called a coral polyp. While corals are the main components of reef structure, they are not the only living participants. Coralline algae cement the myriad corals, and other miniature organisms such as tubeworms and mollusks contribute skeletons to this dense and diverse structure. Together, these living creatures construct many different types of tropical reefs.</description>
      <title> Which of the following kinds of publications would most likely contain this passage?</title>
      <options>
        <o0>a history textbook </o0>
        <o1>an advanced marine biology textbook</o1>
        <o2>a collection of personal essays</o2>
        <o3>a general circulation magazine about science and nature.</o3>
      </options>
      <picture></picture>
      <answer>3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>9e06a62e66944a32985c58cd541ab50e</id>
    <practiceSet>a2dc026da5a84119be23ddaab151b4fc</practiceSet>
    <type>REORDER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:02:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Arrange the options.</description>
      <title></title>
      <options>
        <o0>Two of the taller kids stood on the table to accomplish the adventurous job.</o0>
        <o1>Then I showed them how to fasten the wire into a hook.</o1>
        <o2>I promptly told the children to fetch a broken table and a long and strong  piece of wire.</o2>
        <o3>The small thieves admired my ingenuity and enjoyed themselves running around everywhere in excitement.</o3>
        <o4>One pulling down the branches with hook and the second picking the fruit while others passed them down.</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>2|1|0|4|3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>df90e91215b8442e9c8689025b66e4a4</id>
    <practiceSet>a2dc026da5a84119be23ddaab151b4fc</practiceSet>
    <type>REORDER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:02:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Arrange the options.</description>
      <title></title>
      <options>
        <o0>It must be viewed, as some new epidemic would be viewed, as a common peril to be met by concerted action.</o0>
        <o1>If we are to think wisely about the new problems raised by nuclear weapons, we must learn to view the whole matter in a quite different way.</o1>
        <o2>These conflicts are so virulent and so passionate that they produce a wide spread inability to understand even very obvious matters.</o2>
        <o3>It is a profound misfortune that the whole question of nuclear warfare has become entangled in the age-old conflicts of power politics.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>3|2|1|0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>ffbc8a16865e44e8a8ad371c74f7e79f</id>
    <practiceSet>a2dc026da5a84119be23ddaab151b4fc</practiceSet>
    <type>MULTI_CHOICE_MULTIPLE_ANSWER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct response. More than one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:59</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Harold a professional man who had worked in an office for many years had a fearful dream. In it, he found himself in a land where small slug-like animals with slimy tentacles lived on people's bodies. The people tolerated the loathsome creatures because after many years they grew into elephants which then became the nation's system of transport, carrying everyone wherever he wanted to go. Harold suddenly realised that he himself was covered with these things, and he woke up screaming. In a vivid sequence of pictures this dream dramatized for Harold what he had never been able to put in to words; he saw himself as letting society feed on his body in his early years so that it would carry him when he retired. He later threw off the "security bug" and took up freelance work. As a result of its success, the mural program created by Jane Golden has now become the nation’s largest public art program and a model for other cities throughout the country seeking to help troubled youth.</description>
      <title>According to the passage, which of the given statements are True?</title>
      <options>
        <o0>Harold was not able to understand the dream he had.</o0>
        <o1>Harold screamed after he understood what the dream was and he took freelancing job.</o1>
        <o2>The mural program’s motive is to help the youngsters who are in trouble.</o2>
        <o3>Harold screamed as he found people tolerating the sluggish animal.</o3>
      </options>
      <picture></picture>
      <answer>1|2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>0cead6cc9d8e4232957c946d0abce610</id>
    <practiceSet>a2dc026da5a84119be23ddaab151b4fc</practiceSet>
    <type>MULTI_CHOICE_MULTIPLE_ANSWER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct response. More than one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:59</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>The standard of medicine in the United States is generally agreed to be very high. There is no shortage of well qualified specialists, and there is a lot of individual attention. Treatment is backed up by the latest in the way of medical technology. Doctors and hospitals do their utmost not to make mistakes, because if they do they risk being made to pay out enormous sums in compensation. But the American health care system has what look like insoluble problems. There are in fact two systems side by side. One is the private system run on the basis of free competition. The other is the public system which had to be created because such a large part of the population, including many of the elderly, could not afford to pay for the absurdly expensive private treatment. The public system is vast. A huge proportion - more than 10 per cent - of the United States federal budget goes on it. Yet there are still very large numbers of Americans who are not covered even by this service. The government tries to keep expenditure down and so sets limits to the income of people using the system. Millions of the unemployed are another important group that is excluded. </description>
      <title>What can patients expect with regard to treatment in the U.S.A.?</title>
      <options>
        <o0>Frequent mistakes by doctors.</o0>
        <o1>Very honest hospitals.</o1>
        <o2>Personal attention.</o2>
        <o3>Some of the most skilful nurses in the world.</o3>
        <o4>Latest medical technology.</o4>
      </options>
      <picture></picture>
      <answer>2|4</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>f82c14f4bef948bf8ddf9a739575c458</id>
    <practiceSet>a2dc026da5a84119be23ddaab151b4fc</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Species {blank} in nature confers many benefits on the species involved, but it can also become a point of weakness when one species involved in the relationship {blank} by a catastrophe. Thus, flowering plant species dependent on insect pollination, as {blank} to self-pollination or wind pollination, could be {blank} when the population of insect-pollinators is depleted by the use of {blank}.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>antagonism</o1>
          <o2>interdependence</o2>
          <o3>associated</o3>
          <o4>connection</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>have affected</o1>
          <o2>had affected </o2>
          <o3>affected</o3>
          <o4>is affected</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>combat</o1>
          <o2>favored</o2>
          <o3>denying </o3>
          <o4>opposed </o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>endangered </o1>
          <o2>threaten </o2>
          <o3>defendable</o3>
          <o4>unexposed</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>fungicide </o1>
          <o2>defoliant </o2>
          <o3>DDT</o3>
          <o4>pesticides</o4>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>1|3|3|0|3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>391b86d84ca542429d3113d679405851</id>
    <practiceSet>a2dc026da5a84119be23ddaab151b4fc</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Most consumer-goods markets are significantly different. {blank} , there are many rather than few potential customers. Each {blank} a relatively small percentage of potential sales. Rarely do members of a particular market segment group themselves neatly into a meaningful program target. There are {blank} differences among consumers with similar demographic characteristics. Even with all the past decade’s advances in information technology, direct selling of consumer goods is {blank} , and mass marketing—a marketing approach that aims at a wide audience—remains the only economically {blank}mode.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>typically</o1>
          <o2>sometimes</o2>
          <o3>rarely</o3>
          <o4>seldom</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>refuses</o1>
          <o2>differs</o2>
          <o3>presents</o3>
          <o4>represents </o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>substantial </o1>
          <o2>inconsiderable</o2>
          <o3>untrustworthy</o3>
          <o4>abundant</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>occasional </o1>
          <o2>typical</o2>
          <o3>sufficient</o3>
          <o4>rare</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>attained </o1>
          <o2>transmittable</o2>
          <o3>feasible</o3>
          <o4>cinch</o4>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>0|3|0|3|2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>c44545600a6f4cd5a014735798b2a6b9</id>
    <practiceSet>a2dc026da5a84119be23ddaab151b4fc</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Japanese firms {blank} the highest levels of manufacturing efficiency in the world automobile industry. Some observers of Japan have assumed that Japanese firms use the same manufacturing equipment and {blank} as United States firms but have benefited from the {blank} characteristics of Japanese employees and the Japanese culture. However, if this were true, then one would expect Japanese auto plants in the United States to {blank} no better than factories run by United States companies.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>achieved</o1>
          <o2>have achieved</o2>
          <o3>had been achieved</o3>
          <o4>are achieving</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>inventions</o1>
          <o2>researches</o2>
          <o3>experiments</o3>
          <o4>techniques</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>typical</o1>
          <o2>isolated </o2>
          <o3>unique</o3>
          <o4>quotidian</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>give results</o1>
          <o2>be result-oriented</o2>
          <o3>perform</o3>
          <o4>dissuade</o4>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>1|3|2|2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>741259e608de4e8a8699acd1b8100e1d</id>
    <practiceSet>a2dc026da5a84119be23ddaab151b4fc</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>{blank}inventory, a massive problem for many businesses, has several causes, some of which are {blank} Overstocks may accumulate through production overruns or errors. Certain styles and colors prove {blank} . With some products—computers and software, toys, and books—last year’s models are difficult to move even at huge discounts. {blank} the competition introduces a better product. But in many cases the public’s buying tastes simply change, leaving a manufacturer or distributor with thousands (or millions) of items that the {blank} public no longer wants.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>moderate</o1>
          <o2>enormous</o2>
          <o3>excess</o3>
          <o4>economical </o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>unavoidable</o1>
          <o2>exorable</o2>
          <o3>uncertain</o3>
          <o4>assured</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>unpopular</o1>
          <o2>despised</o2>
          <o3>lousy</o3>
          <o4>favored</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>mostly</o1>
          <o2>occasionally</o2>
          <o3>hardly</o3>
          <o4>usually</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>cognizant</o1>
          <o2>reliable</o2>
          <o3>fickle</o3>
          <o4>sneaking</o4>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>2|0|0|1|2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>a9258589558c4d50a6a11a0ac4088ddc</id>
    <practiceSet>a2dc026da5a84119be23ddaab151b4fc</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Global temperature records set in 2015, the hottest year so far, may become the new norm by 2025, if carbon emissions continue to rise at the same rate, a new study {blank} . Human activities had already locked in this new normal for future temperatures, but {blank} climate action could prevent record extreme seasons year after year, said Sophie Lewis from the Australian National University. "If we continue with business-as-usual emissions, extreme seasons will {blank} be the norm within decades," said Lewis. "If we don't reduce our rate of emissions the record hot summer of 2013 in Australia — when we saw temperatures {blank} 50 degrees Celsius in some areas — could be just another average summer season by 2035," she added.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>has warned</o1>
          <o2>is warning</o2>
          <o3>warned</o3>
          <o4>warns</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>eventually</o1>
          <o2>repeated</o2>
          <o3>immediate</o3>
          <o4>continuous </o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>Inevitably</o1>
          <o2>literally</o2>
          <o3>unconditionally</o3>
          <o4>probably</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>reaching</o1>
          <o2>approaching</o2>
          <o3>targeting</o3>
          <o4>holding</o4>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>0|2|0|1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>8087e891337d4185849aaa4f0d64908f</id>
    <practiceSet>76866578defd49e5be08b21dd869e474</practiceSet>
    <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:59</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Much of the blood on the street flows essentially from uncivil behavior of drivers who refuse to respect the legal and moral rights of others. So the massacre on the road may be regarded as a social problem. Safety standards for vehicle have been raised both at the point of manufacture and through periodic road-worthiness inspections. In addition, speed limits have been lowered. Due to these measures, the accident rate has decreased. But the accident experts still worry because there has been little or no improvement in the way drivers behave.</description>
      <title>According to the passage, traffic accidents may be regarded as a social problem since</title>
      <options>
        <o0>the motor vehicle is a very dangerous invention</o0>
        <o1>the accidents have more to do with hazardous conditions than hazardous drivers</o1>
        <o2>most of the accidents are caused by drivers who don't pay attention to the traffic rules</o2>
        <o3>the irresponsibility that accounts for much of the problem is not confined to drivers</o3>
      </options>
      <picture></picture>
      <answer>1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>f6247abd3c7448aea298160b415208f4</id>
    <practiceSet>76866578defd49e5be08b21dd869e474</practiceSet>
    <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:59</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>You may have heard that tomatoes and processed tomato products like tomato sauce and canned tomatoes protect against some types of cancer. The cancer-preventing properties of tomato products have been attributed to lycopene. It is a bright red pigment found in tomatoes and other red fruits and is the cause of their red color. Unlike other fruits and vegetables, where nutritional content such as vitamin C is diminished upon cooking, processing of tomatoes increases the concentration of lycopene. Lycopene in tomato paste is four times more than in fresh tomatoes. This is because lycopene is insoluble in water and is tightly bound to vegetable fiber. Thus, processed tomato products such as pasteurized tomato juice, so up, sauce, and ketchup contain the highest concentrations of lycopene. Cooking and crushing tomatoes as in the canning process and serving in oil-rich dishes such as spaghetti sauce or pizza greatly increase assimilation from the digestive tract into the bloodstream. Lycopene is a fat-soluble substance, so the oil is said to help absorption to a great extent.</description>
      <title>According to the passage, it is true that lycopene ----.</title>
      <options>
        <o0>can only be found in processed tomato products</o0>
        <o1>is absorbed by the body more easily when accompanied by the oil</o1>
        <o2>loses its cancer-preventing property when the tomato is processed</o2>
        <o3>lowers the risk of having cancer only when it is consumed together with vitamin</o3>
      </options>
      <picture></picture>
      <answer>2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>02ae86edb13f43ee9c149b2bbb4bdd25</id>
    <practiceSet>76866578defd49e5be08b21dd869e474</practiceSet>
    <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:59</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Traditionally, many linguists stressed the importance of mastering grammar structures first while teaching English. In recent years, the majority of educators have become more aware of the fallacy of this approach and other approaches promoting vocabulary development have gained popularity. It has been found out without vocabulary to put on top of the grammar system, the learners can actually say very little despite being able to manipulate complex grammatical structures in exercise drills. It is obvious that to learn English, one needs to learn many words. Native speakers have a vocabulary of about 20,000 words but foreign learners of English need far fewer. They need only about 5,000 words to be quite competent in speaking and listening. The reason for this seemingly small number is the nature of words and the frequency with which they appear in a language. It seems clear that frequent words should be among the first words to learn because they will be met most of ten and will be needed in speech or writing.</description>
      <title> It is stated in the passage that</title>
      <options>
        <o0>a great number of educators today believe that mastering grammar points is more important than learning words while studying a foreign language.</o0>
        <o1>grammar drills are effective in teaching the most frequently encountered English words.</o1>
        <o2>an approach based on mastering grammar structures first to teach English is at most unlikely to find supporters today</o2>
        <o3>the number of English words which must be learned to communicate with a foreigner exceeds 20,000 </o3>
      </options>
      <picture></picture>
      <answer>2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>99aa97b00cac4486ab43eb6b54d0b083</id>
    <practiceSet>76866578defd49e5be08b21dd869e474</practiceSet>
    <type>REORDER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:02:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Arrange the options.</description>
      <title></title>
      <options>
        <o0>All levels of demand, whether individual, aggregate, local, national, or international are subject to change.</o0>
        <o1>At the same time, science and technology add new dimensions to products, their uses, and the methods used to market them.</o1>
        <o2>Aggregate demand fluctuates with changes in the level of business activity, GNP, and national income.</o2>
        <o3>The demand of individuals tends to vary with changing needs and rising income.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>0|3|2|1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>7af50ba72e5e4f3fb5a3e6dab863fcb7</id>
    <practiceSet>76866578defd49e5be08b21dd869e474</practiceSet>
    <type>REORDER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:02:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Arrange the options.</description>
      <title></title>
      <options>
        <o0>There is no complete knowledge about anything. </o0>
        <o1>Our thinking is the outcome of knowledge, and knowledge is always limited.</o1>
        <o2>Knowledge always goes hand in hand with ignorance.</o2>
        <o3>Therefore, our thinking which is born out of knowledge, is always limited under all circumstances.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>1|2|0|3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>40d25ebc01ac424584c3ebbdbd3de329</id>
    <practiceSet>76866578defd49e5be08b21dd869e474</practiceSet>
    <type>MULTI_CHOICE_MULTIPLE_ANSWER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct response. More than one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:02:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>The grey wolf also known as the timber wolf or wolf is a mammal of the order Carnivore. Genetic studies indicate the grey wolf shares a common ancestry with the domestic dog and might be its ancestor. Many other grey wolf subspecies have been identified however the actual number of subspecies is still open to discussion. Though once abundant over much of North America and areas of Europe and Asia, the grey wolf inhabits a very small portion of its former range because of the widespread destruction of its habitat. Gray wolves are highly adaptable and have thrived in forests, deserts, mountains, tundra and grasslands. They function as social predators and hunt in packs organized according to strict social hierarchies. It was originally believed that this comparatively high level of social organization was related to hunting success, and while this still may be true to a certain extent, emerging theories suggest that the pack has less to do with hunting and more to do with reproductive success.</description>
      <title>It is understood from the passage that</title>
      <options>
        <o0>the number of grey wolf subspecies has been determined with certainty by researchers</o0>
        <o1>it is known that grey wolf subspecies inhabits very small portion.</o1>
        <o2>there is no consensus on how many grey wolf subspecies exist</o2>
        <o3>there are few grey wolf subspecies which continue living today</o3>
        <o4>grey wolf subspecies have increased in number in the last decades</o4>
      </options>
      <picture></picture>
      <answer>1|2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>bb912c953cef41319feb9558fa72bcb3</id>
    <practiceSet>76866578defd49e5be08b21dd869e474</practiceSet>
    <type>MULTI_CHOICE_MULTIPLE_ANSWER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct response. More than one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:02:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Autism is a brain development disorder that impairs social interaction and communication and causes restricted and repetitive behavior, all starting before a child is three years old. The genetics of autism are complex and it is generally unclear which genes are responsible for it. Autism affects many parts of the brain but how this occurs is also poorly understood. Autism is strongly associated with agents that cause birth defects. Other proposed causes, such as childhood vaccines, are controversial and the vaccine hypotheses lack convincing scientific evidence. The number of people known to have autism has increased dramatically since the 1980s. Parents usually notice signs in the first two years of their child's life. Early behavioral cognitive intervention can help children gain self-care, social and communication skills but there is no cure for it. Few children with autism live independently after reaching adulthood, but same become successful and an autistic culture has developed, with same seeking a cure and others believing that autism is a condition rather than a disorder.</description>
      <title>It can be understood from the passage that </title>
      <options>
        <o0>autistic children cannot hear the sounds and are unable to talk with others.</o0>
        <o1>even if the treatment for autism starts early, the child doesn't have any chance to recover completely.</o1>
        <o2>when they become an adult all autistic people can live as actively as normal people do.</o2>
        <o3>people with autism should be encouraged to live on their own.</o3>
        <o4>scientists are unclear which genes are responsible for the development of autism.</o4>
      </options>
      <picture></picture>
      <answer>1|4</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>fa59d162b2814bf8bedb9b01fe65a9ff</id>
    <practiceSet>76866578defd49e5be08b21dd869e474</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>This year we've seen {blank} loops of online commentary and Hollywood  {blank} about the enduring whiteness of American cinema and how {blank} challenges continue to restrict filmmakers of color. So it was not surprising that there was so much {blank} around the October release of first-time director Nate Parker's film The Birth of a Nation. The story of Nat Turner's slave rebellion and {blank} , as seen through the artistic vision of a young, black filmmaker, caused a bidding war at the Sundance Film Festival at the height of the #OscarsSoWhite campaign.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>self-empowerment  </o1>
          <o2>endless </o2>
          <o3>joyful</o3>
          <o4>structural </o4>
          <o5>infrastructure</o5>
          <o6>hand-wringing</o6>
		  <o7>anticipation</o7>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>1|5|3|6|0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>442de68990314521a9c0937717946d13</id>
    <practiceSet>76866578defd49e5be08b21dd869e474</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>A lot of people want to migrate but there are few {blank} to allow them to do so legally. What most would-be migrants will do is look at ways of using {blank} and trafficking networks. That has very serious impact – on well-being of migrant who might find self in dangerous and {blank} situation. But also on host country because irregular migrants will never be able to {blank} . Won’t be able to send children to school, rights abused. One of the other aspects, because fewer channels to migrate legally, and because turn to smuggling, this benefits highly- {blank} criminal networks, making billion of dollars smuggling and trafficking people – it’s become in a way the new {blank} trade.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>smuggling</o1>
          <o2>critical</o2>
          <o3>organized </o3>
          <o4>slave</o4>
          <o5>built</o5>
          <o6>channels</o6>
          <o7>integrate</o7>
          <o8>communicate</o8>
          <o9>exploitative</o9>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>5|0|8|6|2|3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>6c7b83a5b26f436d85e5cac908b02457</id>
    <practiceSet>76866578defd49e5be08b21dd869e474</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Until you know the language and culture really well, these cultural associations can create a real {blank} to enjoying and understanding books written in English. What I mean by ‘cultural associations’ is {blank} to – I don’t know - historical or literary figures, to religious or traditional practices, to TV personalities, games or meals that a reader who is part of the culture will pick up and understand, but which can be {blank} to other readers. The point about reading books from your own culture and tradition {blank} into English is that you are removing this kind of problem.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>related</o1>
          <o2>references </o2>
          <o3>perplexed</o3>
          <o4>bewildering</o4>
          <o5>converted </o5>
          <o6>translated  </o6>
          <o7>barrier</o7>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>6|1|3|5</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>bea667567c874661b5641a25a86d339f</id>
    <practiceSet>76866578defd49e5be08b21dd869e474</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Environmental campaigners believe cuts aren’t enough. They’re calling for {blank} changes in our lifestyles, especially in the richer nations. This would include {blank} away from fossil fuels to sources of energy which are less harmful to the environment, like solar power, or fuels made from plants known as biofuels. This is especially important in the {blank} nations which are the biggest consumers of energy and therefore the biggest {blank} .</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>polluters </o1>
          <o2>industrialized</o2>
          <o3>drastic</o3>
          <o4>getting</o4>
          <o5>developing </o5>
          <o6>huge</o6>
          <o7>switching </o7>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>2|6|1|0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>f0e8d1200bbb48e9b637ee3866a47d8b</id>
    <practiceSet>76866578defd49e5be08b21dd869e474</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Over the years, a large number of laws and {blank} have been developed based on the United Nations Universal Declaration of Human Rights. They’re meant to {blank} citizens, and to confront human rights {blank} wherever they occur. Around the world countries and regions have written their own {blank} . We’ve heard about the European Convention of Human Rights. There’s also an American Convention and an African Charter.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>violations </o1>
          <o2>restrict</o2>
          <o3>conventions</o3>
          <o4>protect</o4>
          <o5>offense</o5>
          <o6>charters</o6>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>5|3|0|2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>e1421cd833be4656af8cd9d3029a15eb</id>
    <practiceSet>76866578defd49e5be08b21dd869e474</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Before outsiders first visited their land they knew nothing about the {blank} , of others or the government or the modern life. However in the 1980s miners found gold in the region and soon thousands of miners rushed into the area which resulted in the {blank} of the Yanomamis' homeland. During that time 20 % of them died due to many reasons. Today they try hard to {blank} their land and traditions, which doesn't seem so {blank} to do.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>existence</o1>
          <o2>effrontery</o2>
          <o3>submissiveness</o3>
          <o4>actuality</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>extolment</o1>
          <o2>exploitation</o2>
          <o3>palatability</o3>
          <o4>misconduct</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>sequester</o1>
          <o2>ensue</o2>
          <o3>maintain </o3>
          <o4>isolate</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>easy </o1>
          <o2>onerous </o2>
          <o3>complicated</o3>
          <o4>convenient</o4>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>0|1|2|0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>4f8aee12700d470b815d2a667ff14c56</id>
    <practiceSet>76866578defd49e5be08b21dd869e474</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>A history of the Kaveri will {blank}  include the history of all the ancient kingdoms of the extreme south of India, except perhaps the Pandyan, but the history of the land along its lower course would greatly {blank} in interest that of the countries in which its upper course lies. At the head of the island of Srirangam the river branches off into two, and acquires the {blank} to branch off again and again, till, having given birth to the Tanjore delta and grown more and more {blank}, it becomes an {blank} streamlet, the thin waters of which vanish into the thirsty sands of Kaverippattinam, within almost a few yards of the sea.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>critically</o1>
          <o2>uncertainly</o2>
          <o3>inevitably</o3>
          <o4>influentially</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>fail</o1>
          <o2>contribute</o2>
          <o3>outperformed</o3>
          <o4>surpass</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>propensity</o1>
          <o2>tendency</o2>
          <o3>capability</o3>
          <o4>control </o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>attenuated </o1>
          <o2>weaken</o2>
          <o3>toughened</o3>
          <o4>vigorous</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>insignificant </o1>
          <o2>valuable</o2>
          <o3>substantially</o3>
          <o4>evitable</o4>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>2|3|1|0|0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>145c7c62e65d4dfea895fa10842b7495</id>
    <practiceSet>76866578defd49e5be08b21dd869e474</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Carbon sinks, 70% forest cover, powered almost entirely by mountain streams--Bhutan is a {blank} child for green living. It is the only country in the world that is carbon negative, which means it produces more oxygen than it consumes. Bhutan {blank} about 2.2 million tonnes of carbon annually, yet its forests absorb three times this amount, which creates a carbon sink. Sure, it’s a small country with a population of only 750,000, but other smaller countries—the Maldives, Luxembourg—haven’t managed this yet. Flying into Bhutan over the Himalayas, the first thing you notice are the trees. A thick {blank} of green wraps around the mountains, a complete contrast to the {blank} hills of India.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>poster</o1>
          <o2>young</o2>
          <o3>growing</o3>
          <o4>sticker</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>Has generated</o1>
          <o2>will generate</o2>
          <o3>has been generating</o3>
          <o4>generates</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>blanket</o1>
          <o2>carpet </o2>
          <o3>mask</o3>
          <o4>surface </o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>bare</o1>
          <o2>denumerable</o2>
          <o3>despoil</o3>
          <o4>denuded</o4>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>0|3|0|3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>1b21ed8f44cf48c18e213e0c70dc5c62</id>
    <practiceSet>76866578defd49e5be08b21dd869e474</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Facebook is the largest social network on the web in terms of traffic. Primarily  {blank} on Students, facebook has been gaining market share  {blank} and more significantly a supportive user base nowadays. Since their launch in 2004, they have been able to obtain over 20 million users in the U.S. Alone and {blank} worldwide to other English-speaking countries, with more to follow in the future.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>reinforced</o1>
          <o2>focused</o2>
          <o3>emerged</o3>
          <o4>based </o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>constantly</o1>
          <o2>deliberately</o2>
          <o3>reluctantly</o3>
          <o4>consistently</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>expand</o1>
          <o2>immigrate</o2>
          <o3>decline</o3>
          <o4>explore</o4>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>1|0|0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>867d6a701620489eb570483834e8cfb3</id>
    <practiceSet>76866578defd49e5be08b21dd869e474</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Recent years have been a news bonanza for dinosaur fans. With the {blank} of fossils great and small, scientists have broken new ground in their quest to understand the amazing creatures that roamed our planet millions of years ago. And that won't be all—it's {blank} that less than 1 percent of all dinosaur species have been discovered. Scientists have found the fossil skull of a 135-million-year-old sea crocodile they've nicknamed "Godzilla." The fossil has been given the scientific name Dakosaurus andiniensis. This fearsome creature was very different from other crocodile species. Marine crocodiles have long {blank} and many sharp teeth, but "Godzilla's" head and teeth looked more like T. rex's than his modern cousin's. This ancient crocodile also had flippers instead of legs and a tail like a fish's to {blank} it through the ocean. The discovery was made in Patagonia, an area of Argentina that was once under the Pacific Ocean.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>research</o1>
          <o2>invention</o2>
          <o3>search</o3>
          <o4>discovery</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>considered</o1>
          <o2>guessed</o2>
          <o3>estimated</o3>
          <o4>approximate</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>nose</o1>
          <o2>nostril</o2>
          <o3>snouts</o3>
          <o4>organ</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>propel</o1>
          <o2>hinder</o2>
          <o3>exist</o3>
          <o4>hinder</o4>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>3|2|2|0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>99fce33acbc04323b899d10293b300a2</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1f77c</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Curriculum-based measurement of reading (CBM-R) is used to estimate oral reading fluency.{blank} many traditional published tests, CBM-R materials are often comprised of 20 to 30 alternate forms or passages. {blank}, CBM-R assessment materials were sampled from curricular materials. Recent research has documented the potentially {blank} effects of poorly controlled alternate forms on CBM-R outcomes. The purpose of this study was to examine alternate procedures for the selection of passages that comprise CBM-R passage-sets. The study examined four procedures for the {blank} and selection of passages, including {blank} sampling, Spache readability formula, mean level of performance evaluation, and Euclidean Distance evaluation. The latter two procedures relied on field testing and evaluation of student performance. Each of eighty-eight students in second- and third-grade were {blank} 50 CBM-R passages. Generalizability and dependability studies were used to examine students' performance on these passages and evaluate CBM-R passage selection procedures. Results provide support for the use of field testing methods (i.e., calculating performance means and Euclidean Distances) for passage selection. Implications are discussed for future research and practice.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>unlike</o1>
          <o2>similarly</o2>
          <o3>rather than</o3>
          <o4>as a result</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>Historically</o1>
          <o2>Earlier</o2>
          <o3>Basically</o3>
          <o4>Relatively</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>destabilized</o1>
          <o2>deleterious</o2>
          <o3>positive</o3>
          <o4>friendly</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>result </o1>
          <o2>assessment</o2>
          <o3>ranking</o3>
          <o4>evaluation</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>methodical</o1>
          <o2>unorganized</o2>
          <o3>aimed</o3>
          <o4>random</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>supervised</o1>
          <o2>interpreting</o2>
          <o3>administered</o3>
          <o4>urging</o4>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>0|0|1|3|3|2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>f4b1a9a0bec742788f7972ffff3c8eed</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1f77c</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Male lions are rather {blank} about expanding their energy in hunting more than three quarters of kills are made by lionesses are in front, tensely scanning ahead, the cubs lag playfully behind and the males bring up the rear, walking slowly, their {blank} heads nodding with each step as if they were bored with the whole matter. But {blank} may have survival value. With lionesses busy hunting, the males function as guard for the cubs, protecting them {blank} from hyenas.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>critical</o1>
          <o2>uncertain</o2>
          <o3>reticent</o3>
          <o4>unabashed</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>minute</o1>
          <o2>itsy</o2>
          <o3>sharp</o3>
          <o4>massive</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>slothfulness</o1>
          <o2>activeness</o2>
          <o3>intelligence</o3>
          <o4>silence</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>particularly</o1>
          <o2>vigorously</o2>
          <o3>generally</o3>
          <o4>indistinctly</o4>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>2|3|0|0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>10d577bcc7b848e3b3347b902f75bba8</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1f77c</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>The history of ropes and knots is so dim and ancient that really little is known of their origin. That earliest man used cordage of some kind and by his {blank} succeeded in tying the material together is indisputable, for the most ancient carvings and decorations of prehistoric man show knots in several forms. Doubtless the trailing vines and plants first suggested ropes to human beings; and it is quite {blank} that these same vines, in their various {blank} and twinings, gave man his first idea of knots. Since the earliest times knots have been everywhere  {blank} with human affairs; jugglers have used them in their tricks; they have become almost a part of many occupations and trades, while in song and story they have become the symbol of {blank} and strength.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>ingenuity</o1>
          <o2>experience</o2>
          <o3>inventions</o3>
          <o4>reality</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>unbelievable</o1>
          <o2>probable</o2>
          <o3>dubious</o3>
          <o4>possibility</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>turnings</o1>
          <o2>twistings </o2>
          <o3>untwinings</o3>
          <o4>tanglings</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>interwoven</o1>
          <o2>confused</o2>
          <o3>reticulate</o3>
          <o4>compared </o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>unreliability</o1>
          <o2>unsteadiness</o2>
          <o3>steadfastness</o3>
          <o4>untiring</o4>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>0|1|1|0|2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>8f23a30bc2d94767a6581e6ea6cc69fc</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1f77c</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>The importance of fluency and vocabulary in comprehension was established in part in true experiments, with instruction that improved fluency and vocabulary also improving comprehension, making the {blank} connections between fluency and vocabulary and comprehension clear.  There has been much experimental {blank} establishing that when readers are taught to use comprehension strategies, their comprehension, in fact, improves. This is powerful evidence of the causal relationship between comprehension {blank} use and comprehension, with the relevant research outcomes discussed in the next section. The conclusion from this section, however, is a different one: Good readers use comprehension strategies {blank} when they read. When {blank} readers are taught comprehension strategies, they are being taught to read as good readers do.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>formal</o1>
          <o2>semi-formal</o2>
          <o3>intentional</o3>
          <o4>casual</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>expectation</o1>
          <o2>refutation</o2>
          <o3>destruction</o3>
          <o4>evidence</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>practicality</o1>
          <o2>strategy</o2>
          <o3>meaning</o3>
          <o4>planning</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>carelessly</o1>
          <o2>seriously</o2>
          <o3>consciously</o3>
          <o4>impassively</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>burgeoning</o1>
          <o2>withering</o2>
          <o3>experienced</o3>
          <o4>sincere</o4>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>3|3|1|2|0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>72576bb5c21a4dae88138c144e56f48b</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1f77c</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>A team of computer scientists and paleontologists from Sandia National Laboratories and the New Mexico Museum of Natural History and Science Museum {blank} the sound that a Parasaurolophus dinosaur made when it lived during the late Cretaceous period. The team accomplished this feat by using a rare 4.5 foot long fossil of the dinosaur's skull, computed tomography (CT) scans, and {blank} supercomputers. The Parasaurolophus had a bony tubular crest that extended back from the top of its head. Many scientists believed the crest, containing a labyrinth of air cavities and shaped like a trombone, might have been used to produce {blank} sounds. Once a 3-D model of the crest was created, the computer was able to simulate blowing air through it to {blank} the tones it was capable of making. As expected, the dinosaur apparently emitted a {blank} low-frequency rumbling sound that could change in pitch.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>created</o1>
          <o2>has developed</o2>
          <o3>has recreated</o3>
          <o4>discovered</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>huge</o1>
          <o2>powerful</o2>
          <o3>familiar</o3>
          <o4>similar</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>unique</o1>
          <o2>distinctive</o2>
          <o3>familiar</o3>
          <o4>similar</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>apply</o1>
          <o2>create</o2>
          <o3>amplify</o3>
          <o4>play</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>resonating</o1>
          <o2>resonate</o2>
          <o3>tremble</o3>
          <o4>quiet</o4>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>2|1|1|2|0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>0842d877d5fe4dafa65dd6d3a6e15721</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1f77c</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Since antibiotics were discovered in 1928, the medical community has been using them as the treatment of choice against {blank} infections. They have become so {blank}; in fact, that modern medicine now faces the possibility of them becoming {blank} as bacteria evolves into antibiotic‐resistant strains. This might suggest that the use of living creatures to fight human disease is a bad idea; nature does sometimes tend to have a will of its own {blank} human desires and best intentions. But perhaps the key is not to abandon nature in our {blank} of scientific control, but to work in cooperation with it. To this end, scientists are attempting to solve the antibiotic‐resistance problem by looking to the past. Before antibiotics, doctors treated bacterial infections with specialized viruses called phages, which kill disease‐causing bacteria.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>skin</o1>
          <o2>critical </o2>
          <o3>ubiquitous</o3>
          <o4>against</o4>
          <o5>pursuit</o5>
          <o6>custody</o6>
          <o7>ineffective</o7>
          <o8>bacterial </o8>
          <o9>ineffective </o9>
          <o10>despite </o10>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>7|2|6|9|4</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
<question>  
  <id>0842d877d5fe4dafa65dd6d3a6e15785</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1f77c</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Good readers attempt to {blank} the ideas in text to get the main ideas out of the text. This can involve {blank} the structure of the text as the reader {blank} on the meaning of each part of the text. Sometimes the reader will jump around in text to construct a main idea, perhaps looking back at some information read quickly the first time and looking ahead to read something that was noted to be in the text during the {blank} skim. Sometimes good readers make notes about ideas in different parts of the text to assist {blank} of the text.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>reflects</o1>
          <o2>studying</o2>
          <o3>consolidated</o3>
          <o4>absorbs</o4>
          <o5>pre-reading</o5>
          <o6>integration</o6>
          <o7>analyzing</o7>
          <o8>integrate</o8>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>7|6|0|4|5</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>b867a94fe88941dc905f3ce2bd5c9b93</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1f77c</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Almost all the {blank} ways of referring to children who find literacy learning difficult imply a weakness in the children.  We take the position that teaching must be designed to meet the needs of each child and that educators must {blank} search for effective ways to serve the children they teach. Most learning problems exist not within the child but in the {blank} of the system to find a way to teach him…Without intervention, they can {blank} confusions and fall into behaviors that we then diagnose as reading disabilities.  What was an early weakness that would respond to instruction becomes a long-term {blank}.  We need to remember that a difficulty is not necessarily a disability.  By intervening early and using a {blank} of different instructional techniques, we can put most children back on track.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>radical</o1>
          <o2>repertoire</o2>
          <o3>neglect </o3>
          <o4>inadequacy</o4>
          <o5>deficit</o5>
          <o6>perpetuate</o6>
          <o7>conventional</o7>
          <o8>constantly</o8>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>6|7|3|5|4|1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>086c672c86e0464892153e7f0b2edb99</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1f77c</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>One kind of brain-scanning device is used by doctors to monitor normal as well as abnormal activity in a patient's brain. The device provides {blank} measurements of blood flow in the brain, a known  {blank} of how the brain is working. {blank}, the device requires patients to remain completely still with their heads in the scanning machine, which makes a very loud noise. Under these uncomfortable conditions, it is {blank} that doctors can get accurate measurements. A new head-mounted device that measures eye movements rather than blood flow and allows patients to move around will undoubtedly provide better brain {blank}. Thus, the new head-mounted device should replace the older device at all hospitals and research institutions.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>indicator</o1>
          <o2>doubtful </o2>
          <o3>inaccurate</o3>
          <o4>functions</o4>
          <o5>unfortunately </o5>
          <o6>measurements</o6>
          <o7>basically </o7>
          <o8>precise</o8>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>7|0|4|1|5</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>84a1832d9aeb4d2d98da0cf123237b7d</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1f77c</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Even though we might think that a large chunk of rock, especially like a rocky mountain, is a permanent part of the landscape, in reality it is {blank} changing just like everything else on earth. Mountains, huge {blank}and even grains of sand seem permanent to us because they change slowly over time. Rock material is broken down, {blank}, dissolved and transported elsewhere though erosion. Erosion is an important part of the life cycle of rocks which can span hundreds of thousands of years. Without the forces of erosion to transport and move worn away rock elsewhere, rock debris would{blank}in place. </description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>boulders </o1>
          <o2>continuously</o2>
          <o3>assembled</o3>
          <o4>accumulate</o4>
          <o5>constantly </o5>
          <o6>loosened</o6>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>4|0|5|3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>6249df280f974bc182c0886becfcca46</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1f77c</practiceSet>
    <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:59</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Democratic institutions are devices for reconciling social order with individual freedom and initiative, and for making the immediate power of a country's rulers subject to the  ultimate power of the ruled. The fact that, in Western Europe and America, these devices have worked, all things considered,  not too badly is proof enough that the eighteenth century  optimists were not entirely wrong.  No people that pass abruptly from a state of subservience under the rule of a despot to the completely unfamiliar state of political independence can be said to have a fair chance of being able to govern itself democratically. Liberalism flourishes in an atmosphere of prosperity and declines as declining prosperity makes it necessary for the government  to intervene ever more frequently and drastically in the affairs of its subjects. Over-population and  over-organization are two conditions which ... deprive a  society of a fair chance of making democratic institutions work effectively.</description>
      <title>The author’s primary purpose is apparently to:-</title>
      <options>
        <o0>Explain a requirement and introduce a warning about that requirement.</o0>
        <o1>Argue for the limitation of a certain form of government.</o1>
        <o2>Define the conditions for social order.</o2>
        <o3>Credit certain thinkers with foresight</o3>
      </options>
      <picture></picture>
      <answer>0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>8fdffb38c2af410588129c74bef50d30</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1f77c</practiceSet>
    <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:59</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>At this stage of civilization, when many nations are brought in to close and vital contact for good and evil, it is essential, as never before, that their gross ignorance of one another should be diminished, that they should begin to understand a little of one another's historical experience and resulting mentality. It is the fault of the English to expect the people of other countries to react as they do, to political and international situations. Our genuine goodwill and good intentions are often brought to nothing, because we expect other people to be like us. This would be corrected if we knew the history, not necessarily in detail but in broad outlines, of the social and political conditions which have given to each nation its present character.</description>
      <title>According to the author of 'Mentality' of a nation is mainly product of its</title>
      <options>
        <o0>history.</o0>
        <o1>international position.</o1>
        <o2>Politics.</o2>
        <o3>present character.</o3>
      </options>
      <picture></picture>
      <answer>0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>dd57bbac2a924bd2aedbfe14c43655e5</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1f77c</practiceSet>
    <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:59</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>In the world today we make health and end in itself. We have forgotten that health is really means to enable a person to do his work and do it well. a lot of modern medicine and this includes many patients as well as many physicians pays very little attention to health but very much attention to those who imagine that they are ill. Our great concern with health is shown by the medical columns in newspapers. the health articles in popular magazines and the popularity of television programmes and all those books on medicine. We talk about health all the time. Yet for the most part the only result is more people with imaginary illness. The healthy man should not be wasting time talking about health: he should be using health for work. The work does the work that good health possible.</description>
      <title> Modern medicine is primarily concerned with:</title>
      <options>
        <o0>promotion of good health</o0>
        <o1>people suffering from imaginary illness</o1>
        <o2>people suffering from real illness</o2>
        <o3>increased efficiency in work</o3>
      </options>
      <picture></picture>
      <answer>1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>a470621ec6204f3998c90017639ba593</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1f77c</practiceSet>
    <type>MULTI_CHOICE_MULTIPLE_ANSWER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct response. More than one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:02:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Slavery is a system under which certain persons are totally deprived of personal freedom and compelled to perform labor or services. Although outlawed in nearly all countries, slavery is still practiced in some parts of the world. The evidence for slavery predates written records. It can be found in almost all cultures and continents. Historically, most slaves were captured in wars but some persons were sold into slavery by their parents, or by themselves, as a means of surviving extreme conditions. Ancient Warfare often resulted in slavery for prisoners and their families. Captives were often considered the property of those who captured them and were looked upon as a prize of war. Those captured sometimes differed in ethnicity, nationality, religion, or race from their enslavers, but often were the same as the captors. The dominant group in an area might take captives and turn them into slaves. The possibility always existed of reversals of fortune at the height of the Roman Empire, when powerful nations fought among themselves, anyone could find himself enslaved. </description>
      <title> It can be understood from the passage that the captives of the wars in ancient times ----.</title>
      <options>
        <o0>were killed as soon as they were caught</o0>
        <o1>were accepted as the property of the leader of the dominant group in an area</o1>
        <o2>usually shared certain features in common with the ones who captured them</o2>
        <o3>were mostly the civilians as the captured soldiers were quickly executed</o3>
        <o4>were taken by dominant group and turned  into slaves</o4>
      </options>
      <picture></picture>
      <answer>2|4</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>a2e08009eaee4074b720e23859e2924b</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1f77c</practiceSet>
    <type>MULTI_CHOICE_MULTIPLE_ANSWER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct response. More than one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:02:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>"Two offenses of a very different nature, and by no means of equal magnitude, you last night laid to my charge. The first mentioned was, that, regardless of the sentiments of either, I had detached Mr. Bingley from your sister, and the other, that I had, in defiance of various claims, in defiance of honor and humanity, ruined the immediate prosperity and blasted the prospects of Mr. Wickham. Willfully and want only to have thrown off the companion of my youth, the acknowledged favorite of my father, a young man who had scarcely any other dependence than on our patronage, and who had been brought up to expect its exertion, would be a depravity, to which the separation of two young persons, whose affection could be the growth of only a few weeks, could bear no comparison. But from the severity of that blame which was last night so liberally bestowed, respecting each circumstance, I shall hope to be in the future secured, when the following account of my actions and their motives has been read. If, in the explanation of them, which is due to myself, I am under the necessity of relating feelings which may be offensive to yours, I can only say that I am sorry. The necessity must be obeyed, and further apology would be absurd.”</description>
      <title>The letter writer’s purpose in presenting his comments is</title>
      <options>
        <o0>to defend his actions against the letter reader’s accusations of wrongdoing.</o0>
        <o1>to apologize for offending the letter reader’s feelings with his explanation.</o1>
        <o2>To make clear that the way the reader has reacted as make him feel offended somewhere.</o2>
        <o3>to give the explanation about is behavior and the motive behind his actions.</o3>
        <o4>to satisfy himself in retrospect that his actions were appropriate.</o4>
      </options>
      <picture></picture>
      <answer>0|1|4</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>a1f208cb9fef41509f00247511c45285</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1f77c</practiceSet>
    <type>REORDER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:02:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Arrange the options.</description>
      <title></title>
      <options>
        <o0>No other document gives us so intimate a sense of the tone and temper of the first generation English poets.</o0>
        <o1>Part of the interest of the journal is of course historical.</o1>
        <o2>And the clues to Wordsworth’s creative processes which the journal affords are of decisive significance.</o2>
        <o3>Not even in their own letters do Wordsworth and Coleridge stand so present before us than they do through the references in the journal.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>1|0|3|2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>3e99b9fde5004de6953682bfae33f41e</id>
    <practiceSet>abf2b37f406f44d5bc56c90314c1f77c</practiceSet>
    <type>REORDER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:02:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Arrange the options.</description>
      <title></title>
      <options>
        <o0>Making people laugh is tricky.</o0>
        <o1>At times, the intended humor may simply not come off.</o1>
        <o2>Making people laugh while trying to sell them something is a tougher challenge, since the commercial can fall flat on two grounds.</o2>
        <o3>There are many advertisements which do amuse but do not even begin to set the cash tills ringing.</o3>
        <o4>Again, it is rarely sufficient for an advertiser simply to amuse the target audience in order to reap the sales benefit.</o4>
        <o5>There are indications that in substituting the hard sell for a more entertaining approach, some agencies have rather thrown out the baby with the bath water.</o5>
      </options>
      <answer>0|2|1|4|3|5</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>31906c4ea0d6461daee258d79effe232</id>
    <practiceSet>fc23cb5566904f8a98ee2bbf17a08f47</practiceSet>
    <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:59</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description> Werner Hoeflich spent the evening at his catering job, making white-wine spritzers and mixing vodka with Tab in a spacious apartment overlooking Central Park. There were orchids, thick rugs, a dog with long blond hair. He walked home late from the subway afterward, along the gated and padlocked streets of the Upper East Side. The trees on his block were scrawny and impervious, like invalid aunts. Once he had seen a parakeet in one of those trees, staring down at him, shifting from foot to foot. The bird had sharpened both sides of its beak on the branch and then made a veering, panicky flight to a windowsill far above. Most of Werner's metaphorical moments were painterly - the juxtaposing of the wild bird and the tame tree, the shimmer of the periwinkle, the splurt of titanium white that fell from it onto the pavement. He loved New York for its simple surprises, although in truth, Oregon and Iowa and Arizona and everywhere else had simple surprises as well. Cantaloupe-colored sunrises, banded cows, Dairy Queens, all kinds of things that didn't include black plastic mountains of trash and the smell of dog urine. </description>
      <title>With which of the following statements would the author of the passage most likely agree?</title>
      <options>
        <o0>Every aspect of New York is unique and admirable.</o0>
        <o1>Oregon, Iowa, and Arizona do not have any geographical merit.</o1>
        <o2>A single location can have many facets, both positive and negative.</o2>
        <o3>Large cities tend to lack whimsical and artistic sights.</o3>
      </options>
      <picture></picture>
      <answer>2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>f3d689a0b74040c0b0d3c71cb639c3f8</id>
    <practiceSet>fc23cb5566904f8a98ee2bbf17a08f47</practiceSet>
    <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:59</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>We, as a society, have hard choices to make. It would be nice if our politicians would tell us the truth, explain the tough issues, and give us some choices for how to solve the problems. But until there is a grassroots movement supporting discussion of difficult issues—until the supporting winds blow hard enough for politicians with their fingers in the wind to sense the need to do it—most politicians will continue to leave the tough issues in the Cone of Silence. Until we demonstrate that we can handle the truth, we can expect our politicians to keep lying to us. There will always be some politicians who will lie more than others and some who come very close to telling us the truth. It's easy enough to identify these two types: The lying politicians will usually be saying things that feel comfortable and require no effort on our part; the truth-telling politicians will usually be saying things we'd rather not hear and prefer not to think about.</description>
      <title>The main purpose of the given paragraph is that :-</title>
      <options>
        <o0>the expectations from politicians to tell the truth  depends on societies reaction.</o0>
        <o1>politicians either lie or keep silence instead of telling the truth.</o1>
        <o2>politicians prefer to manipulate the things instead of bringing truth in front of the public.</o2>
        <o3>people are not ready to accept the truth.</o3>
      </options>
      <picture></picture>
      <answer>0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>392bb1013bb3423aa95a4b7ee1659913</id>
    <practiceSet>fc23cb5566904f8a98ee2bbf17a08f47</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>The role that the Great Wall played in the growth of Chinese economy was an important one. Throughout the centuries many {blank} were established along the new border. The garrison troops were instructed to {blank} wasteland and to plant crops on it, roads and canals were built, to mention just a few of the works carried out. All these undertakings greatly helped to increase the country’s trade and cultural exchanges with many {blank} areas and also with the southern, central and western parts of Asia – the formation of the Silk Route. Builders, garrisons, artisans, farmers and peasants left behind a trail of objects, including {blank} tablets, household articles, and written work, which have become extremely valuable archaeological {blank} to the study of defense institutions of the Great Wall and the everyday life of these people who lived and died along the wall.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>evidence</o1>
          <o2>inscribed </o2>
          <o3>prescribing</o3>
          <o4>claim</o4>
          <o5>populated </o5>
          <o6>settlements</o6>
          <o7>reclaim</o7>
          <o8>remote</o8>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>5|6|7|1|0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>601de75bc9a84a1ebe854e95d12f1441</id>
    <practiceSet>fc23cb5566904f8a98ee2bbf17a08f47</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Hachiko, an Akita dog,was born in 1923 and brought to Tokyo in 1924. His owner, Professor Eisaburo Uyeno and he were {blank} friends right from the start. Each day Hachiko would {blank} his owner, a professor at the Imperial University, to Shibuya train station when he left for work. When he came back, the professor would always find the dog {blank} waiting for him. Sadly, the professor died suddenly at work in 1925 before he could return home.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>accompany</o1>
          <o2>patiently</o2>
          <o3>interact</o3>
          <o4>consistently</o4>
          <o5>inseparable</o5>
          <o6>good</o6>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>4|0|1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>75bfbc638c3f4a87b6b094b7fcfa2cb2</id>
    <practiceSet>fc23cb5566904f8a98ee2bbf17a08f47</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>People often ask which is the most difficult language to learn, and it is not easy to {blank} because there are many factors to take into {blank} . Firstly, in a first language the differences are unimportant as people learn their mother tongue {blank} ,  so the question of how hard a language is to learn is only {blank} when learning a second language.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>relevant</o1>
          <o2>consideration</o2>
          <o3>initially</o3>
          <o4>answer</o4>
          <o5>observation </o5>
          <o6>naturally</o6>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>3|1|5|0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>f16cd268e81840a181c945ed486e1c17</id>
    <practiceSet>fc23cb5566904f8a98ee2bbf17a08f47</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>In recent years, more and more lawns are evolving into organic systems as homeowners— {blank} about the long-term effects of chemicals on their children, their pets, and the environment—turn to natural methods to keep their yards healthy and inviting, and, yes, still green and lush, too. Paul Tukey, a self-confessed {blank}  addict, answers the growing demand for organic grass with a {blank}  volume of natural lawn care information. Step by step, he takes readers through the many elements that work together to form a healthy, {blank} lawn.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>focused</o1>
          <o2>organic</o2>
          <o3>comprehensive</o3>
          <o4>mowing</o4>
          <o5>green</o5>
          <o6>concerned</o6>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>5|3|2|1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>a0b44a46bb4a4d019c3a429e5c3cbfc2</id>
    <practiceSet>fc23cb5566904f8a98ee2bbf17a08f47</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:01:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Dividing his {blank} between Epicureanism and ethics, Taras Grescoe set out on a nine-month, worldwide search for a delicious—and humane— {blank} of seafood. What he discovered shocked him. From North American Red Lobsters to fish farms and research centers in China, Bottom feeder takes readers on an {blank} tour through the $55-billion-dollar-a-year seafood industry. Grescoe examines how out-of-control pollution, {blank} fishing practices, and climate change affect what ends up on our plate. More than a screed against a multibillion-dollar industry, however, this is also a balanced and {blank} guide to eating, as Grescoe explains to readers which fish are best for our environment, our seas, and our bodies.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>sensibilities </o1>
          <o2>understanding</o2>
          <o3>unregulated</o3>
          <o4>plate</o4>
          <o5>practical</o5>
          <o6>illuminating</o6>
          <o7>platter</o7>
          <o8>illegal</o8>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>0|3|5|2|4</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>9e586de2befc485db4613767cb8335fd</id>
    <practiceSet>fc23cb5566904f8a98ee2bbf17a08f47</practiceSet>
    <type>REORDER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:02:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Arrange the options.</description>
      <title></title>
      <options>
        <o0>Later on, people began to write on pieces of leather, which were rolled into scrolls.</o0>
        <o1>In the earliest times, people carved or painted messages on rocks.</o1>
        <o2>In the Middle Ages, heavy paper called parchment was used for writing and books were laboriously copied by hand.</o2>
        <o3>With the invention of the printing press in the middle of the fifteenth century, the modern printing industry was born.</o3>
        <o4>Some form of written communication has been used throughout the centuries.</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>4|1|0|2|3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>cff9fcf548854d518c8eebc64b72a487</id>
    <practiceSet>fc23cb5566904f8a98ee2bbf17a08f47</practiceSet>
    <type>REORDER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:02:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Arrange the options.</description>
      <title></title>
      <options>
        <o0>Passivity is not, of course, universal.</o0>
        <o1>So indeed it may be on the fringe of the un-submissive.</o1>
        <o2>However, for most of the soil-bound peasants the problem is not whether to be normally passive or active, but when to pass from one state to another.</o2>
        <o3>In areas where there are no lords or laws, or in frontier zones where all men go armed, the attitude of the peasantry may well be different.</o3>
        <o4>This depends on an assessment of the political situation.</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>0|3|2|1|4</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>515801df9cad4b1586cdccfab89fbe9f</id>
    <practiceSet>fc23cb5566904f8a98ee2bbf17a08f47</practiceSet>
    <type>REORDER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:02:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Arrange the options.</description>
      <title></title>
      <options>
        <o0>If you are used to having your stimulation come in from outside, your mind never develops its own habits of thinking and reflecting.</o0>
        <o1>Marx thought that religion was the opiate, because it soothed people's pain and suffering and prevented them from rising in rebellion.</o1>
        <o2>If Karl Marx was alive today, he would say that television is the opiate of the people.</o2>
        <o3>Television and similar entertainments are even more of an opiate because of their addictive tendencies.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>2|1|3|0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>d2dcc332381d40c3ade7e12dcbfbccba</id>
    <practiceSet>fc23cb5566904f8a98ee2bbf17a08f47</practiceSet>
    <type>MULTI_CHOICE_MULTIPLE_ANSWER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct response. More than one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:02:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>The levels of dissolved oxygen in the world’s ocean waters are declining precipitously. Just like humans, fish need oxygen to survive, and so in ocean areas experiencing significant levels of oxygen scarcity, or hypoxia, fish populations are plummeting. Although some hypoxic areas, called “dead zones,” occur naturally, hypoxia in coastal areas and inland waters is caused mainly by agricultural run-off and by discharge of industrial waste waters. More than one-hundred permanent dead zones, many covering thousands of square miles, exist worldwide today. Since reproductive success is the most critical factor in the sustainability of any species, the extent of this threat to marine life and genetic diversity can hardly be overstated. After several months in hypoxic waters, female fish produce fewer eggs. Moreover, hypoxic conditions serve to alter the normal ratio between two particular hormones manufactured during the embryonic stage when a fish’s gender is determined. During gestation and under these conditions, the mother produces more testosterone, which inhibits the development of female reproductive organs and other female characteristics in the embryo, while promoting the development of male traits. </description>
      <title>The author would probably view the developments discussed in the passage as</title>
      <options>
        <o0>alarming</o0>
        <o1>puzzling</o1>
        <o2>unsurprising</o2>
        <o3>critical</o3>
        <o4>unexpected</o4>
      </options>
      <picture></picture>
      <answer>0|3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>42c9444647c248dba3d207dd1f4c719c</id>
    <practiceSet>fc23cb5566904f8a98ee2bbf17a08f47</practiceSet>
    <type>MULTI_CHOICE_MULTIPLE_ANSWER</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct response. More than one response is correct.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:02:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Smart growth is an approach to development that concentrates on investing in existing communities. By directing growth to communities where people already live and work, smart growth limits the amount of farm land and open space that is developed, making existing communities more attractive; providing a mix of housing, restaurants, parks, cafes, and jobs; and minimizing the need for new water, sewer, and road infrastructure that would increase taxpayer burdens. For rural communities, smart growth means supporting town centers and main streets, attracting and encouraging growth and investment in and around these centers and within existing communities, thus preserving the character of rural towns.In contrast, sprawling development in rural, suburban, and urban areas is automobile-oriented, single-use development—frequently occurring along or at the intersection of nearby highways—that draws economic activity out of downtowns, damaging their vitality and dramatically increasing overall infrastructure needs. Smart growth, in contrast, simultaneously preserves open space and farm land while ensuring that there is an adequate supply of housing for families with a mix of incomes. Smart growth provides residents with a mix of shops, offices, restaurants, and other services that they can get to by automobile, bus, bike, or walking.</description>
      <title>Smart growth :-</title>
      <options>
        <o0>constructs modernized cities.</o0>
        <o1>utilizes open space to develop houses.</o1>
        <o2>focuses on investing in existing communities.</o2>
        <o3>increases the usage of commodities like water, sewer etc.</o3>
        <o4>make  basic facilities like shops, office and other services approachable.</o4>
      </options>
      <picture></picture>
      <answer>2|4</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>eebc5091c6d547fdbc9167245b489af7</id>
    <practiceSet>fc23cb5566904f8a98ee2bbf17a08f47</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Manifestos on the Future of Food and Seed  is a collection of essays that goes to the heart of our {blank}—what we eat and how we grow it. We live in a world with 80,000 edible plants, but only about 150 are cultivated; a world of agricultural {blank} and rampant obesity, yet 800 million still suffer from malnutrition; a world where food is {blank} to travel long distances rather than to be nutritious and flavorful. Manifestos offers {blank} to reverse perhaps the worst food crisis faced in human history.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>desires</o1>
          <o2>strength</o2>
          <o3>feelings</o3>
          <o4>existence</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>sector</o1>
          <o2>development</o2>
          <o3>abundance</o3>
          <o4>research</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>grown</o1>
          <o2>cultivated</o2>
          <o3>modified </o3>
          <o4>stored</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>prescriptions</o1>
          <o2>alternative </o2>
          <o3>solution</o3>
          <o4>basis</o4>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>3|2|2|0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>9017771b0cb24819ab476c8e78f9daf1</id>
    <practiceSet>fc23cb5566904f8a98ee2bbf17a08f47</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>As part of the resurgence of Maori culture, the traditional crafts of carving and weaving are now more {blank}  practiced and Maori artists are increasing in number and influence. Most Maori carvings {blank} human figures, generally with three fingers and either a natural-looking, detailed head or a grotesque head. Surface patterns consisting of spirals, ridges, notches and fish scales decorate most {blank} . The pre-eminent Maori architecture consisted of carved meeting houses decorated with symbolic carvings and illustrations. These buildings were originally designed to be constantly rebuilt, changing and adapting to different {blank} or needs</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>hugely</o1>
          <o2>widely</o2>
          <o3>extremely</o3>
          <o4>largely </o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>feature</o1>
          <o2>elaborate</o2>
          <o3>exemplify</o3>
          <o4>emerge</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>sculptures</o1>
          <o2>statues</o2>
          <o3>idols</o3>
          <o4>carvings</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>requirements </o1>
          <o2>whims</o2>
          <o3>wish</o3>
          <o4>aspects</o4>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>1|0|3|1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>b6b7a0d4d1b543f2993a8220557a3712</id>
    <practiceSet>fc23cb5566904f8a98ee2bbf17a08f47</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>The global population of wild tigers remains {blank} low at fewer than 3500 individuals. Habitat loss, along with {blank} , can undermine the international target recovery of doubling the number of wild tigers by 2022. Using a new satellite-based monitoring system, we {blank} 14 years of forest loss data within the 76 landscapes that have been prioritized for conservation of wild tigers. Our analysis provides an update of the status of tiger habitat and describes new applications of technology to detect {blank} where forest loss is occurring in order to {blank} future habitat loss. </description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>extremely</o1>
          <o2>dangerously</o2>
          <o3>categorically</o3>
          <o4>approximately </o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>killing</o1>
          <o2>preserving</o2>
          <o3>underestimating</o3>
          <o4>poaching</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>examined</o1>
          <o2>experimented </o2>
          <o3>analyzed</o3>
          <o4>detected </o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>closely</o1>
          <o2>unsurely</o2>
          <o3>slightly</o3>
          <o4>precisely</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>curb</o1>
          <o2>maintain</o2>
          <o3>retain</o3>
          <o4>stimulate</o4>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>1|3|2|3|0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>8f764cdd7cc346d0a79384f9b7c0c554</id>
    <practiceSet>fc23cb5566904f8a98ee2bbf17a08f47</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Communities across the country have {blank} that protecting open space, parks, and farm land is a {blank}  that can be used to strengthen existing communities, attract businesses, and avoid the costs of urban and urban {blank} . As part of a package of smart growth programs and {blank} , communities that offer a high quality of life {blank} attract and retain businesses.</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>discovered</o1>
          <o2>found</o2>
          <o3>analyzed</o3>
          <o4>invented</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>strategy</o1>
          <o2>way</o2>
          <o3>path</o3>
          <o4>approach</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>compression</o1>
          <o2>straightening</o2>
          <o3>sprawl</o3>
          <o4>culture</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>discoveries</o1>
          <o2>strategies</o2>
          <o3>policies</o3>
          <o4>communities</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>consistently</o1>
          <o2>constantly</o2>
          <o3>rarely</o3>
          <o4>mostly</o4>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>1|0|2|2|0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>1e64e175e5eb4ddc9478c9a01a89fb78</id>
    <practiceSet>fc23cb5566904f8a98ee2bbf17a08f47</practiceSet>
    <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
    <itemType>READING</itemType>
    <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Achilles was the strongest and most {blank} warrior in the Greek war against the Trojans. As an infant his mother dipped him into the River Styx, which made him {blank} everywhere but the heel by which she held him. For ten years Achilles was a great hero in the Trojan War. But in the end Paris, son of the Trojan king, {blank} wounded Achilles in the heel. Today, the tendon that connects the calf muscles to the heel bone is called the Achilles tendon, and a small but {blank} weakness is known as an “Achilles heel.”</description>
      <title></title>
      <blanks>
        <blank>
          <o1>fearless</o1>
          <o2>powerful</o2>
          <o3>strong</o3>
          <o4>cruel</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>vulnerable</o1>
          <o2>uncertain</o2>
          <o3>responsive</o3>
          <o4>invulnerable</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>possibly</o1>
          <o2>inconsiderably</o2>
          <o3>fatally</o3>
          <o4>casually</o4>
        </blank>
        <blank>
          <o1>minor</o1>
          <o2>dangerous</o2>
          <o3>considerable</o3>
          <o4>noticeable</o4>
        </blank>
      </blanks>
      <answer>0|3|2|1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
</questions>
