<?xml version = "1.0"?>
<questions>

<question>
  <id>84f955d0b52b42999fe1e2c8338e86d1</id>
  <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>A recent survey has shown that the number of people in the United Kingdom who do not {blank} to get internet access has risen. These people, who are {blank} as 'net refuse niks', make up 44% of UK households, or 11.2 million people in total. The research also showed that more than 70 percent of these people said that they were not interested in getting {blank} to the internet. This number has risen from just over 50% in 2005, with most giving {blank} of computer skills as a reason for not getting internet access, though some also said it was because of the cost.</description>
    <title>Reading - Reading: Fill in the blanks - Q1</title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>Called</o0>
        <o1>intend</o1>
        <o2>extend </o2>
        <o3>lack</o3>
        <o4>less</o4>
        <o5>connected</o5>
        <o6>known</o6>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>1|6|5|3</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>e4a0da7ab02141a7b42f4dfc9f8d5aa6</id>
  <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Ada Lovelace was the daughter of the poet Lord Byron. She was taught by Mary Somerville, a well-known {blank} and scientific author, who introduced her to Charles Babbage in June 1833. Babbage was an English mathematician, who first had the idea for a programmable computer.
In 1842 and 1843, Ada {blank} the work of an Italian mathematician, Luigi Menabrea, on Babbage's Analytical Engine. Though mechanical, this machine was an important step in the history of computers; it was the design of a mechanical general-purpose computer. Babbage worked on it for many years until his death in 1871. However, because of {blank} , political, and legal issues, the engine was never built. The design of the machine was very modern; it {blank} the first completed general-purpose computers by about 100 years.</description>
    <title>Reading - Reading: Fill in the blanks - Q2</title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>anticipated</o0>
        <o1>economic </o1>
        <o2>translated</o2>
        <o3> researcher</o3>
        <o4>philosophers </o4>
        <o5>financial</o5>
        <o6>contributed</o6>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>3|2|5|0</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>2470d3967a0d4fe4ab073fa3dd892c28</id>
  <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>The tiny black computer with its rubber keys {blank} the home computer age both in the UK and elsewhere, which led to a {blank} in computer manufacturing and developed software programmers whose talent is still {blank} today. The ZX Spectrum was the brainchild of the entrepreneur Clive Sinclair, who had previously developed one of the first cheap and slim pocket calculators. The Spectrum was Sinclair's fourth computer, but was by far the most {blank} .</description>
    <title>Reading - Reading: Fill in the blanks - Q3</title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>successful </o0>
        <o1>proved</o1>
        <o2> boom</o2>
        <o3>ignited</o3>
        <o4>evident</o4>
        <o5>invent</o5>
        <o6>exploding</o6>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>5|2|4|0</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>744b82f1b4b6420ab7f192a90587714b</id>
  <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>It's important to remember that Bhopal was not an {blank} accident, it was a manifestation of corporate penny {blank} on maintenance and upgrades at an industrial facility that handled deadly reagents. It's {blank} rare that we put corporate executives or board members on trial for such failures, but that should change. Their personal fortunes are made by {blank} the revenue from such operations in good times; their liberty and wealth should be at risk when it goes wrong due to their {blank} .</description>
    <title>Reading - Reading: Fill in the blanks - Q4</title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>Ignore</o0>
        <o1>very</o1>
        <o2>mismanagement</o2>
        <o3>reaping</o3>
        <o4>squeezed</o4>
        <o5>unavoidable</o5>
        <o6>extremely</o6>
        <o7>pinching</o7>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>5|7|6|3|2</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>4e279eb1e79044dfa6cbf6d94d403b12</id>
  <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank. To undo answer choice, click on reset button.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>When Diane Wilson, fourth-generation shrimp-boat captain and mother of five, learns that she lives in the most polluted county in the United States, she decides to fight back. She {blank}  a campaign against a multibillion-dollar corporation that has been covering up spills, silencing workers, flouting the EPA, and dumping lethal ethylene dichloride and vinyl chloride into the bays along her beloved Texas Gulf Coast. In an epic tale of {blank} , Wilson takes her fight to the courts, to the gates of the chemical plant, and to the halls of power in Austin. Along the way she meets with scorn, bribery, character {blank} , and death threats. Finally Wilson realizes that she must break the law to win justice: She resorts to nonviolent {blank} , direct action, and hunger strikes.</description>
    <title>Reading - Reading: Fill in the blanks - Q5</title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>launches </o0>
        <o1>disobedience</o1>
        <o2>setup</o2>
        <o3>adventurous</o3>
        <o4>extermination</o4>
        <o5>bravery</o5>
        <o6>assassination</o6>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>0|5|6|1</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>19c11cc3d5354009b4483ec9dcdeca9d</id>
  <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Over the past two decades, an extreme view of global warming has developed. While it contains some facts, this view also contains exaggerations and misstatements, and has sometimes resulted in unreasonable environmental policies.
According to this view, global warming will cause the polar ice to melt, raising global sea levels, flooding entire regions, destroying crops, and displacing millions of people. However, there is still a great deal of uncertainty regarding a potential rise in sea levels. Certainly, if the earth warms, sea levels will rise as the water heats up and expands. If the polar ice caps melt, more water will be added to the oceans, raising sea levels even further. There is some evidence that melting has occurred; however, there is also evidence that the Antarctic ice sheets are growing. In fact, it is possible that a warmer sea surface temperature will cause more water to evaporate, and when wind carries the moisture-laden air over the land, it will precipitate out as snow, causing the ice sheets to grow. Certainly, we need to have better knowledge about the hydrological cycle before predicting dire consequences as a result of recent increases in global temperatures.
This view also exaggerates the impact that human activity has on the planet. While human activity may be a factor in global warming, natural events appear to be far more important. Climate variability has always existed and will continue to do so, regardless of human intervention.

Which one of the following is true as per the given passage?</description>
    <title>Reading - Multiple choice, choose single answer - Q6</title>
    <options>
      <o0>Sea level is going to increase to great extent.</o0>
      <o1>Global warming is not only attributed to human activities but to natural climate changes also.</o1>
      <o2>Certain steps are required to reduce the rate of global warming.</o2>
      <o3>Global warming is caused by variations in the sun’s radiation and the earth’s orbit?</o3>
    </options>
	<picture></picture>
    <answer>1</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>8e7b42971ba946609f4f0403c1dcc623</id>
  <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>It should be no surprise that anti-Semitism still exists, just as bigotry against blacks, or Muslims, or Sikhs, or Tutsis, or indeed Catholics still goes on. That Jews were the victims of the most systematic genocide ever attempted lend a particularly sinister resonance to anti-Semitism, but as a prejudice it is hardly unique. Mass murder of the Jews, at least in the Western world, is no longer on the agenda, and it is surely not what Gibson had in mind [in his 2007 outburst]. But social prejudice is bad enough. It is at least one sign of progress that anti-Semitism, like racial prejudice against black people, is no longer socially acceptable. We cannot call people 'yids' or 'niggers' without being taken to task for it, and this is a good thing. According to the author of 'Mentality' of a nation is mainly product of its.

Which technique or device does the author NOT use in this passage?
</description>
    <title>Reading - Multiple choice, choose single answer - Q7</title>
    <options>
      <o0>Broad generalizations.</o0>
      <o1>Rhetorical questions</o1>
      <o2>Ethos</o2>
      <o3>Comparisons and analogy.</o3>
    </options>
	<picture></picture>
    <answer>1</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>d5a0329c4b04432ca998f2f9951e76a0</id>
  <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
  <type>REORDER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description></description>
    <title>Reading - Re-order Paragraphs - Q8</title>
    <options>
      <o1>Events intervened, and in the late 1930s and 1940s, Germany suffered from “over-branding”.</o1>
      <o2>The British used to be fascinated by the home of Romanticism.</o2>
      <o3>But reunification and the federal government's move to Berlin have prompted Germany to think again about its image.</o3>
      <o4>The first foreign package holiday was a tour of Germany organized by Thomas Cook in 1855.</o4>
      <o5>Since then, Germany has been understandably nervous about promoting itself abroad.</o5>
    </options>
    <answer>2|0|4|1|3</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>7914653043754f74821e0a2d2b014bb0</id>
  <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
  <type>REORDER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>The text boxes in the left panel have been placed in a random order. Restore the original order by moving the text boxes from the left panel to the right panel.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description></description>
    <title>Reading - Re-order Paragraphs - Q9</title>
    <options>
      <o1>They argue that it is this, which has led to the bankruptcy in many states.</o1>
      <o2>Here was a commission whose members worked very hard, did exemplary research and homework, before coming up with a list of recommendations that balanced economic efficiency with safety nets for disadvantaged labour.</o2>
      <o3>It reminds us of the political shenanigans during the implementation of the Fifth pay Commission.</o3>
      <o4>How many times have you heard experts, politicians and the finance minister refer to the implementation of the pay hikes following the commission's report as the singular cause for the increase in government expenditure?</o4>
      <o5>Barring P. Chidambram, who was then the finance minister, every single political party and politician opposed the implementation of the recommendations and are directly responsible for the current fiscal crises in the Centre and the states.</o5>
    </options>
    <answer>2|3|0|1|4</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>00f208a297d9485eac91d26fae415f80</id>
  <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_MULTIPLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct response. More than one response is correct.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Many people like to eat pizza, but not everyone knows how to make it. Making the perfect pizza can be complicated, but there are lots of ways for you to make a more basic version at home. When you make pizza, you must begin with the crust. The crust can be hard to make. If you want to make the crust yourself, you will have to make dough using flour, water, and yeast. You will have to knead the dough with your hands. If you do not have enough time to do this, you can use a prepared crust that you buy from the store. 
After you have chosen your crust, you must then add the sauce. Making your own sauce from scratch can take a long time. You have to buy tomatoes, peel them, and then cook them with spices. If this sounds like too much work, you can also purchase jarred sauce from the store. Many jarred sauces taste almost as good as the kind you make at home. 
Now that you have your crust and your sauce, you need to add the cheese. Cheese comes from milk, which comes from cows. Do you have a cow in your backyard? Do you know how to milk the cow? Do you know how to turn that milk into cheese? If not, you might want to buy cheese from the grocery store instead of making it yourself. When you have the crust, sauce, and cheese ready, you can add other toppings. Some people like to put meat on their pizza, while other people like to add vegetables. Some people even like to add pineapple! The best part of making a pizza at home is that you can customize it by adding your own favorite ingredients.
 

According to the author, which of the following ingredients do you need to have ready before you can add the toppings? </description>
    <title>Reading - Multiple choice, choose multiple answer - Q10</title>
    <options>
      <o0>crust</o0>
      <o1>milk</o1>
      <o2>sauce</o2>
      <o3>patatoes</o3>
      <o4>pulses</o4>
      <o5>cheese</o5>
    </options>
    <answer>0|2|5</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>996d267e496d431f9317789116725dd6</id>
  <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_MULTIPLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>Read the text and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct response. More than one response is correct.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description> Have you ever wondered what keeps a hot air balloon flying? The same principle that keeps food frozen in the open chest freezers at the grocery store allows hot air balloons to fly. It's a very basic principle: Hot air rises and cold air falls. So while the super-cooled air in the grocery store freezer settles down around the food, the hot air in a hot air balloon pushes up, keeping the balloon floating above the ground. In order to understand more about how this principle works in hot air balloons, it helps to know more about hot air balloons themselves. 
A hot air balloon has three major parts: the basket, the burner, and the envelope. The basket is where passengers ride. The basket is usually made of wicker. This ensures that it will be comfortable and add little extra weight. The burner is positioned above the passenger's heads and produces a huge flame to heat the air inside the envelope. The envelope is the colorful fabric balloon that holds the hot air. When the air inside the envelope is heated, the balloon rises. 
The pilot can control the up-and-down movements of the hot air balloon by regulating the heat in the envelope. To ascend, the pilot heats the air in the envelope. When the pilot is ready to land, the air in the balloon is allowed to cool and the balloon becomes heavier than air. This makes the balloon descend. 
Before the balloon is launched, the pilot knows which way the wind is blowing. This means that she has a general idea about which way the balloon will go. But, sometimes the pilot can actually control the direction that the balloon flies while in flight. This is because the air above the ground is sectioned into layers in which the direction of the wind may be different. So even though the pilot can't steer the balloon, she can fly or higher or lower into a different layer of air. Some days the difference between the direction of the wind between layers is negligible. But other days the difference is so strong that it can actually push the balloon in a completely different direction!


Using the passage as a guide, it can be inferred that which of the following statements are true? </description>
    <title>Reading - Multiple choice, choose multiple answer - Q11</title>
    <options>
      <o0>Air goes up and out the top of a chimney when you light a fire.</o0>
      <o1>Cool air collects about the ceiling when you open a refrigerator.</o1>
      <o2>its not possible to control the direction of balloon.</o2>
      <o3>Smoke from a candle rises after you blow out the flame.</o3>
      <o4>Cold air coming from an air conditioning vent settles about the floor.</o4>
    </options>
    <answer>0|3|4</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>c51337d535844a17a516a4a4a7efe0a5</id>
  <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>With all the {blank} information about what and how to eat for good health, is it any wonder that the majority of us are both overweight and undernourished?
In What to Eat, internationally {blank} nutrition expert Dr. Luise Light cuts through the confusion created by {blank} advertising, fad diet doctors, and the big food lobbies to answer all your nutrition-related questions. Even more important, she arms you with a simple, research-based eating plan {blank} to help you look and feel better than ever--without having to {blank} taste or turn your life upside down.
</description>
    <title>Reading - Reading &amp; Writing: Fill in the blanks - Q12</title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>available</o0>
        <o1>conflicting</o1>
        <o2>unknown</o2>
        <o3>misguiding</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>respected</o0>
        <o1>reputed</o1>
        <o2>known</o2>
        <o3>famous</o3>
        <o4>misleading</o4>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>misleading</o0>
        <o1>misguiding</o1>
        <o2>false</o2>
        <o3>uncensored</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>guaranteed</o0>
        <o1>made</o1>
        <o2>guide</o2>
        <o3>committed</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>compromise</o0>
        <o1>adjust</o1>
        <o2>sacrifice</o2>
        <o3>compensating</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>1|0|0|0|2</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>07ebee190194495a937258d4499a9761</id>
  <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>The UN report says that there is a small window of {blank} in this century for limiting the global temperature increase to 2 degrees centigrade. If this is not done, humanity will face a series of climactic changes that will {blank} havoc on the planet. These will include flooding of coastal areas, crop failures, epidemics, severe water scarcity and increase in natural disasters. According to the report, climate change will affect the world’s poor most. Global warming will {blank} droughts and flooding which will destroy the sources of live hood for poor people in Africa, Asia and South America. The poorer sections will also be the most {blank} to health disaster like spread of malaria and diarrhea. The H.D.R also makes it clear that the rich countries have to take the main responsibility for controlling emissions.</description>
    <title>Reading - Reading &amp; Writing: Fill in the blanks - Q13</title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>desire</o0>
        <o1>opportunity</o1>
        <o2>hope</o2>
        <o3>restriction</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>emphasize</o0>
        <o1>develop</o1>
        <o2>consider</o2>
        <o3>wreak</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>initiate</o0>
        <o1>contribute</o1>
        <o2>bestow</o2>
        <o3>accord</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>prone</o0>
        <o1>dangerous</o1>
        <o2>initiate</o2>
        <o3>open</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>1|3|0|0</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>7458a897b6ee42a4b9c20e8b3f7ed8e2</id>
  <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Most experts agree that global peak oil production, when demand exceeds supply, will occur within the next 15 years and will {blank} change the very fabric of our industrialized world. As fossil fuels power every {blank} of the American economy, how can we avoid an energy crisis and a possible {blank} of our economy? Today, China and India have {blank} to attain our western quality of life; but at the rate and the way we use the world's energy resources, their ambition will be physically impossible. In addition to increasing geopolitical conflicts, the process of extracting and using these crucial resources is {blank} the very own habitat that we depend on to prosper as a species - pushing the earth's climate and ecosystem to a point of no-return. It is clear that in order for us to survive our modern self-destructive societies, we will have to change course drastically and as fast as possible.</description>
    <title>Reading - Reading &amp; Writing: Fill in the blanks - Q14</title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>dramatically</o0>
        <o1>drastically</o1>
        <o2>perhaps</o2>
        <o3>immediately</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>facet</o0>
        <o1>situation</o1>
        <o2>fact</o2>
        <o3>stage</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>collapse</o0>
        <o1>expansion</o1>
        <o2>downfall</o2>
        <o3>plunge</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>aspirations</o0>
        <o1>aspire</o1>
        <o2>inspiration</o2>
        <o3>desire</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>jeopardize</o0>
        <o1>refraining</o1>
        <o2>engendering</o2>
        <o3>insuring</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>1|0|0|0|2</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>194c89d336134e8d9876a045904af688</id>
  <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Although the schooling of fish is {blank} form of animal social behavior, how the school is formed and maintained is only beginning to be understood in detail. It had been thought that each fish maintains its position {blank} by means of vision. Our work as shown that, as each fish maintains its position, the lateral line, an organ sensitive to transitory changes in water {blank} , is as important as vision. In each species a fish has a “preferred” distance and dangle from its nearest neighbor. The ideal separation and bearing, however, are not maintained rigidly. The result is a {blank} arrangement that appears like a random aggregation. The tendency of the fish to remain at the preferred distance and angle, however, serves to maintain the structure. Each fish, having established its position, uses its eyes and its lateral lines simultaneously to measure the speed of all the other fish in the school. It then adjusts its own speed to match a weighted average that {blank} the contribution of nearby fish.</description>
    <title>Reading - Reading &amp; Writing: Fill in the blanks - Q15</title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>familiar</o0>
        <o1>invented</o1>
        <o2>existing</o2>
        <o3>unknown</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>mainly</o0>
        <o1>basically</o1>
        <o2>chiefly</o2>
        <o3>considered</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>flow</o0>
        <o1>reconciliation</o1>
        <o2>storage</o2>
        <o3>displacement</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>probabilistic</o0>
        <o1>proper</o1>
        <o2>problematic</o2>
        <o3>deterministic</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>emphasizes</o0>
        <o1>values</o1>
        <o2>ignores</o2>
        <o3>considers </o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>0|2|3|0|0</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>b292b8022bc74061986c766bb5649674</id>
  <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction>In the text below some words are missing. Click on each blank, a list of choices will appear. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Harrisburg, now part of Houston, {blank} in 1823, and Houston itself, founded in 1836 by J. K. and A. C. Allen and named for Sam Houston, was promoted as a {blank} to Harrisburg and soon served as capital of the Texas republic. In the course of the 19th cent. Houston grew from a muddy town on Buffalo Bayou to a {blank} railroad center. However, its {blank} expansion came after the digging of a ship channel on Buffalo Bayou and Galveston Bay, linking it to the Gulf and making it a deepwater port. The development of the coastal oil fields poured quick wealth into the city; the natural gas, sulfur, salt, and limestone deposits also in the area laid the basis for its great chemical {blank}.</description>
    <title>Reading - Reading &amp; Writing: Fill in the blanks - Q16</title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>was settling</o0>
        <o1>was settled</o1>
        <o2>had settled</o2>
        <o3>settled</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>supportive</o0>
        <o1>associate</o1>
        <o2>rival</o2>
        <o3>oppose</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>prosperous</o0>
        <o1>expensive</o1>
        <o2>dense </o2>
        <o3>populated</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>sensible</o0>
        <o1>huge</o1>
        <o2>creative</o2>
        <o3>phenomenal</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>production</o0>
        <o1>reaction</o1>
        <o2>equation</o2>
        <o3>reactor</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>1|2|0|3|0</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>ff3a931c6ac94374989c4c7f8a80695a</id>
  <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction></instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>"As a farmer I was determined that we should get on the computer bandwagon", says Krishnappa Jagannath, the 40-year old head of the Gram Panchayat who initiated the whole process three years ago. With tips from a computer, and his brother in the US, Jagannath drew up a plan and convinced others of its merit. Within no time, he was able to raise Rs. 65,000 from the public, enough for the purchase of two assembled Pentium II computers. That was easy enough, but who would operate these machines? Jagannath decided that it had to be the villagers themselves. He got in touch with a software company, which agreed to train the villagers. Although wary initially, the people knew it was worth a try. As they realized it was not so difficult, more and more villagers joined in. Those like T. S. Shobha who showed a greater aptitude were sent for extensive training.

The urge in Krishnappa Jagannath's mind was
</description>
    <title>Reading - Multiple choice, choose single answer - Q1</title>
    <options>
      <o0>To buy a computer for his home.</o0>
      <o1>To initiate a computer revolution in his village.</o1>
      <o2>To start cleanliness drives in the village.</o2>
      <o3>To spread awareness about computers among the masses.</o3>
    </options>
    <answer>1</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>71a6a6d4aa464e4ca7a1bbd5fd40e17e</id>
  <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_SINGLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction></instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Can a person’s greatness be recognized only in retrospect, by those who live after him? In my view this is unfairly generalized. In some areas, especially the arts, greatness is often recognizable in its nascent stages. However, in other areas, particularly the physical sciences, greatness must be tested over time before it can be confirmed. In still other areas, such as business, the incubation period for greatness varies from case to case. We do not require a rear-view mirror to recognize artistic greatness whether in music, visual arts, or literature. The reason for this is simple: art can be judged at face value. There’s nothing to be later proved or disproved, affirmed or discredited, or even improved upon or refined by further knowledge or newer technology. History is replete with examples of artistic greatness immediately recognized, then later confirmed.

What is the author’s perspective on recognizing a person’s greatness or caliber?
</description>
    <title>Reading - Multiple choice, choose single answer - Q2</title>
    <options>
		<o0>It is unfair to give recognition only after reciprocating the work.</o0>
      <o1>People who live after a great man are not the best judges of his work.</o1>
      <o2>It is unfair to assume that whatever be the case, it is only after he is gone, that one can retrospect his work.</o2>
      <o3>It is unfounded to assume that, in all cases, this recognition can be done only after he is no more.</o3>
	</options>
    <answer>2</answer>
	<picture></picture>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>5a59aa205a03472e8724e0b68b1540ef</id>
  <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_MULTIPLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction></instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>In Asia and much of the third World, trees are still destroyed in the old-fashioned way: they are cut down for fuel and cropland. In Europe, there is a new and potentially more deadly culprit. The German call it 'Waldsterben', the dying forest syndrome. But the disease is far more than a German phenomenon. Since it was first observed by German scientists in the autumn of 1980, the mysterious malady has raced across Europe, blighting woods in countries as far apart as Sweden and Italy. Explanations for the epidemic range from a cyclic change in the environment to a baffling form of tree cancer. But the most convincing evidence points to air pollution. Indeed, saving the rapidly deteriorating forests of Europe will probably require a two-pronged strategy: an offensive campaign that includes the breeding of pollution-immune trees and a defensive scheme that calls for reductions in toxic emissions. But both will require more money than is currently being spent on such measures, as well as total commitment to protecting the environment.

What are the points of target that the strategy to fight the problem of dying forests includes in itself?</description>
    <title>Reading - Multiple choice, choose multiple answer - Q3</title>
    <options>
		<o0>Finding methods to sustain life for trees and all types of vegetation.</o0>
      <o1>An aggressive movement directed towards breeding of trees that are resistant to pollution.</o1>
      <o2>Conservative efforts for demanding reduction in emission of toxic substances which lead to air pollution.</o2>
      <o3>The attempts to save the trees from being cut and popularizing other alternatives for their use.</o3>
	  <o4>Making available more and more scientific methods that can help reduce the air pollution.</o4>
	</options>
    <answer>1|2</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>f1211069c1714cf6880f169af0326d72</id>
  <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
  <type>MULTI_CHOICE_MULTIPLE_ANSWER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction></instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Though the U.S. prides itself on being a leader in the world community, a recent report shows that it lags far behind other industrialized countries in meeting the needs of its youngest and most vulnerable citizens. The U.S. has a higher infant mortality rate, a higher proportion of low birth weight babies, a smaller proportion of babies immunized against childhood diseases and a much higher rate of adolescent pregnancies. These findings, described as a "quiet crisis" requiring immediate and far-reaching action, appeared in a report prepared by a task force of educators, doctors, politicians and business people. According to the report, a fourth of the nation's 12 million infants and toddlers live in poverty. As many as half confront risk factors that could harm their ability to develop intellectually, physically and socially. Child immunizations are too low, more children are born into poverty and more are in substandard care while their parents work and more are being raised by single parents. When taken together, these and other risk factors can lead to educational and health problems that are much harder and more costly to reverse.

What were the requirements posed by the "quiet crisis" report?
</description>
    <title>Reading - Multiple choice, choose multiple answer - Q4</title>
    <options>
	<o0>Distribution of the report among the common masses.</o0>
      <o1>To focus on the costs that the revealed factors may incur on the government.</o1>
      <o2>To pay heed to the various statistical figures and reports.</o2>
      <o3>No immediate action on the findings laid down.</o3>
	  <o4>Far reaching impact of the actions taken.</o4>
	</options>
    <answer>1|2|4</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>35e778bac7e648c2b315a13ea9372ab9</id>
  <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
  <type>REORDER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction></instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description></description>
    <title>Reading - Re-order Paragraphs - Q5</title>
    <options>
      <o1>Events intervened, and in the late 1930s and 1940s, Germany suffered from “over-branding”.</o1>
      <o2>The British used to be fascinated by the home of Romanticism.</o2>
      <o3>But reunification and the federal government's move to Berlin have prompted Germany to think again about its image.</o3>
      <o4>The first foreign package holiday was a tour of Germany organized by Thomas Cook in 1855.</o4>
      <o5>Since then, Germany has been understandably nervous about promoting itself abroad.</o5>
    </options>
    <answer>2|0|4|1|3</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>0057b38dd38442fb853f6fd4ba108b4d</id>
  <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
  <type>REORDER</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction></instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description></description>
    <title>Reading - Re-order Paragraphs - Q6</title>
    <options>
      <o1>He is like a Kantian listening to consequentialist arguments: he refuses to think that way.</o1>
      <o2>But on the other hand, that is "not what they should say, given their position as a whole".</o2>
      <o3>Suppose Jones has a religious conviction that he should base his political views on his religious convictions.</o3>
      <o4>Jones listens to the arguments and objections of others with different views, but is unconvinced.</o4>
      <o5>On the one hand, public reason liberals might seem to tell Jones to refrain from public discussion and voting.</o5>
    </options>
    <answer>2|4|0|1|3</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>263042c3778447ee93eea31f0c59883c</id>
  <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction></instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>In 1955, Rosa Parks was an African American living in Montgomery, Alabama - a city with laws that strictly {blank} blacks and whites. On 1 December 1955, after her day of work as a seamstress at a local department store, Rosa Parks boarded a city bus. When she refused to give up her seat to a white man, the bus driver called police, and Rosa Parks was {blank} and fined. The resulting bus boycott by African-Americans, led by Reverend Martin Luther King, Jr., caused a national {blank}. The boycott was a success and led to desegregation in Montgomery and elsewhere in the United States. Over time, Rosa Parks became a national icon of civil rights and African-American pride. Parks worked as an aide to Michigan Congressman John Conyers, Jr. from 1966 until her {blank} in 1988, and she founded the Rosa and Raymond Parks Institute for Self Development in 1987. She was awarded the Presidential Medal of Freedom by Bill Clinton in 1996.</description>
    <title>Reading - Reading: Fill in the blanks - Q7</title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>Isolated</o0>
        <o1>penalized	</o1>
        <o2>retirement	</o2>
        <o3>sensation</o3>
        <o4>segregated</o4>
        <o5>establishment</o5>
        <o6>restricted</o6>
        <o7>arrested</o7>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>Isolated</o0>
        <o1>penalized</o1>
        <o2>retirement</o2>
        <o3>sensation</o3>
        <o4>segregated</o4>
        <o5>establishment</o5>
        <o6>restricted</o6>
        <o7>arrested</o7>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>Isolated</o0>
        <o1>penalized	</o1>
        <o2>retirement	</o2>
        <o3>sensation</o3>
        <o4>segregated</o4>
        <o5>establishment </o5>
        <o6>restricted</o6>
        <o7>arrested</o7>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>Isolated</o0>
        <o1>penalized</o1>
        <o2>retirement</o2>
        <o3>sensation</o3>
        <o4>segregated</o4>
        <o5>establishment</o5>
        <o6>restricted </o6>
        <o7>arrested</o7>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>4|7|3|2</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>d069921ff3804d9c972cbdbf2da9b253</id>
  <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction></instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>By the middle of the 18th century, differences in life, thought, and interests had {blank} between the mother country and the growing colonies. Local political institutions and practice {blank} significantly from English ways, while social customs, religious beliefs, and economic interests added to the {blank} sources of conflict. The British government, like other imperial powers in the 18th century, favored a policy of {blank} the Navigation Acts were intended to regulate commerce in the British interest. These were only loosely enforced, however, and the colonies were by and large allowed to develop freely with little {blank} from England.</description>
    <title>Reading - Reading: Fill in the blanks - Q8</title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>diverged</o0>
        <o1>huge</o1>
        <o2>mercantilism</o2>
        <o3>developed</o3>
        <o4>existence</o4>
        <o5>interference</o5>
        <o6>segregated</o6>
        <o7>potential</o7>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>diverged</o0>
        <o1>huge</o1>
        <o2>mercantilism</o2>
        <o3>developed</o3>
        <o4>existence</o4>
        <o5>interference</o5>
        <o6>segregated</o6>
        <o7>potential</o7>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>diverged</o0>
        <o1>huge</o1>
        <o2>mercantilism</o2>
        <o3>developed</o3>
        <o4>existence</o4>
        <o5>interference</o5>
        <o6>segregated</o6>
        <o7>potential</o7>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>diverged</o0>
        <o1>huge</o1>
        <o2>mercantilism</o2>
        <o3>developed</o3>
        <o4>existence</o4>
        <o5>interference</o5>
        <o6>segregated</o6>
        <o7>potential</o7>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>diverged</o0>
        <o1>huge</o1>
        <o2>mercantilism</o2>
        <o3>developed</o3>
        <o4>existence</o4>
        <o5>interference</o5>
        <o6>segregated</o6>
        <o7>potential</o7>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>3|0|7|2|5</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>d169275510524d42903538a9d3399ce0</id>
  <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction></instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Louis Armstrong was the most{blank}jazz trumpeter of the 20th century. Like Jelly Roll Morton, Armstrong began playing in New Orleans clubs and saloons in his early teens. By the 1920s Armstrong was {blank} the country and leading his own band, the Hot Five, later the Hot Seven. He continued to tour and record throughout his life and was particularly famous for his {blank}, loose-limbed improvisations; some call him the first great jazz improviser. His gravelly voice and sunny {blank} were a hit with the non-jazz public, and later in his career he became a sort of cheerful ambassador of jazz, even appearing as himself in movies like High Society and Hello, Dolly!. The theme song from the latter film became his most {blank} known recording.</description>
    <title>Reading - Reading: Fill in the blanks - Q9</title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>hugely</o0>
        <o1>famous</o1>
        <o2>persona </o2>
        <o3>visiting</o3>
        <o4>widely</o4>
        <o5>characteristics</o5>
        <o6>talented</o6>
        <o7>innovative</o7>
        <o8>touring</o8>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>hugely</o0>
        <o1>famous</o1>
        <o2>persona </o2>
        <o3>visiting</o3>
        <o4>widely</o4>
        <o5>characteristics</o5>
        <o6>talented</o6>
        <o7>innovative</o7>
        <o8>touring</o8>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>hugely</o0>
        <o1>famous</o1>
        <o2>persona </o2>
        <o3>visiting</o3>
        <o4>widely</o4>
        <o5>characteristics</o5>
        <o6>talented</o6>
        <o7>innovative</o7>
        <o8>touring</o8>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>hugely</o0>
        <o1>famous</o1>
        <o2>persona </o2>
        <o3>visiting</o3>
        <o4>widely</o4>
        <o5>characteristics</o5>
        <o6>talented</o6>
        <o7>innovative</o7>
        <o8>touring</o8>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>hugely</o0>
        <o1>famous</o1>
        <o2>persona </o2>
        <o3>visiting</o3>
        <o4>widely</o4>
        <o5>characteristics</o5>
        <o6>talented</o6>
        <o7>innovative</o7>
        <o8>touring</o8>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>1|8|7|2|4</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>49b75b8f747040209be7ea904d713ca3</id>
  <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction></instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Dwight Eisenhower had long {blank} the importance of highways, even before he became president in 1953. In 1919 as a young lieutenant colonel in the army he had {blank} the first transcontinental military motor convoy from Washington, DC, to San Francisco. Like most American motorists, the soldiers traveled on dirt roads and {blank} bridges; it took about two months for them to cross the country. And years later, during World War II, he observed the advantages of the German autobahn network, which made for safe and efficient mobility.

The Federal-Aid Highway Act of 1954 set aside $175 million for the construction of an interstate highway system. However, even more money was needed for the system that Eisenhower -{blank}, and he continued to press for funds. Two years later, the expanded Federal-Aid Highway Act of 1956 authorized a budget of $25 billion, of which the federal share was to be 90%.
</description>
    <title>Reading - Reading: Fill in the blanks - Q10</title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>dreamt</o0>
        <o1>accompanied </o1>
        <o2>thought</o2>
        <o3>realized</o3>
        <o4>envisioned</o4>
        <o5>associated</o5>
        <o6>crumbling</o6>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>dreamt</o0>
        <o1>accompanied </o1>
        <o2>thought</o2>
        <o3>realized</o3>
        <o4>envisioned</o4>
        <o5>associated</o5>
        <o6>crumbling</o6>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>dreamt</o0>
        <o1>accompanied </o1>
        <o2>thought</o2>
        <o3>realized</o3>
        <o4>envisioned</o4>
        <o5>associated</o5>
        <o6>crumbling</o6>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>dreamt</o0>
        <o1>accompanied </o1>
        <o2>thought</o2>
        <o3>realized</o3>
        <o4>envisioned</o4>
        <o5>associated</o5>
        <o6>crumbling</o6>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>3|1|6|4</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>d6e06a160b094d77bde50e2c54f47e4e</id>
  <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction></instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Scientists have found that small calcium deposits in foetal membranes lead to a mother's water breaking early - solving the mystery behind why some babies are born {blank} .
The study suggests that dietary or other interventions may prevent those preterm births.
Researchers from US Nationwide Children's Hospital found that in preterm, premature rupture of the foetal membranes - that is, water breaking significantly early- the amniotic sac contains {blank} deposits and early markers of bone formation. The membranes, then, are less elastic and more {blank} to breaking.
"We do see calcium deposits in full term births as well, which is probably part of the normal -{blank} of the membranes at the appropriate time," said Irina Buhimschi from Nationwide Children's Hospital.</description>
    <title>Reading - Reading &amp; Writing: Fill in the blanks - Q11</title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>untimely</o0>
        <o1>prematurely</o1>
        <o2>hastily</o2>
        <o3>handicapped</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>1|0|2|3</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>3fe1d220fe0b40e99ddd8a4f556d2934</id>
  <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction></instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Temporary or selective memory loss seems something ingrained in the functioning of a government. The hard fact is people don’t forget. Some months back, Haryana government {blank} over the Harapppa-era archaeological wonder at Rakhigarhi  and quickly announced a museum to store the {blank} and the newest history of the place. The village panchayat, too, agreed to lease out a piece of land for a nominal fee. Today, the museum is nowhere in sight, as the government announcement seems lost in its files.
The archeologists believe the site offers new vistas into ancient civilization and requires {blank} efforts to decode the life and times of Harappan generation. “Rakhigarhi represents the 5000-year-old civilization, contemporary to the ancient Mesopotamia,” says an archaeologist. Rakhigarhi villagers have shown {blank} and given five acres to the state government for just Rs 1 per acre to set up a museum in the village. That was about two years ago. The state government, too, agreed and {blank} a budget of Rs 24 crore in February this year. 
</description>
    <title>Reading - Reading &amp; Writing: Fill in the blanks - Q12</title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>deprecated</o0>
        <o1>gloated</o1>
        <o2>concealed</o2>
        <o3>jubilate</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>1|1|0|3|0</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>6d11222fd07c48c8a0665d87e444b7a8</id>
  <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANKS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction></instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>Diamond nanothreads may be used to make clothes, electronics and construction materials in the future, scientists have {blank} . Researchers are working out how many ways {blank} can use diamond nanothread.
First created by Pennsylvania State University last year, one-dimensional DNT is similar to carbon nanotubes, hollow cylindrical tubes 10,000 times {blank} than human hair, stronger than steel - but brittle.
"DNT, by comparison, is even thinner, incorporating kinks of hydrogen in the carbon's hollow structure, called Stone-Wale  transformation defects, which I've discovered reduces {blank} and adds flexibility," said Haifei Zhan, from Queensland University of Technology in Australia.
</description>
    <title>Reading - Reading &amp; Writing: Fill in the blanks - Q13</title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>claimed</o0>
        <o1>researched</o1>
        <o2>invented</o2>
        <o3>imposed</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>0|2|1|0</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>2e9e9de695f045faa2580f5e287f0205</id>
  <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction></instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>It’s so peaceful at Regis Station. The only sounds are the wind whipping across the tundra and my own breathing. I didn’t think I’d like it out here. The solitude. The lack of stimulus. Some people have to have another person around to keep them straight. For me, it’s another {blank} experience, like bungy-jumping in Queenstown, or skydiving over Monterey Bay. Instead of the adrenaline rush of freefall, it’s an opportunity to {blank} the unknown.
Larry dropped me off here in the ATV three hours ago. He should be over halfway back to McKinlay Station by now. He was the only one of the Grise Fjord Inuit who would drive me out here. Not one of the McKinlay scientists would do it.  Larry’s a jovial sort, always smiling with those {blank} , yellow teeth of his. He likes to crack jokes and tell stories about his family, but he didn’t say a word for the {blank} three-hour drive out to Regis Station.
</description>
    <title>Reading - Reading &amp; Writing: Fill in the blanks - Q14</title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>new</o0>
        <o1>severe</o1>
        <o2>acute</o2>
        <o3>extreme</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>avoid</o0>
        <o1>address</o1>
        <o2>confront</o2>
        <o3>ignore</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>splintered</o0>
        <o1>fixed</o1>
        <o2>smashed</o2>
        <o3>burst</o3>        
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>entire</o0>
        <o1>hectic</o1>
        <o2>tiring</o2>
        <o3>unknown</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>3|2|0|0</answer>
  </template>
</question>
<question>
  <id>41cdd5351ad14e9a9c714dda647d9311</id>
  <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
  <type>FILL_IN_BLANK_WITH_OPTIONS</type>
  <itemType>READING</itemType>
  <instruction></instruction>
  <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
  <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
  <template>
    <description>When the last ship vanished into the sky, afterburners {blank} briefly in the dense black cloud ceiling that {blank} our world, there were fires. There were more of us then, and we poured angry through the streets, a human pyroclastic flow, burning indiscriminately. There were Molotov-on-car fires, one or two apartment buildings set fire, {blank} fires. One guy, someone’s kid brother, set fire to himself in the streets like that Buddhist monk so many years ago. The monk, if you believe the writers from back then, never made a sound while he burned. The kid brother {blank} , long and loud. It was a time of fires, when they left us, but there was never a fire like this.</description>
    <title>Reading - Reading &amp; Writing: Fill in the blanks - Q15</title>
    <blanks>
      <blank>
        <o0>lambent</o0>
        <o1>flickering</o1>
        <o2>scorch</o2>
        <o3>squint </o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>disclosed</o0>
        <o1>underestimated</o1>
        <o2>enlightened</o2>
        <o3>shrouded</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>dumpster</o0>
        <o1>haul</o1>
        <o2>dump</o2>
        <o3>recycle</o3>
      </blank>
      <blank>
        <o0>shouted</o0>
        <o1>cry</o1>
        <o2>screamed</o2>
        <o3>pierce</o3>
      </blank>
    </blanks>
    <answer>1|3|0|2</answer>
  </template>
</question>
</questions>