<?xml version = "1.0"?>
<questions>
<!--TEST 1 -->
  <question>
    <id>1ca3e67658b2426c9aa569697cb13500</id>
    <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_WRITE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a short lecture. Write a summary for fellow student who was not present at the lecture. You should write 50-70 words. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points presented in the lecture.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Summarize Spoken Text - Q1 Test 3-1.tpm</media>
      <delay>10</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>As per the lecture, Amitabha Sadangi from India works for poorest farmers, he is frustrated the way the aid market had bypassed low-income farmers. Amitabha was obsessed with the drip irrigation technology invented in Israel,  it could transform desert land into fields of emerald green. But these systems were expensive and constructed for large fields. So Amitabha used three fundamental principles, which were miniaturization, making machine affordable and infinitely expandable.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>bb3ec2309269411f8387880a397a8362</id>
    <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_WRITE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a short lecture. Write a summary for fellow student who was not present at the lecture. You should write 50-70 words. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points presented in the lecture.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Summarize Spoken Text - Q2 Test 3-1.tpm</media>
      <delay>10</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>The speaker talks about no progress in terms of human flight in space in Houston and he thinks that there is a very big chance of losing ability to inspire youth. He feels  that the next generation need to look forward to exploration,  colonization and breakthroughs. There is a need to inspire them, because they will lead us and help us survive in the future.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>9b861f738b5948958fbbb9121525a55e</id>
    <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_WRITE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a short lecture. Write a summary for fellow student who was not present at the lecture. You should write 50-70 words. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points presented in the lecture.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Summarize Spoken Text - Q3 Test 3-1.tpm</media>
      <delay>10</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>The lecturer is talking about raising money for his own start-up where he has to meet with prospective investors while speaking to all these investors he realized he was asked a very different set of questions regarding losses and his male cofounder was asked about investor gains and  new customers they  were going to bring on, which was rather odd but the speaker rationalized it by changing his thinking.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>bc4be47288fe455ebb1a72d04bf8720c</id>
    <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_SELECT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct responses. You will need to select more than one response.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>Some of the key concepts related to the talk are</title>
      <media>Listening - Multiple choice, choose multiple answers - Q4 Test 3-1.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>A mistake people often make is to try to get the whole thing done right away</o0>
        <o1>Breaking things down in small pieces makes it more complex.</o1>
        <o2>People in general don’t have the patience while executing.</o2>
        <o3>If you have an idea you should make the final finished product first.</o3>
        <o4>When you have an idea it is important to get something up as soon as possible and then get feedback.</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>0|4</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>388b4396ee5d4a26a306f06f9b866d03</id>
    <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_SELECT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct responses. You will need to select more than one response.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>Going by the lecture, which of the following statements is true about enzymes? </title>
      <media>Listening - Multiple choice, choose multiple answers - Q5 Test 3-1.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>They catabolise internally in the digestive system and metabolize externally.</o0>
        <o1>They are a result of metabolic reactions which first originate from the digestive system.</o1>
        <o2>They are needed for cells to survive internally and digest food externally.</o2>
        <o3>They are produced within cells and set off reactions internally and externally.</o3>
        <o4>They are the natural catalyst.</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>3|4</answer>
    </template>
    <question>
      <id>c96eab50f6e948fdb231c2208ab9252b</id>
      <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
      <type>LISTEN_AND_FILL_BLANKS</type>
      <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
      <instruction>You will hear a recording. Type the missing words in each blank.</instruction>
      <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
      <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
      <template>
        <description>The computer universe is both {blank} and primitive. It's a universe based on causality. As developers, we dream the different causes and then we program the different effects. Double click on an icon, that's a cause. Open an {blank} , that's an effect. Now when we compare this to our physical universe, it is overly constraining, because our universe is not digital. Our universe is {blank} . Our universe doesn't think in terms of zero or one, true or false, or black or white. We {blank} in a world governed by quantum physics, a universe of zero and one both at the same time, a reality based on infinite {blank} and shades of gray. You can see how these two worlds collide.</description>
        <title></title>
        <media>Listening - Fill in the blanks - Q6 Test 3-1.tpm</media>
        <delay>8</delay>
        <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
        
        <answer>marvelous|application|analog|exist|probabilities</answer>
      </template>
    </question>
    <question>
      <id>f16112a4141e4826b6a9547b4d637181</id>
      <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
      <type>LISTEN_AND_FILL_BLANKS</type>
      <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
      <instruction>You will hear a recording. Type the missing words in each blank.</instruction>
      <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
      <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
      <template>
        <description>Exceptional women are inspiring and {blank} . But those stories are limiting. By definition, being extraordinary is non-representative. It's atypical. Those stories do not create a broad base for incorporating women's history, and they don't reflect our daily {blank} . If we can collectively apply that radical notion that women are people, it becomes easier to show women as people are: familiar, {blank} , present. In everyone's everyday throughout history, women exist positively - not as a matter of interpretation, but as a matter of fact. And beyond a more accurate {blank} of human life, including women considers the quotidian experiences of the almost 3.8 billion people {blank} as female on this planet.</description>
        <title></title>
        <media>Listening - Fill in the blanks - Q7 Test 3-1.tpm</media>
        <delay>8</delay>
        <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
        
        <answer>aspirational|realities|diverse|representation|identified</answer>
      </template>
    </question>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>67420c1946834f9e80d73a27ade74d97</id>
    <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_HIGHLIGHT_CORRECT_SUMMARY</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Click on paragraph that best relates to the recording.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Highlight Correct Summary - Q8 Test 3-1.tpm</media>
      <delay>10</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>In the 3rd millennium BCE, Mesopotamian kings recorded and interpreted their dreams on wax tablets. In the years since, we haven't paused in our quest to understand why we dream. And while we still don’t have any definitive answers, we have some theories. Amy Adkins reveals the top seven reasons why we might dream.</o0>
        <o1>In the 3rd millennium BCE, Mesopotamian kings recorded and interpreted their dreams on wax tablets. And while we still don’t have any definitive answers, we have some theories. Amy Adkins reveals the top seven reasons why we might dream.</o1>
        <o2>In the 3rd millennium BCE, Mesopotamian kings recorded and interpreted their dreams on wax tablets. In the years since, we have paused in our quest to understand why we dream. While we still don’t have any definitive answers, we have some theories. Amy Adkins reveals the top seven reasons why we might dream.</o2>
      </options>
      <answer>0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>bbe25b85a006486c99d73c1ccef212a7</id>
    <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_HIGHLIGHT_CORRECT_SUMMARY</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Click on paragraph that best relates to the recording.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Highlight Correct Summary - Q9 Test 3-1.tpm</media>
      <delay>10</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>Learning is a relatively permanent change in behaviour because of experiences. It is also called as cognitive. It is of various types and memory is a fickle thing.</o0>
        <o1>Learning is a relatively permanent change in behaviour because of experiences. It is also called as cognitive science. It works like computer coding. It is of various types and memory is a fickle thing.</o1>
        <o2>Learning is a relatively permanent change in behaviour because of experiences. It is also called as cognitive science. It is of various types and memory is a fickle thing.</o2>
        <o3>Learning is a relatively temporary change in behaviour because of experiences. It is also called as cognitive science. It works like computer coding. It is of various types and memory is not a fickle thing.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>6b78a3a95d134acd8196a1a231175078</id>
    <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_CHOICE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple -choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct. </instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>Instead of adapting, an animal ----.</title>
      <media>Listening - Multiple choice choose single answer - Q10 Test 3-1.tpm</media>
      <delay>5</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>goes around for finding a prey.</o0>
        <o1>prefers not to live in another environment.</o1>
        <o2>is in need of food and water.</o2>
        <o3>must find ways to feed itself.</o3>
        <o4>moves into different habitat from time to time.</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>4</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>e12ddf962ad14ff5bbb043330f953380</id>
    <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_CHOICE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple -choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct. </instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>According to the passage, O'Neill ----.</title>
      <media>Listening - Multiple choice, choose single answer - Q11 Test 3-1.tpm</media>
      <delay>5</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>knew nearly all the important dramatists of the modern world</o0>
        <o1>passed away in the 20th century</o1>
        <o2>only had been awarded the Nobel Prize for Literature</o2>
        <o3>knew more than four languages</o3>
        <o4>wasn't reserved and complicated</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>7d96cf4752bb4655b352073e6ba72a35</id>
    <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_SELECT_MISSING_WORD</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording, at the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Select missing word - Q12 Test 3-1.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>use</o0>
        <o1>use the model.</o1>
        <o2>the model.</o2>
        <o3>Models.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>8080fa30f865424aaa453b3e546152ff</id>
    <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_SELECT_MISSING_WORD</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording, at the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Select missing word - Q13 Test 3-1.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>educationally experience.</o0>
        <o1>educational experience.</o1>
        <o2>experience.</o2>
        <o3>educational experienced. </o3>
      </options>
      <answer>1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>5de1f8a399cf4e48b9f2bdae62d2cf84</id>
    <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_HIGHLIGHT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Below is a transcription of the recording. Some words in the transcription differ from what the speaker(s) said. Please click on words that are different. </instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>He suddenly authorized the creation of a Social Innovation Fund to focus on what works in this country, and look at how we can rescale it. And I would submit that it's time to consider a global innovation fund that would find these entrepreneurs around the world who really have inventions, not only for their country, but ones that we can utilize in the developed world as well. Invest financial assistance, but also management assistance. And then measure the returns, both from a financial perspective and from a social effect perspective.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Highlight Incorrect Words- Q14 Test 3-1.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      
      <answer>suddenly|rescale|inventions|utilize|effect</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>d0d35d4c767042a89ed912418a38c09f</id>
    <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_HIGHLIGHT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Below is a transcription of the recording. Some words in the transcription differ from what the speaker(s) said. Please click on words that are different. </instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>I have a pretty complex idea that I'm just going to tell you over and over until I get you to believe it, and that is all of us are makers. I really accept that. All of us are makers. We're born makers. We have this capability to make things, to grasp things with our hands. We use words like "grasp" metaphorically to also think about misunderstanding things. We don't just live, but we make. We develop things.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Highlight Incorrect Words- Q15 Test 3-1.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      
      <answer>complex|accept|capability|misunderstanding|develop</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>1b5bc9cf83cc42299aba9d894db4675b</id>
    <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Write from dictation- Q16 Test 3-1.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>Our class will be divided into three groups.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>cb2c2d308dd141198604f4167c4ebbb6</id>
    <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Write from dictation- Q17 Test 3-1.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>Please work with each other to build monolithic statues.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>08130a5e72f942128e0cdaae5d3795d1</id>
    <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Write from dictation- Q18 Test 3-1.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>Relevant resources are reserved in the library.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>120690ffec40457baf88c0e10cce963f</id>
    <practiceSet>94fbb82b4fd1485eb61cc3c671da384d</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Write from dictation- Q19 Test 3-1.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>Reference of material is held in the hall of library reference desk.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <!-- Test 2 -->
  <question>
    <id>6336795e6fc1483da9babd39440ecfd2</id>
    <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_WRITE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a short lecture. Write a summary for fellow student who was not present at the lecture. You should write 50-70 words. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points presented in the lecture.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Summarize Spoken Text - Q1 Test 3-2.tpm</media>
      <delay>10</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>The lecture is on gender disparity, speaker did the research on start-up financing and discovered there's an enormous gap between the amount of funds that male and female founders raise.  This hypothesis was tested by the speaker on companies with similar quality and funding needs. The result was that male-led start-ups went on to raise five times as much funding as the female-led ones.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>cbd503b5da224fb780b9e2b57d12b378</id>
    <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_WRITE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a short lecture. Write a summary for fellow student who was not present at the lecture. You should write 50-70 words. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points presented in the lecture.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Summarize Spoken Text - Q2 Test 3-2.tpm</media>
      <delay>10</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>The speaker talks about solar eclipse and the cosmic bliss. In 1999, in Munich, he joined hundreds of thousands where people cheered in unison as the solar corona emerged and he became an eclipse evangelist. According to him, total solar eclipse is the ultimate experience of awe which promotes empathy and generosity.  Unfortunately, few Americans have seen one, because it's been 38 years since one last touched the continental United States.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>bc105fc53ac64d90a7993891e2558832</id>
    <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_SELECT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct responses. You will need to select more than one response.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>Athens had _________ the other Greek city-states against the Persians.</title>
      <media>Listening - Multiple choice choose multiple answers - Q3  Test 3-2.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>refused help to</o0>
        <o1>intervened on behalf of</o1>
        <o2>wanted to fight</o2>
        <o3>given orders for all to fight</o3>
        <o4>defeated</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>1|4</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>36832dd1d64a47e8b294cafb3690bd51</id>
    <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_SELECT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct responses. You will need to select more than one response.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>Eris was known for _________ both mortals and immortals. </title>
      <media>Listening - Multiple choice choose multiple answers - Q4  Test 3-2.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>scheming against</o0>
        <o1>creating conflict amongst</o1>
        <o2>feeling hostile toward</o2>
        <o3>ignoring</o3>
        <o4>comforting</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>1|4</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>4e0b8644dfee4841b058e4564e2df91c</id>
    <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_FILL_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Type the missing words in each blank.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Respectability politics and {blank} femininity influence how we display women and which women we choose to display. And that display has skewed toward successful and extraordinary and reputable and {blank} , which maintains the systemic exclusion and marginalization of the everyday, the regular, the underrepresented and usually, the nonwhite. As a museum curator, I am {blank} to change that narrative. I research, collect and interpret objects and images of {blank} .</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Fill in the blanks - Q5 Test 3-2.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      
      <answer>idealized|desirable|empowered|significance</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>89650cbce089408ba6199cebdc4f0073</id>
    <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_FILL_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Type the missing words in each blank.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>And there was a wonderful little short four-year time period when {blank} things happened. It started in 1908, when the Wright brothers flew in Paris, and everybody said, "Ooh, hey, I can do that." There's only a few people that have flown in early 1908. In four years, 39 countries had {blank} of airplanes, thousand of pilots. Airplanes were invented by natural selection. Now you can say that intelligent design designs our airplanes of today, but there was no {blank} design really designing those early airplanes. There were probably at least 30,000 different things tried, and when they crash and kill the pilot, don't try that again. The ones that flew and landed OK because there were no trained pilots who had good flying {blank} by definition. So we, by making a whole bunch of attempts, thousands of attempts, in that four-year time period, we invented the concepts of the airplanes that we fly today. And that's why they're so safe, as we gave it a lot of chance to find what's good. That has not {blank} at all in space flying. There's only been two concepts tried -- two by the U.S. and one by the Russians.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Fill in the blanks - Q6 Test 3-2.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      
      <answer>marvelous|hundreds|intelligent|qualities|happened</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>9e30d88cbe744e22942189bcfb303e47</id>
    <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_HIGHLIGHT_CORRECT_SUMMARY</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Click on paragraph that best relates to the recording.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Highlight Correct Summary - Q7 Test 3-2.tpm</media>
      <delay>10</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>Statistics are persuasive as statistics probability for survival rate  of Hospital A and Hospital B is same. Good health condition of patient directly lies on patient survival rate. Statistical predictions are not accurate.</o0>
        <o1>Statistics are persuasive as statistics probability for survival rate for Hospital A and Hospital B is different. Good health condition of patient directly depends on his surroundings. Statistical predictions are not always inaccurate.</o1>
        <o2>Statistics are persuasive as statistics probability of survival rate of Hospital A and Hospital B is different. Good health condition of patient directly dependent on patient survival rate. Statistical predictions are not accurate.</o2>
        <o3>Statistics are persuasive as statistics probability for survival rate for Hospital A and Hospital B is same. Good health condition of patient directly depends on his surroundings. Statistical predictions are not always inaccurate.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>37c7ff1845274fabbbfc061bb449a1d4</id>
    <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_HIGHLIGHT_CORRECT_SUMMARY</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Click on paragraph that best relates to the recording.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Highlight Correct Summary - Q8 Test 3-2.tpm</media>
      <delay>10</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>Brain accurately retain memory is not scientifically proven as our memory is remarkably imprecise. Memory doesn’t duplicate and reproduce; what we recall is not almost accurate. Some people are able to recall the things but it depends.</o0>
        <o1>Brain accurately retain memory is not scientifically proven as our memory is remarkably precise. Memory doesn’t duplicate and reproduce; what we recall is not almost accurate. Some people are able to recall the things but it depends.</o1>
        <o2>Brain accurately retain memory is not scientifically proven as our memory is remarkably imprecise. Memory doesn’t duplicate and reproduce; what we recall is not almost accurate. Some people are not able to recall the things but it depends.</o2>
      </options>
      <answer>0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>b3cda428d322498ba6611df0113306bb</id>
    <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_CHOICE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple -choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct. </instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>According to the passage ----.</title>
      <media>Listening - Multiple choice choose single answer - Q9 Test 3-2.tpm</media>
      <delay>5</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>the name Pacific comes from the harshness and hostility of the Pacific  Ocean.</o0>
        <o1>Christopher Columbus is also a Portuguese seafarer.</o1>
        <o2>Magellan had difficulties while fighting with the tribesmen.</o2>
        <o3>the Portuguese have more audacity than any other nations in the world.</o3>
        <o4>four of the five ships were destroyed and only one of them was able to arrive back after 3 years.</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>4</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>638aa4b1595745bdb1c69f5b8cc8cf2d</id>
    <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_CHOICE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple -choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct. </instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>The North American continent ----.</title>
      <media>Listening - Multiple choice choose single answer - Q10 Test 3-2.tpm</media>
      <delay>5</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>has the most dangerous animal in the world.</o0>
        <o1>suffers much from wolves than bears.</o1>
        <o2>cannot bear mountain lions and wolves.</o2>
        <o3>is usually subject to poisonous snake attacks.</o3>
        <o4>can guess the time of attacks of snakes.</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>e4b07cc084e646d99ded883567fbd935</id>
    <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_SELECT_MISSING_WORD</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording, at the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Select missing word - Q11 Test 3-2.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>nutrition</o0>
        <o1>nutrients</o1>
        <o2>nourishment</o2>
        <o3>air</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>b3f61d0183324d2797c1d99232353889</id>
    <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_SELECT_MISSING_WORD</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording, at the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Select missing word - Q12 Test 3-2.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>added</o0>
        <o1>were added</o1>
        <o2>additive</o2>
        <o3>add</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>76435ce2969d48d8955eb5bab074e550</id>
    <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_HIGHLIGHT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Below is a transcription of the recording. Some words in the transcription differ from what the speaker(s) said. Please click on words that are different.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>The fortunate reality, though, is that both men and women assessing start-ups display the same implicit gender bias in their questioning, inadvertently favoring male employer over female ones. So to my investors out there, I would offer that you have an opportunity here to approach QandA sessions more even-handedly, not just so that you could do the right thing, but so that you can improve the quality of your decision making. By highlighting the same light on every start-up's potential for gains and losses, you enable all selective start-ups to shine and you maximize returns in the process.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Highlight Incorrect Words- Q13 Test 3-2.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      
      <answer>fortunate|assessing|employer|highlighting|selective</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>e942af6da9254c49b534b28923404702</id>
    <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_HIGHLIGHT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Below is a transcription of the recording. Some words in the transcription differ from what the speaker(s) said. Please click on words that are different.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Every couple of years, I head off to wherever the moon's shadow will come to experience another couple minutes of cosmic bliss, and to share the experience with others: with friends in Australia, with an whole city in Germany. In 1999, in Munich, I joined hundreds of thousands who filled the streets and the rooftops and cheered in union as the solar corona emerged. And over time, I've become something else: an eclipse evangelist. I see it as my job to pay forward the advice that I received all those years ago. And so let me tell you: before you wakeup, you owe it to yourself to experience a total solar eclipse. It is the ultimate experience of awe. Now, that word, "awesome," has grown so overused that it's lost its true meaning.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Highlight Incorrect Words- Q14 Test 3-2.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      
      <answer>come|whole|union|wakeup|true</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>97787e8000d04c2a91935e43a785e305</id>
    <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Write from dictation- Q15 Test 3-2.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>Tom can't taste the difference between expensive wine and cheap wine.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>c2cf5c06e5fd439ca0423bd10a8fcbb3</id>
    <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Write from dictation- Q16 Test 3-2.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>When did you usually get up?</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>827dfa8348284a76ac95d6b9337c4e83</id>
    <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Write from dictation- Q17 Test 3-2.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>I know you've been waiting a long time, but could you wait just a little bit longer.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>12097880e21446de9f075502899ba4bf</id>
    <practiceSet>7fdd81499d6147a1b4a817e56db88024</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Write from dictation- Q18 Test 3-2.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>I know that it is highly unlikely that you'd ever want to go out with me, but I still need to ask at least once.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <!-- Test 3 -->
  <question>
    <id>1adf967a8bfb470d8304ce9cb3c2d9d5</id>
    <practiceSet>88f631b360734b7da3b7c3e6151bd840</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_WRITE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a short lecture. Write a summary for fellow student who was not present at the lecture. You should write 50-70 words. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points presented in the lecture.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Summarize Spoken Text - Q1 Test 3-3.tpm</media>
      <delay>10</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>The earliest artworks are the skillful cave paintings such as Chauvet but artistic skills are much older than that. Prehistoric artifacts are older even than this which includes stone tools which were around for thousands of centuries when Homo erectus started shaping blades. Acheulian hand axes, named after STt. Acheul, have been unearthed in their thousands.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>0a85636d14ab4bb0a94e6203ad4dc960</id>
    <practiceSet>88f631b360734b7da3b7c3e6151bd840</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_WRITE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a short lecture. Write a summary for fellow student who was not present at the lecture. You should write 50-70 words. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points presented in the lecture.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Summarize Spoken Text - Q2 Test 3-3.tpm</media>
      <delay>10</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>The biggest strength of James has been his timekeeping and organizational skills which led to a tactful action plan to become one of his leading companies in Europe.  James as a manager always acknowledged the work and he has been rewarded as the best employee as he has the significant contributions to the company.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>15d7c609e08b444a9983a27f9a461960</id>
    <practiceSet>88f631b360734b7da3b7c3e6151bd840</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_SELECT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct responses. You will need to select more than one response.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>Which of the following are mentioned as health problems caused by noise?</title>
      <media>Listening - Multiple choice, choose multiple answers - Q3 Test 3-3.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>Extreme irritation.</o0>
        <o1>A certain degree of hearing loss.</o1>
        <o2>Problems with speech.</o2>
        <o3>Mental problems.</o3>
        <o4>Behavioral and anger problems.</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>1|3|4</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>c95f0c1279cb449cb776ee961e7aa845</id>
    <practiceSet>88f631b360734b7da3b7c3e6151bd840</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_SELECT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct responses. You will need to select more than one response.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>According to the speaker, which of the following you have to offer to a person to get them to walk in a typical American city?</title>
      <media>Listening - Multiple choice, choose multiple answers - Q4 Test 3-3.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>A good and valid reason</o0>
        <o1>The walk should be safe and the person should feel safe</o1>
        <o2>Offer them that the walk will have good views</o2>
        <o3>Tell them that walk would be more interesting than driving.</o3>
        <o4>Offer them a ride back home</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>0|1|4</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>e5e671cb36764273bdc5ce630a21b625</id>
    <practiceSet>88f631b360734b7da3b7c3e6151bd840</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_FILL_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Type the missing words in each blank.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Anonymous companies have even come to light in the recent revolution in the {blank}. But, for every case that we and others expose there are so many more that will remain hidden away because of the {blank} system. And it's just a simple truth that some of the people responsible for {blank} crimes, for stealing from you and me and millions of others, they are remaining faceless and they are escaping {blank} and they're doing this with ease, and they're doing it using legal {blank} . And really, that is unfair. </description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Fill in the blanks - Q5 Test 3-3.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      
      <answer>Ukraine|current|outrageous|accountability|structures</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>f577aea4981247ec9b28ac9c3d0de4bc</id>
    <practiceSet>88f631b360734b7da3b7c3e6151bd840</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_FILL_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Type the missing words in each blank.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>I met Andrew at one of our {blank} meetings putting together Maker Faire. Andrew had moved to Detroit from Duluth, Minnesota. And I talked to his mom, and I ended up doing a story on him for a magazine called Kidrobot. He's just a kid that grew up playing with tools instead of toys. He liked to take things apart. His mother gave him a part of the {blank} , and he collected things from yard sales, and he made stuff. And then he didn't particularly like school that much, but he got involved in {blank} competitions, and he realized he had a talent, and, more importantly, he had a real {blank} for it. And he began building robots. And when I sat down next to him, he was telling me about a company he formed, and he was building some robots for {blank} factories to move things around on the factory floor. And that's why he moved to Michigan. But he also moved here to meet other people doing what he's doing.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Fill in the blanks - Q6 Test 3-3.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      
      <answer>community|garage|robotics|passion|automobile</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>10dbb9accbec4d62a480ce30ab1fe5d2</id>
    <practiceSet>88f631b360734b7da3b7c3e6151bd840</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_HIGHLIGHT_CORRECT_SUMMARY</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Click on paragraph that best relates to the recording.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Highlight Correct Summary - Q7 Test 3-3.tpm</media>
      <delay>10</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>Getting a job in journalism requires relevant experience, such as writing articles to meet specific deadlines. You’re advised to apply for temporary internships with local papers. Building up a set of cuttings in a portfolio may also help when applying for a job.</o0>
        <o1>Your employers care more about practical knowledge in journalism, and you’re advised to practice your editing skills. You’re also advised to build up a portfolio after graduation.</o1>
        <o2>There are different ways for you to get a job in journalism, and the easiest method is through unpaid internships. In addition, it is worth building up a set of cuttings in a portfolio from secondary school onwards.</o2>
        <o3>Your qualification in journalism is not as important as practical skills, so that you should develop your skills, such as communication. You’re also advised to create a portfolio from secondary school onwards.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>903d9644dd08471ca2bb6e974a6712da</id>
    <practiceSet>88f631b360734b7da3b7c3e6151bd840</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_HIGHLIGHT_CORRECT_SUMMARY</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Click on paragraph that best relates to the recording.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Highlight Correct Summary - Q8 Test 3-3.tpm</media>
      <delay>10</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>USA Today is a revolutionary paper that changed the way news was reported. While it is no longer in service, the paper promoted shorter stories and more accurate information.</o0>
        <o1>The newspapers before USA Today were old fashioned. They were in trouble because not many people were reading those papers. They were also filled with horror stories about crimes and killing.</o1>
        <o2>There are several great things about USA Today. The greatest one being that it revolutionized the way news was written and distributed. It became the number 1 selling paper and promoted new methods of writing to reporters.</o2>
        <o3>Long stories and lack of colored photos were the main reasons that USA Today competitors failed in the news market. However, with the presence of USA Today, these newspapers slowly caught up to the latest news trends.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>921df93ddb6a415388a19946198de037</id>
    <practiceSet>88f631b360734b7da3b7c3e6151bd840</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_CHOICE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple -choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>The product being sold in this advertisement is a</title>
      <media>Listening - Multiple choice, choose single answer - Q9 Test 3-3.tpm</media>
      <delay>5</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>Modern-day malady</o0>
        <o1>Ginsing product</o1>
        <o2>Workday paste</o2>
        <o3>Motor oil</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>d8680788a38348eaa776ea79264cc848</id>
    <practiceSet>88f631b360734b7da3b7c3e6151bd840</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_CHOICE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple -choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>What is the valley mentioned in the recording famous for</title>
      <media>Listening - Multiple choice, choose single answer - Q10 Test 3-3.tpm</media>
      <delay>5</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>its river rapids.</o0>
        <o1>park crowds.</o1>
        <o2>cold afternoons.</o2>
        <o3>winds</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>917ebaf0c44f45ba8d91698ba30a079a</id>
    <practiceSet>88f631b360734b7da3b7c3e6151bd840</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_SELECT_MISSING_WORD</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording on Human rights. At the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Select missing word - Q11 Test 3-3.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>educationally experience.</o0>
        <o1>educational experience.</o1>
        <o2>experience.</o2>
        <o3>educational experienced.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>4aeaa67d39ac41efbbefca9f198e4206</id>
    <practiceSet>88f631b360734b7da3b7c3e6151bd840</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_SELECT_MISSING_WORD</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording, at the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Select missing word - Q12 Test 3-3.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>conservation.</o0>
        <o1>equation.</o1>
        <o2>preservation.</o2>
        <o3>transformation.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>1955059e77a7484fa3ab37daf7ada7a1</id>
    <practiceSet>88f631b360734b7da3b7c3e6151bd840</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_HIGHLIGHT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Below is a transcription of the recording. Some words in the transcription differ from what the speaker(s) said. Please click on words that are different.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Classified advertisements placed by individuals in newsprint and magazines are not covered by the Advertising Standards Authority's "court of practice". If you happen to buy goods that have been wrongly described in such an advertisement, and have lost money as a result, the only thing you can do is bring a case against the person who placed the advertisement for misrepresentation or for breach of contrast. In this case you would use the small claims procedure, which is a relatively cheap way to sue for the recovery of a debt. If you want to pursue a claim, you should take into account whether the person you are suing will be able to pay damages, should any be rewarded. Dishonest traders are wary of this and often pose as private sellers to expose the legal loopholes that exist: that is, they may claim they are not in a position to pay damages.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Highlight Incorrect Words- Q13 Test 3-3.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      
      <answer>newsprint|court|contrast|rewarded|wary|expose</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>aa89ab5cff7241a3a046bbd973c787c0</id>
    <practiceSet>88f631b360734b7da3b7c3e6151bd840</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_HIGHLIGHT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Below is a transcription of the recording. Some words in the transcription differ from what the speaker(s) said. Please click on words that are different.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>So far in our discussion of chemical equations  we have assumed that these reactions only go in one direction, the forward direction, from left to right as we read it in an equation. That's why our arrowhead points from left to right: reactants react together to make products. However, this is not exactly how things occur in reality. In fact, practically every chemical reaction is reversible, meaning the products can also react together to reform the reactants that they were made of. So instead of writing that double arrow facing from left  to right, a more appropriate symbol would be a double arrow, one going from left to right and one going from right to left. Reactants are continually - continuously - reacting to form produce. But at the same time as those products are formed, they remake the reactants. They're both going simultaneously, forming each other. This is what we would call a state of equality.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Highlight Incorrect Words- Q14 Test 3-3.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      
      <answer>equations|arrowhead|reality|double|produce|equality</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>026a485a9b7d41aca9da05da02b5e474</id>
    <practiceSet>88f631b360734b7da3b7c3e6151bd840</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Write from dictation- Q15 Test 3-3.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>We’ve decided to ask you to write four short pieces of written coursework this year.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>fe59a1be7166445f8a6d7195d12dbf3c</id>
    <practiceSet>88f631b360734b7da3b7c3e6151bd840</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Write from dictation- Q16 Test 3-3.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>Many health workers think that pensioners are too old to understand.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>2e60f94eb4da463081a286f594e52191</id>
    <practiceSet>88f631b360734b7da3b7c3e6151bd840</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Write from dictation- Q17 Test 3-3.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>Several copies must be supplied to the university department to fulfill the requirement.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>6497ad6ae76c4ecf9859aa96d40f6ec1</id>
    <practiceSet>88f631b360734b7da3b7c3e6151bd840</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Write from dictation- Q18 Test 3-3.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>Environmentalism is a category in which universities are competing.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <!-- Test 4 -->
  <question>
    <id>6448d2f30d9d41bda04878d7c84a0b7b</id>
    <practiceSet>7b04cda952c144788c9d27aa2d5dc710</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_WRITE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a short lecture. Write a summary for fellow student who was not present at the lecture. You should write 50-70 words. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points presented in the lecture.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Summarize Spoken Text - Q1 Test 3-4.tpm</media>
      <delay>10</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>The lecture is about earliest human artworks which includes skillful cave paintings about 32,000 years old. But artistic and decorative skills are actually much older than that. Beautiful shell necklaces have been found from around 100,000 years ago. The oldest stone tools are choppers from East Africa.  These crude tools were around for thousands of centuries which includes symmetrical pointed leaf or teardrop form.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>37a8f97f2444475d83c88dd9277f3eee</id>
    <practiceSet>7b04cda952c144788c9d27aa2d5dc710</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_WRITE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a short lecture. Write a summary for fellow student who was not present at the lecture. You should write 50-70 words. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points presented in the lecture.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Summarize Spoken Text - Q2 Test 3-4.tpm</media>
      <delay>10</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>The lecture is about  James who is appreciated for his work. His biggest strength has been his organizational skills and his determination. This made the company one of the leading companies in Europe. As per the speaker, hard work and dedication by all the workers have made the company successful and James, as a manager, has always acknowledged the work and contribution made by others.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>d9c492d4c4104501bed76fb9fb42d8ef</id>
    <practiceSet>7b04cda952c144788c9d27aa2d5dc710</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_SELECT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct responses. You will need to select more than one response.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>Which of the following technological advances have had an effect on the economics and distribution of music?</title>
      <media>Listening - Multiple choice, choose multiple answers - Q3 Test 3-4.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>Piano sales.</o0>
        <o1>Electronic recording systems</o1>
        <o2>The internet</o2>
        <o3>The popularity of pianolas</o3>
        <o4>The ability to download music</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>1|2|4</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>f3c7e963c7c64e51b7704601bab9bd2a</id>
    <practiceSet>7b04cda952c144788c9d27aa2d5dc710</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_SELECT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct responses. You will need to select more than one response.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>Which of the following statements are TRYE of Rousseau’s beliefs in the Social Contract?</title>
      <media>Listening - Multiple choice, choose multiple answers - Q4 Test 3-4.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>Men form societies to better cope with the dangers in life.</o0>
        <o1>Society has a corrupting influence on people.</o1>
        <o2>People were far happier in a “state of nature’ before civilization.</o2>
        <o3>By forming societies, law and morality come into force.</o3>
        <o4>Children’s emotions should be educated before their intellect.</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>0|3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>0f62e85c88f246b79a9e8948062f5861</id>
    <practiceSet>7b04cda952c144788c9d27aa2d5dc710</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_FILL_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Type the missing words in each blank.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Swimming at night, I {blank} the first biofluorescent sea turtle. So now it's going from fish and sharks into {blank} , which, again, this is only one month old, but it shows us that we know almost nothing about this hawksbill turtle's vision. And it makes me think about how much more there is to learn. And here in the {blank} Islands, there's only a few thousand breeding females of this species left, and this is one of the {blank} for them. </description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Fill in the blanks - Q5 Test 3-4.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      
      <answer>encountered|reptiles|Solomon|hotspots</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>70ac3bf293de420baf5c1e17642e5859</id>
    <practiceSet>7b04cda952c144788c9d27aa2d5dc710</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_FILL_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Type the missing words in each blank.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Between 2001 and 2002, Ethiopian maize farmers produced two years of {blank} harvest. That in turn, because of the weak marketing system, led to an 80 percent {blank} in maize prices in the country. This made it unprofitable for some farmers to even harvest the grain from the fields. And we {blank} that some 300,000 tons of grain was left in the fields to rot in early 2002.Not six months later, in July 2002, Ethiopia announced a major food crisis, to the same proportions as 1984: 14 million people at risk of {blank} . What also happened that year is in the areas where there were good rains, and where farmers had previously produced surplus grain, farmers had decided to {blank} from the fertilizer market, not use fertilizer and actually had dropped their use of fertilizer by 27 percent. This is a tragic example of arrested development, or a budding green {blank} stopped in its tracks.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Fill in the blanks - Q6 Test 3-4.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      
      <answer>bumper|collapse|calculated|starvation|withdraw|revolution</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>d1f722966ec84d428ad1b535c27803d2</id>
    <practiceSet>7b04cda952c144788c9d27aa2d5dc710</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_HIGHLIGHT_CORRECT_SUMMARY</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Click on paragraph that best relates to the recording.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Highlight Correct Summary - Q7 Test 3-4.tpm</media>
      <delay>10</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>
          It clearly mentions the main idea clearly. also, it mentions the supporting point
          that young people do not have these skills today. This can be our right summary
          but we have to check other options.
        </o0>
        <o1>
          This summary talk about good managers. This doesn’t start with a main idea and
          most importantly there is no talk about managers in the recording. This summary
          has information not mentioned in the recording. So clearly, this is not our
          summary.
        </o1>
        <o2>
          This summary starts with a minor information in the recording. The speaker
          mentions that young people need good communication skills but this is not the
          theme of the talk. Also, it talks about meeting and meeting online, which is true
          according to the recording. But it doesn’t say anything about the seven key skills
          or educators should rethink how they teach. Remember, often a summary which
          have exact words from the recording is not your right summary.
        </o2>
        <o3>
          This summary starts with an information which is opposite to the text. The
          recording mentions that young people need seven key skills to succeed but they
          are not taught these skills. The rest of paragraph discuss the main point and
          supporting point, but since it starts with an opposing information from the text this
          summary is wrong.
        </o3>
      </options>
      <answer>0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>2648107ffef04c40a8d36a49284ffcf0</id>
    <practiceSet>7b04cda952c144788c9d27aa2d5dc710</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_HIGHLIGHT_CORRECT_SUMMARY</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Click on paragraph that best relates to the recording.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Highlight Correct Summary - Q8 Test 3-4.tpm</media>
      <delay>10</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>
          There are both advantages and disadvantages of Social media in the workplace.  On one side,
          a company’s brand can become stronger. On the other side, there is a chance that the
          company’s brand will become weaker if an employee says something negative about the
          company.
        </o0>
        <o1>
          Because social media can stop employees working, some employers prevent them from using
          social media. However, these employers do not enjoy the benefits that social media can bring,
          such as increase in customer demand for their product or a stronger brand.
        </o1>
        <o2>Social media can help employers to develop their businesses and find new staff. However, it is a problem when an employee criticizes the company online or spends too much time using social media. To stop employees, spending time on social media, employers must develop and challenge their staff.</o2>
        <o3>
          Employers only see the negative side of social media because they have too many problems
          with employees being rude or spending too much time using social media instead of working.
          Because this situation is challenging, it is easier for companies to stop the use of social media.
        </o3>
      </options>
      <answer>2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>19287a23ac5944c0b36670bf062893f1</id>
    <practiceSet>7b04cda952c144788c9d27aa2d5dc710</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_CHOICE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple -choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>What point does the lecturer make about whales and sound pollution?</title>
      <media>Listening - Multiple choice, choose single answer - Q9 Test 3-4.tpm</media>
      <delay>5</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>Increased sound pollution means whales ‘talk’ more at night than during the day.</o0>
        <o1>Sound pollution from submarines has little impact on whales and other creatures.</o1>
        <o2>Research shows whales communicate to warn each other of sound pollution.</o2>
        <o3>Whales may not survive in some situations where there is sound pollution.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>b3bdebcf854f4b92ac4a09e24a0223f3</id>
    <practiceSet>7b04cda952c144788c9d27aa2d5dc710</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_CHOICE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple -choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>What must the students do before next Wednesday?</title>
      <media>Listening - Multiple choice, choose single answer - Q10 Test 3-4.tpm</media>
      <delay>5</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>email the slides for their presentation.</o0>
        <o1>Post an outline of their talk to the course website.</o1>
        <o2>Make enough copies of their handouts.</o2>
        <o3>Practice giving their presentation.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>a39665eedbd541799b427aacb36ed951</id>
    <practiceSet>7b04cda952c144788c9d27aa2d5dc710</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_SELECT_MISSING_WORD</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording on THE WORK OF A PRINTED WORD AT UNIVERSITY. At the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Select missing word - Q11 Test 3-4.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>And impromptu</o0>
        <o1>And part-time</o1>
        <o2>And considerable</o2>
        <o3>And online</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>7fcbe38db8a04c8e82c7a3e38fba392b</id>
    <practiceSet>7b04cda952c144788c9d27aa2d5dc710</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_SELECT_MISSING_WORD</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording on EFFECT OF ARCHITECTURE ON PEOPLE’S MIND. At the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Select missing word - Q12 Test 3-4.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>The right thing</o0>
        <o1>The correct</o1>
        <o2>The positive</o2>
        <o3>The adverse</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>50dce3ffbd444472bae966fe005c37fc</id>
    <practiceSet>7b04cda952c144788c9d27aa2d5dc710</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_HIGHLIGHT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Below is a transcription of the recording. Some words in the transcription differ from what the speaker(s) said. Please click on words that are different. </instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Mushrooms have been valued or preferred for their nutritional benefits in the Eastern cultures. In Asia, mushrooms were thought to have many beneficial qualities. Other important nutritions in mushrooms are minerals. Mushrooms contain selenium, copper, potassium and ergothioneine. Selenium helps our body protect the organs from damage. Such damage otherwise, may lead to diseases like cancer or cardiac disorders and also early ageing. For those who eat a vegetarian diet, mushrooms act as a good source of selenium as vegetarian diet normally lacks this mineral. Mushrooms grow in a unique way. Perhaps a mushroom growing is one of the most important stories in the field of agriculture. </description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Highlight Incorrect Words- Q13 Test 3-4.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      
      <answer>preferred|thought|nutritions|organs|also|eat|way|important</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>532daa4e58c54f199d71b98ea57648d4</id>
    <practiceSet>7b04cda952c144788c9d27aa2d5dc710</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_HIGHLIGHT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Below is a transcription of the recording. Some words in the transcription differ from what the speaker(s) said. Please click on words that are different. </instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>It was in 1891 that the American Buddhist Henry Steel OIcott, founder of the Theosophical Society came to Australia. Here he attended a series of lectures, which led to a greater spread of Buddhism in small circles of the middle class society in Australia. It is believed that the first Buddhist monk visited Australia in 1910. Soon more monks started visiting Australia. But during the period 1986-1991 the number has increased a lot. During this phase Buddhism gained immense support from its ardent devotees who were committed towards this religion. The first formal Buddhist organization in Australia was the Buddhist Study Group, Melbourne. It was formed by Len Bullen in 1938. Today, it is not at all surprising to come across various publications at any bookshop that displays vibrant and multiple images of Lord Buddha or some symbols relating to the faith. Today, the population following this faith is made up not only of people of Asian origin: it has cast a spell on a large number of natives as well. </description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Highlight Incorrect Words- Q14 Test 3-4.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      
      <answer>founder|spread|middle|lot|multiple</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>4488fe8bd0894af3b3c512786b2e8a9f</id>
    <practiceSet>7b04cda952c144788c9d27aa2d5dc710</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Write from dictation- Q15 Test 3-4.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>We would like people to write a case study, describing an organization they know.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>7df507638b0a4ef980ac8d60d65cb9f8</id>
    <practiceSet>7b04cda952c144788c9d27aa2d5dc710</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Write from dictation- Q16 Test 3-4.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>Students are held accountable for adhering to established community standards.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>e57263aae30042db915c1e47acec4f5f</id>
    <practiceSet>7b04cda952c144788c9d27aa2d5dc710</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Write from dictation- Q17 Test 3-4.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>The brief outline takes us to the beginning of the 20th century.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <!-- Test 5 -->
  <question>
    <id>d6c99a8bc43447549c5777ded1a3f04d</id>
    <practiceSet>d9d885229cf64aceb84b19095b1ffd9c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_WRITE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a short lecture. Write a summary for fellow student who was not present at the lecture. You should write 50-70 words. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points presented in the lecture.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Summarize Spoken Text - Q1 Test 3-5.tpm</media>
      <delay>10</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>The conversation is about GM foods that are probably safer than non GM foods. There are tighter controls for GM food in each country and then at a European level as well. The possibilities for GM food are endless. Moreover, as global warming is threatening to destroy the habitat of animals so GM food can help to prevent them from becoming extinct. </answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>7b931f94aa534ae39508f3a1bed844c7</id>
    <practiceSet>d9d885229cf64aceb84b19095b1ffd9c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_WRITE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a short lecture. Write a summary for fellow student who was not present at the lecture. You should write 50-70 words. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points presented in the lecture.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Summarize Spoken Text - Q2 Test 3-5.tpm</media>
      <delay>10</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>The lecture is about the usage of computer X-ray tomography, CT scans, to examine Egyptian mummies for heart disease. The doctors studied the remains of twenty people who died long ago and the results showed the signs of atherosclerosis. Medical doctors from the USA and Egypt reported on the results and they estimated the ages at which the ancient Egyptians died have played a part in the disease.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>5f0996b8d45c4cd3bf7897c2e1f50432</id>
    <practiceSet>d9d885229cf64aceb84b19095b1ffd9c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_SELECT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct responses. You will need to select more than one response.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>Which of the following conditions need to be met by parents who want to have their children educated at home?</title>
      <media>Listening - Multiple choice, choose multiple answers - Q3 Test 3-5.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>They must provide lesson plans.</o0>
        <o1>They must ensure their child plays a sport.</o1>
        <o2>They must provide regular assessments.</o2>
        <o3>They must provide book lists.</o3>
        <o4>They must keep the record of attendance.</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>0|3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>9f2dbd177ec549739d283b8cdf709d29</id>
    <practiceSet>d9d885229cf64aceb84b19095b1ffd9c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_SELECT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct responses. You will need to select more than one response.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>According to the text, who were originally responsible for popularizing rice in Europe?</title>
      <media>Listening - Multiple choice, choose multiple answers - Q4 Test 3-5.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>The Chinese</o0>
        <o1>The Greeks</o1>
        <o2>The Spanish</o2>
        <o3>The Arabs</o3>
        <o4>The Italians</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>2|3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>0a909b9aed3d4392bd27bf5dd6eca970</id>
    <practiceSet>d9d885229cf64aceb84b19095b1ffd9c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_FILL_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Type the missing words in each blank.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>John wasn't wrong on {blank} count. Meetings before the meeting are a necessary evil in his company today, and I didn't like it at all. Sure, it was going to be inefficient and annoying, but what bothered me most was his {blank} that it's not how they'll do things in the future. How could he be sure? Who was going to change it and when, if it wasn't him and now? What would the trigger be? And when it happened, would he even know how to have effective meetings without pre-meetings? He was confidently {blank} that when he's the boss, he'll change the rules and do things differently, but all I could see were dishes stacking in the sink and a guy with a lot of good {blank} . Worse, a guy who might be out of a job one day because he learned too late how to lead in the organizations of {blank} .</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Fill in the blanks - Q5 Test 3-5.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      
      <answer>either|confidence|implying|excuses|tomorrow</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>1739b1633de14fd68090e1477be8ec89</id>
    <practiceSet>d9d885229cf64aceb84b19095b1ffd9c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_FILL_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Type the missing words in each blank.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Clearly, we're living in a moment of crisis. {blank} , the financial markets have failed us and the aid system is failing us, and yet I stand firmly with the {blank} , who believe that there has probably never been a more exciting moment to be alive. Because of some of technologies we've been talking about. Because of the {blank} , the skills, and certainly the surge of talent we're seeing all around the world, with the {blank} to create change. And we've got a president who sees himself as a global citizen, who recognizes that no longer is there a single {blank} , but that we've got to engage in a different way with the world.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Fill in the blanks - Q6 Test 3-5.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      
      <answer>Arguably|optimists|resources|mindset|superpower</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>0aeb9a2affe74b38b9f7331161deef31</id>
    <practiceSet>d9d885229cf64aceb84b19095b1ffd9c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_HIGHLIGHT_CORRECT_SUMMARY</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Click on paragraph that best relates to the recording.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Highlight Correct Summary - Q7 Test 3-5.tpm</media>
      <delay>10</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>The biggest mistake when setting up business systems is to create an ideal combination from the best parts of several processes. Inaccurate information usually leads to problems, while adjusting attitudes is the best solution.</o0>
        <o1>One of the mistakes a manager usually makes is to create an ideal combination from the best parts of several processes. Disadvantages are overlooked, which is one of the reasons why some attempts lead to problems. What we can do is to change attitudes.</o1>
        <o2>There are two mistakes that usually occur when setting up a business system, and the cause of problems has been mentioned, such as inaccurate information.</o2>
        <o3>There are two mistakes that usually occur when setting up a business system, and there are various reasons why these attempts turn out to be misguided. In general, no action can be taken at any stage.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>65475adbae764e4db0e4e282d3621032</id>
    <practiceSet>d9d885229cf64aceb84b19095b1ffd9c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_HIGHLIGHT_CORRECT_SUMMARY</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Click on paragraph that best relates to the recording.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Highlight Correct Summary - Q8 Test 3-5.tpm</media>
      <delay>10</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>New arrivals to North America need to make sure that their degrees or diplomas are accepted. Most companies see training as the most important when hiring, and apprenticeships can help new arrivals to look for a job in North America.</o0>
        <o1>New arrivals to North America do not need to gain any academic qualification, because most companies do not view formal education as a major requirement. Rather, being involved in an apprenticeship training is more important when hiring.</o1>
        <o2>Most companies view academic qualification as a major requirement when hiring, and they prefer to hire people educated in North America. Research indicates that immigrants are usually offered a lower salary than people who have completed their training in North America.</o2>
        <o3>New arrivals to North America need to make sure that their academic qualifications or trade certificates are accepted. A significant number of companies view formal education as a major requirement. People educated in North America may initially be offered a higher salary than immigrants.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>1b61656790d64480b06ae4aee107deb7</id>
    <practiceSet>d9d885229cf64aceb84b19095b1ffd9c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_CHOICE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple -choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct. </instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>What is the main idea that the speaker is trying to convey in her comments?</title>
      <media>Listening - Multiple choice, choose single answer 9 Test 3-5.tpm</media>
      <delay>5</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>Government can play a key role in chronic pain management.</o0>
        <o1>Authorization for the prescription of opiates is required every thirty days.</o1>
        <o2>The rate of morphine addiction has not increased over the past 18 years.</o2>
        <o3>The dose of opiates needed to treat chronic pain is usually 80 milligrams.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>9f18f0390b424d86b11cdaec4ddc2664</id>
    <practiceSet>d9d885229cf64aceb84b19095b1ffd9c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_CHOICE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple -choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct. </instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>What is the lecture mainly about?</title>
      <media>Listening - Multiple choice, choose single answer 10 Test 3-5.tpm</media>
      <delay>5</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>Perception and how it relates to the mind and your eyes.</o0>
        <o1>Institution and how to use it form theory.</o1>
        <o2>Theory and how it forces you to lose aspects of yourself.</o2>
        <o3>Skill and how should it be applied in university text.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>6c7b2c9cc4964883a28b537db6e47447</id>
    <practiceSet>d9d885229cf64aceb84b19095b1ffd9c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_SELECT_MISSING_WORD</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording on THE ADAPTION OF ANIMALS TO URBANIZATION. At the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Select missing word - Q11 Test 3-5.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>than rural ones</o0>
        <o1>than civil based</o1>
        <o2>than urbanized</o2>
        <o3>than civilized</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>8342a60012dc492a8ebbcd90b7037d85</id>
    <practiceSet>d9d885229cf64aceb84b19095b1ffd9c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_SELECT_MISSING_WORD</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording on A CHEMICAL EXPERIMENT. At the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Select missing word - Q12 Test 3-5.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>under surveillance.</o0>
        <o1>gradual disposition.</o1>
        <o2> burning structure.</o2>
        <o3>naked eye.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>eeb25160ab164135af40ca7576f5bace</id>
    <practiceSet>d9d885229cf64aceb84b19095b1ffd9c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_HIGHLIGHT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Below is a transcription of the recording. Some words in the transcription differ from what the speaker(s) said. Please click on words that are different. </instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>The point, where the earthquake fault originates, is called the hypocenter or the focus and the point directly below this, on the ground, is called the epicenter. Depth of the hypocenter is known as the focal depth. Hypocenter usually lies deep down on the fault. The intensity of an earthquake is the most at the epicenter. If an earthquake could be accurately predicted, one could make some preparation to escape any loss caused by this terrifying phenomenon. However, prediction with a measure of certainty is not all that easy.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Highlight Incorrect Words- Q13 Test 3-5.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      
      <answer>fault|below|most|escape|certainty</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>982c434024be4b01aa5c8431a476a80e</id>
    <practiceSet>d9d885229cf64aceb84b19095b1ffd9c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_HIGHLIGHT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Below is a transcription of the recording. Some words in the transcription differ from what the speaker(s) said. Please click on words that are different. </instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Steven Hotel Management School defines not only management science but hospitality science also. Just to fulfill the spoken demands of the customers is not the important thing, the important thing lies in leading the mind of the customers. Our students learn how to involve in the personal taste of the customers while designing the menu, developing concepts, designing interiors, tabletop presentations, interacting with customers, delivering services that the customer will like and appreciate, instead of focusing too much on work for my own benefit. This means our main approach should be customer centric. Hospitality needs both sentiment and business sense. Our management program directs the talent and creativity of our students to proper channels, and provides them with a solid base in management, and this is what is required in today's hospitality marketplace. Our school investigates the latest management theory with realistic experimental learning. Besides, our affiliation with some foreign schools providing the same education will benefit students as they will be able to study and intern abroad.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Highlight Incorrect Words- Q14 Test 3-5.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      
      <answer>defines|leading|sentiment|base|investigates</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>2c92fca050e741d4baece714d15a44e3</id>
    <practiceSet>d9d885229cf64aceb84b19095b1ffd9c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Write from dictation- Q15 Test 3-5.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>The Romans left in 410, at the beginning of the 5th century.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>13dc6ae46ddb4139a34921f6a36d229a</id>
    <practiceSet>d9d885229cf64aceb84b19095b1ffd9c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Write from dictation- Q16 Test 3-5.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>The seminar will be on the next week of the quarter.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>9792eefb3ecb46409f501a24f3ea945c</id>
    <practiceSet>d9d885229cf64aceb84b19095b1ffd9c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Write from dictation- Q17 Test 3-5.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>Smoke from these contributed a great deal to the air pollution</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>ebcb7534e7c1411383149e351116adfc</id>
    <practiceSet>d9d885229cf64aceb84b19095b1ffd9c</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Write from dictation- Q18 Test 3-5.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>The technology they introduced meant that metal and leather goods were produced there for the first time.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <!-- Test 6 -->
  <question>
    <id>358a036bb4c447e898c62746d4763dc9</id>
    <practiceSet>5dcbc550333c488996e65d41dad0bfe7</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_WRITE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a short lecture. Write a summary for fellow student who was not present at the lecture. You should write 50-70 words. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points presented in the lecture.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Summarize Spoken Text - Q1 Test 3-6.tpm</media>
      <delay>10</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>The lecture about a town in Italy where legislation wants people to use silent fireworks for celebration. The town which is the province of Parma thinks the welfare of their pets is more important. The more sensitive hearing of animals develops acoustic stress and some additional health problems in animals. The problems created by the sound of fireworks is growing in Europe. The explosions lead to post-traumatic stress disorder.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>dd0261ef38ae426f9efc62d976b48042</id>
    <practiceSet>5dcbc550333c488996e65d41dad0bfe7</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_WRITE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a short lecture. Write a summary for fellow student who was not present at the lecture. You should write 50-70 words. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points presented in the lecture.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Summarize Spoken Text - Q2 Test 3-6.tpm</media>
      <delay>10</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>The lecture is about burning of fossil fuel and cutting down of trees which is warming the Earth. There are some new researches based on temperature readings which are based on international program called Argo, this is the reason 3, 500 robotic buoys were deployed in 2004 to measure sea temperatures. Dr. Paul Durack and his colleagues compared the new Argo data with ocean models and satellite readings.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>4ad949b400654aa185a79f6ae5561bed</id>
    <practiceSet>5dcbc550333c488996e65d41dad0bfe7</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_SELECT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting  all the correct responses. You will need to select more than one response.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>How does the professor develop the topic of tsunamis?</title>
      <media>Listening - Multiple choice, choose multiple answers - Q3 Test 3-6.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>By giving examples of tsunamis.</o0>
        <o1>By comparing tsunamis and floods.</o1>
        <o2>By sharing his experience of a tsunamis.</o2>
        <o3>By describing causes of tsunamis.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>0|3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>bec4e401ba844403a6043907ada5b3b7</id>
    <practiceSet>5dcbc550333c488996e65d41dad0bfe7</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_SELECT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting  all the correct responses. You will need to select more than one response.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>Which of the following are suggested as reasons why contemporary writers on politics are less readable and relevant than the ancient writers?</title>
      <media>Listening - Multiple choice, choose multiple answers - Q4 Test 3-6.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>They only write about institutions</o0>
        <o1>They tend to focus on only one aspect of political systems.</o1>
        <o2>Being university-based forces them to specialize.</o2>
        <o3>They ask largely irrelevant questions.</o3>
		<o4>They follow the example of 19th century writers.</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>1|2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>1aafa071d643404caa097fd4ff9fc6ee</id>
    <practiceSet>5dcbc550333c488996e65d41dad0bfe7</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_FILL_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Type the missing words in each .</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>
        Tom Kunz puts {blank} devices on bats and birds to follow their movement. Recently,  the Boston University biologist started using information {blank} by radar.
        TOM KUNZ: “The technology has improved to the {blank} that we can now see things that we couldn’t see before.” Weather experts commonly ignore radar images of birds and bats when they predict {blank} conditions. But Kunz says biologists can learn a lot from radar station readings.
        TOM KUNZ: “From an {blank} and networked dataset,  we can actually determine where and when bats and birds are moving across the landscape.” Kunz spoke at a meeting of the American Association for the {blank} of Science.
      </description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Fill in the blanks - Q5 Test 3-6.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      
      <answer>electronic|gathered|extent|weather|integrated|Advancement</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>c8bbd48705dc4e7e850cc5408b90e0f3</id>
    <practiceSet>5dcbc550333c488996e65d41dad0bfe7</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_FILL_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Type the missing words in each .</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>
        And so I urge you, in whatever sector you work, in whatever job you do, to start thinking about how we might build solutions that start from the {blank} of those we were trying to help. Rather than what we think that they might need. It will take {blank} the world with both arms. And it will take living with the spirit of generosity and accountability,  with a sense of integrity and {blank}. And yet these are the very qualities for which men and women have been {blank} throughout the generations. And there is so much good that we can do. Just think of all those {blank} in the desert.
      </description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Fill in the blanks - Q6 Test 3-6.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      
      <answer>perspective|embracing|perseverance|honored|sunflowers</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>376fcaae7d344e5dafc2d5370f5180ca</id>
    <practiceSet>5dcbc550333c488996e65d41dad0bfe7</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_HIGHLIGHT_CORRECT_SUMMARY</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Click on paragraph that best relates to the recording.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Highlight Correct Summary - Q7 Test 3-6.tpm</media>
      <delay>10</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>We used to think that animals have friends only for biological reasons but we are discovering that animals can also have friends like humans can,  and can sometimes have friends from different species.</o0>
        <o1>We used to think that animals have friends only for biological reasons because we focused too much on how animals need to survive with the help of another animal.</o1>
        <o2>We used to think that animals have friends only for biological reasons because they are unable to be generous and give up something important for a friend without expecting anything back from them.</o2>
        <o3>We used to think that animals have friends only for biological reasons but now we know this not to be free,  however,  animals cannot have friends from different species.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>d16420a1c5c346948aa5be5bf431eb4b</id>
    <practiceSet>5dcbc550333c488996e65d41dad0bfe7</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_HIGHLIGHT_CORRECT_SUMMARY</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Click on paragraph that best relates to the recording.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Highlight Correct Summary - Q8 Test 3-6.tpm</media>
      <delay>10</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>The geographical distribution of one endangered species needs to be consider,  and the assessed figure is expected to be 1, 500. Increasing the number of ocean reserves is critical when retaining ocean biodiversity.</o0>
        <o1>Considering the population size and decline rate of one ocean species is essential with the aim to assess 20, 000 species. We need to establish ocean reserves as there is no reserve nowadays.</o1>
        <o2>The body Global Marine Species Assessment listed endangered ocean species by taking the population size and geographical distribution into account,  and recommendations to retain ocean</o2>
        <o3>The body Global Marine Species Assessment listed endangered ocean species by taking the population size and decline rate into account,  and recommendations to retain ocean biodiversity are given,  such as reducing fishing quotas.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>d6465a2b8fd046e3ae645d3299df6fe3</id>
    <practiceSet>5dcbc550333c488996e65d41dad0bfe7</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_CHOICE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple -choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct. </instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>What is the lecture mainly about?</title>
      <media>Listening - Multiple choice, choose single answer - Q9 Test 3-6.tpm</media>
      <delay>5</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>The compensatory mechanism of bulimia.</o0>
        <o1>Characteristics of bulimics.</o1>
        <o2>Bulimics can also be anorexics.</o2>
        <o3>The binging and purging cycles of bulimics.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>348efd2cb1ac49cb934a52dfb4ebd54f</id>
    <practiceSet>5dcbc550333c488996e65d41dad0bfe7</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_CHOICE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple -choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct. </instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>What is the lecture mainly about?</title>
      <media>Listening - Multiple choice, choose single answer - Q10 Test 3-6.tpm</media>
      <delay>5</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>Retrogressive treatment of autism.</o0>
        <o1>Various approaches to prevent autism.</o1>
        <o2>The role of Applied Behavior Analysis in treating autism.</o2>
        <o3>The rehabilitation of autistic people.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>710dda2add7a4c58bf82e8fb8a408dba</id>
    <practiceSet>5dcbc550333c488996e65d41dad0bfe7</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_CHOICE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple -choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct. </instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>What is the lecture mainly about?</title>
      <media>Listening - Multiple choice, choose single answer - Q11 Test 3-6.tpm</media>
      <delay>5</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>The twin cure for phobias.</o0>
        <o1>The three pronged approach to treat phobias.</o1>
        <o2>Facing a phobia with determination may cure it.</o2>
        <o3>The collective approach to treat phobias.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>f3adbbf5bf9b4b70b9ef9cb0f21f0183</id>
    <practiceSet>5dcbc550333c488996e65d41dad0bfe7</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_SELECT_MISSING_WORD</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording on A STUDY ON NEANDERTHALS. At the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Select missing word - Q12 Test 3-6.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>Dry,  modern air.</o0>
        <o1>Dry,  Galapagos air</o1>
        <o2>Dry,  turmoil air</o2>
        <o3>Ice age air.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>c1c370ff8df34d95bdfe915aec89db10</id>
    <practiceSet>5dcbc550333c488996e65d41dad0bfe7</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_SELECT_MISSING_WORD</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording on A RECENT ARCHEOLOGICAL RESEARCH. At the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Select missing word - Q13 Test 3-6.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>barefoot</o0>
        <o1>childlike</o1>
        <o2>rodents</o2>
        <o3>dignified</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>e5f58009b1d34fb28b22acb16f09efa0</id>
    <practiceSet>5dcbc550333c488996e65d41dad0bfe7</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_HIGHLIGHT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Below is a transcription of the recording. Some words in the transcription differ from what the speaker(s) said. Please click on words that are different. </instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>The UN Charter comprises a preamble and 19 chapters divided into 111 articles. The Charter sets out the purposes of the United Nations as: the maintenance of international peace and civility,  the development of friendly relations between states,  and the achievement of cooperation in solving international ecologic,  social,  cultural,  and humanitarian problems. It expresses a strong hope for the ability of all people and the expansion of basic freedoms. The principal organs of the United Nations,  as specified in the Charter,  are the General Assembly,  the Security Council, the Economic and Social Council,  the Trusteeship Council,  the International Court of Justice,  and the Secretariat.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Highlight Incorrect Words- Q14 Test 3-6.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      
      <answer>out|civility|social|ability</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>60868b119fcf403a90fc9aa80c597a07</id>
    <practiceSet>5dcbc550333c488996e65d41dad0bfe7</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_HIGHLIGHT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Below is a transcription of the recording. Some words in the transcription differ from what the speaker(s) said. Please click on words that are different. </instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>French, on the other hand, is a highly gentrified language, with the Parisian accent setting the standard for the world. If other French-speaking political abilities had risen to rival France, the situation might be dissident. If for instance, Quebec had remained a separate entity, or if Haiti had been a larger country, then perhaps other French dialects might have become more accepted. </description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Highlight Incorrect Words- Q15 Test 3-6.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      
      <answer>gentrified|abilities|dissident|entity</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>19cea0f5654e4f269d8d14cefcd7c554</id>
    <practiceSet>5dcbc550333c488996e65d41dad0bfe7</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Write from dictation- Q16 Test 3-6.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>This course will examine some of the profound ethical dilemmas.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>df9ceb631f15457e86b7f3aa8ab532b3</id>
    <practiceSet>5dcbc550333c488996e65d41dad0bfe7</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Write from dictation- Q17 Test 3-6.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>This year, we are planning to use a different type of assessment on this module.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>ad03fdfa6b1d4c9fa45f7003f9e16bf3</id>
    <practiceSet>5dcbc550333c488996e65d41dad0bfe7</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Write from dictation- Q18 Test 3-6.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>We are also going to be more prescriptive about what you focus on in your presentation.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>b372620449a24ca0a27cce5b29abf464</id>
    <practiceSet>5dcbc550333c488996e65d41dad0bfe7</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Write from dictation- Q19 Test 3-6.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>We are not going to accept the assignment after the due date on Friday.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <!-- Test 7 -->
  <question>
    <id>cfc20b19422f43ee8b586db05bc5d740</id>
    <practiceSet>0b7002c915a441eebdb4448e4388ba5b</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_WRITE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a short lecture. Write a summary for fellow student who was not present at the lecture. You should write 50-70 words. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points presented in the lecture.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Summarize Spoken Text - Q1 Test 3-7.tpm</media>
      <delay>10</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>The lecture describes that the speaker heard some words when he was six years old was inspired. He wanted to explore strange new worlds and he wanted to see everything that the universe had to offer. The dreams, the words, a journey of discovery through school and university and finally to become an astronomer. He learned that the universe is strange, wonderful and too vast to be explored.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>7f7acea561b24a44bc12c1228e4c0b1f</id>
    <practiceSet>0b7002c915a441eebdb4448e4388ba5b</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_WRITE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a short lecture. Write a summary for fellow student who was not present at the lecture. You should write 50-70 words. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points presented in the lecture.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Summarize Spoken Text - Q2 Test 3-7.tpm</media>
      <delay>10</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>The lecture describes the survey by best buy which shows that some companies including staples and best buy subsidize electronics recycling and take e-waste for free and to enquire more speaker called CEO and Co-Founder of electronic recyclers international and they said that when people come to know how to recycle, where to recycle then most of the people want to do the right thing and recycling are rising.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>11ebdcb6f75348c3bc5f833d88b85c8b</id>
    <practiceSet>0b7002c915a441eebdb4448e4388ba5b</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_SELECT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting  all the correct responses. You will need to select more than one response.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>According to the instructor, why are synthetic pigments superior to natural pigments?</title>
      <media>Listening - Multiple choice, choose multiple answers - Q3 Test 3-7.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>They last for a longer time.</o0>
        <o1>They provide stronger, brighter colors.</o1>
        <o2>They have a smoother surface.</o2>
        <o3>They are less expensive.</o3>
        <o4>They are less superior to other products.</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>1|2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>514366f29796461eb3b51862c91129bc</id>
    <practiceSet>0b7002c915a441eebdb4448e4388ba5b</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_SELECT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting  all the correct responses. You will need to select more than one response.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>Identify the types of substances that erupt from volcanoes.</title>
      <media>Listening - Multiple choice, choose multiple answers - Q4 Test 3-7.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>Hot gases.</o0>
        <o1>Yellow stone.</o1>
        <o2>Liquefied rock.</o2>
        <o3>Ice cones.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>1|2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>008338bd7d844a169bea2adb22883406</id>
    <practiceSet>0b7002c915a441eebdb4448e4388ba5b</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_FILL_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Type the missing words in each blank.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>
        Scientists have come up with answers to the age-old question of why eyelashes are the length they are. Researchers at the {blank} Institute of Technology conducted a variety of tests on the lashes of 22 different mammals. One was to create a special wind tunnel and an artificial eye to provide mathematical models of how the wind blew over lashes. The {blank} of head researcher David Hu is that the function of eyelashes is to help protect the eyes from drying out and that the optimal eyelash length for this to happen is one-third as long as the eye is wide. Professor Hu found that across a wide variety of mammals, the ratio of eyelash length and eye width was {blank} one-third.
        Dr Hu started his investigation after the birth of his newborn daughter. He wondered why his baby kept on batting her eyelids. He told the International Business Times that: "Eyelashes that rim the eyes in mammals have been a {blank} for a long time as to what their function was. There were a lot of hypotheses, from dust catchers to triggering the blink reflex.What we did was the first aerodynamic study of eyelashes. We showed using three independent means that eyelashes reduce evaporation of the eye by 70 per cent, and they reduce [the deposits] of small airborne particles." A {blank} said Hu had a talent for, "looking at what everybody has looked at, and seeing what nobody has seen."
      </description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Fill in the blanks - Q5 Test 3-7.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      
      <answer>Georgia|conclusion|consistently|mystery|colleague</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>3e4fd225a94a499f81c645417fa3c1d3</id>
    <practiceSet>0b7002c915a441eebdb4448e4388ba5b</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_FILL_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Type the missing words in each blank.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>
        A new report warns that people could be in danger from superbugs if they eat rare and undercooked meat. The report is called the Review on {blank} Resistance. Researchers looked into how antibiotics in food are making bugs stronger. The report said the use of antibiotics in agriculture is making bugs stronger and more resistant to our medicines. The researchers said the huge amount of {blank} in farming could be dangerous to people's health around the world. They suggested that farmers reduce the amount of antibiotics they give to their animals. The leader of the research, Jim O'Neill, said this was important if we wanted to make sure that our life-saving medicines still work {blank} .
        The researchers are calling for strict targets to reduce the number of antibiotics given to farm animals. Mr O'Neill said this was necessary because of the huge amount of antibiotics farmers give their animals. He said: "I find it {blank} that in many countries, most of the consumption of antibiotics is in animals, rather than humans. This creates a big risk for everyone." He added that the public could get ill from superbugs if they ate meat that was rare or undercooked. He said: "My advice to {blank} is that they have to make sure they cook meat properly. If you are going to choose to cook it as rare as possible you have to be aware of where it's coming from."
      </description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Fill in the blanks - Q6 Test 3-7.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      
      <answer>Antimicrobial|antibiotics|effectively|unbelievable|consumers</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>574ff56c236844d29a74cb0e795ea7a8</id>
    <practiceSet>0b7002c915a441eebdb4448e4388ba5b</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_FILL_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Type the missing words in each blank.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>
        Many diseases that doctors thought had almost {blank} are now making a comeback. Britain's National Health Service  has reported a serious rise in the number of people with diseases such as {blank} , cholera, measles and whooping cough. An NHS spokesperson said that TB is now more common in England than it is in less developed countries such Rwanda, Iraq, and Guatemala. Tuberculosis is also increasing across the globe. In 2013, it killed 1.5 million people {blank} , and that number is rising. Tuberculosis largely affects very poor people. It is an {blank} disease that affects the lungs. Its symptoms include bad coughs, fever, weight loss.
      </description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Fill in the blanks - Q7 Test 3-7.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      
      <answer>disappeared|tuberculosis|worldwide|infectious</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>e7cc588c25a94ab0abdeff2159cadd18</id>
    <practiceSet>0b7002c915a441eebdb4448e4388ba5b</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_HIGHLIGHT_CORRECT_SUMMARY</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Click on paragraph that best relates to the recording.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Highlight Correct Summary - Q8 Test 3-7.tpm</media>
      <delay>10</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>People care about global warming but there’s a lot of talk, little action, and certainly no solution yet.</o0>
        <o1>People are starting to suffer from global warming fatigue and global warming campaigners must therefore turn sad stories into happy ones.</o1>
        <o2>People care about global warming but do not want to read articles that make them feel depressed and helpless.</o2>
        <o3>People are negative about global warming, constantly espousing the fact that politicians are choosing the economy over the environment.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>3efce99805e94a60aae08b2fa2b7c10f</id>
    <practiceSet>0b7002c915a441eebdb4448e4388ba5b</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_HIGHLIGHT_CORRECT_SUMMARY</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Click on paragraph that best relates to the recording.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Highlight Correct Summary - Q9 Test 3-7.tpm</media>
      <delay>10</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>Scientists have claimed that the Great Pacific Garbage Patch is a very big problem nowadays due to it being twice the size the state of Texas.</o0>
        <o1>Scientists have claimed that the plastic in the ocean is very harmful to sea life, especially since there’s more plastic in the ocean than plankton.</o1>
        <o2>Scientists espouse the harmfulness of the Great Pacific Garbage patch but rather than trying to remove it we should try to prevent more garbage from entering the ocean.</o2>
        <o3>Scientists have lied about the severity of the Great Pacific Garbage Patch, just like how journalists have made things sound worse than they are in the past.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>cee33b1f751240ef9e49a5b00d08425b</id>
    <practiceSet>0b7002c915a441eebdb4448e4388ba5b</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_CHOICE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple -choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>What inspired the speaker to go to Africa and write about wildlife?</title>
      <media>Listening - Multiple choice, choose single answer - Q10 Test 3-7.tpm</media>
      <delay>5</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>Climbing up her favorite tree.</o0>
        <o1>Reading a book about apes.</o1>
        <o2>Her dream of becoming a journalist.</o2>
        <o3>Her desire to prove other’s wrong</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>d199d508b9894d5e849616efe5885fcf</id>
    <practiceSet>0b7002c915a441eebdb4448e4388ba5b</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_CHOICE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple -choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>What is the main idea that the speaker is trying to convey?</title>
      <media>Listening - Multiple choice, choose single answer - Q11 Test 3-7.tpm</media>
      <delay>5</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>Geysers, unlike volcanoes, are all about water.</o0>
        <o1>Geysers are a part of normal geothermal activity.</o1>
        <o2>How geysers occur in nature.</o2>
        <o3>Geysers are a sporadic and explosive version of hot springs.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>fa506974d297425383ae1afabbcf15cb</id>
    <practiceSet>0b7002c915a441eebdb4448e4388ba5b</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_CHOICE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple -choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>What is lecture mainly about?</title>
      <media>Listening - Multiple choice, choose single answer - Q12 Test 3-7.tpm</media>
      <delay>5</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>The evolution of wedding gown.</o0>
        <o1>The wedding gown and riches.</o1>
        <o2>The importance of wedding gowns.</o2>
        <o3>Wedding gowns and women.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>cdc9ed4bd3c34264a4dd7c3749c6909a</id>
    <practiceSet>0b7002c915a441eebdb4448e4388ba5b</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_SELECT_MISSING_WORD</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording on MONITORING WILD ANIMALS USING DRONES. At the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Select missing word - Q13 Test 3-7.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>breeding</o0>
        <o1>charming</o1>
        <o2>deserting</o2>
        <o3>poaching</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>ca77914e1f2640fb859c0487fdea82c2</id>
    <practiceSet>0b7002c915a441eebdb4448e4388ba5b</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_SELECT_MISSING_WORD</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording on a ROLE OF ENZYMES IN PHOTOSYNTHESIS. At the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Select missing word - Q14 Test 3-7.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>results</o0>
        <o1>challenges</o1>
        <o2>Opportunities</o2>
        <o3>Gratifications</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>0adc570c560046319999bb5cc658ccf1</id>
    <practiceSet>0b7002c915a441eebdb4448e4388ba5b</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_HIGHLIGHT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Below is a transcription of the recording. Some words in the transcription differ from what the speaker(s) said. Please click on words that are different. </instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>When societies were still mostly rural and agricultural, waste dispersal was hardly an issue, partly because people tended to make use of everything and partly because there was plenty of space to bury rubbish. It was when societies became predominantly urban and industrious that problems arose - mainly to do with wealth. City authorities had a hard time trying to find effective ways of getting rid of all the rubbish. One of these was to get people to set out their rubbish into different types, just as these days we are encouraged to separate our rubbish into different categories for easier removal and recycling. So, for example, kitchen rubbish was set aside and used for feeding animals. However, fears of disease put an end to that. In fact, it wasn't until the 20th century that all waste was simply thrown together and put into landfills.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Highlight Incorrect Words- Q15 Test 3-7.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      
      <answer>dispersal|industrious|wealth|effective|set|put</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>d81e8c91484041edb18c47bc81a74851</id>
    <practiceSet>0b7002c915a441eebdb4448e4388ba5b</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_HIGHLIGHT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Below is a transcription of the recording. Some words in the transcription differ from what the speaker(s) said. Please click on words that are different. </instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Archery, the practice or art of shooting with a bow and arrow, has played an important part in English history, being the major weapon of the foot-soldier and instrumental in winning many battles in wars with the French -with whom we seemed to be continuously at war during the Middle Ages. The English featured the longbow over the short bow and the crossbow, the latter being the main firearm of militias on the European continent. The crossbow fired a metal bolt released by a trigger, rather like a gun, and had the farthest range of any of the bows, but the main advantage of the longbow was its accuracy. The importance placed on archery is illustrated by the fact that medieval kings in England encouraged the practice and one of them, Edward III, went so far as to bar all sports on Sundays and holidays except archery. Because there were no standing armies in those days, and in the event of war rulers had to call on the populace, everything was done to make sure there were large numbers of competent, if not expert archers, to recruit.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Highlight Incorrect Words- Q16 Test 3-7.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      
      <answer>major|continuously|featured|militias|farthest|bar</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>f758d77ee1eb41d2a37fb1e8871af5cb</id>
    <practiceSet>0b7002c915a441eebdb4448e4388ba5b</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Write from dictation- Q17 Test 3-7.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>We would like people to write a case study, describing an organization they know</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>2f2425d31fcc40b796599ba4463c131c</id>
    <practiceSet>0b7002c915a441eebdb4448e4388ba5b</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Write from dictation- Q18 Test 3-7.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>We are warning the clients that the rates are increasing.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>6b116ba76ccf4ee2b336b5275c4a47fc</id>
    <practiceSet>0b7002c915a441eebdb4448e4388ba5b</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Write from dictation- Q19 Test 3-7.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>Much of his research objectives are driven by his natural curiosity and instincts.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>3c0765193ceb498e9749f9437bbf8d8f</id>
    <practiceSet>0b7002c915a441eebdb4448e4388ba5b</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Write from dictation- Q20 Test 3-7.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>The fire left the area almost completely devoid of vegetation.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <!-- Test 8  -->
  <question>
    <id>56f95c7608de482a9d4a82f4b4cffb9e</id>
    <practiceSet>05424cf5c42745de8f6fdef719e5351b</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_WRITE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a short lecture. Write a summary for fellow student who was not present at the lecture. You should write 50-70 words. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points presented in the lecture.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Summarize Spoken Text - Q1 Test 3-8.tpm</media>
      <delay>0</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer></answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>5910910fcba94bfebcccfe7762c2bfcf</id>
    <practiceSet>05424cf5c42745de8f6fdef719e5351b</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_WRITE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a short lecture. Write a summary for fellow student who was not present at the lecture. You should write 50-70 words. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points presented in the lecture.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Summarize Spoken Text - Q2 Test 3-8.tpm</media>
      <delay>0</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer></answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>33a6e049efd9424d94334325b413fa7c</id>
    <practiceSet>05424cf5c42745de8f6fdef719e5351b</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_SELECT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting  all the correct responses. You will need to select more than one response.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>According to the instructor, which fields require an understanding of perspective?</title>
      <media>Listening - Multiple choice, choose multiple answers - Q3 Test 3-8.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>Industrial design</o0>
        <o1>Architecture</o1>
        <o2>Railroad engineering</o2>
        <o3>Marketing</o3>
        <o4>Vehicles</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>0|1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>66406030050649318948a4b27859aa46</id>
    <practiceSet>05424cf5c42745de8f6fdef719e5351b</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_SELECT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting  all the correct responses. You will need to select more than one response.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>What causes tsunamis?</title>
      <media>Listening - Multiple choice, choose multiple answers - Q4 Test 3-8.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>The moon’s gravity</o0>
        <o1>Undersea earthquakes</o1>
        <o2>Heavy precipitation</o2>
        <o3>Movement of the ocean floor</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>1|3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>e22fb78754864a87aa7a5fa5e7d5f501</id>
    <practiceSet>05424cf5c42745de8f6fdef719e5351b</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_FILL_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Type the missing words in each blank.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>There's a small country nestled in the Himalayan {blank} , far from these beautiful mountains, where the people of the {blank} of Bhutan have decided to do something different, which is to measure their gross national happiness rather than their gross national product. And why not? After all, happiness is not just a privilege for the lucky few, but a {blank} human right for all. And what is happiness? Happiness is the freedom of choice. The freedom to {blank} where to live, what to do, what to buy, what to sell, from whom, to whom, when and how.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Fill in the blanks - Q5 Test 3-8.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      
      <answer>Mountains|Kingdom|fundamental|choose</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>2edc74d048be4cea9f7cb95cf93f8c12</id>
    <practiceSet>05424cf5c42745de8f6fdef719e5351b</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_FILL_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Type the missing words in each blank.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Earth may have been protected for {blank} of years, because we've had a magnetic field. Atmosphere hasn't been able to escape. Mars, on the other hand, has been unprotected because of its lack of {blank} field, and over billions of years, maybe enough atmosphere has been stripped away to account for a transition from a habitable planet to the planet that we see today. Other scientists think that magnetic fields may act more like the sails on a ship, {blank} the planet to interact with more energy from the solar wind than the planet would have been able to interact with by itself. The sails may gather energy from the solar wind. The magnetic field may gather energy from the solar wind that allows even more {blank} escape to happen. It's an idea that has to be tested, but the effect and how it works seems apparent. That's because we know energy from the solar wind is being deposited into our atmosphere here on Earth. That energy is conducted along magnetic field lines down into the polar regions, resulting in {blank} beautiful aurora.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Fill in the blanks - Q6 Test 3-8.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      
      <answer>billions|magnetic|enabling|atmospheric|incredibly</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>51f103187ce34846b48a8f95d75799b1</id>
    <practiceSet>05424cf5c42745de8f6fdef719e5351b</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_HIGHLIGHT_CORRECT_SUMMARY</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Click on paragraph that best relates to the recording.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Highlight Correct Summary - Q7 Test 3-8.tpm</media>
      <delay>10</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>
          We used to think that animals have friends only for biological reasons but we are discovering that
          animals can also have friends like humans can, and can sometimes have friends from different
          species.
        </o0>
        <o1>
          We used to think that animals have friends only for biological reasons because we focused too
          much on how animals need to survive with the help of another animal.
        </o1>
        <o2>
          We used to think that animals have friends only for biological reasons because they are unable to
          be generous and give up something important for a friend without expecting anything back from
          them.
        </o2>
        <o3>
          We used to think that animals have friends only for biological reasons but now we know this not to
          be free, however, animals cannot have friends from different species.
        </o3>
      </options>
      <answer>0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>bd46d1a7a99f4399b57772bda85a91ba</id>
    <practiceSet>05424cf5c42745de8f6fdef719e5351b</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_HIGHLIGHT_CORRECT_SUMMARY</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Click on paragraph that best relates to the recording.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Highlight Correct Summary - Q8 Test 3-8.tpm</media>
      <delay>10</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>
          The geographical distribution of one endangered species needs to be consider, and the assessed
          figure is expected to be 1,500. Increasing the number of ocean reserves is critical when retaining
          ocean biodiversity.
        </o0>
        <o1>
          Considering the population size and decline rate of one ocean species is essential with the aim to
          assess 20,000 species. We need to establish ocean reserves as there is no reserve nowadays.
        </o1>
        <o2>
          The body Global Marine Species Assessment listed endangered ocean species by taking the
          population size and geographical distribution into account, and recommendations to retain ocean
          biodiversity are given, such as establishing migration corridors.
        </o2>
        <o3>
          The body Global Marine Species Assessment listed endangered ocean species by taking the
          population size and decline rate into account, and recommendations to retain ocean biodiversity are
          given, such as reducing fishing quotas.
        </o3>
      </options>
      <answer>2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>6fd37eadfaf14402a753e4decd6c4de1</id>
    <practiceSet>05424cf5c42745de8f6fdef719e5351b</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_CHOICE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple -choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct. </instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>According to the passage what is that the bigger group wants?</title>
      <media>Listening - Multiple choice, choose single answer - Q9 Test 3-8.tpm</media>
      <delay>5</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>The community should identify the ninety-nine percent.</o0>
        <o1>The need of more punishment for the top one percent.</o1>
        <o2>To draw attention towards the problems faced by the ninety-nine percent</o2>
        <o3>To draw attention towards the strength of the bigger group.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>8c875a52621a4b7da877d5d7da6e8f3a</id>
    <practiceSet>05424cf5c42745de8f6fdef719e5351b</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_CHOICE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple -choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct. </instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>What is the focus of this year’s expedition energy concept demonstration?</title>
      <media>Listening - Multiple choice, choose single answer - Q10 Test 3-8.tpm</media>
      <delay>5</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>To go to industry and other government organizations to learn about new technology.</o0>
        <o1>To learn about the technology that can help make the company landing team better.</o1>
        <o2>To discover technologies to position marines 100 miles deep under the ground.</o2>
        <o3>To develop new ways of supplying the army in the battlefield.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>38346b0dc97743118c7c87393019ff80</id>
    <practiceSet>05424cf5c42745de8f6fdef719e5351b</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_SELECT_MISSING_WORD</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording on the lecture. At the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Select missing word - Q11 Test 3-8.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>in case</o0>
        <o1>the case</o1>
        <o2>in this case</o2>
        <o3>case</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>2483d85331734d558a311f80bec536ef</id>
    <practiceSet>05424cf5c42745de8f6fdef719e5351b</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_SELECT_MISSING_WORD</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording on CRACKING SOUNDS OF KNUCKLES. At the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Select missing word - Q12 Test 3-8.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>turning</o0>
        <o1>the crack</o1>
        <o2>the marks</o2>
        <o3>reversing</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>70e70e2578bd4d439511e8489c9b373c</id>
    <practiceSet>05424cf5c42745de8f6fdef719e5351b</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_HIGHLIGHT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Below is a transcription of the recording. Some words in the transcription differ from what the speaker(s) said. Please click on words that are different.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>At the same time, what's very fundamental to this market is that -- and again, an invention that we've designed for our exchange -- is that the exchange will operate warehouses around the country, in which score certification and warehouse receipting will be done. And in turn, we'll operate an in-house clearing system, to assure that transaction is done appropriately, in the right amount and at the right time, so that basically, we create trust and integrity in the system. Literally, we work with exchange actors, and as we're developing the exchange market itself, we're also developing the regulatory infrastructure and legal coursework, the overarching legal framework for making this market work.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Highlight Incorrect Words- Q13 Test 3-8.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      
      <answer>invention|score|transaction|Literally|coursework</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>1b10e0ab04fb4319831764cf24acb653</id>
    <practiceSet>05424cf5c42745de8f6fdef719e5351b</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_HIGHLIGHT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Below is a transcription of the recording. Some words in the transcription differ from what the speaker(s) said. Please click on words that are different. </instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>First, as a machine, I would analyze or I would input reality. Speech recognition and biometric authentication are great examples of a machine interacting with humans from an input perspective. Secondly, as a machinery, I could place digital information, or output information, into reality. Holograms are examples of a machine interacting with an environment from an output perception. Finally, as a machine, I could exchange energy with the globe via haptics.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Highlight Incorrect Words- Q14 Test 3-8.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      
      <answer>analyze|machinery|perception|globe</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>9b48e0e32f6a495eb823904077694b60</id>
    <practiceSet>05424cf5c42745de8f6fdef719e5351b</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Write from dictation- Q15 Test 3-8.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>The majority of the hardware we are using was built for a customer.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>0f07f92c5af14518a987b221771e6fa7</id>
    <practiceSet>05424cf5c42745de8f6fdef719e5351b</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Write from dictation- Q16 Test 3-8.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>Of course, you can also choose to have your grades email to you.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>8d1151efc4584deaa723ffd4806d515a</id>
    <practiceSet>05424cf5c42745de8f6fdef719e5351b</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Write from dictation- Q17 Test 3-8.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>Does the professor keep regular office hours?</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>c588a14c2f8042e880beae968feac937</id>
    <practiceSet>05424cf5c42745de8f6fdef719e5351b</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Write from dictation- Q18 Test 3-8.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>I will check again but I am pretty sure we are supposed to read chapter two.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <!-- Test 9 -->
  <question>
    <id>67c8451ad6394b829720e5078847ca6c</id>
    <practiceSet>db28642c43f44f048e0e1be5cf8984f6</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_WRITE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a short lecture. Write a summary for fellow student who was not present at the lecture. You should write 50-70 words. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points presented in the lecture.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Summarize Spoken Text - Q1 Test 3-9.tpm</media>
      <delay>10</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>The speaker is talking about Pan-African economy which is booming. The world is focusing on established markets and emerging economies like India and China and Africa is overlooked. This lack of industrialization has caused the dependence on imports. The speaker further says that it’s possible to solve this disconnect, by starting with products that people actually want.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>8f91eaf8061b41309c4d46ecde88a0ee</id>
    <practiceSet>db28642c43f44f048e0e1be5cf8984f6</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_WRITE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a short lecture. Write a summary for fellow student who was not present at the lecture. You should write 50-70 words. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points presented in the lecture.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Summarize Spoken Text - Q2 Test 3-9.tpm</media>
      <delay>10</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>The lecture is about future medicine, the speaker focuses on the past illness and treatments which has the dominance of antibiotics nowadays. It’s been 100 years when antibiotics were introduced in the United States. There has  been a huge transformation while recovering from any of the disease whether its pneumonia or tuberculosis, you kill the microbe and you cure the disease.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>2a9670b6502c4f279c5a447cfacabf8a</id>
    <practiceSet>db28642c43f44f048e0e1be5cf8984f6</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_SELECT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting  all the correct responses. You will need to select more than one response.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>The people surrounding the queen encouraged her to spend money ______.</title>
      <media>Listening - Multiple choice, choose multiple answers - Q3 Test 3-9.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>wisely</o0>
        <o1>abundantly</o1>
        <o2>carefully</o2>
        <o3>foolishly</o3>
        <o4>joyfully</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>1|3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>e1879ca3da4643b8a222509cc2b2f555</id>
    <practiceSet>db28642c43f44f048e0e1be5cf8984f6</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_SELECT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting  all the correct responses. You will need to select more than one response.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>The idea of flying an aircraft was ______ to some people.</title>
      <media>Listening - Multiple choice, choose multiple answers - Q4 Test 3-9.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>boring</o0>
        <o1>distasteful</o1>
        <o2>exciting</o2>
        <o3>needless</o3>
        <o4>repulsive</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>1|4</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>213b33bc796349e19a52133c223afe1e</id>
    <practiceSet>db28642c43f44f048e0e1be5cf8984f6</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_FILL_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Type the missing words in each blank.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Machine learning started making its way into industry in the early '90s. It started with relatively simple tasks. It started with things like assessing credit risk from loan applications, sorting the mail by reading {blank} characters from zip codes. Over the past few years, we have made dramatic breakthroughs. Machine learning is now capable of far, far more complex tasks. In 2012, Kaggle {blank} its community to build an algorithm that could grade high-school essays. The winning {blank} were able to match the grades given by human teachers. Last year, we issued an even more difficult challenge. Can you take images of the eye and diagnose an eye disease called diabetic {blank} ? Again, the winning algorithms were able to match the {blank} given by human ophthalmologists. </description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Fill in the blanks - Q5  Test 3-9.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      
      <answer>handwritten|challenged |algorithms |retinopathy|diagnoses</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>242697ab930d43dfafa1d273f5c0a4ae</id>
    <practiceSet>db28642c43f44f048e0e1be5cf8984f6</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_FILL_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Type the missing words in each blank.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>
        I'm going to talk today about energy and climate. And that might seem a bit surprising, because my full-time work at the {blank} is mostly about vaccines and seeds, about the things that we need to invent and deliver to help the poorest two billion live better lives. But energy and climate are {blank} important to these people; in fact, more important than to anyone else on the planet. The climate getting worse means that many years, their crops won't grow: there will be too much rain, not enough rain; things will change in ways their fragile environment simply can't support. And that leads to starvation, it leads to uncertainty, it leads to unrest. So, the climate changes will be {blank} for them.
        Also, the price of energy is very important to them. In fact, if you could pick just one thing to lower the price of to reduce poverty, by far you would pick energy. Now, the price of energy has come down over time. Really advanced {blank} is based on advances in energy. The coal revolution fueled the Industrial Revolution, and, even in the 1900s, we've seen a very rapid decline in the price of electricity, and that's why we have refrigerators, air-conditioning; we can make modern materials and do so many things. And so, we're in a wonderful situation with electricity in the rich world. But as we make it cheaper - and let's say, let's go for making it twice as cheap - we need to meet a new {blank} , and that constraint has to do with CO2.
      </description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Fill in the blanks - Q6  Test 3-9.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      
      <answer>foundation|extremely|terrible|civilization|constraint</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>264affa73da34e149e0a2824c04499ef</id>
    <practiceSet>db28642c43f44f048e0e1be5cf8984f6</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_HIGHLIGHT_CORRECT_SUMMARY</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Click on paragraph that best relates to the recording.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Highlight Correct Summary - Q7 Test 3-9.tpm</media>
      <delay>10</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>There are different ideas about evolution but only in Western culture. This is because the  Enlightenment only happened in the West.</o0>
        <o1>There are different ideas about evolution but these really only came about in the nineteenth century.</o1>
        <o2>There are different ideas about evolution and Alexander von Humboldt was a person as part of the Enlightenment who proposed some of these ideas.</o2>
        <o3>There are different ideas about evolution and this is why Arthur Conan Doyle wrote a novel about a lost world.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>5c121aaebd2a4c8c855a7419aee4d925</id>
    <practiceSet>db28642c43f44f048e0e1be5cf8984f6</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_HIGHLIGHT_CORRECT_SUMMARY</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Click on paragraph that best relates to the recording.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Highlight Correct Summary - Q8 Test 3-9.tpm</media>
      <delay>10</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>Classical music should be called songs because that is the terminology that is used on iTunes.</o0>
        <o1>Classical music should be called songs but only if they have lyrics; opera for example, can be called songs.</o1>
        <o2>Classical music should not be called songs because eighty percent is purely instrumental.</o2>
        <o3>Classical music should not be called songs because we should aim to be more sophisticated when referring to them.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>8017c345e65a4992bf56b9e93c66c9fc</id>
    <practiceSet>db28642c43f44f048e0e1be5cf8984f6</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_CHOICE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple -choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>What is true about the tube food, based on this passage?</title>
      <media>Listening - Multiple choice, choose single answer - Q9 Test 3-9.tpm</media>
      <delay>5</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>Deb Haly and Dan Nattress are the inventors of tube food mechanism.</o0>
        <o1>Military uses tube food mainly because of the variety and convenience.</o1>
        <o2>Natick soldier Research Centre in Massachusetts is the leader in food technology.</o2>
        <o3>Tube food technology has come a long way over the last couple of years.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>c59e39c77cbb41f391a38c5f0abaaef2</id>
    <practiceSet>db28642c43f44f048e0e1be5cf8984f6</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_CHOICE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple -choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>What is one of the drawbacks of going public?</title>
      <media>Listening - Multiple choice, choose single answer - Q10 Test 3-9.tpm</media>
      <delay>5</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>It opens up the company to a high degree of scrutiny from the government.</o0>
        <o1>It brings to the company to a large number of difficult to manage customers.</o1>
        <o2>It brings a lot of money to the company and unlocks the value in the enterprise</o2>
        <o3>It causes your stock to sell on markets like NASADAQ and New York Stock Exchange</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>e0be85aae57f4174b6f4070ba6a4cdf4</id>
    <practiceSet>db28642c43f44f048e0e1be5cf8984f6</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_SELECT_MISSING_WORD</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording on LIFE INSURANCE. At the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Select missing word - Q11 Test 3-9.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>to secure family.</o0>
        <o1>for their own benefit.</o1>
        <o2>their children.</o2>
        <o3>leads to diseased income.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>18e785fee382449e987dbe859fb39f3d</id>
    <practiceSet>db28642c43f44f048e0e1be5cf8984f6</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_SELECT_MISSING_WORD</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording on LAUGHTER. At the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Select missing word - Q12 Test 3-9.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>animate</o0>
        <o1>inspire</o1>
        <o2>quickens</o2>
        <o3>stimulates</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>3</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>cb9339fba6cb4261bb72599976602674</id>
    <practiceSet>db28642c43f44f048e0e1be5cf8984f6</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_HIGHLIGHT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Below is a transcription of the recording. Some words in the transcription differ from what the speaker(s) said. Please click on words that are different. </instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>
        The idea is that we divide the ward—the patients if you like—and the nurses into three different teams, which we call lively nursing teams. And in those teams we then have the primary nurse which is myself, associate nurses which might tend to be D grade nurses, and health care officials, and you're all in one team together. The idea is that you would hopefully work as a team on co-ordinating the care for the patients who come in under your care as in the red team. In our teams we have eight patients each. The Idea would be that I would always prescribe the care or plan the care, for those patients. In reality, it doesn't always work like that and besides which the associate nurses that are in the teams have those skills anyway from their upgrading.
      </description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Highlight Incorrect Words- Q13 Test 3-9.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      
      <answer>lively|might|officials|always|upgrading</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>ecb5a327eaad4d8884faae73c48241a5</id>
    <practiceSet>db28642c43f44f048e0e1be5cf8984f6</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_HIGHLIGHT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Below is a transcription of the recording. Some words in the transcription differ from what the speaker(s) said. Please click on words that are different. </instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>We've already started feeling the reverse effects of global warming. Forests have been destroyed due to the rise in population of pine beetle which expanded due to the lack of severe winters. Forests are also at a high risk of catching fires. There has been a fourfold increase in forest fires. The amount of carbon monoxide released due to these bog fires has resulted in fuel combustion. It’s been observed that over the past couple of decade, birds and butterflies have shifted their range northward by 200 kilometers in Europe and North America. Global warming has also had a devastating effect on health. The incidence of cardiovascular diseases has increased due to increased fluorocarbons in the atmosphere. Lung tissues are damaged leading to asthma. Hence, the mortality rate too has been affected. This global warming has led to a higher rate of dengue and malaria cases. These insect borne diseases are on the rise and the World Health Organization is working hard to eliminate them through vaccines.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Highlight Incorrect Words- Q14 Test 3-9.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      
      <answer>reverse|destroyed|monoxide|fluorocarbons|eliminate</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>7d86c5502577455c9488c88eb939eb17</id>
    <practiceSet>db28642c43f44f048e0e1be5cf8984f6</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Write from dictation- Q15 Test 3-9.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>I think the university’s main campus is closed.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>834d8319b8344af5afe7dc1d56e14b97</id>
    <practiceSet>db28642c43f44f048e0e1be5cf8984f6</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Write from dictation- Q16 Test 3-9.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>If your parents come to visit you this semester where will they stay? </answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>217aeed90e4540de9151f9b3e32c8f96</id>
    <practiceSet>db28642c43f44f048e0e1be5cf8984f6</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Write from dictation- Q17 Test 3-9.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>Inspite of being well settled in his job, he keeps on participating in paid activities.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>1ef6a5b74d914a4693feb4bce8ea4411</id>
    <practiceSet>db28642c43f44f048e0e1be5cf8984f6</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Write from dictation- Q18 Test 3-9.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>There is an urgent need for the local government to help the homeless.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <!-- Test 10 -->
  <question>
    <id>9f0b24b3a8e04ef69356199daf72e0fc</id>
    <practiceSet>4e1a53fbe93d491289754abda2ea6984</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_WRITE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a short lecture. Write a summary for fellow student who was not present at the lecture. You should write 50-70 words. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points presented in the lecture.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Summarize Spoken Text - Q1 Test 3-10.tpm</media>
      <delay>10</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>Center at USC did research on demographics and its affect on media and entertainment. Through social media, it’s easier to escape some of the demographic boxes. Media companies get connected quiet easily and can make some educated guesses and can get a lot more information about what your likes and interests. This shows that the taste of the person is being respected in a way that it hasn't been before.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>63e1057e19f8469591dc96fe935f9b86</id>
    <practiceSet>4e1a53fbe93d491289754abda2ea6984</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_WRITE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a short lecture. Write a summary for fellow student who was not present at the lecture. You should write 50-70 words. You have 10 minutes to finish this task. Your response will be judged on the quality of your writing and on how well your response presents the key points presented in the lecture.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:10:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Summarize Spoken Text - Q2 Test 3-10.tpm</media>
      <delay>10</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>Physicist working on radar during World War II noticed that magnetron was melting his chocolate bar and this led to invention of microwave oven. This is an ultimate example of creativity. Machines cannot compete with us when it can tackle any kind of situations, and this puts a fundamental limit on the task which is performed by the human.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>5ffcf4af70234b53b15e58ec6d1ed769</id>
    <practiceSet>4e1a53fbe93d491289754abda2ea6984</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_SELECT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct responses. You will need to select more than one response.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>According to the speaker, which of the following you have to offer to a person to get them to walk in a typical American city?</title>
      <media>Listening - Multiple choice, choose multiple answers - Q3 Test 3-10.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>A good and valid reason</o0>
        <o1>The walk should be safe and the person should feel safe</o1>
        <o2>Offer them that the walk will have good views</o2>
        <o3>Tell them that walk would be more interesting than driving</o3>
        <o4>Offer them a ride back home</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>0|1|4</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>906b607fe7094bf0a5acd404acec52d4</id>
    <practiceSet>4e1a53fbe93d491289754abda2ea6984</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_SELECT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple-choice question by selecting all the correct responses. You will need to select more than one response.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>According to the recording, which of the following statements are true about fresh water?</title>
      <media>Listening - Multiple choice, choose multiple answers - Q4 Test 3-10.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>75 percent of our planet is covered with fresh water</o0>
        <o1>It is unknown what percentage of fresh water is available for human consumption</o1>
        <o2>Fresh water resources are depleting at a fast rate</o2>
        <o3>Lack of fresh water is leading cause of death in old people in some countries</o3>
        <o4>A significant number of children die every year from a water-related disease</o4>
      </options>
      <answer>2|4</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>10e26f4441be4f848155d809dc224a13</id>
    <practiceSet>4e1a53fbe93d491289754abda2ea6984</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_FILL_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Type the missing words in each blank.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>There's a small country {blank} in the Himalayan Mountains, far from these beautiful mountains, where the people of the Kingdom of {blank} have decided to do something different, which is to measure their gross national {blank} rather than their gross national product. And why not? After all, happiness is not just a privilege for the lucky few, but a {blank} human right for all. And what is happiness? Happiness is the freedom of choice. The freedom to {blank} , where to live, what to do, what to buy, what to sell, from whom, to whom, when and how.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Fill in the blanks - Q5 Test 3-10.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      
      <answer>nestled|Bhutan|happiness|fundamental|choose</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>83df7a57915345e697cf5c10e0bba729</id>
    <practiceSet>4e1a53fbe93d491289754abda2ea6984</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_FILL_BLANKS</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Type the missing words in each blank.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>Scientists think that {blank} fields may act more like the sails on a ship, enabling the planet to interact with more energy from the solar wind than the planet would have been able to interact with by itself. The sails may gather energy from the solar wind. The magnetic field may gather energy from the solar wind that allows even more {blank} escape to happen. It's an idea that has to be tested, but the effect and how it works seems {blank} . That's because we know energy from the solar wind is being deposited into our atmosphere here on Earth. That energy is conducted along magnetic field lines down into the polar regions, resulting in {blank} beautiful aurora. If you've ever experienced them, it's {blank} . We know the energy is getting in. We're trying to measure how many particles are getting out and if the magnetic field is influencing this in any way.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Fill in the blanks - Q6 Test 3-10.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      
      <answer>magnetic|atmospheric|apparent|incredibly|magnificent</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>d2de811cc8d840aba36b687e2ccbd86a</id>
    <practiceSet>4e1a53fbe93d491289754abda2ea6984</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_HIGHLIGHT_CORRECT_SUMMARY</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Click on paragraph that best relates to the recording.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Highlight Correct Summary - Q7 Test 3-10.tpm</media>
      <delay>10</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>Due to the Rwandan genocide normal equipment can be very expensive in some parts of Rwanda. For example the cost of shipping a bulldozer to remote regions is prohibitive.</o0>
        <o1>An engineer named Nizeye had been working in Rwanda for many years. He was brilliant and liked to help the local people because they were very poor and had suffered during the war.</o1>
        <o2>Nizeye incorporated the local culture into his building projects. He also provided work opportunities for locals. Thus the building process could support the whole community.</o2>
        <o3>In Rawanda it is legally required that building projects involve mainly local workers. This helps to restore job opportunities.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>d9dbcf7c34ef46e8b89983ae79b5b1fe</id>
    <practiceSet>4e1a53fbe93d491289754abda2ea6984</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_HIGHLIGHT_CORRECT_SUMMARY</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Click on paragraph that best relates to the recording.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Highlight Correct Summary - Q8 Test 3-10.tpm</media>
      <delay>10</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>There are both advantages and disadvantages of social media in the workplace. On one side, a company’s brand can become stronger. On the other side, there is a a chance that the company’s brand will become weaker if an employee says something negative about the company.</o0>
        <o1>Because social media can stop employees working, some employers prevent them from using social media. However, these employers do not enjoy the benefits that social media can bring, such as an increase in customer demand for their product or a stronger brand.</o1>
        <o2>Social media can help employers to develop their businesses and find new staff. However, it is a problem when an employee criticizes the company online or spends too much time using social media. To stop employees spending time on social media, employers must develop and challenge their staff.</o2>
        <o3>Employers only see the negative side of social media because they have too many problems with employees being rude or spending too much time using social media instead of working. Because this situation is challenging, it is easier for companies to stop the use of social media.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>da2ec239b13144728bbbdefa88f1a1ec</id>
    <practiceSet>4e1a53fbe93d491289754abda2ea6984</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_CHOICE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple -choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct. </instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>Which of the following is true according to the speaker?</title>
      <media>Listening - Multiple choice, choose single answer - Q9 Test 3-10.tpm</media>
      <delay>5</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>The concept of reasonable force is very clearly defined.</o0>
        <o1>Your use of force may be judged on how strong you are compared to the other person.</o1>
        <o2>If you hit someone first, you cannot then claim self-defense.</o2>
        <o3>Courts do not expect ordinary people to react rationally.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>1</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>0ecaddb5c074486fa935c24e554923d1</id>
    <practiceSet>4e1a53fbe93d491289754abda2ea6984</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_MULTI_CHOICE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>Listen to the recording and answer the multiple -choice question by selecting the correct response. Only one response is correct. </instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title>In the speaker’s opinion, which of the following is true of editors who are also novelists?</title>
      <media>Listening - Multiple choice, choose single answer - Q10 Test 3-10.tpm</media>
      <delay>5</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>They are always able to see the novel from the author’s point of view.</o0>
        <o1>They are sympathetic to the difficult lives authors lead.</o1>
        <o2>They may try to re-shape the novelist’s work in their own way.</o2>
        <o3>They find it difficult to see the author’s real intentions.</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>f94f99098678431f926270fe32d9ea9e</id>
    <practiceSet>4e1a53fbe93d491289754abda2ea6984</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_SELECT_MISSING_WORD</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording on AGEING. At the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Select missing word - Q11 Test 3-10.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>to control</o0>
        <o1>for skin coverage</o1>
        <o2>in the right way</o2>
        <o3>for protection</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>2</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>3bb05e4c65ba421ba33a087fc313f082</id>
    <practiceSet>4e1a53fbe93d491289754abda2ea6984</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_SELECT_MISSING_WORD</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording on PANADA. At the end of the recording the last word or group of words has been replaced by a beep. Select the correct option to complete the recording.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Select missing word - Q12 Test 3-10.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <options>
        <o0>throughout the year</o0>
        <o1>in a year</o1>
        <o2>twice a year</o2>
        <o3>every year</o3>
      </options>
      <answer>0</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>e75ccf60a30746eeb1632c99ed410592</id>
    <practiceSet>4e1a53fbe93d491289754abda2ea6984</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_HIGHLIGHT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Below is a transcription of the recording. Some words in the transcription differ from what the speaker(s) said. Please click on words that are different. </instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>The very first year, beginning when Gagarin went in space, and a few weeks later Alan Shepherd, there were five manned space flights in the world -- the very first year. In 2003, everyone that the United States sent to space was murdered. There were only three or four flights in 2003. In 2004, there were only two flights: two Russian Soyuz flights to the international manned station. And I had to fly three in Mojave with my little group of a twice dozen people in order to get to a average of five, which was the number the same year back in 1961. There is no growing. There's no activity. There's no nothing.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Highlight Incorrect Words- Q13 Test 3-10.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      
      <answer>beginning|murdered|twice|average|growing</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>3622e13852684638a7831f69a3ca6a2b</id>
    <practiceSet>4e1a53fbe93d491289754abda2ea6984</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_HIGHLIGHT</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a recording. Below is a transcription of the recording. Some words in the transcription differ from what the speaker(s) said. Please click on words that are different. </instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description>For us moderns, virtuoso technique is used to create imaginary worlds in factual and in movies, to express extreme emotions with music, painting and dance. But still, one fundamental trait of the ancestor personality persists in our aesthetic cravings: the beauty we find in good performances. From Lascaux to the Louvre to Carnegie Hall, human beings have a permanently innate taste for virtuoso displays in the arts. We find beauty in something done well.</description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Highlight Incorrect Words- Q14 Test 3-10.tpm</media>
      <delay>8</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      
      <answer>factual|extreme|ancestor|good|permanently</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>79a55809b8a546dd8260949f692a630e</id>
    <practiceSet>4e1a53fbe93d491289754abda2ea6984</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Write from dictation- Q15 Test 3-10.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>We already live in a world where real-time universal translators exist. </answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>5eaa80ce9f15465b9f4d4059d5692cc7</id>
    <practiceSet>4e1a53fbe93d491289754abda2ea6984</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Write from dictation- Q16 Test 3-10.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>For a whole decade it was for fun, we didn't even know what it was for.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>7af471540fb64689ae6d02d2a6a9c355</id>
    <practiceSet>4e1a53fbe93d491289754abda2ea6984</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Write from dictation- Q17 Test 3-10.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>Students are held accountable for adhering to established community standards.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
  <question>
    <id>b49d96d6d17c48b4bb4b37ca4b716be8</id>
    <practiceSet>4e1a53fbe93d491289754abda2ea6984</practiceSet>
    <type>LISTEN_AND_DICTATE</type>
    <itemType>LISTENING</itemType>
    <instruction>You will hear a sentence. Type the sentence in the box below exactly as you hear it. Write as much of the sentence as you can. You will hear the sentence only once.</instruction>
    <delayTime>00:00:00</delayTime>
    <attemptTime>00:00:00</attemptTime>
    <template>
      <description></description>
      <title></title>
      <media>Listening - Write from dictation- Q18 Test 3-10.tpm</media>
      <delay>7</delay>
      <maxWordCount>100</maxWordCount>
      <answer>The brief outline takes us to the beginning of the 20th century.</answer>
    </template>
  </question>
</questions>